<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>City of Walls and Secrets</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to two fox antelopes, grazing on a hill side. They look
                up at the monorail tracks behind them as a monorail goes past, pushed by two
                earthbenders. Cut to inside the car where Aang, Katara, Sokka, Toph, and Momo are
                awaiting their arrival at Ba Sing Se. Katara looks out from the window and notices
                the Inner Wall of the Earth Kingdom capital drawing closer.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Look, the Inner Wall! <charAction>Cut to a shot
                of the monorail approaching the wall. Cut back inside monorail.</charAction> I can't
            believe we finally made it to Ba Sing Se in one piece.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly skeptically.</charAction> Hey, don't jinx it! We can still be
            attacked by some giant exploding Fire Nation spoon. Or find out the city's been
            submerged in an ocean full of killer shrimp!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly annoyed, yet still jokingly.</charAction> You been hitting the
            cactus juice again?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm just sayin', weird stuff happens to us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A man, sucking a corn plant in his mouth, takes a seat between Toph and
                Sokka, startling them. The scene changes to Aang and Katara looking out the windows,
                the former closing his eyes sadly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sympathetically.</charAction> Don't worry Aang, we'll find
            Appa.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Doubtfully.</charAction> It's such a big city.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Somewhat optimistically.</charAction> He's a giant bison! Where could
            someone possibly hide him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene shows the monorail entering the Inner Wall. Cut to Sokka, Katara,
                and Aang viewing the giant city through the windows.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Realizing the city's gigantic size.</charAction> Oh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The three notice that Ba Sing Se stretches almost as far as their eyes can
                see, and it has many roads and buildings. Their train enters the monorail station,
                stopping there. All of them disembark.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Back in the city. Great.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> What's the problem? It's amazing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot shows Sokka and Toph with Momo resting on her
                shoulder.</charAction> It's just a bunch of walls and rules. You wait, you'll get
            sick of it in a couple of days.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to Aang looking at the bison whistle in his palm, and he
                blows it. </description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm comin' for ya, buddy. <charAction>Katara walks over to the downtrodden Aang, and
                places her hand on his shoulder. More confidently.</charAction> He's here; I can
            feel it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot changes to the monorail departing, behind the team. Cut to the
                other side of the track, where there is a woman with long dark hair that billows in
                the wind. She approaches them with a strange smile on her face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excited.</charAction> Hello, my name is Joo Dee! I have been given the
            great honor of showing the Avatar around Ba Sing Se. And you must be Sokka, Katara, and
            Toph! Welcome to our wonderful city. Shall we get started?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yes. We have information about the Fire Nation army that we need to deliver to the
            Earth King, immediately.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Great! Let's begin our tour. And then I'll show you to your new home here. I think
            you'll like it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly annoyed.</charAction> Ugh! <charAction>Walks up to Joo
                Dee.</charAction> Maybe you missed what I said. We need to talk to the king about
            the War, it's important.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up on Joo Dee's face.</charAction> You're in Ba Sing Se now.
            Everyone is safe here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar has a confused look on their faces regarding Joo Dee's strange
                statement. Cut to an overhead shot of the area of the city near the wall. An ostrich
                horse pulls a carriage through the streets. Many shops and refugees line the
                streets. Cut to a shot of the inside of the carriage containing Joo Dee and Team
                Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>This is the Lower Ring.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What's that wall for?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, Ba Sing Se has many walls! There are the ones outside protecting us, and the
            ones inside, that help maintain order. <charAction>Shot changes to outside the carriage
                as the camera pans across some refugees.</charAction> This is where our newest
            arrivals live, as well as our craftsman and artisans, people that work with their hands.
                <charAction>Shot changes back to inside the carriage.</charAction> It's so quaint
            and lively!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of two men conversing in an alley. One of them is holding a
                large sword that glistens in the light. Both glare at the carriage as it passes. Cut
                back to the carriage, where Katara becomes unnerved, her face blanking out, while
                Momo, who was looking out of the window by hanging from the ceiling, quickly
                retreats completely into the carriage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> You do want to watch your step, though.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervous look on her face.</charAction> Why do they have all these poor
            people blocked off in one part of the city?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Upset and somewhat bored.</charAction> This is why I never came here
            before. I always heard it was so different from the way the monks taught us to live.
                <charAction>Looks out the window.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to another part of the Lower Ring. Cut to Zuko walking
                down the street. Iroh catches up to him from behind, holding a large vase with
                several orange flowers placed in it. Cut to a close-up of Zuko staring coldly at the
                flora and Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I just want our place to look nice, in case someone brings home a lady friend!
                <charAction>He gives Zuko a nudge with the elbow.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bleakly.</charAction> This city is a prison. I don't want to make a life
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to overhead view of the street they are walking down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Life happens wherever you are, whether you make it or not. Now come on, I found us
            some new jobs, and we start this afternoon!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot from behind Zuko and Iroh as they walk away. Someone's feet
                step out in front. Cut to a close-up of Jet staring angrily at the two
                firebenders.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Look at them, firebenders living right under everyone's nose.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot and Smellerbee walk up to Jet from an alley.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, you saw a man with a hot cup of tea. It doesn't prove he's a firebender. And
            what if he is, are we supposed to attack them‌? I thought we were starting over here,
            changing our ways.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>We are. When I get the evidence I need, I'll report them to the police and let them
            handle it. <charAction>Walks forward a bit and turns his head to face the
                pair.</charAction> Ok‌ay?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Smellerbee and Longshot exchange glances. Cut to a shot of the Middle Ring,
                where Joo Dee is continuing the tour in the carriage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>This is the Middle Ring of Ba Sing Se, home to the financial district, shops and
            restaurants, and the university.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to side-view of carriage. Aang and Sokka looks out of the windows,
                bored.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, we met a professor from the Ba Sing Se University. He took us to an ancient
            underground library where we discovered information about the war that is
                <charAction>Cut to inside carriage. Leaning toward Joo Dee, losing his
                patience.</charAction>
            <description>absolutely crucial for the Earth King to hear</description>!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling; excitedly.</charAction> Isn't history fascinating? Look, here's
            one of the oldest buildings in the Middle Ring, Town Hall!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The carriage stops and Joo Dee exits. Sokka stares at her,
                annoyed.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Is that woman deaf? She only seems to hear every other word I say.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It's called "being handled". Get used to it. <charAction>Crosses her arms as
                everyone else glares sadly at Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a small tea shop in the Lower Ring, with Jet leaning
                against the shop's wall. He turns around and peeks inside the window, spotting Zuko
                and Iroh speaking with the shop's owner. Cut to Jet's view.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pao">Pao</speaker>
        <speech>Well, you certainly look like official tea servers. <charAction>Cut to close-up of
                Pao.</charAction> How do you feel‌?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Zuko and Iroh wearing aprons. Iroh desperately attempts to tie the
                string behind his back, but his effort is in vain.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Ridiculous.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, does this possibly come in a larger size? <charAction>Cut to a view behind Iroh
                with the apron strings not quite long enough to tie.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to side-view of the threesome.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pao">Pao</speaker>
        <speech>I have extra string in the back. Have some tea while you wait!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pao pours some tea in two cups, hands them to his new employees, and heads
                to the back of the shop. Cut to frontal view of Iroh and Zuko. Iroh takes a sip from
                his cup, but his face contorts in disgust.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Quickly holds the cup at a distance.</charAction> Blech!
                <charAction>Looks at it in disgust.</charAction> This tea is nothing more than hot
            leaf juice!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Iroh closely examines his cup. In an annoyed tone.</charAction> Uncle,
            that's what all tea is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> How could a member of my own family say something
            so horrible?! We'll have to make some major changes around here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh angrily takes the tea pot and heads over to the window Jet is spying
                through. Jet gasps and moves away just in time as Iroh dumps the tea out the window.
                Jet slowly stalks around the corner of the shop and leaves. The scene changes to the
                carriage in which Team Avatar is touring in, which is now in the Upper
                Ring.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>The Upper Ring is home to our most important citizens. Your house is not too far
            from here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to the carriage passing by another wall with a tall gate. Behind it,
                the roof of an enormous building can be seen.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up.</charAction> What's inside that wall?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a closer view of the tall gate. Three men are standing in the
                gateway, wearing dark robes and wide brimmed hats turn their eyes toward the group,
                looking somewhat hateful at them. Cut to inside the carriage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And who're the mean-looking guys in robes?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Inside is the Royal Palace. Those men are agents of the Dai Li, the cultural
            authority of Ba Sing Se. They are the guardians of all our traditions!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view. Bored and annoyed.</charAction> Can we see the king
            now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view.</charAction> Oh no, one doesn't just pop in on the Earth
            King!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Overhead view of inside of carriage. Aang nods his head, sadly. Cut to a
                shot of sky, with Momo flying, and descending and landing on the roof of a small
                house.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Here we are! Your new home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to behind the gang looking down at Joo Dee. A messenger comes, gives
                Joo Dee a scroll, and leaves.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view.</charAction> More good news! Your request for an audience
            with the Earth King is being processed, and should be put through in about month.
                <charAction>Cut to behind the gang looking down at Joo Dee.</charAction> Much more
            quickly than usual!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view of Team Avatar. Surprised.</charAction> A month?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view. Smiling widely.</charAction> Six to eight weeks,
            actually. <charAction>Closes her eyes and grins.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a brief shot of the house before cutting to the
                inside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up side-view.</charAction> Isn't it nice? I think you'll really
            enjoy it here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to view of entire room from the back.</charAction> I think we would
            enjoy it more if we weren't staying for so long. Can't we see the Earth King
                any sooner?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view over Sokka's shoulder. Smiling.</charAction> The Earth
            King is very busy running the finest city in the world! <charAction>Close-up on Sokka,
                as an annoyed expression covers his face.</charAction> But he will see you as soon
            as time permits.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Momo and Aang. Aang turns to look out the window
                determined.</charAction> If we're going to be here for a month, we should spend our
            time looking for Appa. <charAction>At the sound of Appa's name, Momo wakes
                up.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of Aang with Joo Dee behind. Bows.</charAction> I'd like to
            escort you anywhere you'd like to go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Katara and Toph. Annoyed.</charAction> We don't
                need a babysitter.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to view of room from the back. Toph gets up and walks toward the
                door.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I won't get in the way. <charAction>She takes a step, blocking Toph's
                path.</charAction> And to leave you alone would make me a bad host!
                <charAction>Close-up of Toph, from behind, with Joo Dee in front.</charAction> Where
            shall we start?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph turns around in annoyance. The scene changes to a brief overhead shot
                of the city before changing to a bowl of food tied to a pole. Momo jumps on the bowl
                and starts to eat, but is scared by a cat owl, who screeches at him. Cut to a shot
                of the room, where Team Avatar, accompanied by Joo Dee, is in a pet store and
                speaking with the owner at the counter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pet store owner">Pet store owner</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot.</charAction> I'm sorry, but I haven't heard anything
            about a flying bison. I didn't even know there were
            any.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to shot of Aang and Sokka, Joo Dee lurking behind.</charAction> If
            someone wanted to sell a stolen animal without anyone knowing, where would they
            go‌?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly frustrated.</charAction> Where's the black market? Who runs it?
                <charAction>Pointing at him accusingly.</charAction> Come on, you know!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pet store owner">Pet store owner</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot. Nervous and perspiring.</charAction> Uh ...
                <charAction>Looks at Joo Dee, who is standing behind Sokka and Aang, shaking her
                head.</charAction> That would be illegal. You'll have to leave now; your lemur is
            harassing my sparrowkeets.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of Momo eating the birds' food while defending himself from
                the sparrowkeets. The scene fades to an overhead shot of Ba Sing Se University, and
                cuts to Team Avatar standing in front of a student. A few students are walking
                around.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="University student">University student</speaker>
        <speech>Hmm ... I've never seen any sandbenders or nomads around here. <charAction>Frontal
                shot.</charAction> You should ask Professor Zei, he teaches the class on desert
            cultures.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction>
            Right. And which of your professors could we ask about the
            war with the Fire Nation?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="University student">University student</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Uh ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The student looks at Joo Dee, behind Sokka, who shakes her head at him.
                Sokka notices this from the corner of his eye, but she quickly stops before he can
                see it fully.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="University student">University student</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot. Still very nervous.</charAction> I don't know. I'm not a
            political science student ... I've got to get to class.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He stands up and goes away, but trips, dropping his scrolls. He quickly
                picks them back up, and hurries to go. Joo Dee waves at him, smiling.</description>
            <description>Cut to a shot of Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Toph standing at the steps of
                their house. Joo Dee is still sitting in the carriage, and talking to them through
                the window.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I'm sorry no one has seen your bison. Why don't you go get some rest‌?
                <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Someone will be over with dinner, later.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As the carriage drives off, Sokka, followed by the rest of the gang,
                notices a man in the house across from them peeking through a window at them.
                Close-up shot of the man's door as his head recedes back. Cut back to the gang from
                behind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He gestures to the rest of Team Avatar to follow him.</charAction> Hey,
            come with me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone follows Sokka across the street. Cut to a shot of Sokka knocking
                on the front door. The same man appears and opens the door, smiling at
                them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pong">Pong</speaker>
        <speech>You're the Avatar! <charAction>Side-view of gang.</charAction> I heard you were in
            town. <charAction>Overhead view.</charAction> I'm Pong.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of gang. Smiles.</charAction> Nice to meet you, Pong.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So, Pong, what's goin' on with this city? Why is everyone here so scared here to
            talk about the war?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pong">Pong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Shifts his eyes to the sides.</charAction> War? Scared?
            What do you mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Slightly annoyed.</charAction> I can feel you
            shaking.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pong">Pong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Look, I'm just a minor government official.
                <charAction>Looks to the sides to confirm that no one is present except
                them.</charAction> I've waited three years to get this house. I don't want go get
            into trouble.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tight side-view of the gang and Pong.</charAction> Get in trouble with
            who?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pong">Pong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puts his finger on his mouth, and whispers.</charAction> Shh, listen,
            you can't mention the War here. <charAction>Overhead view.</charAction> And whatever you
            do, stay away from the Dai Li.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As he closes the door, everyone looks at each other's faces in confusion.
                Fade to a shot of some apartments. Jet spies on Zuko and Iroh, from a balcony in the
                shadows, hiding behind a clothesline in the apartment across theirs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Would you like a pot of tea?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of Jet.</charAction> We've been working in a tea shop all day!
                <charAction>View from the outside in to the window where Zuko lays on a
                bed.</charAction> I'm sick of tea!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pan across to Iroh through another window.</charAction> "Sick of tea?"
            That's like being sick of breathing! <charAction>He rummages through the cupboard
                beneath the counter, where he is standing. Close-up view of kettle.</charAction>
            Have you seen the spark rocks to heat up the water?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view. Whispering to himself.</charAction> They're not there.
                <charAction>Opens his fist to show some emerald colored rocks. Close-up
                side-view.</charAction> You'll have to firebend, old man. <charAction>He sees Iroh
                going inside, and narrows his eyes.</charAction> Where're you going?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>View through window. Coming back to the counter.</charAction> I borrowed
            our neighbors'. Such kind people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Close-up of kettle. He strikes the rocks near a pile of twigs below the
                teapot, and creates a flame. Jet, frustrated, ducks behind the clothesline and
                leaves.</description>
            <description>Fade the next morning, and the scene changes to a blue jay chirping, before
                the camera pans down to Team Avatar's house. Cut to Katara coming out from the door,
                yawning and stretching. She takes a roll of papers on a mail slot attached to the
                wall, and reads it briefly, gasping with excitement, before running back inside. The
                others are all lounging around the upper part of the living room, and she runs to
                inform them about the information in the roll.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I got it! I know how we're going to see the Earth King!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> How are we supposed to do that?
                <charAction>Mimicking Joo Dee.</charAction> "One doesn't just
                pop in on the Earth King!"</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of her and Aang. Reading from the papers.</charAction> The
            king is having a party at the palace tonight for his pet bear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You mean, platypus bear?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, it just says 'bear'.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view. He is lying upside down.</charAction> Certainly you mean
            his pet skunk bear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Or his armadillo bear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Gopher bear?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of room.</charAction> Just ... bear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>This place ... is weird.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Growing excited again.</charAction> The palace will be packed. We can
            sneak in with the crowd!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lies down.</charAction> Won't work.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Slightly confused.</charAction> Why not?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Over Katara's shoulder view.</charAction> Well, no offense to you simple
            country folk, but a real society crowd will spot you a mile away. You've got no manners!
                <charAction>Takes a pastry from a bowl and eats it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Excuse me? <description>I've</description>
            got no manners?! You're not exactly "lady fancy fingers!"</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Burps. Over Katara's shoulder view.</charAction> I learned proper
            society behavior and chose to leave it. <charAction>Throws
                the half eaten pastry to the side.</charAction> You never learned anything. And
            frankly, it's a little too late. <charAction>She picks her nose and flicks the snot off
                her finger.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of room. Excitedly.</charAction> Aha, but you learned it! You
            could teach us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I'm mastering every element. How hard could manners be‌?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang grabs a nearby curtain and puts it around himself like a noble's robe,
                and talks in a very sophisticated manner.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Good evening, Mr. Sokka Water Tribe, Ms. Katara Water Tribe, Lord Momo of the Momo
            Dynasty. Your Momo-ness. <charAction>Frontal view of Momo as he peeks at Aang from under
                the carpet and slightly bows.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up also wearing a curtain like a robe. Mimicking a typical high
                class person.</charAction> Avatar Aang, how do you do? Go on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang bows to Sokka, and Sokka, trying to outdo Aang's bow, bows back. Aang
                tries to further out do Sokka's bow with a deeper bow and Sokka returns this bow
                with an even deeper bow. Both of them try to bow at the same time, but they knock
                each other's foreheads' together and fall down.</description>
            <description>Toph walks toward Katara with the legs of Aang and Sokka seen on the
                floor.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Katara might be able to pull it off, but you two would be lucky to pass as
            busboys!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Sokka and Aang, who are still on the ground with curtains still on
                top of them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But I feel so fancy! <charAction>Toph's snot falls on Sokka's
            forehead.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a shot of house, at dusk, and changes to inside the
                house, where Sokka and Aang are playing a game. Close-up of their
                hands.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Closing his hands into a fist.</charAction> Earth!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wriggling his hands.</charAction> Fire!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka grumbles at losing the game, while Aang raises his hands,
                triumphantly, and flicks Sokka's forehead while grinning. Katara and Toph enter the
                room from a door, wearing makeup, exquisite Earth Kingdom dresses, and holding a fan
                each. Toph and Katara stare at the boys calmly before giving in to a fit of giggles.
                Aang blushes and stares dreamily at the sight of Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stunned.</charAction> Wow, you look beautiful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka flicks Aang's forehead. Katara opens her mouth to reply to Aang's
                compliment, but is stopped by Toph placing her fans in front of her
                mouth.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Don't talk to the commoners, Katara. First rule of society.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the room as Aang and Sokka watch the two girls
                leave.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Sokka and Aang.</charAction> We'll get in the party, and then find a
            way to let you in through the side gate.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sound of a gong is heard as Momo walks past them, wearing one of the
                curtains as a cape. Aang looks at Sokka, who merely shrugs.</description>
            <description>Cut to outside the tea shop where Iroh and Zuko are working. A man walks in
                through the door. Jet is shown to be spying on the shop from an alley. Cut to
                close-up of Jet's face with an expression of suspicion. Cut to a view behind him.
                Smellerbee and Longshot walk up behind Jet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, we need to talk.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>What‌? Oh great, it's you guys. Where have you been‌? <charAction>Overhead view of
                alley.</charAction> I could use some help with surveillance here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>We've been talking, <charAction>Cut to side-view of the threesome, tea shop in
                background.</charAction> and we think you're becoming obsessed with this. It's not
            healthy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot.</charAction> Oh, really? You both think this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Frontal view of Longshot and Smellerbee. Longshot places his arm on
                Smellerbee's shoulder in agreement with her statement.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>We came here to make a fresh start. But you won't let this go. Even though there is
            no real proof!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Well, maybe if you'd help me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of threesome.</charAction> Jet, you gotta stop this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe you've forgotten why we need to start over. <charAction>View of Longshot and
                Smellerbee from behind Jet. Longshot and Smellerbee look down,
                guiltily.</charAction> Maybe you've forgotten about how the Fire Nation left us all
            homeless‌. How they wiped out all the people we loved. If you don't want to help me,
            I'll get the evidence on my own. <charAction>He goes toward the tea
            shop.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to outside of tea shop, before switching to its interior, where Iroh is
                pouring tea to a customer.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Customer">Customer</speaker>
        <speech>This is the best tea in the city!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> The secret ingredient is love. <charAction>He
                waves a hand through the steam coming from the teapot and walks toward the back of
                the shop where the owner is, while Zuko gives him a disgusted
            look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pao">Pao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view. Turning to Iroh.</charAction> I think you're due for a
            raise.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the door as it is suddenly slammed open by Jet; he
                enters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I'm tired of waiting! <charAction>Pointing an accusing finger at Iroh and
                Zuko.</charAction> These two men are firebenders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet unsheathes his hook swords and prepares to fight. View from behind Jet.
                Iroh and Zuko quickly exchange a look, not knowing what to do. Cut to view of Iroh
                at the back of the tea shop with Jet at the entrance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I know they're firebenders, I saw the old man heating his tea!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Customer">Customer</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Bleakly.</charAction> He works in a tea shop.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> He's a firebender! I'm
                telling you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Customer">Customer</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Stands up, along with another man.</charAction> Drop your
            swords, boy. Nice and easy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. To Zuko.</charAction> You'll have to defend yourself. Then
            everyone will know. Go ahead, show them what you can do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet slowly walks toward Zuko and Iroh with his swords. Just as one of the
                customers is about to draw his swords, Zuko steps in front and grabs them
                instead.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You want a show? I'll give you a show!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko takes the customer's broadswords and enters a fighting stance. He
                pulls a table in front of him with his foot and kicks it at Jet, who slices the
                table with his swords and jumps over it. As he lands, he swings both hook swords at
                the Fire Nation prince, who deflects the attack and jumps backward on to another
                table, which is sliced in half by Jet, swinging one sword through the middle of the
                table. Zuko steps onto one half of the table and balances on one foot. Jet continues
                his attack by cutting the legs on the half of the table Zuko is standing on. Zuko
                quickly jumps up, and as he lands, he swings both broadswords at Jet's feet, and Jet
                somersaults away and lands in a crouching position before charging forward at Zuko
                again. Zuko swings both of his swords at Jet. Just as both weapons clash together,
                the scene freezes and cuts to the Ba Sing Se Palace. Several high class citizens are
                lined up and being admitted inside by a guard, who is checking the invitation of one
                group before letting them pass. Toph and Katara are next in line and approach
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Invitation please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Formally.</charAction> I think this will do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph shows the official seal of the Beifong family to the guard. The camera
                cuts to a closer, detailed shot of the seal, before cutting to the
                guard.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>No entry without an invitation. Step out of line, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> Look, the Pangs and the Yum Soon Hans are
            waiting in there for us! I'm going to have to tell them who
            didn't let me in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unyielding.</charAction> Step out of line please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As the guard points his finger to the side, Katara and Toph move out
                disappointedly, when Katara notices a carriage, from which Long Feng comes out, and
                two Dai Li agents bow to him. Katara has an idea, and she, along with Toph, go to
                the leader of the Dai Li.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view.</charAction> Sir, I'm sorry to bother you, but my cousin lost
            our invitations. <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> She's blind. <charAction>Again,
                normally.</charAction> Do you think you could help us? Our family's inside and I'm
            sure they're very worried.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up view as he smiles and bows his head.</charAction> I am honored,
            please come with me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Long Feng walks toward the guard at the entrance with Toph and Katara
                following him. The guard bows to him and the three of them go into the palace. As
                they are walking in, Toph and Katara stick their tongues out at the guard while his
                back is turned. The scene changes to an overhead shot inside the palace. At one end
                of the table is Bosco the bear eating a steak, his drool dripping of his chin.
                Seated to either side of him are two guests.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Older guest">Older guest</speaker>
        <speech>He's taking all the good stuff!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Younger guest">Younger guest</speaker>
        <speech>Quiet! You don't know what I had to do to get seats this
            near the bear!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Bosco slightly hits the younger guest before pouncing onto the table and
                eating a large plate of meat in front of him. Cut to a close shot of the bear
                gorging. As he moves his head, Toph, Katara, and Long Feng walk into the
                hall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>It's beautiful, isn't it? <charAction>Close-up shot. Turning to the
                girls.</charAction> By the way, I'm Long Feng. I'm a cultural minister to the
            king.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>View of her and Toph.</charAction> I'm Kwa Mai, and this is ... Dum.
                <charAction>Toph frowns and pulls a string hanging from Katara's headdress, causing
                her pain.</charAction> Ow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot.</charAction> Now where is your family? I'd
                love to meet them.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view. Feigning looking around.</charAction> Uh ... I don't see them
            right now, but I'm sure we'll find them soon. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> Thanks
            for all your help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As they walk away, Long Feng appears in front of them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, as your escort it would be dishonorable to abandon you ladies without
            finding your family first. We'll keep looking. <charAction>He turns around and leads the
                two girls, while Katara glances at Toph, nervously.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to outside the palace. Aang peeks around the pedestal of a statue of a
                lion. Cut to a shot of Aang and Sokka peeking around both sides of the
                pedestal.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Worried and nervous.</charAction> Where are they?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Sokka duck behind the pedestal.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Look, I came up with a back-up plan. <charAction>He picks Momo up.</charAction> We
            dress Momo like a ghost, okay? <charAction>Moves Momo in a circle.</charAction> He flies
            by the guards, creating a distraction. Then, we blast a hole in the wall-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang stands up and looks over the pedestal, and points to some busboys, as
                Sokka stands up. Cut to some busboys unloading supplies from a carriage and taking
                them inside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Or we could go in as these guys. Toph said we might pass as busboys!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of Aang and Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay ... <charAction>Rolls his eyes.</charAction> But remember that Momo ghost plan.
            I think it's a winner. <charAction>Smiling, he and Aang sink behind the
                pedestal.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to outside the tea shop, as Zuko bursts out through the
                door and tumbles onto the street. Jet runs after him and strikes at Zuko with both
                swords. Zuko defends the strike and both combatants lock swords.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot with a sinister grin.</charAction> You must be getting
            tired of using those swords. <charAction>Close-up shot of Zuko with a look of
                annoyance.</charAction> Why don't you go ahead and firebend at me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>View behind the fighters as they move off screen to reveal Zuko at the door
                to the tea shop.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Please, son, you're confused! You don't know what you're doing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Jet and Zuko, fighting. Zuko swings at Jet, but Jet stops
                Zuko's broadsword with the ends of his hook swords, spins around and deflects it to
                the side. Zuko spins with his swords and tries to counterattack, but Jet hooks the
                ends of his swords together and begins to swing them at Zuko in large circular
                motions. Zuko retreats back a few steps to defend himself.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Bet you wish he'd help you out with a little fire blast right now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Jet swings at Zuko's feet, Zuko stabs one of his broadswords through the
                hilt, pinning it to the ground. Jet looks at it with annoyance before focusing back
                on Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><description>You're</description> the one who needs help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Both the combatants lose a sword, and continue fighting with only one. He
                turns in a circle and tries to swipe at Zuko, but Zuko quickly advances and swings
                his sword at Jet. Jet pulls his attack just in time to bend backward and avoid
                Zuko's blade, cutting the straw sticking out of Jet's mouth in half. The scene
                replays, but the second time, zooms in on the straw. Jet regains balance, and jumps
                backward onto the edge of a well.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You see that‌?! <charAction>Aerial view.</charAction> The Fire Nation is trying to
            silence me. <charAction>View behind Zuko looking at Jet.</charAction> It'll
                never happen.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet begins to attack again, hooking his sword to the top of the well and
                sending a flying kick toward Zuko.</description>
            <description>The scene cuts back inside to the palace, where Aang and Sokka are seen,
                standing back to back, fully dressed as busboys, serving refreshments to the guests
                of the party. Aang begins pouring a drink while Sokka is serving food to people who
                pass by.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>A little worried.</charAction> Where are Toph and Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Forget about them! Just keep an eye out for the king. <charAction>He grows slightly
                annoyed as Momo's tail, which has been sticking out of Aang's hat, begins to wag in
                his face.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly nervous.</charAction> I don't know what he looks like.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You know, royal, flowing robe, fancy jewelry.
                <charAction>He grabs Momo's tail, still wagging in his face, and vigorously stuffs
                it back into Aang's hat.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans around the room to show the party guests, all fitting
                Sokka's description. They are all adorned in fancy, flowing robes and headpieces,
                chatting and eating food.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That could be anyone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Aang and Sokka as the camera pans right to show Toph, walking
                up to the duo.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Trying to speak in a fancy voice.</charAction> Another crab puff,
            please. <charAction>Sokka leans in, eyes closed, with his tray to hand her a puff,
                unaware it's her.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised and happy.</charAction> You found us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Back to her normal voice.</charAction> I'd know your little footsteps
            anywhere, Twinkle Toes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara catches up to the group, and Aang blushes when he sees
                her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opening his eyes, realizing who they are. Sarcastically.</charAction>
            Thanks for letting us in!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of her face.</charAction> Sorry, but the guy who escorted us in
                <description>won't</description> let us out of his sight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans out to show all of the party guests, none of which seem to
                be following them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly confused, not seeing anyone following them.</charAction>
            What guy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the group. As they look around for Long Feng,
                Joo Dee approaches the group, and is anxious to see them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing here? You have to leave immediately, or we will be in terrible
            trouble!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Joo Dee tries to push Sokka, but he blocks her with his tray.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Not until we see the king.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee">Joo Dee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of her face.</charAction> You don't understand. You must
            go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Joo Dee shoves Sokka on Aang, causing him to spill the water inside the
                pitcher he was carrying on a guest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guest">Guest</speaker>
        <speech>Aarrrh! Oh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry. No, don't shout.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang uses his hands and foot to airbend a gust at the guest. His hat is
                blown off, along with Momo. It dries the water on her, but also turns her hair,
                clothes, and makeup into a mess, leading Aang to smile sheepishly. The guest is
                briefly shocked, but smiles in amazement.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guest">Guest</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amazed.</charAction> The Avatar! I didn't know the Avatar would be
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>All the guests' attention is now focused on Aang. Joo Dee's large, happy
                smile quickly turns sour and is replaced by a frown and a look of dread. Aang looks
                around at the guests as Momo hides back under the hat on the floor and slinks away.
                Aang blushes and waves at the crowd, laughing nervously, as Sokka leans in toward
                Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> You keep their attention while I look for the
            king.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>View of Aang from above.</charAction> Watch this, everybody!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Wide-view of the room. Aang jumps out of his busboy clothes and lands on
                the long dining table as Sokka walks off into the crowd. Aang swings his arms over
                the guests' drinks, waterbending the liquid out of the cups. He jumps onto a pitcher
                and balances on top of it, while continuing to waterbend. Aang brings the liquid
                above his head and creates a swirling multicolored ball. The crowd cheers and claps
                as he spins around. Bosco growls with delight at Aang's antics.'</description>
            <description>Scene changes to outside the tea shop, where Zuko and Jet are fighting.
                Zuko growls as he swings his sword at Jet, who dodges the attack. He moves on to
                Zuko's side, and they end up back-to-back. Zuko and Jet attempt to strike the
                opponent behind them, but neither can get past the other's defense. Cut to a shot of
                two Dai Li agents walking toward the fight.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dai Li agent">Dai Li agent</speaker>
        <speech>Drop your weapons.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aerial view. Zuko and Jet step away and face each other. Zuko lowers his
                sword, as Jet points at Zuko and Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Arrest them! <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> They're firebenders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Panning view from behind Jet facing Iroh and Zuko.</charAction> This
            poor boy is confused. We're just simple refugees.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pao">Pao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing to Jet.</charAction> This young man wrecked my tea shop, and
            assaulted my employees!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Customer">Customer</speaker>
        <speech>It's true, sir. We saw the whole thing. This crazy kid attacked the finest tea maker
            in the city.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view. Blushing.</charAction> Oh, ho, ho. That's very
            sweet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two Dai Li agents walk up to Jet, who looks at them
                angrily.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dai Li agent">Dai Li agent</speaker>
        <speech>Come with us, son.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet swings his hook sword at the agent, who catches the sword with his rock
                gloves. The guard disarms Jet, and both guards pull the boy's arms behind his back,
                binding his wrists together using their rock gloves' stones. Cut to Jet as the
                guards drag Jet away toward a wagon designed for holding captured
                criminals.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You don't understand! They're Fire Nation! You have to believe me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The crowd begins to disperse. Cut to Jet in the wagon, on his knees, as he
                looks up as the doors are shut. The people left in the street watch the wagon go
                away. Longshot and Smellerbee look on, hidden within the crowd, and silently walk
                out of sight.</description>
            <description>Cut to the palace, where two lines of guards walk into the hall. Eight of
                them are carrying a curtained palanquin, The Earth King is sitting on the platform.
                Cut to a shot of the crowd as they marvel in the Earth King's presence. Sokka sneaks
                through the crowd and attempts to get a better view of the king. Cut to the line of
                guards as they place the palanquin down and face the guests. Cut to Sokka as he
                looks over at Aang and points at the king.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aang! The Earth King!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of Aang, who is entertaining Bosco with waterbending bubbles.
                Aang notices him and bends an air scooter, whisking down the table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Greetings, Your Majesty.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Side-view of three guests pulling their food and drinks off the table
                before Aang can run over them with his air scooter. Cut back to overhead view of the
                procession of guards and the Earth King. The platform is carried off while a line of
                guards walk up to the long dining table. Sokka exits the crowd and tries to follow
                the king, but two Dai Li agents grab him and begin leading him away, pulling his
                arms behind his back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, let me go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of a Dai Li agent stepping out from a pillar in the hall
                throws his hands out, causing his rock gloves to fly forward. Cut to Katara and
                Toph. While Katara is looking away, the gloves of the agent grab Toph and pull her
                backward, covering her mouth to keep her silent. A second later, another pair of
                gloves grabs Katara and pulls her back the same way as Toph. Cut to a Dai Li guard
                standing watch. The camera shifts down to show Momo still hiding under the busboy
                hat and trying to sneak past, his ear and tail sticking out from under. The agent
                reaches down and pulls the hat off, with Momo looking up, surprised. Shot cuts back
                to Aang who has reached the other end of the dining table on his air scooter,
                knocking over several dishes. He dismounts the scooter and holds his arms up in
                triumph. Long Feng walks up to Aang from behind the line of guards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>Avatar, it is a great honor to meet you. <charAction>He bows.</charAction> I am Long
            Feng, Grand Secretariat of Ba Sing Se and head of the Dai Li. I'd like to talk to you.
            Your friends will be waiting for us in the library.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Long Feng gestures Aang to follow him, as he goes into the library. Aang
                hesitates for a moment before hopping off the table and following. Cut to a shot of
                the library's large double doors shutting. The camera zooms out to show Aang and his
                friends facing Long Feng, who is sitting in front of a hearth that illuminates the
                area with a green flame.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why won't you let us talk to the king? We have information that could defeat the
            Fire Nation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>The Earth King has no time to get involved with political squabbles and the day to
            day minutia of military activities.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>This could be the most important thing he's ever heard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera shifts behind Aang's party and pans slowly to the right. Long
                Feng is visibly seated in front of them as the camera passes by each
                member.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>What's most important to his royal majesty is maintaining the cultural heritage of
            Ba Sing Se. All his duties relate to issuing decrees on such matters. It's my job to
            oversee the rest of the city's resources, including the military.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> So the king is just a figurehead.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angry.</charAction> He's your puppet!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Oh, no, no. His Majesty is an icon, a god to
            his people. He can't sully his hands with the hourly change of an endless war.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of room.</charAction> But we found out about a solar eclipse
            that will leave the Fire Nation defenseless. You could lead an invasion ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up, annoyed. Shot changes briefly to a confused
                Sokka.</charAction> Enough! I don't want to hear your ridiculous plan.
                <charAction>Cut back to Long Feng.</charAction> It is the strict policy of Ba Sing
            Se that the War not be mentioned within the walls. <charAction>Scene changes as he talks
                to the two Dai Li agents dragging Jet into a dark room, making him sit on a stone
                chair.</charAction> Constant news of an escalating war will throw the citizens of Ba
            Sing Se into a state of panic.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You have to believe me, they're firebenders! They won't stop until they win the
            War.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Several square stones from their rock gloves circle Jet's head and clamp
                down on his skull, holding it in place.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dai Li agent">Dai Li agent</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Calm down, you're safe now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The agent stands in front of Jet, surrounded by a metal track. From behind
                him appears a small orange lantern attached to the track. It travels around the
                track and passes the camera, causing a white flash that cuts back to Long
                Feng.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>Our economy would be ruined, our peaceful way of life – our traditions – would
            disappear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>There is another similar white flash and the scene shifts back to the lamp
                circling the Dai Li agent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dai Li agent">Dai Li agent</speaker>
        <speech>There's no war in Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>What're you talking about? <charAction>Camera changes to an aerial view zooming
                out.</charAction> Where do you think all the refugees come from? You can't hide
            it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Close-up view of Jet as he watches the lamp continues passing by his face.
                The screen flashes white and cuts back to Long Feng.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>In silencing talk of conflict, Ba Sing Se remains a peaceful, orderly utopia: the
            last one on Earth.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and his friends stare at Long Feng with a mix of shock and horror at
                this revelation. The screen flashes white again. Cut to a close-up of Jet. A circle
                of stones covers his mouth, muffling his protests. The lamp passes by his eyes
                again. Cut to a shot of the Dai Li agent standing within the circular track as the
                lamp continues revolving.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dai Li agent">Dai Li agent</speaker>
        <speech>There is no war within the walls. Here we are safe. Here, we are free.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet's eyes widen and his protests become silent, and the brainwashing
                begins to affect him. The screen flashes, and cut to Team Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You can't keep the truth from all these people. They have
            to know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stepping forward, pointing a finger at Long Feng.</charAction> I'll tell
            them! I'll make sure everyone knows!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-view of room.</charAction> Until now, you've been treated as our
            honored guest. <charAction>Cut to side-view of Long Feng and Aang. Long Feng steps
                forward and bends down to look Aang in the eye. Aang stares back at Long Feng,
                angrily.</charAction> But from now on, you will be watched every moment by Dai Li
            agents. If you mention the War to anyone, you will be expelled from the city.
                <charAction>He turns around and walks over to the hearth with the green
                fire.</charAction> I understand you've been looking for your bison. <charAction>View
                of Long Feng turning slightly to look at Aang.</charAction> It would be quite a
            shame if you were not able to complete your quest. <charAction>Aang appears frightened,
                but his expression soon changes to that of anger. Cut to an overhead shot of the
                room. Long Feng sits down, as Joo Dee opens the doors and walks toward the
                group.</charAction> Now, Joo Dee will show you to your home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot from behind Joo Dee as she faces Aang's party. The group
                looks at her with surprise.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee replacement">Joo Dee replacement</speaker>
        <speech>Come with me, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What happened to Joo Dee?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a shot of Joo Dee's face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Joo Dee replacement">Joo Dee replacement</speaker>
        <speech>I'm Joo Dee. <charAction>Bows her head.</charAction> I'll be your host as long as
            you're in our wonderful city.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Joo Dee smiles cheerfully at the group in the same artificial way. Fade to
                credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
