<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Imprisoned</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene opens up in a forest. Katara and Aang are on a raised, grassy
                plateau. A gentle stream is running out beneath it. Katara is folding one of their
                sleeping blankets. Aang is lying on the root of a tree. Momo screeches and lands on
                the plateau as Sokka approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enthusiastically.</charAction> Great, you're back!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang leaps off the root with his airbending, landing beside the Water Tribe
                siblings as Sokka digs in his bag.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's for dinner?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Digs nuts from his bag.</charAction> We've got a few options. First;
            round nuts. And some kind of oval shaped nuts? And some rock-shaped nuts, that might
            just be rocks. <charAction>Throws the rock-shaped nut toward Momo.</charAction> Dig in!
                <charAction>Aang and Katara look at each other then back at
            Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously ... what else you got?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo coos, and sniffs the rock-shaped nut, before taking it with one of his
                paws and slapping it against a stone twice. Attempting to break it, he takes it with
                both paws and slams it down on the big rock. The moment he does so, however, the
                entire earth quakes, making Momo shriek and his hair stand up on end.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What was that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo, believing he may have caused the quake, cautiously drops the rock to
                the ground in test. The quake returns, causing Momo to leap away. </description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It's coming from over there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang and Katara run off-camera.</charAction> Shouldn't we run
                away from huge booms? Not toward them?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The three, joined by Momo, hide behind a fallen tree and spy on a young boy
                bending boulders into the air and punching them into the side of the
                ravine.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>An earthbender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Let's go meet him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He looks dangerous, so we better approach cautiously.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Suddenly Katara is a few feet in front of them, excitedly addressing the
                earthbender.</charAction> Hello there! I'm Katara! What's your name?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The young boy gasps in surprise, dropping the boulder he was bending to the
                ground. He flees quickly, bringing down an avalanche of boulders with his bending to
                block his exit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sokka and Aang approach Katara; yelling.</charAction> Nice to meet
            you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugging.</charAction> I just wanted to say hi.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! That guy's gotta be running somewhere. Maybe we're near a village? And I bet
            that village has a market!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Which means no nuts for dinner!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Katara and Aang chase after Haru.</charAction> Hey! I worked hard to get
            those nuts! <charAction>Momo flies overhead, chasing Katara and Aang.</charAction> Yeah,
            I hate 'em too. <charAction>Slowly follows Katara and Aang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Sokka stroll through the mining village's streets while Aang
                speaks with a shopkeeper under a terrace.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Great hat! <charAction>Tries on the hat.</charAction> I'll trade you some nuts for
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Notices the boy enter a shop. Speaks to herself in
                surprise.</charAction> Hey ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The boy enters into the dark, wooden building and approaches a
                woman.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>Hi, Mom.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech>Where have you been, Haru? You're late! Get started on your chores.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enters the shop's front door, startling Haru.</charAction> Hey. You're
            that kid. Why did you run away before?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, you must have me confused with some other kid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang and Sokka enter the shop.</charAction> No, she doesn't. We saw you
            earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru and his mother gasps in horror at his secret being revealed and both
                the door and window to the small shop are promptly slammed shut.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing by the window.</charAction> They saw you doing what?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>They're crazy, Mom! I mean, look at how they're dressed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang gazes to his conical hat, shifting it about in confusion. Katara
                awkwardly grasps at her dress, looking with astonishment at herself. Sokka quirks an
                eyebrow and smooths out his sleeve.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech>You know how dangerous that is! You know what would happen if they caught you
            earthbending!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tax collector">Tax collector</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Heavy knocks on the door.</charAction> Open up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sokka peeks through the window's blinds.</charAction> Fire Nation! Act
            natural!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru's mother opens the door, allowing the Fire Nation tax collector to
                walk inside. He stares awkwardly at the four children in front of him. Haru grasps
                his chin and stares toward Katara, cross-eyed. Sokka eyeballs an apple. Katara
                hunches forward with her eyes wide open, having stuffed her mouth with berries. Aang
                has his hand atop a barrel, beaming an immense toothy smile. His pose is short-lived
                as the barrel's lid spins, dunking Aang's hand into the barrel of water and causes
                him to fall down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The tax collector stares sourly toward the four children;
                aggressively.</charAction> What do you want? I've already paid you this
            week!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tax collector">Tax collector</speaker>
        <speech>The tax just doubled. <charAction>Arrogantly.</charAction> And we wouldn't want an
            accident, would we? <charAction>Creates a ball of fire between his hands, making
                everyone slightly back away.</charAction> Fire is sometimes so hard to
            control.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru's mother and the tax collector approach the store's counter, where she
                opens a small chest and passes a meager handful of Earth Kingdom currency to the tax
                collector. Haru leans against the counter, staring with contempt toward the Fire
                Nation man.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tax collector">Tax collector</speaker>
        <speech>You can keep the copper ones. <charAction>Walks away, dropping four copper pieces to
                the floor, exits.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Door slams.</charAction> Nice guy. How long has the Fire Nation been
            here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech>Five years. Fire Lord Ozai uses our town's coal mines to fuel his ships.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>They're thugs. They steal from us. And everyone here's too much of a coward to do
            anything about it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angered.</charAction> Quiet, Haru! Don't talk like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curiously.</charAction> But, Haru's an earthbender? He can
            help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech>Earthbending is forbidden. It's caused nothing but misery for this village!
                <charAction>Casts a meaningful glance toward her son.</charAction> He must never use
            his abilities.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How can you say that? Haru has a gift! Asking him not to earthbend is like asking me
            not to waterbend. It's a part of who we are.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shakes head in dismay.</charAction> You don't understand.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I understand that Haru can help you fight back. What can the Fire Nation do to you
            that they haven't done already?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru's mother">Haru's mother</speaker>
        <speech>They could take Haru away! Like they took his father.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to late evening, viewing farmland and a barn. Appa walks into
                the barn. Cut to a closer view of Sokka, Katara, Haru, and Aang standing inside the
                barn.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>My mom said you can sleep here tonight. But you should leave in the
            morning.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks. I'll make sure Appa doesn't eat all your hay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa engulfs a mouthful of hay. Appa pauses, turning to stare dubiously
                toward Aang before continuing to chew hay. The scene switches to Katara and Haru
                taking a walk into the woods outside under the setting sun.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry about what I said earlier. I didn't know about your father.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>That's okay. It's funny, the way you were talking back in the store? It reminded me
            of him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Flattered.</charAction> Thanks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>My father was very courageous. When the Fire Nation invaded, he and the other
            earthbenders were outnumbered ten to one. But they fought back anyway.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He sounds like a great man.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two approach the top of a steep cliff, gazing out to the setting sun
                beyond.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops.</charAction> After the attack, they rounded up my father and
            every other earthbender, and took them away. <charAction>Kneels.</charAction> We haven't
            seen them since.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So that's why you hide your earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. Problem is ... <charAction>Close-up, earthbends two stones in a circle above
                his hand.</charAction> the only way I can feel close to my father now
                <charAction>Crushes the stones to sand with his hands. The sand blows
                away.</charAction> is when I practice my bending. He taught me everything I
            know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sits beside Haru, sets her fingertips on her necklace.</charAction> See
            this necklace? My mother gave it to me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>It's beautiful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I lost my mother in a Fire Nation raid. <charAction>Hangs her head, turning
                away.</charAction> This necklace is all I have left of her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>It's not enough, is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No. <charAction>Hangs her head and turns away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to Katara and Haru who have continued their walk along
                the dirt trail. A loud boom sounds and rock and dust blasts from a distant mine
                entrance. An old man cries out.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Old man">Old man</speaker>
        <speech>Help, help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>The mine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Haru run quickly to the entrance, which has caved in and left a
                tremendous pile of rocks pinning the old man to the ground on his stomach. Sand
                continues to pour down, rocks intermittently falling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Old man">Old man</speaker>
        <speech>Help me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Haru braces his back against the mine entrance. Katara pulls the old
                man.</charAction> Ugh! It's not working! We have to get help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>There's no time, pull harder!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Getting an idea.</charAction> Haru. There's a way
                you can help him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Guilty fear.</charAction> I <description>can't.</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Please, there's no one around to see you. It's the only way!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru leaps away from the falling debris, spinning back to face it as he
                assumes an earthbending form. With a sudden and strong move, he blasts all the rocks
                down the tunnel, freeing the old man.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Haru! You did it! <charAction>The two take place
                beside the old man and aid him walking away from the mine.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At the barn, Katara is sitting up in her bedroll with a lamp in her lap.
                Sokka is lying on a square bale of hay with his blanket over him, and Aang is
                sprawled out on Appa's head with Momo lying on his back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It was so brave of Haru to use his earthbending to help that old man.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You must have really inspired him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I guess so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone should get some sleep, we're leaving at dawn.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unhappily.</charAction> Dawn?! Can't we sleep in for once?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Commandingly.</charAction> Absolutely not! This village is crawling with
            Fire Nation troops. If they discover you're here, Aang, we'll be eating fireballs for
            breakfast. Goodnight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slyly, with a wry smirk.</charAction> I'd rather eat fireballs than
            nuts.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>
            <charAction>With finality.</charAction>
            <description>Goodnight!</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Aang share a few playful chuckles with each other before she
                blows out the lamplight to get some rest.</description>
            <description>Fire Nation troops march on a mission through the dead of night. The man in
                the lead raps on a wooden door. Haru answers the door, suddenly gasping in shock as
                he sees the troops.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Old man">Old man</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points accusingly.</charAction> That's him! That's the
            earthbender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Fire Nation leader shoves the old man out of the way and approaches
                Haru. Haru screams as the man forces Haru into his grip and hauls him
                away.</description>
            <description>In the morning, Katara carries a jar outside of the barn. She sets it down
                beside a water pump and proceeds to waterbend, drawing water out of the spigot and
                into the waiting pot. Picking it up, she spots Haru's mother standing with her back
                to her, gazing toward the distant ocean. Haru's mother slowly turns around, laying a
                tearful gaze upon Katara. Katara realizes Haru has been taken and drops the pot, as
                it shatters to pieces at her feet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enters barn to see Aang and Sokka folding blankets;
                emotionally.</charAction> They took him! They took Haru away!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hurriedly.</charAction> The old man turned him in to the Fire Nation -
            it's all my fault - I forced him into earthbending!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Steps beside her, taking her hand in his and laying his other hand
                supportively behind her shoulder.</charAction> Slow down, Katara. When did this
            happen?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Haru's mother said they came for him at midnight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Then it's too late to track him, he's long gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns defiantly to the open door, clenches fists.</charAction> We don't
            need to track him. The Fire Nation is going to take me right to Haru.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> And ... why would they do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> Because they're going to arrest me for
            earthbending. <charAction>Aang and Sokka share a horrified look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to Sokka and Katara working together to push a boulder
                overtop an air vent on a rocky road.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I thought you were crazy at first, Katara, but this might work. There are
            ventilation shafts throughout these mines. All Aang has to do is send an air current
            from that vent to this one right here. The boulder levitates and
                <description>ta-da!</description> Fake earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Props hands off hips, turns to Aang.</charAction> Aang? Did you get all
            that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Snapping small puffs of air at a sooty copper fritillary butterfly;
                dismissively.</charAction> Sure, sure. I got it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Do you remember your cue?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Continues snapping puffs of air; still dismissive.</charAction> Yeah,
            yeah. Just relax. You're taking all the fun out of this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aggravated.</charAction> By <description>this,</description> do you mean
            intentionally being captured by a group of ruthless firebenders?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Humored.</charAction> Exactly! That's fun stuff!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Group of firebenders with spears approach.</charAction> Here they come!
            Get in your places!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang stops playing with the butterfly and Momo tries catching it as it
                flies away. As the group of spear-wielding guards approach, Katara and Sokka make a
                show of walking into one another by their stomachs before emphatically
                shouting.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While angrily pointing at Katara.</charAction> Get out of my way,
            pipsqueak! <charAction>The soldiers watch in confusion. One of them even raises an
                eyebrow.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily hunched over.</charAction> How dare
            you call me pipsqueak, you giant-eared cretin!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Just as angrily hunched over.</charAction> What did you call
            me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Far too dramatically as her hair loopies move with her
                motion.</charAction> A giant-eared cretin! Look at those things! Do herds of animals
            use them for shade?! <charAction>Imitates an elephant's ears.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Towers over his sister.</charAction> You better back off!
                <charAction>Slips his hand by his mouth and mutters.</charAction> Seriously, back
            off.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>More determined, heightens above her now-cowering brother.</charAction>
            I will not back off! I bet elephants get together and make fun of how large
                your ears are!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's it! You're going down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'll show you who's boss! <charAction>Angrily points at Sokka.</charAction>
            Earthbending style! <charAction>Over-dramatically leaps toward the boulder, clenching
                her fist upward to which there is no reaction. Angrily.</charAction> I said,
            earthbending style!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At Katara's shout, Aang gasps quietly as he realizes his mistake by missing
                his cue. The young airbender ceases playing with the butterfly, leaps up, and blasts
                a strong jet of air into the ventilation duct, suddenly sending the boulder
                levitating into the air. This reveals Momo behind the boulder, who has his arms
                raised, licking himself.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points a finger to the lemur; surprised.</charAction> That lemur! He's
            earthbending!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Katara and Momo each remain in their positions. Katara eyes the man in
                surprise. Sokka, angrily, waves his arms toward her.</charAction> No, you idiot,
            it's the girl!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Oh. <charAction>Blushes shamefully.</charAction> Of course.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka steps beside Katara, laying his hands on her shoulders as the boulder
                falls to the ground. Katara stands patiently.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'll hold her. <charAction>Close-up. Whispers to Katara.</charAction> You've got
            twelve hours to find Haru. We'll be right behind you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guards escort Katara away, leaving Aang, Sokka, and Momo to watch as
                she takes a final glance back. Sokka unhappily tugs at his ears, testing their
                sizes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eyeballs Momo perched off of Aang's shoulder. Points
                accusingly.</charAction> Momo, you have some big ears!
                <charAction>Momo folds his ears back, hunches down, and coos in
                protest.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara is in the back of a Fire Nation transport with other earthbender
                prisoners. She wears a brown, tattered prison garb over her blue Water Tribe outfit
                and stares glumly downward. Sokka and Aang each have conical yellow hats in a crowd,
                attempting to stealthily observe her travel. Katara looks longingly over shoulder as
                the cart bobs along a pier, heading toward a waiting barge on the
                ocean.</description>
            <description>Aang and Sokka chase the barge, riding Appa through the clouds. The
                immense, smoking, off-shore Fire Nation prison rig is seen just ahead. Close-up of
                the rig.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang stares nervously at the barge carrying Katara to the
                prison.</charAction> She'll be fine, Aang. Katara knows what she's doing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>After the barge arrives, six prisoners, including Katara, line up on the
                deck of the prison. Spear-wielding guards stand at either side. A prison warden
                approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smugly.</charAction> Earthbenders. It is my pleasure to welcome you
            aboard my modest shipyard. I am your warden. I prefer to think of you not as prisoners,
                <charAction>Quips smartly.</charAction> but as honored guests. And I hope you come
            to think of me as your humble and caring host. <charAction>Paces
                nonchalantly.</charAction> You will succeed here, if you simply abide-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden pauses, suddenly interrupted by a prisoner in line coughing.
                With no forewarning, the warden leaps into the air and aims a blast of fire at the
                prisoner's legs in anger. The prisoner cowers away for safety as the warden stands
                defiantly toward the man.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Very angrily.</charAction> What kind of guest dishonors his host by
            interrupting him?! Take him below! <charAction>Swings his arms. Some guards escort the
                man away. Mutters.</charAction> One week in solitary will improve his manners.
                <charAction>Continues smug gait.</charAction> Simply treat me with the courtesy that
            I give you-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Approaches Katara, kneeling to stare into her obstinate expression. She
                crosses her eyebrows, scowling coarsely at the man.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>And we'll get along <description>famously.</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The prisoners are taken on a tour of the facility. Below, fellow prisoners
                are seen laboring.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>You will notice, earthbenders, that this rig is made entirely of metal. You are
            miles away from any rock or earth. <charAction>Katara pauses, glancing over the
                expansive ocean to the land far away.</charAction> So, if you have any illusions
            about employing that brutish savagery that passes for bending among you people ...
                <charAction>Lowly.</charAction> forget them. It is impossible. Good day.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A guard escorts the prisoners into the prison courtyard. Katara enters last
                and the metal gates close behind her. Among many earthbender prisoners, Haru takes
                notice of Katara. Above the courtyard, a watchman and the warden monitor the
                scene.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly. Runs and hugs Haru.</charAction> Haru!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> What are you doing here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Somewhat apologetically.</charAction> It's my fault you were captured. I
            came to rescue you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> So, you got yourself arrested?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It was the only way to find you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>You've got guts, Katara. I'll give you that. <charAction>Places hand on her
                shoulder.</charAction> Come on. There's someone I want you to meet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two approach an old, gray-bearded man eating dinner among other
                prisoners.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>Katara. This is my father, Tyro. <charAction>The older man looks up.</charAction>
            Dad. This is Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly bows.</charAction> It's an honor to meet you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hands Katara a bowl.</charAction> Have some dinner, Katara.
                <charAction>Katara accepts the bowl, but grimaces.</charAction> It's not as bad as
            it looks. <charAction>Katara tries a spoonful, but becomes further disgusted. He finds
                humor in this with a small chuckle.</charAction> It's still pretty bad
            though.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Prisoner">Prisoner</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks up and lays a hand on Tyro's shoulder.</charAction> Tyro. The
            prisoners are complaining there aren't enough blankets to go around.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>I'll talk to the guards. In the meantime, make sure the elderly are taken care of.
            The rest of us will simply have to hope for warmer weather.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>If you don't mind me asking, what's your escape plan?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Excuse me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You know, the plan to get everyone off the rig? What is it? Mutiny,
            sabotage?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>The plan? The plan is to survive. Wait out this war. Hope that one day some of us
            can get back home and forget this ever happened.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> How can you say that? You sound like you've
            already given up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, I admire your courage. And I envy your youth. But people's lives are at
            stake here. The warden is a ruthless man, and he won't stand for any rebellion. I'm
            sorry, but we're powerless.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Obstinately.</charAction> We'll see about that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara stands up and carries a trash can lid and a ladle, climbing on top
                of a wooden table. From there, she bangs the ladle against the lid to draw
                attention.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Earthbenders! You don't know me, but I know of you. Every child in my Water Tribe
            village was rocked to sleep with stories of the brave Earth Kingdom, and the courageous
            earthbenders who guard its borders. <charAction>The watchman walks up to talk the
                warden, but the warden stops him and listens.</charAction> Some of you may think
            that the Fire Nation has made you powerless. Yes, they have taken away your ability to
            bend. But they can't take away your courage. And it is your
            courage they should truly fear! Because it runs deeper than any mine you've been forced
            to dig, any ocean that keeps you far from home! It is the strength of your hearts that
            make you who you are. Hearts that will remain unbroken when all rock and stone has
            eroded away. The time to fight back is now! I can tell you the Avatar has returned! So
            remember your courage earthbenders, <charAction>Shouts clearly.</charAction> let us
            fight for our freedom!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara's speech is met with utter silence and a small cough in the
                background, leaving her to fall into sorrow as she realizes the muted answer she
                receives. The warden walks away from the courtyard. Later that night while she is
                sleeping, Aang sneaks into the prison and taps his hand to her shoulder, waking her.
                Urging her to be quiet, he leads her to the perimeter where Sokka and Appa are
                waiting to make their escape.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Your twelve hours are up; where's Haru? We've gotta get outta here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hurriedly.</charAction> We don't have much time. There are guards
            everywhere. Get on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Katara, what's wrong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not leaving. <charAction>Aang and Sokka share a questionable look.</charAction>
            I'm not giving up on these people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to black. Cut to Sokka, Aang, and Katara on the metal
                perimeter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean you're not leaving?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We can't abandon these people! There has to be a way to help them.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe she's right. What do you say, Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I say you're both crazy! <charAction>The trio ducks a searching
                spotlight.</charAction> Last chance! We need to leave, now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sternly.</charAction> No!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shakes his head dismally.</charAction> I hate when you get like this.
            Come on, we better hide.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Katara and Sokka flee. Aang whispers to Appa before joining
                them.</charAction> Go hide.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Captain">Captain</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Appa soars overhead to fly away and hide.</charAction> Look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two guards who witnessed Appa take to the skies approach the warden on
                a catwalk.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Tell me exactly what you saw.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Captain">Captain</speaker>
        <speech>Well, sir, it looked like a flying bison.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>It was a giant flying buffalo, sir. With an empty saddle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Which was it? A buffalo or a bison?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Captain">Captain</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, I'm not sure what the difference is, but that's not really the point, is it,
            sir?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Furiously.</charAction> I'll decide what the point is, fool!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden throws the first guard overboard. The man screams in horror
                before finally being silenced by a splash below.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To the second guard as he straightens up.</charAction> You! Wake up the
            captain. Search the entire rig! <charAction>Turns to walk away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Somewhat timidly.</charAction> That was ... the captain you just threw
            overboard, so ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Still quite annoyed.</charAction> Then wake up someone I
                <description>haven't</description> thrown overboard and search the rig! There's
            something going on here and I don't like it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut scene; Momo peeps over a wooden crate where the trio is safely hiding
                behind numerous boxes. Scene opens up to show the three huddled together seated on
                the metal ground in the darkness.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We don't have much time. What are we gonna do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I wish I knew how to make a hurricane!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Both Sokka and Katara provide Aang with assuredly un-entertained facial
                expressions.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The warden would run away and we'd steal his keys!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Wouldn't he just take his keys with him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm just tossing ideas around.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I tried talking the earthbenders into fighting back but, it didn't work! If there
            was just a way to help them help themselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>For that they'd need some kind of earth, or some rock. Something they can
            bend.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lays her palm to the surface.</charAction> But this entire place is made
            of metal!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, it's not. <charAction>Points to smokestacks.</charAction> Look at the smoke! I
            bet they're burning coal. In other words, <description>earth.</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Morning arrives, the scene gaining light. Sokka and Katara are alone by an
                air duct. Sokka is peering down into it, while Katara kneels beside it with her
                hands on its rim.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's almost dawn. We're running out of time! You sure this is gonna work?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It should. These vents reminded me of our little trick back at the village. We're
            gonna do the same thing, but on a much bigger scale. <charAction>The camera zooms
                through a visual walkthrough of Sokka's explanation.</charAction> There's a huge
            deposit of coal at the base of the silo. And the whole system is ventilated. Aang closed
            off all the vents except one. When he does his airbending the coal only has one place to
            go, right back here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>There's the intruder!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two siblings are suddenly surrounded by a number of spear-wielding Fire
                Nation guards. The prisoners have gathered a safe distance away from this spectacle,
                observing what is happening.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Stay back! I'm warning you! <charAction>Pulls out his boomerang, turning
                back-to-back with his sister.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Roughly.</charAction> Katara, stop! You can't win this fight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Listen to him well, child. You're one mistake away from dying where you
            stand.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A sudden rush of air fills their ears as the facility shakes. The
                ventilation shaft bursts off its hinges as an immense blast of coal soars into the
                air, crashing down into a gathered pile. Everyone present is silent, staring in
                stark surprise at this turn of events. Lastly, Aang leaps out from the barren
                ventilation shaft, landing atop the coal pile and coughing, covered in soot and
                dirt. Momo follows him and Katara runs up to the coal, turning to face the
                earthbenders.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lifting up a piece of coal.</charAction> Here's your chance,
            earthbenders! Take it! Your fate is in your own hands!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru bolts ahead without hesitation, prepared to bend the waiting coal as a
                weapon. Tyro throws his hand up, bracing his son's chest to halt his
                advance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bursts out into highly amused laughter.</charAction> Foolish girl. You
            thought a few inspirational words and some coal would change these people? Look at these
            blank, hopeless faces. Their spirits were broken a long time ago. <charAction>Katara's
                expression dims as she does as instructed, staring at the forlorn
                prisoners.</charAction> Oh, but you still believe in them. How sweet. They're a
            waste of your energy little girl. You <description>failed.</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden finishes his speech by turning to take leave of the facility. As
                he does so, a single piece of coal sails through the air and pelts the back of his
                head. Outraged, the warden spins back to see who dared to attack him. Haru stands
                defiantly levitating three pieces of coal above his hand. The warden sends a blast
                of fire toward Haru, but the fire is blocked, as Tyro raises a wall of coal in his
                defense.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Guards line up and prepare for battle.</charAction> Show no mercy!
                <charAction>The guards send a blast of fire as one toward the rebelling
                prisoners.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The earthbenders work together to haul a sizable mass of coal to block
                the fire.</charAction> For the Earth Kingdom, attack!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Slamming the coal to the ground; chunks of rock assault the guards. The
                battle immediately flares, prisoners ducking blasts of fire and countering with
                fists of coal. Katara and Aang chase after Sokka as he snaps soldiers spears in two
                with his boomerang, tossing the broken shafts to Momo overhead. Momo continues to
                collect other pieces of broken spears that are thrown up to him.</description>
            <description>Tyro and Haru work in unison to compress gathered coal into one lump,
                slinging this through the doors to make way for their escape. The guards on top fall
                down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Get to the ships! We'll hold them off!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Do not let them escape!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Generates an air funnel and holds it between his hands; to Katara and
                Sokka.</charAction> Guys! Throw me some coal!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Sokka drop heaps of coal into his funnel, firing the material
                rapidly at the warden and his fellow benders, knocking them to the ground. Following
                this, Tyro and two other earthbenders work together to lift coal beneath these
                adversaries, moving them away from the rig and over the ocean.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pleading.</charAction> No, please! I can't swim!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry. I hear cowards float. <charAction>Drops their enemies into the
                ocean.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>On the barge headed to their homes, Haru and Tyro approach Katara on its
                deck.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>I want to thank you for saving me. For saving us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to face Haru. Denying.</charAction> All it took was a little
            coal.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>It wasn't the coal, Katara. It was you. <charAction>Katara
            blushes.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you for helping me find my courage, Katara of the Water Tribe. My family and
            everyone here owes you much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So, I guess you're going home now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>Yes. To take back my village. <charAction>Raises his voice to the crowd on the lower
                deck.</charAction> To take back all of our villages! The Fire Nation will regret the
            day they set foot on our land! <charAction>Crowd cheers at Tyro's
            bravado.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Katara.</charAction> Come with us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can't. Your mission is to take back your home. Ours is to get Aang to the North
            Pole. <charAction>Gazes over the rail to see Momo join Aang atop Appa's head, floating
                in the ocean.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>That's him, isn't it? The Avatar. <charAction>Aang airbends an encased piece of
                coal. Momo jumps into his lap.</charAction> Katara, thank you for bringing my father
            back to me. I never thought I'd see him again. I only wish there was some way
            ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I know. <charAction>Reaches for her necklace wistfully, but realizes it is not
                around her neck and panics.</charAction> My mother's necklace! It's gone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back on the prison rig, Zuko stands alone facing the sunset amid coal lying
                sparsely on the deck. He seizes Katara's necklace in his fingers, lifting it to
                stare at it grimly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
