<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Sozins Comet Part 3</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>Note: The commentators recorded the commentaries for "Sozin's Comet, Parts
                1-4" in one sitting, cutting off the commentary just before the credits on each
                episode, with the exception of "Part 4".</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Michael Dante DiMartino">Michael Dante DiMartino</speaker>
        <speech>Welcome back to "Part 3" of the finale, this is Mike.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan Konietzko">Bryan Konietzko</speaker>
        <speech>This is Bryan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And uh, like Bryan had talked about a little bit earlier uh, we-we-we both co-wrote
            this episode, and when we-when we wrote it, it was the length of a normal script,
            about... think it was twenty-five pages maybe, twenty-I don't know. Some-somewhere
            around there, the normal script length that we usually have. And we thought, "yeah,
            this-this will all fit into one episode," but uh, during the storyboard process and
            making the animatic and stuff, um, we realized it had grown to exponential,
                <charAction>Bryan and Mike chuckle.</charAction> an exponential size, and, and that
            it wasn't going to be able, if we had tried to f-keep it all in one episode it would've
            felt really rushed, and we wanted, pacing wise, we wanted it f-to feel more like a f-a
            feature film. So, like, we wanted to hold on shots longer so that the effects could kind
            of, you know, fire could dissipate, and, and just have these longer moments that we
            don't normally get to do in an episode 'cause we're trying to tell the story and get
            through it all in-in twenty-two and a half minutes, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>The exact same thing happened with Dr. Phil. Um, <charAction>Mike laughs
                intermittently.</charAction> I think when he did like his two-hundredth episode, he
            was like, <charAction>Imitates Dr. Phil's Southern accent.</charAction> "you know, we
            just got so much good stuff, we got to do two," you know, so, um, just like our
            colleague Dr. Phil, <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> see, we had the same
            issue.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>So, it was kinda-it was... it was the first time we had ever done that, where we
            hadn't intended something to be too-but uh, yeah, I think it was-it was kinda the story
            was telling us it needed to be paced out longer. And uh, we got to... add in some great
            moments that we wouldn't have been able to. And-and definitely, you know, when we get to
            it, we'll talk about it more, but the end of-of the whole thing, you couldn't just have
            like a one-minute wrap-up, you know, you needed to like let everyone have their moments
            at the end.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A pause in the commentary occurs until the shot pans up to the eel hound
                Sokka, Toph and Suki are riding, the hybrid creature's head swaying as it swims
                through the calm ocean waters, the light from Sozin's Comet bisecting the dark
                orange clouds in the sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>This is one of my favorite shots, I don't know, with this... this is one of my
            favorite shots in the, in the whole last two episodes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> Yeah, and just wanna give a little shoutout to
            JM Animation, who um, uh, animated 320 and 321. Uh, they basically... almost killed
            themselves making <charAction>Bryan and Mike chuckle.</charAction> these two episodes
            back-to-back, with some of the most complex effects and character animation we've done.
                <charAction>Refers to the Fire Nation airships lifting off.</charAction> A lot of CG
            with the ships, and-and things like that, so, they just went above and beyond, and just
            really gave us what I think, you know, there's-there's certain scenes that are just
            feature quality.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, it was a, a grueling process, and um, they just, they worked so hard. Jae
            Myung uh, our animation director who started with us on the-on the pilot, you know, I
            just kept telling him... you know, what-what can we do to simplify this, and-and
            basically, he wanted to make it, he's like, "this is my last chance to work on-on
                Avatar, and I just have to make it the best ever". And
            uh, so a lot of the artists just really-they were so proud of it, and uh, wanted to make
            it as good as it could be, which was our plan from the start. Um, Mike and I had worked
            on all these shows where... the Korean studios were used, you know, I-we've-we've said
            this before, but those studios were used just sort of like a factory situation, um, with
            little to no contact between the showrunners in the States and the artists in Korea. And
            um, we just knew we wanted-we wanted people to be more invested on all levels of the-of
            the project. So... um, you know, we-we didn't want people to uh, live in their,
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> in their studios and under their desks for months
            on end, but um, they just-they-they really wanted this to be something special, so
            they-they pushed themselves that hard. And, I mean, you know, we boarded it and wrote it
            rather ambitiously. Um, I went over to Korea to help 'em, and uh, man, they were like,
            "just draw fire," <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> we-there is so much fire in these two
            episodes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>They...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects; refers to Toph using more kicks with her metalbending during
                her fight against the airship crew.</charAction> Just want to point out that this is
            um, some really cool special kung fu from uh, Sifu Manuel Rodriguez. Um, he-he brought
            his son Scott over to do some really rare, cool Southern Praying Mantis stuff that we
            used for Toph for this scene.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the powerful, sustained fire blasts created by the augmented
                firebenders.</charAction> Yeah, and I just want to point out too that the, like
            Bryan said, all of the fire, I think probably ninety-nine percent of the fire in this
            episode, maybe a hundred percent, is hand-drawn and hand-animated, and the computer is
            used for the glow effects and the coloring and, you know, the lighting and stuff like
            that, but, the actual movement of the fire is uh, is all hand-drawn. So...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Some of these uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... think about that. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... yeah, some of these shots, like single shots in uh, this episode where Aang is
            fighting Ozai, took like a week just to do the in-betweens, and uh, another week to
            color. I mean, fire is... has to be one of the hardest things to animate, um, it's just
            so intricate and organic, and uh, luckily uh, Yu Jae Myung is just one of the most
            amazing effects animators. Um, we're very lucky to have met him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to an Imperial Firebender, Qin Lee, and an airship engineer
                making awkward small talk as they wonder whose birthday it is, being dropped out of
                the airship by the hijackers just as they learn it is actually a crew member's
                birthday.</charAction> So, this is uh, a fabulous scene that <charAction>Bryan
                chuckles.</charAction> got saved from the...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> Fabulous...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> cutting-cutting room floor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... marvelous.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> It's a bit of a digression, bit-bit ridiculous, but
            uh, in such a serious finale, have a little...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> I was-I was totally against it,
                <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> and then uh, I was like, "oh wait, Mike and I
            will do the voices, and then I'll like it." <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> That's right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Naw, that's not why, but we did do the voices.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to the airship engineer wishing the crewmember a
                happy birthday after they surface from the water.</charAction> That's the last joke
            for a while, people. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Yeah, we did need some, some levity.
                <charAction>Brief pause; refers to Ozai's Phoenix King armor, the shoulder guards
                and breastplate being two phoenixes facing away from each other, their wings folded
                over his chest.</charAction> I like Ozai's uh, shoulder pads. <charAction>Refers to
                something on the commentator's display.</charAction> What were those flashes?
                <charAction>Brief pause; refers to the theme playing as Azula meets with Lo and
                Li.</charAction> So, again, I want to, um, point out Jeremy Zuckerman's world-class
            score here. Uh, it was really cool when uh, we sent this to M. Night Shyamalan, he-he
            called me really late one night, he and his family had just finished watching it, and
            one of the first things he said was just like, "aw! I loved the orchestra, just sounded
            amazing, it was like it was so cinematic". And uh, it was really fun, we-we talked about
            really like uh... kinda esoteric things, like, "oh, let's do just textures, and these
            like really, uh, dissonant chord clusters," and Jeremy had all these ideas about
            harmonics and things, you know, things he could really take advantage of the live
            players. And uh, he-I-he wrote some software that would do like digital mock-ups of
            this, these twenty-four note clusters and all these things, and uh, little microtonal
            shifts, and just not the kind of stuff you probably get in animated uh, TV scores.
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I don't even know what any of that is, so...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> I know...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... I just know...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... what most of it is, but even uh, you know...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>In the background.</charAction> I just...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... beyond-beyond the technical nerdiness of it um, it just adds a depth and a-and a
            beauty that uh, we're just so honored to have. <charAction>Refers to the tilt shot with
                Iroh and the other White Lotus Masters, shifting down to show the other members
                behind Iroh.</charAction> This is a really cool sequence. I love that shot, the
            camera shift, it's cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the White Lotus masters fighting the Fire Nation army at Ba
                Sing Se.</charAction> Yeah, it's nice to see the-the White Lotus guys have their
            moment. And...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects; refers to a shot Sozin's Comet fading in and out between
                Iroh breathing, a large ring of fire flaring up around him and the other masters
                every time he breathes in.</charAction> It's cool to show like uh, how the
            firebenders are tied in with this uh, natural event, this phenomenon, with the comet in
            the atmosphere.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Sozin's Comet travelling high above the surface of the Earth,
                never descending downward.</charAction> Aw yeah, that's a good thing to point out
            that peop-might not realize is that, the idea is that the comet is actually
            skimming...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Through the atmosphere.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... through the atmosphere. So-so, it's not, although it's not crashing into the
            Earth, it's-it's like basically just, yeah, just kind of skimming across uh, through the
            atmosphere. <charAction>Refers to the sky being dark reds and orange in the episode's
                various settings.</charAction> So, that's why, you know, the sky glows red, it's
            like basically the s-the sky is on fire.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until the White Lotus masters breach Ba Sing
                Se's outer wall, with Pakku immobilizing his opponents or blocking augmented fire
                blasts with waves of water, while Piandao swiftly breaks apart his enemies' weapons
                with his sword while using it to slide across the ice Pakku bent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, this was a very detailed sound design job by Ben Wynn. A lot of, this whole
            episode was probably, probably the most <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> effects
                <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> he's had to deal with. Just...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects; refers to the roaring sound of Jeong Jeong's fire walls, as
                they push back the fire blasting out from the Fire Nation tanks.</charAction> Yeah,
            we were like, "alright Ben, so, <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> the fire has to be
            bigger than any fire we've ever had. And it all has to sound different, like the fire
            wall has to sound different than the tank fire," and this and that, and just, you know,
            very creative solutions that he came up with. <charAction>Refers to Azula, now alone in
                the palace, trying to tie her own hair, before haphazardly cutting it in her manic
                frustration.</charAction> This is one of our favorite scenes I think uh,
                <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> probably in the whole series.
                <charAction>Refers to the piercing violin strings playing in the
                background.</charAction> Um, here you can hear some of these really... creepy
            harmonics from the violins and things. And uh, again we kind of carefully plotted out
            Azula's unravelling since the end of episode 315. <charAction>Refers to Azula talking to
                a hallucination of Ursa, her mother appearing as a reflection in the
                mirror.</charAction> And this was-this was meant to be when you really knew
                <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> she had cracked.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula's dishevelled, lopsided bangs.</charAction> Yeah, we
            wanted like a visual representation of her craziness of-too. So, like, you know, through
            the series her hair has been perfect, she's always well-dressed, and, you know, very
            proper and stuff, and she just chops off her bangs and her hair's a mess, and, you know,
            just-just an unkempt disaster.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula treating Ursa as though she were actually there, turning
                away from the mirror to look behind her and talk at Ursa.</charAction> I also like
            the-the ambiguity of this scene, is it-is it really her mother? Is it a ghost? Is it
            a... something in her-in her head? <charAction>Refers to Azula breaking the mirror,
                Ursa's reflection fading away as the shards of glass fall to the
                ground.</charAction> You can-if you look really closely as that big piece of glass
            is falling, she's-her mother's fading off. It's kind of a cool little detail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, 'cause you want going into that-her showdown with Zuko, you want that feeling
            of like, not only is she super powerful on this day, she's totally
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> out of her mind, <charAction>Bryan
                affirms.</charAction> and-and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Total loose cannon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> Yeah, she's-it's like how can Azula be more
            dangerous, and like even crazier? <charAction>Mike chuckles; refers to a shot Sozin's
                Comet fading in and out between shots of Ozai raising his head to the sky with his
                eyes closed.</charAction> So, we see that Ozai has the same connection.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Ozai scourging the land below him with a massive, sustained
                stream of fire.</charAction> This was a kinda crazy Seung Hyun had, the s-he called
            it "the seed of fire".</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>See...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Or maybe you called it that, I don't know.
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Naw, he did, he-I remember.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>I never really understood it, but once it was all animated and everything, I think
            it's cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the smoke billowing out from where Ozai's stream of fire hits
                the ground.</charAction> Just want to thank JM Animation for adding all that smoke.
                <charAction>Mike chuckles intermittently.</charAction> They did a beautiful job on
            all that fire, and then we're like, "oh man, but you put the smoke in the other scene,
            you think you could put it on that scene?" and I mean, that was like a weeks worth of
            work. Just crazy. <charAction>Refers to the flocks of birds flying and scattering in the
                background as they flee the Fire Nation's attack.</charAction> I love all those
            birds <charAction>Mike affirms intermittently.</charAction> in the background too. Nice
            scale. Very-it's very-I say this all the time, but it is really hard to get a sense of
            scale in TV animation, you know, just because of the way the process is setup with
            overseas and things. Um...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> And the screen's a lot smaller,
            right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Things just tend to be um, they tend to flatten out
            uh, when they go through the-the process of just kind of-just it's an ine-inevitable
            thing you have to fight. And um, yeah, little things like that are always
            satisfying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to Ozai removing most of his armor and garb, either
                throwing it away or burning it, as he flies off to confront Aang.</charAction> I
            like that he just burns off his clothes, he's like...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background</charAction> Like I...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... "I-I'm not going to need these."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... I think I added that because <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> it was a
            little weird that he was just ripping his clothes off, so I was like, eh,
                <charAction>Mike affirms intermittently.</charAction> he's gotta set them on fire to
            be a little cooler.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Totally.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the shot of Ozai, panning up to show his exposed muscular
                physique.</charAction> And we see Ozai, he's down to his fighting weight.
                <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction> He's pumped.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until Sokka realizes that Aang has returned,
                seeing the damaged airship he brought down through a telescope.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yay. <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>Another brief pause in commentary as the scene fades to black,
                transitioning back to a long shot of Aang and Ozai on separate rock pillars, staring
                each other down before their confrontation.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Alright, the madness begins.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, so uh, Bryan storyboarded, I think all of the Ozai action, right? Or a lot of
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Ozai-Aang battle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... yeah, this stuff in 320. <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> Um, yeah, it was
            really fun. This all took a lot of, a lot of board artists. Mike did a lot of 321, he
            did all of act three, and uh... just a bunch of people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>We got everyone involved...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, everybody.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... Seung Hyun...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Ben...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... basically, as people were finishing their shows, we got them to come and help
            on, <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> on these, 'cause as the board kept getting
            bigger and bigger, we were like, "oh man, we need some help."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. <charAction>Mike chuckles; refers to the pitched wailing sound that plays when
                Ozai bends a circular wave of fire at Aang.</charAction> Like there was like a
            scream in that fire, it's pretty cool. <charAction>Refers to Aang sending a chunk of a
                rock pillar at the pillar Ozai is standing on.</charAction> So, you see Aang's
            hesitation to sort of shoot directly at Ozai, he's always kind of shooting below him,
            or-or throwing something at him that he can avoid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, and-and throughout the-all the action sequences of the-of the finale, we tried
            to be careful about the fact that there was still a story being told. Like we wanted to
            do cool action, we wanted to be exciting and amazing and-and stuff, but we also wanted
            to make sure that there was still this emotional heart driving these action scenes.
                <charAction>Refers to Aang dodging Ozai's attacks more than he attacks.</charAction>
            So, for Aang in this sequence, it's-it's, it's him really trying to evade the Fire Lord,
            you know, he's throwing him shots at him, but he's not, he hasn't made up his mind what
            he's going to do yet, so he's kinda not <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> fully in
            the fight, he's-he's...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> He doesn't have a really good game plan,
                <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> and uh... yeah, there's-there's like
            different, <charAction>Refers to the long shot of the Imperial Firebender's streams of
                fire hitting the ground from above, unleashing a massive wave of fire and smoke on
                the surrounding landscape.</charAction> oh, I love that shot, it's one of my
            favorite ones. Joaquim uh, Dos Santos, the director of uh, 320 and 321, did this
            storyboard. Amazing director. <charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> He,
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> I remember uh... I was-he had done uh, the 316
            action with all the airships, and I said, <charAction>Refers to Sokka slamming their
                commandeered airship into the rest of the airship fleet.</charAction> "hey man,
            think we're going to have you do the uh, Sokka versus the airships in-in 320," and by
            the end of it, he was like, "I am so sick of drawing <charAction>Mike chuckles
                intermittently.</charAction> those stupid airships, with the horns, and the-the tube
            thing in the sky". He was just, oh, he had had enough, but he did a great job.
                <charAction>Brief pause; refers to Sokka's airship scraping along the tops of the
                enemy ships.</charAction> This is a cool moment.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the piercing sounds of metallic scraping as the airships come
                into contact with each other, and the airship the kids are on breaks apart around
                them.</charAction> Yeah, li-the sound is just great in this part, you really feel
            the metal just ripping apart, and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>It was very challenging uh, you know, Ben and Jeremy, the Track Team, really tried
            to plan... they knew the music had to be big, and the sound had to be big, but, um, you
            know, there's only so much, uh, bandwidth that you can take up with uh, the audio, you
            know, something's got to give, something has to step out of the way and-and let the
            other thing be in front. So, they tried to write around each other, and um, and then
            sometimes we made conscious decisions to uh, <charAction>Refers to the music cutting out
                just before Sokka's airship crashes into the first airship.</charAction> like that
            moment right before the crash, like bring the music down so that we can really hear and
            feel the impact of the uh, of the crashes. If you don't do that then you're not-if it's
            loud all the time, you-there's no dynamics, you don't feel the-the impact.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the five Fire Sages being the only attendees at Azula's
                coronation.</charAction> I love that there's like, there's basically nobody there
            'cause <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Azula banished...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> She kicked everybody out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... everyone except the F-the Fire Sages 'cause she-she just needed them for the
            crowning part.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to Zuko and Azula's Agni Kai.</charAction> So, of
            all of the different storylines, I gotta say I feel this one really stole the show. Um,
            there's something about these two siblings, and all the history... and then...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> It's got the most emotional weight behind it,
                <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> somehow.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Dean's, Dean Kelly's storyboards are just amazing. Jae Myung's key animation is just
            amazing. Music, the sound, <charAction>Refers to the theme, Last Agni Kai, that plays as
                Zuko and Azula initiate their Agni Kai, which dominates the scene, with the sounds
                of the siblings' firebending being dulled and muted.</charAction> and this was a
            case where we-we artis-made this artistic decision to-to mute the sound design, and-and
            really kinda turn it down and let this be more of an emotional, um, more of an emotional
            action scene.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, the-the sound mix for this, the-the last four episodes, we kinda did like a
            movie, we mixed them all the same week, and, and it was, creatively, it was really
            satisfying 'cause it-we were all there with Ben and Jeremy, and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> It was the most people we've ever had.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, <charAction>Bryan chuckles.</charAction> there was a lot of people, and it
            took a lot of time. Like, sometimes with these episodes, you know, they're, they're
            good, they're all set, the-our mixer Tom does a great job, and we go in and we're like,
            "yeah, sounds great, we got a few notes," and we're, you know, takes-takes an hour or
            two. This one, we really, there were so many, there were more decisions to be made I
            think, and-and <charAction>Bryan affirms intermittently.</charAction> more-more
            opportunities for doing creative things with the sound and music, that it took a lot
            longer, but it, in the end, we were all just so much happier with how it, how it all
            balanced and stuff like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>I just want to thank Tom for putting up...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background; laughs.</charAction> Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... with all of us, and all the notes. Of course... you know, Jerem-when Ben and
            Jeremy were both in there, Ben was like, "sound up!" <charAction>Mike
                chuckles.</charAction> and Jeremy was like, "music up!" and Tom's like, "I can't
            turn both up". So, that was cool. <charAction>Refers to the long shot of Aang launching
                from one pillar toward another one with airbending, then using his momentum and
                earthbending to send the latter pillar at Ozai.</charAction> That's a shot that
            works better if you have a large TV. <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> Mike... Mike
            uh, was like, "it too small," and I-I wish I had made it a little closer shot,
            but...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>No, but if you-we, we saw one of the shots on a-projected really big, and all these
            shots Bryan did where those characters are really tiny, that are har-it's hard to see on
            TV, totally see 'em on the big screen, and it looks awesome, so.
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Well, here's-here's the thing, we-we storyboarded this right when you got your
            really big TV. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Yeah, right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>And uh, I didn't have a TV at the time. I go over to Mike's house, and you're
            showing me <description>Planet Earth</description>, and, I mean, we're watching these
            tiny, little, you know, elk or whatever, running away from these African dogs or
            something, and they-they were so tiny on the screen, I was like, "man, you know, the-the
            thing in TV is always so close, everything's framed so tight," so I really made this
            conscious effort to uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background; refers to the slow motion sequence of Aang, lightning
                coursing through his body, sending the energy away from Ozai, refusing to kill
                him.</charAction> Cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... do real wide epic shots. But then we were doing retakes, we're like, "man, we
            can't see anything". <charAction>Bryan and Mike laugh.</charAction> So, maybe I went too
            far. But, now I have one of those big TVs.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Unless you got a big TV, <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction> then it looks pretty
            sweet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry, I don't mean to be...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Or sit really close to it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Don't do that stuff, or...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs; refers to Aang pulling the ocean water up to him with
                waterbending, cushioning his fall.</charAction> Love this animation, the water
            coming up, and Aang...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Yeah, it's cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... getting-going into it. <charAction>Refers to Aang's silhouette being visible in
                the wave pushed out from his pulling of the water.</charAction> You even see his
            little shadow <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> like swim underneath the water,
            which I hadn't noticed the first time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the filtered water flowing sound effect that plays while the
                shot is initially framed under the water of Aang's wave.</charAction> Cool sound
            design underwater there. So, you know, the plan was Aang was gonna get his butt whooped
            in this episode. <charAction>Refers to the cut back to Zuko and Azula's fight, the music
                once again dominating, with the sound of the firebending dulled.</charAction>
            Alright, here's-here's this uh, just beautiful music. And not to say that sound design's
            bad, it's just... we-I actually love how it sounds, we-we filtered it down, turned it
            down and let the music just stand in the front.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the tragic timbre of the Last Agni Kai theme.</charAction>
            Yeah, the music was just so emotionally resonant and powerful that every time we-the
            fire was louder, we just like, "ah! We can't really-still can't really hear the music,"
            you know, or you-you can hear it but it wasn't like, wasn't getting you in the gut,
                <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> and uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> This is the best of both worlds, I mean,
                <charAction>Mike affirms intermittently.</charAction> you-now you... the fire sounds
            are kinda distant, but, you know, the emotion is really present, and I th-this is just
            my-this is my favorite sequence.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, and it-it... s-since Aang and Ozai's fight is-is really like non-stop loud
            fire and rocks and everything... I think you-that your ears kinda needed a break too,
                <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> you know, from that, so it's-it's
            cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Also, I like that the-the fights have different characteristics, <charAction>Mike
                affirms.</charAction> I mean, that's something I, uh, being a fan of action, um,
            as-as, you know, a... executive producer on the show all this time, I was always saying
            to the board artists when-you know, either in the kung fu sessions with Kisu, or um,
            when we're storyboarding or doing the start-up meetings, you know, each fight has to
            have its own characteristic, and um... and uh, I really like how this one has a much
            different pace than-than the Aang-Ozai one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula generating lightning, ostensibly to shoot at Zuko; in a
                mock anticipatory tone.</charAction> And then...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Not to say it's better or worse, it's just different.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula instead targeting Katara.</charAction> You're like, aw,
            Azula, you didn't. <charAction>In a mock astonished tone.</charAction> Aw man, she did.
                <charAction>Bryan and Mike laugh; refers to Zuko protecting Katara by redirecting
                the lightning into himself.</charAction> Now, this is just...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the slowed down crackling sounds of the lightning
                strike.</charAction> Another s-cool sound...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Great moment too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... sound. Like...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>Bryan makes several dramatic breathing out noises, mimicking the flashing
                lightning during Zuko's dramatic sacrifice as seen by Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Zuko redirecting the lightning toward the sky while lying on
                the ground, electrical shocks coursing through his shaking body still.</charAction>
            So, Zuko releases most of the electricity, but he didn't
            really do it right, like Uncle warned him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Man, Zuko like sacrifices his life for Katara, and she still didn't go for him. What
            up? Zutarians...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> She-she can go with for him.
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> "Zutarians".</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> They're mad right now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Aw, they're going to be mad. What're you going to do. <charAction>Brief pause;
                refers to and imitates Ozai saying Aang, just like the rest of his "weak" people,
                did not deserve to live in Ozai's world.</charAction> "In my world!"
                <charAction>Brief pause; refers to Aang encasing himself in a sphere of rock to
                protect himself from Ozai's onslaught of fire.</charAction> So, again, everything
            ends bad in this one. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> One more to go!</speech>
    </p>
</root>
