<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Swamp Skiin Throwdown</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>The short opens with a shot of a leaf falling on the swamp, making it
                shine. A catgator surfaces from underneath the leaf, and the camera pans up to show
                Due and Tho watching Sokka making something.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>Sokka, shouldn't you be doing something fun, <charAction>A closer shot of Due and
                Tho.</charAction> or more manly?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td><charAction>Puts a finger of Tho's mouth to quiet him.</charAction> Pay attention,
            simpleton. This ... <charAction>Camera pans to show a hollowed out pumpkin with two
                leaves on top.</charAction> is a water filtration device. <charAction>Runs over to
                it.</charAction> See, your filthy swamp water sits in this hollowed-out pumpkin.
            Then the sunlight makes the water evaporate, leaving behind the swampy impurities.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>You mean the flavor?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yes, genius. It leaves behind the filthy swamp
            flavor. Then the clean water vapor collects on the leaf, and drips into this nice,
            sanitized cup. <charAction>Holds up the cup and takes a refreshing drink.</charAction>
            Ah! I do love clean water.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <td><charAction>From off-camera.</charAction> What'd you say, brain boy? <charAction>The
                camera pans to Aang swamp skiing.</charAction> You love water? Yee-haw!</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Aang creates a large wave, soaking Sokka and destroying his water
                filtration device.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>What you gonna do now?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td><charAction>Very angrily.</charAction> What do you think I'm going to do, leaf head?!
            I'm going to rebuild my water filtration device!</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>Boy, that there's a swamp skiin' throwdown. You can't be playing with pumpkin juice when
            there's a throwdown. It just ain't manly.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td>But ...</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td><charAction>His head suddenly becomes big and red.</charAction> Throwdown!
                <charAction>Sokka does a flip and falls on his head.</charAction> Hey Due, get the
            boat. <charAction>Due walks on-camera carrying a boat.</charAction> We're going swamp
            skiin'.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>At the river shore, Tho and Due put a flotation device on
                Sokka.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <td>Safety first.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Due positions Sokka over the skis. Sokka squirms when he sees a worm,
                beetle, snail, and fish in one of the skis. Sokka evades every attempt Due makes to
                place him in the skis.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>Get your dang feet in the skis, or I'll strap you to Old Slim instead.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Pan to Slim, the catgator, who bites the pumpkin from Sokka's water
                filtration device. Some of the pumpkin juice lands on Sokka. Due finally manages to
                get Sokka into the skis, and Sokka's face turns blue. Out on the river, Sokka holds
                a rope tied to Tho and Due's boat.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <td>You ready?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td><charAction>Flatly.</charAction> No.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>Hit it. Throwdown.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Tho grabs the rudder and Due swings his arms with engine sounds. Sokka
                immediately falls out of his skis and skids along the water until he lets go of the
                rope. A closer shot of Sokka surfacing while Aang quickly skis by in the background
                laughing.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>This time keep your knees bent and your tuckus tucked.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <td>Speaking of your tuckus, looks like Old Slim's got your pants.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Slim holds Sokka's trunks in his mouth stretching it like a muzzle.
                Embarrassed, Sokka lowers most of his head back in the water. Sokka tries to swamp
                ski again, but quickly gets pulled underwater. When he resurfaces, he finds he is
                now riding on Slim, who manages to bite off Sokka's trunks again as he jumps onto a
                tree branch. Aang, riding on one ski, swings by, and a camera shutter clicks when he
                passes Sokka. Sokka's face becomes red. Cut to Sokka attempting another round of
                swamp skiing. He loses one ski and crashes into tree vines. Aang splashes Sokka, and
                Aang does a large trick to jump on the head of Appa, who is also skiing. Cut to
                later, when Sokka is resurfacing from another round of swamp skiing.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td>Guys, can I get out of the water now?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>You tell me. <charAction>To Due.</charAction> Hit it.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>This time, Sokka manages to ski.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td>I-I ... I did it! I'm swamp skiing! <charAction>His eyes make heart
                symbols.</charAction> I love swamp skiing ...!
                <charAction>The camera pans back to the whole world and back to Sokka. Aang swings
                by, smiling.</charAction> In your face, air boy. Who's swamp skiing now?</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <td>Not you.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Aang uses waterbending to freeze a ramp for Sokka to jump off, sending the
                whole boat sailing through the air and crashing into the swamp.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <td><charAction>Falling down the trunk of the tree.</charAction> I hate swamp skiing.</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Slim bites off Sokka's trunks. Due and Tho celebrate the day of swamp
                skiing.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <td>Whoo, now that there's a throwdown!</td>
    </p>
    <p>
        <td>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </td>
    </p>
</root>
