<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Earth King</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens just outside the vast waters of Lake Laogai. Team Avatar
                has stopped on a tiny islet in the center of the lake. Aang is embracing Appa, happy
                upon reuniting with him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I missed you more than you'll ever know, buddy. <charAction>Momo flies into Appa to
                hug him too. Appa licks Aang, which causes Aang to laugh.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka approaches Katara and Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Look, we escaped from the Dai Li. We got Appa back. I'm telling you, we should go to
            the Earth King now and tell him our plan. We're on a roll.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>One good hour after weeks of trouble isn't much of a roll.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We can build on it. If we want to invade the Fire Nation when the eclipse happens,
            we'll need the Earth King's support.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What makes you think we'll get it? I don't know if you've noticed, but things don't
            usually go that smoothly for our little gang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know, but I've got a good feeling about this. This time will be
            different.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, Long Feng is in control of the city. His conspiracy with the Dai Li is too
            powerful. I think we should just keep flying and leave this horrible place behind
            us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'm with Sweetness. I've seen enough of Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Raises arms and
                opens eyes wide.</charAction> And I can't even see!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang flies into the shot.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But now that we have Appa back, there's nothing stopping us from telling the Earth
            King the truth. About the conspiracy and the War.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>See? Aang's with me. <charAction>Puts his arm around Aang and smiles.</charAction>
            It's the whole reason we came here in the first place. We have to try.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thinks for a moment.</charAction> Well, I guess if the Earth King knew
            the truth, things could change. <charAction>Sokka and Aang smile.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up.</charAction> I don't trust the new positive Sokka.
                <charAction>Points at Sokka in an accusing manner.</charAction> Long Feng
            brainwashed you, didn't he!?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang notices a few ships in the lake.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's probably the Dai Li searching for us. <charAction>To Katara.</charAction>
            So?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara thinks for a moment before looking at Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> Let's fly!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They fly toward the Palace, now with no saddle, holding onto Appa's fur for
                dear life, especially Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Can we please buy a new saddle? Riding bareback is terrifying! <charAction>Buries
                face in Appa's back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They get closer to the palace.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There it is! That whole thing is the palace! The Earth King's chamber should be in
            the center!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We have to be careful. Long Feng's probably warned the king that we're
            coming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why would you assume that? If you ask me, I think we're just gonna sail right in
            and- <charAction>A giant rock almost hits them.</charAction> Aahh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What was that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Surface-to-air rocks! <charAction>Sees more being launched.</charAction> More
            incoming!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They dodge a few more rocks. One gets launched right at Aang, but he
                destroys it with his hand. Another is launched at them head on, but Aang slices it
                cleanly in two by swinging his staff at the rock to augment his earthbending. He
                launches himself from Appa to the front of the palace and slams his staff into the
                ground, generating a massive earthen wave to knock back the palace guards. Appa
                lands and roars at the captain's ostrich horse, which causes it to drop the captain
                and run off. As they continue toward the Earth King, more guards appear and launch
                earth cubes at the gang. Toph and Aang use earthbending to block the attacks, while
                Katara uses waterbending to subdue the guards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Water whips two guards.</charAction> Sorry!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara turns around and strikes down more guards with her waterbending,
                though closes her right eye in a sympathetic flinch for a moment as she does so. As
                more guards rush toward them in an attempt to halt Team Avatar's progress, Toph uses
                her earthbending to flip the tiles of the walkway, trapping them between them and
                ensuring a clear passage for the team.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry! We just need to get through to see the Earth King!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>More guards appear on the opposite end of a bridge and launch two giant
                statues at them. Toph and Aang create an earth igloo to block the statues. Katara
                creates an ice ramp to jump to the other side of the bridge and water-whips the
                guards into the water. Aang freezes them in the water as the rest all jump across.
                More surface-to-air rocks appear as guards are coming down a giant staircase. Toph
                uses earthbending to change the stairs into a ramp, causing them all to fall. She
                and Aang use earthbending to escalate themselves up the stairs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously, we're actually on your guys' side! <charAction>Pauses for a
                moment.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>More guards come and Aang and Toph push them away with
                earthbending.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>In there! <charAction>They enter the palace.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They come to an area with three doors. More guards appear and Toph easily
                defeats them all.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, which way to the Earth King?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>How should I know? I'm still voting we leave Ba Sing
            Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph defeats more guards while Sokka opens the doors to find the Earth
                King. The first room is empty, as is the second; outside the second door, a royal
                guard goes flying to the right off-screen. Sokka bursts into a third room, startling
                a woman.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Palace woman">Palace woman</speaker>
        <speech>Burglar! <charAction>Tries to run, trips, and falls flat on her
            face.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shuts the door.</charAction> Sorry. Wrong door.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, Zuko and Iroh return from Lake Laogai. The former seems
                ill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You did the right thing. Letting the Avatar's bison go free.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I don't feel right. <charAction>Gets dizzy and passes out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko! <charAction>Rushes to him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the palace, the team arrives at a pile of rubble. Sokka climbs atop
                it and sees a gigantic door.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Now that's an impressive door. It's gotta go somewhere. <charAction>Drops down from
                the rubble and attempts to kick the door open.</charAction> Yaaah! <charAction>The
                door does not move even slightly. Sokka starts trying to push it open, but to no
                avail. Toph and Aang jump in from behind and bust the door down, knocking Sokka
                forward in the process. He starts rubbing the back of his head.</charAction> A
            little warning next time?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They arrive in the Earth King's chamber with Kuei sitting in his throne.
                Long Feng and his Dai Li agents stand in their way. The team takes fighting stances
                against them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We need to talk to you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns to face the Earth King.</charAction> They're here to overthrow
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, we're on your side. We're here to help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You have to trust us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up with a rising aggravated tone.</charAction> You invade my
            palace, lay waste to all my guards, break down my fancy door, and you expect me to trust
            you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>He has a good point.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>If you are on my side, then drop your weapons and stand down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They look at each other for a moment. Aang drops his staff, Katara puts her
                water whip back in her water skin, Sokka drops his machete, and Toph drops the
                boulder she is levitating.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles.</charAction> See? We're friends, Your Earthiness.
                <charAction>Gives a slight nervous chuckle.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The king says nothing and just continues to frown grimly. Long Feng signals
                the Dai Li to cuff their arms with rock gloves.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles sinisterly.</charAction> Detain the assailants!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Dai Li rush behind Team Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But we dropped our weapons. We're your allies.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>Make sure the Avatar and his friends never see daylight again. <charAction>The king
                looks at him shocked.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar? <charAction>Points at Sokka.</charAction> You're the Avatar?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, no. Him. <charAction>Nudges his head at Aang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Effortlessly breaks free of his earth cuffs and raises his
                arms.</charAction> Over here. <charAction>Re-attaches the
            cuffs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>What does it matter, Your Highness? They're enemies of the state.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Perhaps you're right. <charAction>Sees Bosco sniff and lick Aang, who laughs, and
                smiles at Long Feng.</charAction> Though Bosco seems to like him. <charAction>Looks
                back at the team.</charAction> I'll hear what he has to say. <charAction>Long Feng
                glares at Aang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks forward.</charAction> Well, sir, there's a war going on right now.
            For the past one hundred years in fact. The Dai Li's kept it secret from you. It's a
            conspiracy to control the city, and to control you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>A secret war? That's crazy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>Completely!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Long Feng didn't want us to tell you, so he stole our sky bison to blackmail us. And
            blackmail is the least of his crimes; he brainwashed our friend!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Quickly turns to face the king.</charAction> All lies. I've never even
            seen a sky bison, Your Majesty. Frankly, I thought they were extinct.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sits down.</charAction> Your claim is difficult to believe. Even from an
            Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers in his ear.</charAction> These hooligans are part of an
            anarchist cell that my agents have been tracking for weeks. <charAction>Kuei looks
                shocked at what Long Feng is telling him.</charAction> If you listen to them, you're
            playing right into your own destruction.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thinks for a moment.</charAction> I have to trust my advisor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The agents start taking the team away, but Sokka stops for a
                moment.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! <charAction>Turns to face the king with a big smile.</charAction> I can prove
            he's lying. Long Feng said he's never seen a sky bison. Ask him to lift his
            robe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>What? I am not disrobing! <charAction>The king looks
                thoughtful before looking at Sokka suspiciously.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Sokka smile slyly and nod at each other. Aang blows a large gust
                of air at Long Feng's legs, lifting his robe and revealing a bite mark left by
                Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Right there! Appa bit him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Never met a sky bison, huh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lowers his robe.</charAction> That happens to be a large birth mark.
                <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Thanks for showing everyone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Well I suppose there's no way to prove where those marks came from.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Of course there is!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The group gets Appa and brings him in. He opens his mouth. Aang points at
                the bison's teeth and at Long Feng's mark.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Yup. That pretty much proves it. <charAction>Team Avatar cheers.</charAction> But it
            doesn't prove this crazy conspiracy theory. <charAction>Team Avatar becomes
                downcast.</charAction> Though, I suppose this matter's worth looking into.
                <charAction>Team Avatar look at each other approvingly, while Long Feng glares at
                the king before walking away with his agents.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in Iroh and Zuko's apartment, Zuko is asleep. He wakes
                up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You're burning up. <charAction>Dips a cloth in water.</charAction> You have an
            intense fever. <charAction>Places the cloth on Zuko's forehead.</charAction> This will
            help cool you down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>So thirsty. <charAction>Sits up, but Iroh makes him lie back
            down.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs a bucket with a spoon in it; takes out the spoon.</charAction>
            Here's some clean water to drink. <charAction>Sits him up slightly.</charAction> Stay
            under the blankets and sweat this out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko grabs the spoon from Iroh and drinks the water. He tosses the spoon
                aside and grabs the bucket. He drinks from it, while spilling some out. He tosses
                the bucket aside and lies back down. Iroh pulls the covers more over him. Meanwhile,
                on a train, passengers are shocked to see the Earth King, who is standing in the
                middle of the cart surrounded by guards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Feeling strange from exposition.</charAction> So this is what a train is
            like? I didn't realize it would be this ... public.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So you've never been outside the Upper Ring before?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>I've never been outside the palace. <charAction>Katara and Sokka look at each other;
                the Earth King looks outside and sees Aang flying on Appa.</charAction> Now that's
            the way to travel. <charAction>Looks at Katara and Sokka.</charAction> So, may I ask
            where we're going?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Underneath Lake Laogai, Your Kingliness. To the Dai Li's secret headquarters. You're
            about to see where all the brainwashing and conspiring took place.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the shores of Lake Laogai. The team stand on the shore beside the
                Earth King and his guards. Toph steps to the edge of the water, and with a hop,
                reveals the the secret path to the hatch door entrance, though discovers it has been
                destroyed.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It's gone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh don't tell me- ! <charAction>Gives a thumbs up and a fake smile.</charAction>
            That's okay. Still got my positive attitude.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>The Dai Li must've known we were coming and destroyed the evidence!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks suspicious.</charAction> Hm ...
                <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> That seems awfully convenient.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, if anything, this proves the conspiracy exists even more. <charAction>Smiles
                and nods.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Long Feng was right. This was a waste of time. <charAction>Turns to
                leave.</charAction> If you'll excuse me, I'm going back to the palace.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles with realization.</charAction> The wall. They'll never be able to
            cover that up in time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, yeah. <charAction>Hops to in front of the king.</charAction> If you come with us
            to the Outer Wall, we can prove to you that the secret war is real.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>No Earth King has ever been to the Outer Wall. <charAction>Walks past
                Aang.</charAction> I don't have any more time for this nonsense. <charAction>Aang
                looks depressed.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs up to them.</charAction> If you come with us, this time you can
            ride on Appa. <charAction>The Earth King stops as Appa lows in the background. A pleased
                smile grows on his face.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>En route to the Outer Wall. The Earth King is riding on Appa, holding on
                for dear life and screaming at the top of his lungs in fear, his clothes flapping in
                the wind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>First time flying?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>It's both thrilling and terrifying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> I hate it, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>I have to be honest with you: part of me really hopes that what you're telling me
            about this war isn't true.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I wish it wasn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile at the apartment, Iroh again places the moist cloth over his
                feverish nephew's forehead. Zuko is having a dream that he is the Fire Lord, with no
                scar on his eye. One red and one blue dragon appear and start circling around the
                pillars on each side of him. The blue dragon starts circling around
                Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Blue dragon">Blue dragon</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In Azula's voice.</charAction> It's getting late. Are you planning to
            retire soon, my lord?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not tired.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Blue dragon">Blue dragon</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Into Zuko's ear.</charAction> Relax, Fire Lord Zuko. Just let go. Give
            in to it. Shut your eyes for a while.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko slowly starts to shut his eyes but widely opens them upon hearing the
                other dragon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Red dragon">Red dragon</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In Iroh's voice.</charAction> No, Fire Lord Zuko! Do not listen to the
            blue dragon. You should get out of here right now. Go! Before it's too late!
                <charAction>Both dragons are poised to either side of Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Blue dragon">Blue dragon</speaker>
        <speech>Sleep now, Fire Lord Zuko.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The dragons disappear, and the room they're in, as well as the guards
                watching Zuko, crumble to nothing. The blue dragon reappears in front of him. Two
                golden eyes appear, followed by the face of the blue dragon, which closes
                rapidly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Blue dragon">Blue dragon</speaker>
        <speech>Sleep. <charAction>Voice grows louder and more hostile as it continues
                talking.</charAction> Just like mother!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Charges at Zuko and opens its mouth. Inside the dragon's mouth, Zuko sees
                his mother, Ursa. Within that darkness, the camera draws closer to Ursa, who drops
                her hood.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ursa">Ursa</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko! Help me! <charAction>A distraught Zuko is seen in her
            eyes.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko disappears through the floor. The sleeping Zuko starts sweating.
                Meanwhile, Team Avatar arrives at the Outer Wall and sees the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points at the drill.</charAction> It's still there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> What is that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's a drill. A giant drill <charAction>Cut to the drill.</charAction> made by the
            Fire Nation to break through your walls. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of the king who
                looks horrified.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>On top of the wall, they're looking down at the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe I never knew. <charAction>He looks to his right as he hears
                something.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Appears on an earth elevator with two Dai Li agents.</charAction> I can
            explain this, Your Majesty. <charAction>Walks toward the king.</charAction> This is
            nothing more than ... a construction project. <charAction>Gestures his hand to the
                drill.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Really? Then perhaps you could explain why
            there's a <charAction>Points to the drill as Kuei follows to where she is pointing. Cut
                to the Fire Nation insignia clearly shown on the drill.</charAction> Fire Nation
            insignia on your "construction project".</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The king looks at him suspiciously.</charAction> Well it's imported of
            course. You know you can't trust domestic machinery. <charAction>Looks at them
                worried.</charAction> Surely you don't believe these children instead of your most
            loyal attendant?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks at Team Avatar, who stare back innocently, then at Long Feng, who
                is glaring back.</charAction> Dai Li! Arrest Long Feng! I want him to stand trial
            for crimes against the Earth Kingdom.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Long Feng and Team Avatar look shocked. The two agents behind Long Feng
                share glances, launch shackles onto his arms and pull him in.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Long Feng">Long Feng</speaker>
        <speech>You can't arrest me! You all need me more than you know! <charAction>He is taken
                away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> Looks like Long Feng is long gone! Ha! Ah, yeah,
            I've been waiting to use that one. <charAction>Aang smiles at him and Katara gives him
                an unimpressed look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>That night at the Palace, the Earth King is talking with Team
                Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>I want to thank you, young heroes, for opening my eyes. All this time, what I
            thought was a great metropolis was merely a city of fools. And that makes me the king
            fool. <charAction>Buries his face in one of his hands.</charAction> We're at war. With
            the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's why we came to Ba Sing Se, Your Highness: because we think you can help us
            end the war.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Momo climbs up Kuei's arm.</charAction> We don't have much time. There's
            a comet coming this summer. Its energy will give the firebenders unbelievable strength.
            They'll be unstoppable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But there is hope. Before the comet comes, we have a window of opportunity: A solar
            eclipse is coming. The sun will be completely blocked out by the moon, and the
            firebenders will be helpless.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>What are you suggesting, Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's the day we need to invade the Fire Nation. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of
                the king. Cut back to Sokka.</charAction> The Day of Black Sun.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know. That would require moving troops out of Ba Sing Se. We'd be completely
            vulnerable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're already vulnerable. The Fire Nation won't stop until Ba Sing Se falls. You
            can either sit back and wait for that to happen, or take the offensive and give yourself
            a fighting chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thinks for a moment as everyone waits anxiously.</charAction> Very well.
            You have my support.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar celebrates. Someone else arrives.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General How">General How</speaker>
        <speech>Your Majesty. <charAction>Walks up to Team Avatar and bows to the king.</charAction>
            I apologize for the interruption.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Team Avatar.</charAction> This is General How. He's the leader of the
            Council of Five, my highest ranking generals.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General How">General How</speaker>
        <speech>We searched Long Feng's office. I think we found something that will interest
            everybody. <charAction>Team Avatar look at each other.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In Long Feng's office, a soldier is carrying a box of papers to the
                desk.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General How">General How</speaker>
        <speech>There are secret files on everyone in Ba Sing Se. Including you kids.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Secret files?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes out a scroll and reads the side.</charAction> "Toph Beifong."
                <charAction>Hands the scroll to General How, who hands it to Toph, who hands it to
                Katara.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opens the scroll and reads it.</charAction> It's a letter from your mom.
            Your mom's here in the city. And she wants to see you. <charAction>Toph's eyes widen
                with shock.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Long Feng intercepted our letters from home? <charAction>Shakes her
                head.</charAction> That's just sad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes out another scroll and hands it to Aang.</charAction>
            Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General How">General How</speaker>
        <speech>This scroll was attached to the horn of your bison when the Dai Li captured
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opens the scroll and reads it.</charAction> It's from the Eastern Air
            Temple.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Is there a letter for me and Sokka by any chance?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks in the box.</charAction> I'm afraid not.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He and Katara become downcast.</charAction> Oh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General How">General How</speaker>
        <speech>But there is an intelligence report that might interest you. <charAction>Hands a
                scroll to Katara.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opens the scroll and reads it.</charAction> "A small fleet of Water
            Tribe ships."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked. Appears on Katara's side.</charAction> What? That could be
            Dad!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reads the report with excitement.</charAction> "Protecting the mouth of
            Chameleon Bay. <charAction>Her and Sokka's eyes widen.</charAction> Led by Hakoda."
                <charAction>Katara and Sokka turn to each other in excitement.</charAction> It
                is Dad!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile at the apartment, Iroh is pouring tea.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You should know that this is not a natural sickness, but that shouldn't stop you
            from enjoying tea. <charAction>Feeds Zuko the tea.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What's happening?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Your critical decision. What you did beneath that lake. It was in such conflict with
            your image of yourself that you are now at war within your own mind and body.
                <charAction>Feeds Zuko more tea.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What's that mean? <charAction>Coughs continuously and lies
            down.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You are going through a metamorphosis, my nephew. It will not be a pleasant
            experience, but when you come out of it, <charAction>Takes a cloth and wipes Zuko's
                head.</charAction> you will be the beautiful prince you were always meant to
            be.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in Long Feng's office.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe it. There's a man living at the Eastern Air Temple. He says he's a
            guru.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What's a guru? Some kind of poisonous blow fish?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, a spiritual expert. He wants to help me take the next step in the Avatar
            journey. He says he can teach me to control the Avatar State.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>And I can't believe we know where our dad is now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I know what you mean. My mom's in the city. And from her letter it sounds like she
            finally understands me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This is all such big news! Where do we even start?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I hate to say it, but we have to split up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Split up? We just found Appa and got the family
            back together! Now you want us to separate?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You have to meet this guru, Aang. If we're going to invade the Fire Nation, you need
            to be ready.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, if I'm going to the Eastern Air Temple, Appa and I can drop you off at
            Chameleon Bay to see your dad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Someone has to stay here with the Earth King and help him plan for the invasion.
                <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> I guess that's me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, Sokka. I know how badly you wanna help Dad. You go to Chameleon Bay. I'll stay
            here with the king.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Overjoyed with tears welling in his eyes. Stands up and dances
                happily.</charAction> You are the nicest ... sister ... ever! <charAction>Throws his
                arms around Katara and kisses her on the cheek.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Easy there, big brother ... <charAction>Gives a slight chuckle.</charAction> Though
            you're right. I am.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Outside the Palace, Team Avatar is preparing to leave. The king walks down
                to them. Katara is petting Appa. Aang turns to face her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara? I need to tell you something. <charAction>Starts blushing.</charAction> I've
            been wanting to say it for a long time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What is it, Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rubs the back of his head.</charAction> Katara, I- <charAction>He is cut
                off by Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Throws Aang in a headlock.</charAction> All right. Who's ready to get
            going on our little men-only man trip? <charAction>Noogies Aang. Katara looks at him,
                annoyed.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Aang and Sokka, <charAction>They look at him.</charAction> I wish you a good
            journey. Ba Sing Se owes you its thanks. We look forward to your safe return.
                <charAction>Aang, Katara, and Sokka bow.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka starts climbing atop Appa. A soldier walks up to the
                king.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Soldier">Soldier</speaker>
        <speech>Your Majesty. There are three female warriors to see you. They're from the island of
            Kyoshi.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> That's Suki! <charAction>Falls off
                Appa.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>You know these warriors?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets up.</charAction> Oh yeah. The Kyoshi Warriors are a skilled group
            of fighters. Trustworthy too. They're good friends of ours.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>Then we shall welcome them as honored guests.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang turns to Appa.</charAction> Wait. Aang. <charAction>She hugs him,
                which startles him, then kisses him on the cheek, causing him to
            blush.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'm really gonna miss you guys.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hugs Toph with Aang. Sokka looks away, crossing his arms.</charAction>
            Me too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Everyone goes to hug him.</charAction> Aahh! Great. That's enough.
                <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> Okay, we love each other. <charAction>Pats Aang and
                Katara on the head.</charAction> Seriously.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa flies off. Back at the apartment, Iroh and Zuko are asleep. Zuko wakes
                up and walks into the bathroom. He washes his face with water. When he looks in the
                mirror, he sees himself with no scar, no hair and an arrow tattoo on his head,
                resembling Aang. He looks horrified. He screams himself awake and breathes heavily.
                He touches the scar on his face and closes his eyes. Meanwhile, Appa is flying Sokka
                and Aang. Sokka is resting across Appa's back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You see, Aang? A little positive thinking works wonders. We got the king on our
            side, we got Long Feng arrested, and when we get back, Suki's waiting for me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Dreamily.</charAction> Yeah. Girls are waiting for us. Thanks, positive
            attitude.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Everything is gonna work out perfectly. From now on and forever. <charAction>Aang
                turns around and smiles at him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In a prison, Long Feng is sitting in his cell. A Dai Li agent appears
                outside of the cell.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Agent">Agent</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slides a tray of food underneath the door.</charAction> Dinner.
                <charAction>Long Feng grabs some food.</charAction> The Council of Five and the
            military are loyal to the Earth King, <charAction>Long Feng looks at him.</charAction>
            but the Dai Li remains loyal to you, Long Feng, sir. <charAction>Walks away as Long Feng
                eats his food while smiling sinisterly.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, at a random house, Toph is outside. She exhales deeply and
                knocks on the door. It opens on its own.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enters.</charAction> Hello? Mom? Anyone home? <charAction>Walks to the
                center of the room. She senses something, but is quickly captured in a metal box. In
                a scared voice.</charAction> Hey! Who do you think you're dealing with!?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Xin Fu and Master Yu appear.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>One loud-mouthed little brat who strayed too far from home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the palace, three Kyoshi Warriors are walking up to the king and
                bow.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kuei">Kuei</speaker>
        <speech>In our hour of need, it is with the highest honor that I welcome our esteemed
            allies, the Kyoshi Warriors!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warriors look up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>We are the Earth King's humble servants.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The middle warrior is shown to have gold eyes, showing that it is really
                Azula, Mai, and Ty Lee disguised as Kyoshi Warriors, whom they have previously
                defeated.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
