<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Boiling Rock Part 1</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene opens to the Western Air Temple at nightfall. Zuko is pouring tea
                to give to the members of Team Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a tray full of tea cups with Zuko's hand holding a kettle and
                filling up the empty cups.</charAction> No one can make tea like Uncle
                <charAction>Camera pans up to Zuko's face.</charAction>, but hopefully I learned a
            thing or two. Would you like to hear Uncle's favorite tea joke?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sure. <charAction>Cut to an overhead of the group sitting around a
                fire.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I like jokes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Bring it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Okay. <charAction>Serves tea to The Duke and Haru and stands up with his
                tray.</charAction> Well, I can't remember how it starts, but the punch line
                <charAction>The boys help themselves to the tea.</charAction> is "Leaf me alone, I'm
            bushed!" <charAction>No response.</charAction> Well, it's funnier when Uncle tells
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Right ... maybe that's because he remembers the whole thing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone else laughs. Zuko smiles a little.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It's nice to get a chance to relax a little. It hardly ever happens.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko hands tea to Teo and Toph. He subsequently approaches
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, can I talk to you for a second? <charAction>Stands up and walks
                out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko sets down the tray of tea. The camera switches to a shot of him and
                Sokka walking away from where the rest of the group is gathered.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>So, what's up? <charAction>Appa wakes up and looks as they walk past
                him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>If someone was captured by the Fire Nation, where would they be taken?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean? Who was captured?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>When the invasion plan failed, some of our troops were taken. I just want to know
            where they might be.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I can't tell you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What? Why not?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Trust me. Knowing would just make you feel worse. <charAction>Turns to leave, but is
                stopped by Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's my dad. He was captured too. I need to know what I put him through.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It's not good, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>My guess is, they were taken to the Boiling Rock.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What's that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The highest security prison in the Fire Nation. <charAction>Sokka looks at him,
                horrified.</charAction> It's on an island in the middle of a boiling lake. It's
            inescapable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So, where is this place?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Why do you need to know? What are you planning?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Nothing. <charAction>Pauses for a moment.</charAction> Boy, you're so
            paranoid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It's in the middle of a volcano between here and the Fire Nation. You guys actually
            flew right past it on your way here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks, Zuko. <charAction>Yawns.</charAction> Just knowing makes me feel
            better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, I'm sure it does.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to later that night. With everyone asleep, Sokka sneaks away from
                everyone. He sighs and almost steps on Momo, narrowly avoiding tripping over him and
                waking him up. He climbs onto Appa, who awakes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Appa.</charAction> Shhh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa goes back to sleep, as Sokka climbs on top of him. However, as he
                climbs up, he notices Zuko is already in the saddle with his arms
                crossed.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Not up to anything, huh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Falls off Appa, his bag's contents fall out.</charAction> Fine, you
            caught me. I'm gonna rescue my dad. You happy now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm never happy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Picking up the fallen items.</charAction> Look, I have to do this. The
            invasion plan was my idea, it was my decision to stay when things were going wrong.
                <charAction>Zuko jumps off of Appa.</charAction> It's my mistake, and it's my job to
            fix it. I have to regain my honor. You can't stop me, Zuko. <charAction>Pushes Zuko
                aside and begins to climb up Appa on Appa's saddle.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You need to regain your honor? Believe me, I get it. I'm going with you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No. I have to do this alone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>How are you going to get there? On Appa? Last time I checked, prisons don't have
            bison daycares. <charAction>Sokka stops climbing, sighs, and looks back at
                Zuko.</charAction> We'll take my war balloon. <charAction>They walk off to the war
                balloon.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Appa and Momo, still sleeping at sunrise. The Duke gives Appa some
                hay. Katara notices that Momo is holding a note.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What does it say?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>"Need meat. Gone fishing. Back in a few days. Sokka and Zuko." <charAction>As she
                says this, Aang yawns and turns around to lie back down.</charAction> One more
            thing. "Aang, practice your firebending while I'm gone. Do twenty sets of fire fists and
            ten hot squats every time you hear a badgerfrog croak. Zuko."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A badgerfrog croaks, waking Aang from his rest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Nobody else has homework. <charAction>Stands up and
                walks to a spot and starts hot squatting while Katara and Toph walk
                away.</charAction> One hot squat, two hot squat, three hot squat, four hot squat
            ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene cuts to Zuko and Sokka in the air in the war balloon. Zuko blasts
                fire into the tank to keep it moving. A moment of awkward silence between the two
                follows.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Pretty clouds.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah ... fluffy. <charAction>Sokka whistles.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What? Oh, I didn't say anything. You know, a friend of mine actually designed these
            war balloons.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>No kidding.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yep, a balloon ... but for war.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>If there's one thing my dad's good at, it's war. <charAction>Blasts more fire into
                the tank.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, it seems to run in the family.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks at Sokka, defensively.</charAction> Hey, hold on. Not everyone in
            my family is like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know, I know, you've changed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Downcast.</charAction> I meant my uncle. He was more of a father to me.
            And I really let him down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I think your uncle would be proud of you. Leaving your home to come help us? That's
            hard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It wasn't that hard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Really? You didn't leave behind anyone you cared about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I did have a girlfriend. Mai.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles and looks at Zuko with interest.</charAction> That gloomy girl
            who sighs a lot?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles.</charAction> Yeah. Everyone in the Fire Nation thinks I'm a
            traitor. I couldn't drag her into it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>My first girlfriend turned into the moon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked for a moment. Looks up at the sky briefly, before glancing back
                at Sokka.</charAction> That's rough, buddy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Nightfall. Sokka is asleep, snoring loudly. Zuko continues to keep the tank
                full. He stops to look out in the distance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>There it is! <charAction>Sokka awakens to see it.</charAction> There's plenty of
            steam to keep us covered. As long as we're quiet, we should be able to navigate through
            it without being caught.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As they enter the volcano's steam, the balloon begins losing altitude
                quickly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frantically blasting fire into the tank.</charAction> We're going down!
            The balloon's not working anymore! <charAction>Blasts fire up into the
                balloon.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The air outside is just as hot as the air inside so we can't fly!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Falls to the side as the balloon tips.</charAction> So what are we
            supposed to do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know! Crash-landing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The balloon skids along the boiling water, splashing Sokka's hand, which he
                shakes while blocking his mouth to prevent himself from screaming. The balloon hits
                the base of the rock, ejecting the two from it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at the destroyed war balloon.</charAction> How are we gonna get
            off the island if the balloon won't work?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We'll figure something out! I suspected it might be a one-way ticket.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You knew this would happen and you wanted to come anyway?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks to the destroyed balloon.</charAction> My dad might be here! I had
            to come and see!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle always said I never thought things through. But this ... this is just
            crazy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gathers parts from the balloon together.</charAction> Hey, I never
            wanted you to come along in the first place! And for the record, I always think things
            through! But my plans haven't exactly worked, so this time, I'm playing it by ear. So
            there. <charAction>After the hot water on the balloon burns his hand, Sokka kicks it
                into the water.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It doesn't work anyway, and we don't want anyone to find it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I hope you know what you're doing. <charAction>They both turn to look at the
                prison.</charAction> There's no turning back now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Morning. Zuko and Sokka have entered the prison, and come out of a supply
                room filled with reserve guard uniforms. Both of them wear prison guard
                uniforms.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I hope these disguises work.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We just need to lay low and find my dad as soon as possible.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A series of guards run by. One of them runs back and looks at
                them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Guards! There's a scuffle in the yard. Come on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two go to the yard. Prisoners are gathered in a circle as the guards
                move through to the inside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>I didn't do anything! I'm going back to my cell.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whips fire at him.</charAction> Stop right there, Chit Sang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko tries to approach, but Sokka grabs his arm to stop him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We can't blow our cover.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>I've had it with your unruly behavior!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>What did I do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>He wants to know what he did. <charAction>To Zuko and Sokka.</charAction> Isn't that
            cute? <charAction>Gives them a look when they say nothing.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, very cute, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Super cute.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks up to Chit Sang.</charAction> You didn't bow down when I walked
            by, Chit Sang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>What? That's not a prison rule.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>Do it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Make me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The bully guard walks away, but as he is leaving, he whips fire at Chit
                Sang. Chit Sang blocks it, and redirects it at him. The bully guard breaks the blast
                with a kick.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>Tsk, tsk. Firebending is prohibited. You're going in the cooler.
                <charAction>Pointing at Sokka.</charAction> You! Help me take him in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers to Zuko.</charAction> Meet back here in an hour.
                <charAction>Runs up to Chit Sang and the guard.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back inside, Chit Sang is led to a cooler.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>The warden will deal with you soon. <charAction>Sokka closes the doors.</charAction>
            Can you believe this guy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Playing along.</charAction> Prisoners! Am I right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>Ugh. Tell me about it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meal time for the guards. Zuko is getting food, noticeably the only guard
                wearing a helmet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, new guy! I know it's the rule to have your helmet on at all times, but this is
            the lounge. Relax.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>But what if there's an incident? If I'm not prepared, someone could strike me on the
            head.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guards laugh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>Give it a week, he'll loosen up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Can the new guy ask you veterans a few questions about the prison?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bluntly.</charAction> No, you can't date the female guards.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Trust me, you don't want to. <charAction>The female guard throws a cup at him, which
                causes the guard sitting behind him to laugh.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>No, that's not it. The Boiling Rock, it holds the Fire Nation's most dangerous
            criminals, right? <charAction>The other guards nod.</charAction> So what about war
            prisoners?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In the yard, the warden arrives on the gondolas. Meanwhile, Sokka and the
                bully guard continue to stand guard by the cooler. Sokka is looking inside at Chit
                Sang who is shivering.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It sure looks cold in there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>That's why we call it the cooler. He won't be firebending there. <charAction>Notices
                someone coming; lowers his mask.</charAction> It's the warden! <charAction>He and
                Sokka stand to attention.</charAction> Look alive!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opens the cooler.</charAction> So Chit Sang, I hear you used firebending
            to try to escape. You should know better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>I wasn't trying to escape.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>He's lying! I saw it with my own eyes. <charAction>He is pushed aside by one of the
                warden's bodyguards.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>No one has ever, ever escaped from here. I'd sooner jump in the Boiling Lake myself
            than let that record fall. Don't forget it. Now go back to your shivering.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in the yard. Zuko approaches Sokka, but does not know it is
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Hey there, fellow guard, how goes it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lifts up his helmet's visor.</charAction> Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Shhh! Listen, I asked around the lounge. There are no Water Tribe prisoners.
                <charAction>Lifts up his visor.</charAction> I'm afraid your father's not
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What? Are you sure, did you double-check?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I'm sure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No. No! <charAction>Bangs his fists against the wall in
            frustration.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm really sorry, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So we came all this way for nothing? I failed ... again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, <charAction>Holds his chin in thought.</charAction> what would Uncle say?
                <charAction>Cut to a frog-view as he looks up at the sky.</charAction> Sometimes,
            clouds have two sides, <charAction>Walks over to the railing.</charAction> a dark and
            light, and a silver lining in between. It's like a silver sandwich! <charAction>Close-up
                of a disinterested Sokka; voice-over.</charAction> So ... when life seems hard ...
                <charAction>Sokka glances to the side.</charAction> take a bite out of the silver
            sandwich!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka's eyes widen when he notices something; close-up of his cheerful
                expression as he gets up. Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko while Sokka runs up to grab
                the railing next to him, excitedly looking down to the yard below.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe we haven't failed after all!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>That's the spirit! <charAction>Folds his arms.</charAction> I can't believe that
            worked. <charAction>Looks down.</charAction> I didn't even know what I was
            saying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, what you said made no sense at all. But look ... <charAction>As he points, the
                camera shifts to an overhead view of the yard, before rapidly zooming in on a
                dejected-looking Suki.</charAction> It's Suki!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suki, sitting in the prison yard in prison garb, looks up at hearing the
                continuous ringing of a bell.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Prisoners, <charAction>Suki gets
                up.</charAction> back in your cells!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the prison yard from ground level as the prisoners start
                to walk back inside. Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko and Sokka. The latter's eyes are
                now rapidly blinking pink hearts, while Zuko gives him a conspicuous look. Sokka
                does not pay attention and lowers the visor of his helmet with a smile before
                dashing out of the scene with a surprised Zuko quicking turning his head and looking
                after him. Cut to the prisoners' housing area. Camera slowly pans to show a guard
                mopping the floor and another one doing his rounds. Cut to Suki lying on her bed and
                staring at the ceiling in sadness. The door to her cell opens and closes,
                illuminating her face as her eyes turn to the door. Cut to a further off side-shot
                of Sokka entering Suki's cell.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sits up; aggressively.</charAction> What is it? Did I do something
            wrong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Crosses arms.</charAction> You mean you don't recognize me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up. She averts her eyes; bitterly.</charAction> You people all
            look the same to me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot; smugly.</charAction> Oh? Then maybe you'll recognize
            this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka purses his lips and attempts smooching sounds as he leans in to kiss
                Suki. His lips are suddenly grasped by a hand. The camera switches to the side-shot
                as Suki violently shoves him against the door. Frontal shot of Sokka as he makes
                contact with the door, his helm flinging off in the process. He looks bewildered to
                Suki. Cut to a close-up of Suki, her left arm still stretched out in the move she
                used to push him away. Her angry expression instantly brightens.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka! <charAction>Runs up to him; cut to a side-view.</charAction> It's
            you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suki rushes to pull Sokka into an embrace. Still bewildered, he does not
                immediately return the gesture. Cut to a frontal shot of Sokka, Suki resting her
                head on his shoulder, and he mellows into the embrace, returning it in all honestly
                while closing his eyes. Cut to a close-up side-shot of Suki, who is tearing up out
                of joy.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>They both stand up, not releasing each other.</charAction> The other
            Kyoshi Warriors, are they here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>No. I don't know where they are. They locked me in here because I'm the
            leader.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Places his right hand on her left cheek.</charAction> Well, you won't be
            here for long. I'm busting you out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> I'm so glad <charAction>Places her hand over
                Sokka's on her face and closes her eyes.</charAction> to see you Sokka.
                <charAction>Opens them again.</charAction> I knew you'd come.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a side-shot of the now-reunited couple as they gaze lovingly at each
                other. They release hands, placing them on the other's arms, and lean in to kiss;
                Suki throws her arms around Sokka's neck. Cut to a close-up frontal shot of Zuko
                standing guard outside the cell. He suddenly looks to his right. Cut to a further
                off shot, showing the entire hallway, revealing that the sound that drew Zuko's
                attention was a guard ascending nearby stairs. He taps on the cell door to get Sokka
                and Suki's attention. Cut to inside the cell where the couple stops kissing, Sokka
                casting a suspicious look to the door. Cut back to outside the cell, where the
                female guard approaches Zuko, who is standing in front of the cell door, his arms
                crossed behind his back. He turns to her as she pulls up next to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>Excuse me. <charAction>Cut to a shot from behind Zuko.</charAction> I need to get
            into that cell.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot from over the guard's shoulder.</charAction> No, you can't go in
            there! <charAction>Looks at the prison cell; unsure.</charAction> The lights are out.
                <charAction>Points at the door.</charAction> The prisoner could sneak up on
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up. Cut to a side-shot; annoyed.</charAction> Step aside, fool.
                <charAction>She raises her left arm to push Zuko out of the way, though before she
                can touch him, he grabs hold of the arm and turns her around, slamming her face
                first against the door.</charAction> Hey, hey, what are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She turns to retaliate against Zuko's action. Cut to inside the cell, where
                Zuko's head can be seen through the looking hole as he is slammed against the door.
                The camera pans down to show Sokka and Suki pushed against the door, looking up in
                worry. Sokka's expression turns serious as he lowers his gaze and puts on his
                helmet. Cut to a close-up shot of the guard's right calf as Zuko plants his own leg
                behind it. Switch to a further off shot. Zuko grabs a hold of the woman's right arm
                and forces her to bend backward, thus averting her sight from the door that slides
                open. Sokka quickly exits the cell and shuffles away, his back pressed against the
                wall. The female guard manages to push Zuko's face up with her left arm, regaining a
                more leveled pose herself. Cut to a close-up side-shot of her from underneath Zuko's
                arms as she looks to her right.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Instantly cut to a frontal shot of Sokka, who freezes over.</charAction>
            Guard, help! <charAction>He turns to look at the struggle.</charAction> I think he's an
            impostor! <charAction>Frontal shot of Sokka, looking unsure.</charAction> Arrest
            him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the gondola making its way to the prison. Cut back to
                inside the prison as the struggle continues.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>Get him off me and arrest him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs Zuko and throws him down on the floor.</charAction> You're under
            arrest! <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Don't worry, I'll figure it out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka leads Zuko away, followed by the female guard. Later, Zuko, now in
                prison garb, is in an isolated room. The door opens, revealing the
                warden.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Well, well, well. I never thought I'd find you in here, <charAction>Smiles evilly
                and walks into the cell.</charAction> Prince Zuko.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> How did you know who I am?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>How could I not? You broke my niece's heart.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Even more shocked.</charAction> You're Mai's uncle? I never meant to
            hurt her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Quiet! You're my special prisoner now. And you'd best behave. If these criminals
            found out who you are, the traitor prince who let his nation down, why they'd tear you
            to shreds.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Folds his arms.</charAction> So what's in it for you? Why don't you just
            tell my father to come collect a reward?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, in due time, believe me, I intend to collect. <charAction>Walks away and shuts
                the door.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Outside the cells, Sokka comes down and sees Zuko and Suki mopping
                floors.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, good, you guys have met.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, we met a long time ago.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>We did?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Somewhat angrily.</charAction> Yeah, you kind of burned down my
            village.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops mopping for a second.</charAction> Oh, sorry about that. Nice to
            see you again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko and Suki stop mopping and hide from the other guards beside a
                staircase.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So, listen, I think I have an escape plan. I checked out the coolers again, and the
            point of them is to keep firebenders contained, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So, they're completely insulated and sealed to keep the cold in. Well, to keep the
            cold in, it also has to keep the heat out, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Just get to the point, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's a perfect boat for getting through the boiling water.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exchanges a worried glance with Suki.</charAction> The cooler as a boat?
            Are you sure?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm telling you, it'll work. <charAction>Flashes back to Sokka walking around the
                island; voice-over.</charAction> I walked around the perimeter. There's a blind spot
            between two guard towers. It's the perfect launching point. <charAction>Sokka puts a
                miniature boat in the water and watching it float away.</charAction> I already
            tested it out. We'll roll the cooler into the water and just float with the current.
            It'll take us straight across. As long as we don't make a sound, no one will notice.
                <charAction>Fade back to Sokka talking to Zuko and Suki.</charAction> And
            bing-bang-boom, we're home free.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>But how are you going to get the cooler out?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>From the staircase.</charAction> Yeah, how are you going to get the
            cooler out? <charAction>Jumps down.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Covering up.</charAction> What? We didn't ... w-we didn't say
            that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, you heard wrong.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>I heard you hatching an escape plan, and I want in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>There's nothing to get in on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, the only thing we're hatching is ... an egg?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko lowers his head and Suki covers her eyes while they both sigh in
                annoyance. Cut back to Chit Sang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unconvinced.</charAction> Okay, well, I come with you or the warden
                <charAction>Camera pans from a serious-looking Zuko to Suki.</charAction> hears
            about this egg, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> I guess we have no choice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, you're in. <charAction>Handing Zuko a wrench.</charAction> Now first we need
            someone to unbolt the cooler, from the inside.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I can get you inside.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the stairs as two guards look down at the prison area.
                Chit Sang walks out from behind the stairs and stands in a spot. Zuko pretends to be
                mopping and bumps into Chit Sang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! What are you, stupid? Watch where you're going! <charAction>Shoves
                Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, you watch who you're shoving! <charAction>He pushes Chit
            Sang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>I think you mean whom I'm shoving!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two scuffle as the prisoners cheer them on. They break apart and Zuko
                goes for a punch. Chit Sang throws Zuko onto the floor. </description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching. Yelling.</charAction> I need backup over here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko dodges Chit Sang as he tries to elbow him. Zuko blasts fire at Chit
                Sang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>No firebending! <charAction>Pointing.</charAction> Into the cooler!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko is taken down and escorted away by two guards. Sokka looks at Suki,
                who is mopping and looks back, as he walks off. Later, Sokka opens the
                cooler.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I can take you back to your cell if you've learned your lesson.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Raises his head slightly and releases a small breath of fire to warm
                himself up.</charAction> Yes, I have ... completely. <charAction>Reveals all the
                removed bolts and screws, which makes Sokka smile.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lifts his visor; whispering.</charAction> I got Suki and Chit Sang out
            of their cells a few minutes ago. They'll be waiting for us at the shore.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Someone's coming! <charAction>Takes Sokka into the cooler and closes the
                door.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, new arrivals coming in at dawn.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>Anybody interesting?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Nah, just the usual. Some robbers, a couple traitors, some war prisoners,
                <charAction>Sokka looks at Zuko with shock and worry.</charAction> though I did hear
            there might be a pirate.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>No fooling!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>War prisoners. It could be your father.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Well, what should we do? Are we going ahead with the plan or are we waiting another
            night?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know! Is it right for me to risk Suki's freedom, all of our freedom on the
            slim chance that my dad is gonna show up?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It's your call, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to outside the prison, night time. Suki and Chit Sang are waiting for
                Sokka and Zuko until they hear them above, rolling the, now detached, cooler down
                the hill. Suki and Chit Sang move to help.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Took you guys long enough. <charAction>Cut briefly to two other prisoners, a male
                sitting on a rock, and a female waving.</charAction> This here's my girl and my best
            buddy, they're coming too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Fine. Everybody in the cooler. Let's go. <charAction>They move the cooler into the
                water. Cut to Sokka lifting a rock hiding his Water Tribe
            outfit.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Are you sure you wanna go? You're the one who said you wanted to redeem yourself.
            Redeem your honor. Rescuing your dad is your chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching.</charAction> Your dad?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns to Zuko.</charAction> If I had just cut my losses at the invasion,
            maybe we wouldn't be in this mess. Maybe sometimes it's just better to call it quits
            before you fail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>No, it's not. Look Sokka, you're going to fail a lot before things work
            out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing.</charAction> That supposed to make me feel better?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sokka moves away.</charAction> Even though you'll probably fail over and
            over and over again ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously, not helping.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> You have to try every time. You
            can't quit because you're afraid you might fail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing by the cooler boat.</charAction> Hey, if you two are done
            cuddling, can we get a move on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No. I'm staying. You guys go. <charAction>To Suki.</charAction> You've been here
            long enough.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not leaving without you, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm staying, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Not me, I'm out. Let's roll, baby. <charAction>Pushes the cooler into the lake and
                jumps in.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We gave up our only chance of escaping. I hope we haven't just made a huge
            mistake.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As morning arrives, the cooler holding Chit Sang, his buddy, and his
                girlfriend is still within the perimeter of the prison. The current escapees are
                sweating as the cooler slowly floats with the current.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Aah, this current is so slow. I can use this to paddle. <charAction>Rips off a piece
                of the cooler. When he puts the piece of metal in the water, the steaming water
                splashes on to his hand, causing him to scream loudly.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A watchman catches notice. Two watchmen hit an alarm bell as the warden
                approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Guards! Secure the perimeter and lock down the prisoners! Now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Many guards appear to lock down the prisoners as we see one guard use a
                fire whip to control the prisoners. Cut to the outside of the prison walls as the
                camera pans down to Sokka, Suki, and Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The plan failed! They're caught!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to the warden near a launcher.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Get the fugitives and throw them in the cooler!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard #2">Male guard #2</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The guard in charge of the steering wheel turns toward the
                warden.</charAction> Uh ... they are in a cooler, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>One that's bolted down and not floating in the water! This is a lockdown! We have
            new prisoners arriving! Everything must be completely secure!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The male guard fires a large ballista bolt, catching hold of the cooler,
                and drags it back toward the prison.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The gondola's moving. <charAction>Cut to a side-view of the gondola approaching the
                prison. Cut to a view of the prison yard as the gondola nears its stop. Cut to Sokka
                and Suki now in the yard.</charAction> This is it. <charAction>Cut to the gondola
                arriving. Cut to Sokka, Zuko and Suki in the yard.</charAction> If my dad's not
            there, we've risked everything for nothing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>We had to. <charAction>Holds Sokka's hand.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, come on ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a large man with a tattoo and nose ring comes off the gondola
                first.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Is that him? <charAction>Cut to Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>My dad doesn't have a nose ring. <charAction>Cut briefly to the gondola as several
                men step off.</charAction> Where is he? <charAction>Cut to the gondola briefly as we
                see one more prisoner exit. Hakoda does not appear.</charAction> That's it? That
            can't be it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Comforting.</charAction> I'm sorry, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, no.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, you! Get off the gondola!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the gondola as Hakoda steps out.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Sokka, Shocked.</charAction> Dad ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to the words "TO BE CONTINUED ..." followed by the
                credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
