<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Storm</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode begins in Aang's dream. The scene itself, dominated by a tinge
                of warm yellow, is filled with clouds for a moment before Aang slides into the frame
                of the shot, his face happy as he flicks the reins. The shot switches to a far view,
                showing that he is riding Appa, who is flapping his six legs in unison up and down
                as if he were a bird. The camera pans to the right, revealing Sokka as he pulls
                alongside Appa, using Aang's glider to fly with the Avatar. The shot cuts to a
                close-up of the Water Tribe warrior as he turns his head toward Aang, grinning
                broadly and contentedly at him. Cut to Aang as his face exhibits the same contented
                grin. He turns his attention to his right and the camera follows his gaze, revealing
                Katara sitting atop the head of an enormous Momo; she waves at Aang. Camera moves
                back to a wide frontal shot of the group coursing leisurely through the open
                sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> We need you, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up as he is looking toward Katara; contentedly.</charAction> I
            need you, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang notices something out of the corner of his eyes. As he turns toward
                it, his expression changes to shock. Focusing on Aang's face, the camera turns 180
                degrees and switches to his point of view as the sky's coloring changes to a dark,
                ominous gray, revealing a churning storm cloud before him. Cut back to Aang, who
                yanks Appa's reins in fright.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Be careful, guys! <charAction>He looks to his left
                and right, uneasy.</charAction> Guys?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene rapidly zooms out, revealing that Aang and Appa are alone,
                surrounded by nothing but the darkening sky. Cut back to Aang's point of view as
                Gyatso, in lotus, floats downward, positioning himself in front of
                Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Gyatso?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispering, his tone sad.</charAction> Why did you disappear?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot; his voice soft and sad.</charAction> I didn't mean
            to.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a side-view of the two monks, not a meter apart from one another.
                Aang reaches out to Gyatso, but before he can touch him, Gyatso turns gray and
                dissipates into smoke; it blows over Aang, causing him to raise his left arm in
                front of his face and turn away to shield himself from it. Frontal shot of Aang as
                the last of the smoke washes over him. He peeks over his arm, but instantly raises
                his head, his eyes growing big in shock; a dark shadow passes over him as the shot
                cuts to a distant side-view of Appa being swallowed by the dark cloud.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> We need you, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A bolt of lightning splits the shot for an instant before cutting to a
                frontal shot of a screaming and frightened Aang, wrestling with the reins, as he and
                Appa are caught in the belly of the storm with rain beating down on them. Cut to an
                underwater shot as Aang and Appa plummet into the ocean. The duo floats for a
                moment. Cut to a close-up of Aang's hand as his grip on Appa's reins loosens and
                they slip from his limp grasp.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso and Katara">Gyatso and Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Echoing voice-over.</charAction> We need you, Aang. <charAction>Cut to a
                downward view of an unconscious Aang sinking.</charAction> We need you. We need you,
            Aang. We need you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Unmoving, Aang sinks and disappears into the darkness of the ocean. For a
                fraction of a second, lightning splits the shot once again and the silhouette of the
                Fire Lord surrounded by flames appears.</description>
            <description>The scene cuts to reality as Aang, gasping for air and shooting upright,
                startles Momo, who was curled up on top of Aang. Momo leaps onto Katara's stomach,
                causing her to shoot up with a startled look on her face, before jumping on Sokka's,
                who shoots up, still sleepy, halfheartedly wielding his dagger and
                boomerang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Drowsily.</charAction> What's going on? <charAction>He looks
                around.</charAction> Did we get captured again?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot looking down, sliding right; Aang turns to his
                friends.</charAction> It's nothing. I just had a bad dream. <charAction>He curls up,
                facing away from them.</charAction> Go back to sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curls up, facing away from Aang.</charAction> Don't have to tell me
            twice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot of Aang with Katara behind him, looking at him in
                concern.</charAction> Are you all right, Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking lost.</charAction> I'm okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You seem to be having a lot of nightmares lately. You want to tell me about
            it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Briefly closing his eyes.</charAction> I think I just need some
            rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting up behind Katara; upbeat.</charAction> You guys want to hear
            about my dream? <charAction>Katara glares at him, an expression Sokka
                returns.</charAction> That's okay. I didn't want to talk about it anyway.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka lies down, disappearing from view; Katara does the
                same.</description>
            <description>Scene changes to waves crashing on a sandy shore under a blue sky. Cut to a
                wide frontal shot of Katara as she carries their packs toward Appa, who yawns. As
                the animal closes its mouth again, Aang is revealed sitting on his head, while Sokka
                sits on the saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Look at those clear skies, buddy! <charAction>Pets Appa's head. Cut to a close shot
                as he looks up at a flock of birds arranged in a "V" flying overhead, their
                goose-like honking audible.</charAction> Should be some smooth flying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an overhead shot looking down of Katara looking into a bag before
                holding it upside down, sprinkling the ground with crumbs; Momo instantly eats them.
                Sokka walks past her toward Appa, carrying some of their luggage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking from the contents of the bag up to Aang.</charAction> Well, we
            better smoothly fly <charAction>She steps onto Appa's tail and walks to the
                saddle.</charAction> ourselves to a market, 'cause we're out of food.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-shot as he suddenly straightens up, his tone serious.</charAction>
            Guys, wait. This was in my dream. <charAction>Momo lands on the pack behind
                him.</charAction> We shouldn't go to the market.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot cuts beside Sokka, facing out toward Katara and Aang, who turn to
                look at him; curious.</charAction> What happened in your dream?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot; his eyes are bugged out in terror and the camera zooms in
                on him, rolling slightly as the shot takes on a greenish tint and alien music dubs
                the scene.</charAction> Food eats people! <charAction>The colors return to normal as
                the shot cuts to Katara's face as she shakes her head. Behind her, Aang goes back to
                adjusting the reins. Cut to Sokka again as he points at Momo.</charAction> Also,
            Momo could talk. <charAction>He glares at Momo while crossing his arms.</charAction> You
            said some very unkind things.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo's ears droop as Sokka speaks. Cut to downward looking shot of a flock
                of birds in V-formation flying over the open ocean. As the scene pans to the left,
                Zuko's ship sails into view. Cut to the deck, where Iroh stands on the deck, with
                Zuko looking through a spyglass behind him. As the flight of birds passes over
                Iroh's head in the distance, he sniffs the air and Zuko lowers the spyglass to turn
                to his uncle, who speaks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>There is a storm coming. A big one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You're out of your mind, Uncle. <charAction>Walking up to Iroh.</charAction> The
            weather's perfect. There's not a cloud in sight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot cuts behind the two, facing the prow of the ship and showing a
                clear sea and sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>A storm is approaching from the north. <charAction>He turns to face
                Zuko.</charAction> I suggest we alter our course and head southwest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Taking a few steps in Iroh's direction, pointing briefly
                northward.</charAction> We know the Avatar is traveling northward, so we will do the
            same.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to his face; stern.</charAction> Prince Zuko, consider the safety of
            the crew.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to his face as he advances on his uncle angrily.</charAction> The
            safety of the crew doesn't matter!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Behind them, Lieutenant Jee walks onto deck, inadvertently overhearing the
                conversation. As Zuko realizes Jee is behind him and turns to face him, his
                expression briefly loses its raging intensity. A quick close-up shows Jee raising an
                eyebrow as Zuko walks over to him; another cut shifts the view to the lieutenant's
                side as Zuko, addressing Jee directly, struts up to him, dominantly looking him
                right in the eyes from a close distance as he finishes speaking.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Finding the Avatar is far more important than any individual's safety.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Zuko walks away, Jee glares after him. The shot switches, showing Zuko
                leaving the deck through the door at the base of the superstructure. Cut to a
                frontal shot of Jee, who looks slightly enraged as Iroh walks over to
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reassuringly, a twinge of uncertainty in his voice, almost as if he does
                not fully believe what he is saying.</charAction> He doesn't mean that. He's just
            all worked up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a seaside hamlet built on the side of a cliff face,
                the roofs all teal-green; a collection of houses sits back from the waterfront,
                where a row of warehouses adjoins the docks. Among the several ships moored on the
                town's four piers is Appa, floating in the water by himself. Cut to Katara, who
                stands in front of a small merchants' stand, suspiciously eying a
                watermelon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Merchant woman">Merchant woman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Scowling.</charAction> Ahhh, it's good. It's perfect, I'm telling
            you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shaking the watermelon, which emits an audible sloshing
                sound.</charAction> I don't know if I like the sound of that swishing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Merchant woman">Merchant woman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>As the shot zooms out, the merchant moves around the stand where Katara
                stands. Sokka and Aang, staff in hand, stand beside them; the former is filling a
                basket with fruit.</charAction> Swishing means it's ripe! It's the ripe juices
            swishing around, eh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Taking a step toward Katara.</charAction> I think it's true, Katara.
            Swishing means it's ripe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>As the shot cuts to a frontal view of her, she puts the melon back on
                the stand.</charAction> I just realized we're out of money anyway.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Shopkeeper">Shopkeeper</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed, grabbing a basket full of fruits from Sokka.</charAction>
            Awww!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Sokka walks past the merchant, she indignantly kicks him in the rear,
                drawing a cry of pain from Sokka. Cut to Sokka, Katara, and Aang on the docks. Sokka
                is rubbing where the lady kicked him and seems downcast.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Out of food and out of money. Now what are we supposed to do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You could get a job, smart guy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A fisherman and his wife are walking behind the gang. As Katara finishes,
                they begin a loud, heated conversation, which is overheard easily by Aang, Katara,
                and Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>We shouldn't go out there! Please, the fish can wait. There's going to be a terrible
            storm. <charAction>Camera cuts to show Aang, who appears alarmed by the
                prediction.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>You're crazy. It's a nice day: <charAction>Gesturing to the sky with both
                arms.</charAction> No clouds, no winds, no nothing. So quit your nagging,
            woman.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously suggesting to Katara and Sokka.</charAction> Maybe we should
            find some shelter?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Indicating the fair weather.</charAction> Are you kidding? Shelter from
            what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>My joints say there's going to be a storm! A bad one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Well, it's your joints against my brain.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>Then I hope your brain can find someone else to haul that fish, 'cause I ain't
            comin'.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Then I'll find a new fish hauler and pay him double what you get! <charAction>Cut to
                a side shot of the couple, showing Sokka running up to them.</charAction> How do you
            like that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interrupting, raising his hand.</charAction> I'll go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>You're hired! <charAction>Shoots a triumphant look at his wife, who scowls
                back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>After a short pause, to Katara and Aang.</charAction> What? You said get
            a job ... and he's <description>paying double</description>.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rounding on Sokka, his expression wild.</charAction> Double? Who told
            you that nonsense?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to Zuko's ship on the open ocean. As the shot pans right,
                a massive bank of darkening clouds, having appeared seemingly out of nowhere, rolls
                into view, looming in front of the ship. Cut to the deck, where Lieutenant Jee and
                several other soldiers stand a short distance from the shot, staring at the clouds.
                Zuko walks into the foreground, regarding the clouds as Jee and the others turn to
                face him. Iroh walks between Zuko and Jee as the latter taunts the
                former.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lieutenant Jee">Lieutenant Jee</speaker>
        <speech>Looks like your uncle was right about the storm after all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pleasantly.</charAction> Lucky guess.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whirling around and walking toward Jee; angry.</charAction> Lieutenant!
            You'd better learn some respect <charAction>Jabs two fingers into Jee's
                chest.</charAction> – or I will teach it to you. <charAction>Begins to walk away
                from Jee, who follows Zuko with his eyes, continuing his taunting after a short
                pause.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>What do you know about respect? <charAction>Behind Jee, Iroh's expression turns to
                panic and he makes a cutting motion at his throat with his hand, trying to signal
                Lieutenant Jee to stop. Cut to Zuko's back as he stops walking before switching to
                his face as he listens to Jee's words.</charAction> The way you talk to everyone
            around here, from your hard-working crew to your esteemed uncle, shows you know nothing
            about respect! <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Iroh's face as he gasps slightly,
                reaching out a hand in desperation before moving it to his forehead in resignation,
                believing Jee has gone too far. Cut back to Zuko's face, contorted with
                rage.</charAction> You don't care about anyone but yourself! Then again, what should
            I expect from a spoiled prince?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko turns around and extends his right arm as if preparing to firebend.
                Lieutenant Jee does the same.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Easy now. <charAction>Both Zuko and Jee wrist-block the other's arm; smoke rises
                from a furious Zuko's hand. Interrupting the staredown, Iroh extends an arm and
                pulls theirs apart; the smoke fades.</charAction> Enough! We're all a bit tired from
            being at sea so long. I'm sure after a bowl of noodles, everyone will feel much
            better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Lieutenant Jee walks away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I don't need your help keeping order on my ship.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh puts a comforting hand on Zuko's right shoulder, but Zuko shrugs it
                off and walks away. Scene changes back to a dock at the fishing town, where Team
                Avatar stands. Sokka is carrying supplies onto the fisherman's boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, maybe this isn't such a good idea. Look at the sky.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I said I was going to do this job. I can't back out just because of some bad
            weather.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>The boy with the tattoos has some sense. You should listen to him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Boy with tattoos? <charAction>The fisherman turns around to look at
                Aang.</charAction> Airbender tattoos. Well, I'll be a hog monkey's uncle. You're the
            Avatar, ain't ya?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That's right. <charAction>Katara and Aang smile.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Well, don't be so smiley about it. <charAction>Katara and Aang frown
                now.</charAction> The Avatar disappeared for a hundred years! You turned your back
            on the world!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Don't yell at him! Aang would never turn his back on anyone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, he wouldn't, huh? Then I guess I must have imagined the last hundred years of
            war and suffering. <charAction>Aang's eyes widen.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang is the bravest person I know. He's done nothing but help people and save lives
            since I met him. <charAction>Behind Katara's back, Aang slowly begins to backpedal away
                from her.</charAction> It's not his fault he disappeared, right Aang?
                <charAction>Katara turns around to see Aang backing away.</charAction> Aang, what's
            wrong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A look of shock and horrified guilt on his face, Aang opens his glider and
                vaults into the air, rapidly disappearing into the distance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>That's right! Keep flying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're a horrible old man! <charAction>She gets on Appa, who is floating beside the
                dock.</charAction> Appa, yip yip!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Appa flies out of the water, a big wave splashes the fisherman. Sokka
                walks out from below deck on the boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! They left without saying good-bye!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Your friends ain't too polite, are they?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know! This one time, I was ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hands Sokka a crate, interrupting him impolitely.</charAction> Yeah,
            yeah, yeah, yeah. Get below deck!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to show Katara riding on Appa in the rain, trying to find
                Aang. The shot cuts to show a cave in the side of a cliff face. Camera changes to a
                view of Katara outside the cave and Aang sitting alone inside, surrounded by
                darkness.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Quietly.</charAction> I'm sorry for running away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay. That fisherman was way out of line.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, he wasn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What do you mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Speaks in a sad voice.</charAction> I don't want to talk about
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It has to do with your dream, doesn't it? <charAction>Puts her hand on his
                shoulder.</charAction> Talk to me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, it's kind of a long story.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly, Momo leaps past Aang and Katara, startling them. Appa has also
                entered the cave. He nuzzles Aang's head with his nose, making Aang smile. Aang pats
                Appa's chin.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm going to try to get a little fire going.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Next scene shows Katara and Aang sitting around a fire. Momo is lying on
                Aang's lap.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll never forget the day the monks told me I was the Avatar. I was playing with
            some other kids just outside the South Wall. I was trying to teach them how to do the
            air scooter.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to a flashback when Aang is with some other Air
                Nomads.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>First you got to form the ball, then you got to get on quick.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang is seen riding around on the scooter in the court. One of the boys
                tries it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #1">Air Nomad boy #1</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, here goes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The boy forms it and tries getting on, but spins and falls off. Aang gently
                gets off his.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You kind of have to balance on it like it's a top.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #1">Air Nomad boy #1</speaker>
        <speech>Man, that's hard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #2">Air Nomad boy #2</speaker>
        <speech>Where'd you learn that trick, Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I made it up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #2">Air Nomad boy #2</speaker>
        <speech>Wow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Council of Elders shows up at that moment.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, come with us. We need to speak with you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to when Aang and the elder monks are in the meeting
                room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>How do you know it's me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>We have known you were the Avatar for some time. Do you remember these?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Monk Tashi airbends a wrapped-up mat to Aang. It opens up, revealing four
                toys.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Those were some of my favorite toys when I was little! <charAction>He picks up the
                propeller toy.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>You chose them from among thousands of toys, Aang. The toys you picked were the four
            Avatar relics. These items belonged to Avatars past. Your own past lives.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I just chose them because they seemed fun.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He smiles and pulls the cord on the propeller toy, sending the propeller
                spinning into the air. It spins through the air and the scene cuts back to a close
                view of the five monks. The toy goes over Monk Tashi's head.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>You chose them because they were familiar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Normally we would have told you of your identity when you turned sixteen, but there
            are troubling signs. Storm clouds are gathering.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pasang">Pasang</speaker>
        <speech>I fear that war may be upon us, young Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>We need you, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang lowers his head, his responsibility crushing him. His head stays
                lowered as the flashback ends and his head remains lowered in the present as well.
                Cut to a wider shot of Aang on the left, Katara on the right, the fire between them.
                Katara looks upon him with concern and sympathy. The scene changes back to Zuko's
                ship. Jee is talking about Zuko to a couple other men.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sick of taking his orders! I'm tired of chasing his Avatar! I mean, who does
            Zuko think he is?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Do you really want to know?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jee is shown standing up at the sound of Iroh's voice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>General Iroh. We were just- <charAction>Iroh cuts him off.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay. May I join you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>Of course, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh is shown sitting down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Massages his beard.</charAction> Try to understand. My nephew is a
            complicated young man. He has been through much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to a flashback. Zuko walks up to the curtains to get in the
                war room, but the guard on the left moves in front of the curtain to stop
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Let me in!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Places his hands on Zuko's shoulders.</charAction> Prince Zuko, what's
            wrong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I want to go into the war chamber <charAction>Points to the guard.</charAction> but
            the guard won't let me pass!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Leads Zuko away with his left hand still on his
            shoulder.</charAction> You're not missing anything, trust me. These meetings are
            dreadfully boring.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>If I'm going to rule this nation one day, don't you think I need to start learning
            as much as I can?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Very well. But you must promise not to speak. <charAction>Another elder soldier
                walks by them into the war chamber.</charAction> These old folks are a bit
            sensitive, you know?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bows to Iroh.</charAction> Thank you, Uncle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko and Iroh walk into the war room. The meeting starts.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bujing">Bujing</speaker>
        <speech>The Earth Kingdom defenses are concentrated here. <charAction>Bujing shows the place
                on the map.</charAction> A dangerous battalion of their strongest earthbenders and
            fiercest warriors. So I am recommending the forty-first division.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Elder soldier">Elder soldier</speaker>
        <speech>But the forty-first is entirely new recruits. How do you expect them to defeat a
            powerful Earth Kingdom battalion?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bujing">Bujing</speaker>
        <speech><description>I don't</description>. They'll be used as a distraction while we mount
            an attack from the rear. What better to use as bait than fresh meat?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Zuko is shown standing up.</charAction> You can't sacrifice an entire
            division like that! Those soldiers love and defend our nation! How can you betray
            them?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera shows everyone in the war room staring at Zuko, save for Iroh, who
                is kneeling behind his nephew. The scene changes back to the present
                time.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko was right, you see, <charAction>Massages his beard again.</charAction> but it
            was not his place to speak out. And there were dire consequences. <charAction>Slightly
                bows his head.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes back to Aang and Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So you were upset that you were the Avatar? Why wouldn't you be excited about
            it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I didn't know how to feel about it. All I knew was that after I found out,
            everything began changing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes back to flashback. Aang enters into the South Wall again. The
                Air Nomad kids are shown on air scooters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, not bad! You guys have been practicing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #2">Air Nomad boy #2</speaker>
        <speech>Not only that! We made up a game you can play with the air scooters!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Great! <charAction>Aang is shown making his own. But everyone else makes theirs
                vanish.</charAction> What's going on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #1">Air Nomad boy #1</speaker>
        <speech>Now that you're the Avatar, it's kind of an unfair advantage for whichever team
            you're on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But I'm still the same! Nothing's changed! So, what? I can't play?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #1">Air Nomad boy #1</speaker>
        <speech>That's the only fair way.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #2">Air Nomad boy #2</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang is shown leaving the South Wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Air Nomad boy #1">Air Nomad boy #1</speaker>
        <speech>Okay. Now, who wants Jinju on their team?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jinju is shown in the corner with a gas around him, laughing. Scene changes
                to Aang and Gyatso playing a game of Pai Sho. Aang is shown moving a
                piece.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Very interesting move, young one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Gyatso is shown using airbending to make a spiral, flipping a part of
                Aang's clothing. Gyatso quickly moves two pieces around. Aang is shown flipping his
                clothing back into place.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Gyatso and Aang laugh. Monk Tashi appears.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>You're playing games with him? The Avatar should be training!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Aang has already trained enough for today.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>Time is short. <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Come with me. I must test you on
            some high level techniques.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>No. As long as I'm his guardian, I will decide when he trains ... and when he gets
            his butt kicked at Pai Sho.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>Hmph.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Monk Tashi is shown walking away. The flashback ends, and the scene changes
                to on Zuko's ship. A flashback appears of the fire in front of the Fire Lord's
                throne rising.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>After Zuko's outburst in the meeting, the Fire Lord became very angry with him.
                <charAction>Flashback quickly ends.</charAction> He said the challenge against the
            general was an act of complete disrespect! And there was only one way to resolve
            this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>Agni Kai. A fire duel.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>That's right. Zuko looked upon the old general he had insulted and declared that he
            was not afraid. But Zuko misunderstood. <charAction>Flashback shows an overview of the
                chamber; the camera cuts to show Zuko preparing for the Agni Kai.</charAction> When
            he turned to face his opponent, he was surprised to see it was not the general.
                <charAction>Flashback shows the tippet that was on Zuko's shoulders fall down to the
                ground.</charAction> Zuko had spoken out against the general's plan, but by doing so
            in the Fire Lord's war room, it was the Fire Lord whom he had disrespected.
                <charAction>Frontal shot of a surprised Zuko; as the camera zooms in on him, his
                expression changes to one of fear.</charAction> Zuko would have to duel his own
            father.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a wall of the cave. The shot pans down to show Katara and a
                sad-looking Aang around their campfire. While Momo is asleep in his lap, Aang stares
                off into the fire with unseeing eyes as he continues his story.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Then, just when I was feeling better, something worse happened.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to flashback of Monk Tashi and Monk Gyatso speaking to Monk
                Pasang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Aang needs to have freedom and fun. He needs to grow up as a normal boy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tashi">Tashi</speaker>
        <speech>You cannot keep protecting him from his destiny.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pasang">Pasang</speaker>
        <speech>Gyatso, I know you mean well, but you are letting your affection for the boy cloud
            your judgment.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>All I want is what is best for him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pasang">Pasang</speaker>
        <speech>But what we need is what's best for the world. You and Aang must be separated! The
            Avatar will be sent away to the Eastern Air Temple to complete his training.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang is shown looking through a hole in the ceiling, shocked at the news
                that he just heard.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That's awful, Aang. I don't know what to say.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up.</charAction> How could they do that to me? They wanted to
            take away everything I knew and everyone I loved! <charAction>He activates the Avatar
                State.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Whoa! Hot cinders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang comes out of the Avatar State, walks to the fire, and sits down
                again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry I got so mad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You have the right to be angry after the monks sent you away like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, that's not exactly what happened. <charAction>Flashback starts again, showing
                Aang looking out the window of his bedroom.</charAction> I was afraid and confused.
            I didn't know what to do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Flashback shows Aang lying on his bed before changing to Gyatso walking to
                Aang's room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gyatso">Gyatso</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, I'm not going to let them take you away from me. Aang? <charAction>Gyatso is
                shown opening the door more, spotting the scroll, and opening it up. He gasps, and
                sees a storm coming outside the window.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Still in present, but flashback playing still.</charAction> I never saw
            Gyatso again. <charAction>Flashback shows Aang and Appa through the storm, and how Aang
                got into the iceberg.</charAction> Next thing I knew, I was waking up in your arms
            after you found me in the iceberg.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Flashback shows Katara's face that was seen in "The Boy in the Iceberg".
                The flashback ends.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You ran away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>And then the Fire Nation attacked our temple. My people needed me and I wasn't there
            to help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You don't know what would have-.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The world needed me and I wasn't there to help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The fisherman was right! I did turn my back on the world!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're being too hard on yourself, even if you did run away. I think it was meant to
            be. If you had stayed, you would have been killed along with all the other
            airbenders.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You don't know that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I know it was meant to be this way. The world needs you now. You give people
            hope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes back to Zuko's ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>When Prince Zuko saw that it was his father who had come to duel him, he begged for
            mercy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Flashback shows a side overview of the Agni Kai chamber where Ozai is
                advancing on Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a side-view of Zuko.</charAction> Please, Father. I only had the
            Fire Nation's best interest at heart. I'm sorry I spoke out of turn!
                <charAction>Slightly lowers his head.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a frontal shot from a worm's eye perspective of Ozai's silhouette
                walking up to Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>You will fight for your honor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot; kneels on his knees and forearms, while looking at the
                floor.</charAction> I meant you no disrespect. <charAction>Gazes up at his father,
                tears shimmering in his eyes as his voice starts to waver.</charAction> I am your
            loyal son.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Far off frontal shot of Zuko as Ozai's shadow and eventually his head
                come into view.</charAction> Rise and fight, Prince Zuko!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a side-view from behind some of the spectators as Ozai reaches Zuko,
                who lowers his head to the floor again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Young Zuko">Young Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I <description>won't</description> fight you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>You will learn respect, <charAction>Zuko pushes himself up on his knees and hands.
                Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko as he starts to shake.</charAction> and suffering will
            be your <charAction>Zuko looks up at Ozai, tears streaming down his face.</charAction>
            teacher.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a frontal view of Zhao, Iroh, and Azula in the crowd. While Iroh
                clenches his teeth and looks fearful and worried on Zuko's behalf, Zhao looks on
                with a smirk on his face, while Azula smiles and raises her left fist in front of
                her chest in anticipation.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over; Iroh closes his eyes and averts his head to the
                left.</charAction> I looked away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As the sound of a fire blast is heard, Zuko is screaming "no", which
                echoes. While the faces of the spectators are brightened by the flames, the camera
                slowly zooms in on Iroh's averted face. The scene switches from the past to the
                present, where Iroh is sitting in the same manner.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>I always thought that Prince Zuko was in a training accident.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>It was no accident. After the duel, the Fire Lord said that by refusing to fight,
            Zuko had shown shameful weakness. As punishment, he was banished and sent to capture the
            Avatar. Only then could he return with his honor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>So that's why he's so obsessed. Capturing the Avatar is the only chance he has of
            things returning to normal.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Things will never return to normal. But the important thing is the Avatar gives Zuko
            hope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to show Zuko meditating, while having flashbacks of his
                younger life. He is stopped by a hit on the ship. Scene changes to Aang and Katara.
                The fisherman's wife appears.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>Help! Oh, please help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs lady and brings her near the fire.</charAction> It's okay. You're
            safe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>But my husband isn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean? Where's Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>They haven't returned! They should have been back by now! And this storm is becoming
            a typhoon! They're caught out at sea!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm going to find him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm going with you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>I'm staying here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The fisherman's wife is shown sitting down by the fire. Aang and Katara are
                shown about to leave on Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We'll be back soon. I promise.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara fly out. Scene changes to Zuko's ship, with Zuko on the
                deck.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Where were we hit?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The helmsman!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko and Lieutenant Jee are shown climbing up a ladder to help a man who is
                about to fall. Lightning goes down to the middle of the ship, where Iroh is. He uses
                redirection so it does not damage the ship. Scene changes to Katara and Aang looking
                for the fisherman and Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Where are they?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa is shown descending, hitting the water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, Appa! The boat! There!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko is shown spotting Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jee">Jee</speaker>
        <speech>What do you want to do, sir?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Let him go. We need to get this ship to safety.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Then we must head directly into the eye of the storm.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to show Sokka and the fisherman rocking back and forth on the
                boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm too young to die!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not, but I still don't wanna!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang shows up. He jumps down onto the boat. As a pole is falling down, Aang
                brings up fours pouts of water, splitting the pole in half. After the pole splits in
                half, Sokka and the fisherman are shown hugging each other. A rope is
                seen.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hang onto the rope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The fisherman and Sokka do so. Appa starts flying again. The rope swings
                up, making Sokka and the fisherman land on the saddle. A big wave hits the gang
                underwater. Everyone is shown floating away from Appa. Aang goes into the Avatar
                State and saves everyone. They all go back to the cave where the fisherman's wife
                is. Scene changes to Zuko and Iroh together.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle, I'm sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Your apology is accepted.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to Appa, Katara, Aang, Sokka, and the fisherman at the cave.
                The fisherman's wife runs up to the fisherman and hugs him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman's wife">Fisherman's wife</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, you're alive! You owe this boy an apology!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>He doesn't have to apologize.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>What if, instead of an apology, I give him a free fish and we call it even?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, I don't eat meat.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>Fish ain't meat!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously, you're still going to pay me, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The fisherman hands Sokka a fish. Katara and Aang are shown in a corner of
                the cave.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, I think you were right before. I'm done dwelling on the past.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Really?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I can't make guesses about what would have turned out if I hadn't run away. I'm here
            now and I'm going to make the most out of it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I don't think you're gonna have those nightmares anymore.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fisherman">Fisherman</speaker>
        <speech>And if you weren't here now, well, I guess I wouldn't be either. Thank you for
            saving my life, Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Do you hear that? It stopped raining.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone goes outside. Appa shakes raindrops off himself, splashing
                everyone.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Appa!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
