<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Day of Black Sun Part 2</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan Konietzko">Bryan Konietzko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Imitates Katara naming the four elements in a dramatic
                tone.</charAction> Water. Earth. Fire. And Air. This is Bryan Konietzko, co-creator
            of Avatar, and uh, art director and stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Michael Dante DiMartino">Michael Dante DiMartino</speaker>
        <speech>This is Mike DiMartino, the other co-creator, an-and executive producer of the
            show.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>And story editor and stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, we do a lot of stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Not me, Mike, but...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs; brief pause.</charAction> So, we're here to talk about the
            second half of the big invasion eclipse, uh, event, which was a, you know, story idea we
            had pretty early on. We knew there was going to be a, an eclipse and an invasion sort of
            event.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> Yeah, Mi-I remember Mike, um, I think maybe
            even before we pitched the show, had this idea of the Day of Black Sun, and uh, we knew
            there would be some really big, uh, invasion attempt by the good guys.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>When the firebenders would, would have no power. Seemed like a logical strategic
            choice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>'Cause we always, since we wanted the so-called, you know, magic of Avatar, the
            bending, to be more of a natural type. We really wanted the um, like natural phenomena
            to have an effect on the bending, so that it wasn't always just a constant, you know,
            thing, it was something that was tied in with the energies of the, the Earth.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> This episode was written by Aaron Eha-Ehasz,
            and uh, directed by Joaquim Dos Santos, two very capable and big contributors to the
            show throughout this-in all the seasons.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> So, this was um... a really big episode also
            for uh, Zuko and there was uh... y-you know, very early on in development, um, we knew
            that Zuko would eventually confront his father, and um, you know, years ago we didn't
            know that it-exactly that when it would happen, we weren't sure if it would, you know, I
            think the idea that it coincided with the Day of Black Sun came a bit later. But, you
            know, this was something that we had been looking forward to telling for years, and uh,
            I remember when we went to South Korea to start the series production on season one, I
            remember like <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> the whole animation crew at JM Animation
            gathered around and it was like story hour, like they wanted to hear the whole story,
            even though we were just starting season one. So, I sat there and pitched it to them,
            and then it was translated into Korean, and uh, our friend uh, Seung Hyun was working
            there at the time, and when I said, you know, "and then Zuko's going to get confront his
            father and tell him this and that, and there's going to be this big lightning thing,"
            and I just remember he was like, <charAction>In an enthusiastically pleading
                tone.</charAction> "I want to, I want to draw that!"
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> So, we were all really excited about it for
            years.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And I think he did end up drawing some of it, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, he did. <charAction>Mike and Bryan laugh.</charAction> All worked out.
                <charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> And there was uh, before we started recording,
            Mike reminded me that there was a lot of uh, lot of upset fans, uh, at the end of season
            two, um, really <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> traumatized by the choice that Zuko
            made, and uh, I think we even had letters from people asking us to...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Change the ending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... to-to, yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>"Can you reanimate the end of season two?", like we had already obviously done it
            all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>And aired it. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>And I think it was on DVD or...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Yeah, we were-we were like...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>In the background.</charAction> when we were on tour.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... if you want to send us like...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Couple hundred <charAction>Mike
                laughs.</charAction> thousand dollars? <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... then, yeah, sure, we'll-we'll...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>No problem. <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> It's a big retake budget, but uh,
                <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> we can do it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I remember even in s-season one, like the, you know, fourth episode or
            something, people were like, "Zuko's totally going to join their group, and-and help
            them fight the Fire Lord," <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction> and we're like,
            well...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>There goes the element of surprise. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>I mean, we kinda di-we were like, aw, they already figured it out, but we were like,
            well that's not going to happen like-I think s-some people expected it to happen like
            right away, and we're like, you gotta-gotta earn that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>And also, <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> you know, after the initial like,
            "wow, they figured that one out quick," the-there wasn't ever really meant to be a
            surprise, the main thing is the character arc <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction>
            that Zuko goes through to get there. Um, and, you know, unfortunately for the fans who
            are upset at the end of 220, you know, that character arc's going to involve mistakes,
            and um, people often say you learn a lot more from your mistakes than you do your, um,
            successes. So, that's uh, what we had planned for Zuko, we didn't want it to just be
            like, you know, so easy for him to uh, choose the right path. 'Cause he's, you know, he
            has a complex life, that's always been an issue for him. Complex family.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And once he does choose the right path, it's-the kids don't just say, "alright,
            cool. C'mon in."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Imitates Team Avatar; in a mock accepting tone.</charAction>
            "Sure."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>You see... it's a lot harder than that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, you know, for Mike and I, and-and Aaron and-and the other creative people
            involved, um, you know, we're trying to tell a-a deep, richer and more, um... realistic
            story-not in the sense that, you know, I mean, people can't shoot fire and stuff, but
            just treating these characters, uh, their problems and their-their character arcs
            with-with respect, like we've said many times. So, yeah, for Zuko, we just wanted to uh,
            treat it realistically, and unfortunately, none of us make the right decisions all the
            time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>I thought people could shoot fire.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Oh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a mock slight accusatory tone.</charAction> You never told me they
            couldn't. <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction> I can't believe...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Are you still going to work on the
            show?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Aw yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Now you know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>I guess so. I can't believe you told me now though.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>People can't create wind. <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction> Let's just leave
            it at that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the Fire Nation official, Qin, that Aang, Sokka, and Toph
                accost in the bunker.</charAction> So, that guy, some people might not realize,
            that's-he's actually appeared in a couple other episodes. He's, uh, he's uh, War
            Minister, uh, Qin.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Is that...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Qin. <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction>
            Qin, Kin, something. I don't know, I think that's it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>I actually don't even know his family name...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> But, he...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... I just know he-I just know him as the war minister.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, he's the war minister. He was in "The Drill", and he was the guy who found the
            uh, the war balloon in season one, <charAction>Refers to the first mass deployment of
                the Fire Nation war balloons and airships.</charAction> which we all know plays an
            important role in this-this episode.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, it's kind of why he's here, back in the Fire Nation, <charAction>Mike
                affirms.</charAction> he's got the uh, the whole airship, uh, zeppelin, you know,
            fleet launched now, which is there. Big secret weapon, and, you know, they-I don't know,
            maybe they had some prototypes, it would've been pretty quick. <charAction>Bryan and
                Mike chuckle.</charAction> He would've built those things pretty quick if-117 was
            the first time they had the idea. But they...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Sus-you gotta suspend your disbelief.
                <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction> It's alright.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the mechanist telling the invasion force to put on their
                eclipse glasses.</charAction> And there's the guy who built the uh, war
            balloons.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gives an affirming murmur.</charAction> He's gonna feel bad
            later...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, these uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>In the background.</charAction> after what he did.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the eclipse glasses the invasion force uses.</charAction>
            little side note, these, um, little glasses they're putting on are actually like leather
            with thin slits. Um, sort of similar to, I think sometimes in like desert cultures,
            you'll see these glasses, they reduce the-they're not really glasses, there's no glass
            in them, but they reduce the sun glare, um, and allows people to see, and then also for
            sandstorms. And uh, we specifically got the idea of them from, uh, a great Inuit film
            called The Fast Runner. Think it's-I think the Inuit name is Atan-Atanarjuat, something
            like that. Really great film, um, lot of great inspiration for the Water Tribes came
            from that film. And uh, yeah, they had a-a character in that movie that had really cool
            leather... glasses, I think for cutting down the glare. <charAction>Refers to Zuko
                unsheathing his swords at his father, as he orders Ozai to sit and
                listen.</charAction> Oh hey, here we are in this uh, scene, <charAction>Mike
                laughs.</charAction> and I'm talking about eyewear. <charAction>Mike
                laughs.</charAction> This is what we were gonna talk, <charAction>Refers to the cut
                to Team Avatar confronting Azula.</charAction> ah, it's gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, they'll-they-they come back, it's alright.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, you're right, you're right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Anyways, they're not-they're not fancy uh,
            sunglasses, they're just leather.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. <charAction>Refers to Azula divulging to Team Avatar that she knew about the
                invasion plan months in advance.</charAction> So, this-Azula knowing they were
            coming was kinda set up in season two, where uh, she had disguised herself as a Kyoshi
            Warrior, and was uh, hanging out with the king there for a while. So, she heard all
            about the fact that there was this eclipse coming, so, really, the kids had no chance,
            they were-she knew the whole time, so they had time to prepare and get the zeppelins
            going and stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, obviously they wanted to, you know, they were gonna give it a fighting shot of
            keeping them from invading, um, but they, you know, the... the good guy-good guys allied
            forces were able to penetrate the wall and, and get in. So, this was their uh, second
            phase of their plan. Sort of lure them in and then trap 'em.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula summoning two Dai Li agents to fight Team
                Avatar.</charAction> And Azula has her, this is actually the first time we see that
            she has the Dai Li agents. They're-I remember in-I think it was the first episode of
            season three, there wa-there was a scene where you saw some Dai Li agents, but I
            remember we-we cut that out because... by that time, we were writing this episode or had
            the animatic, and it was like, wanted it to be more of a surprise at that moment that
            you didn't know like, <charAction>Refers to the bent earth Toph trapped Azula in
                crumbling apart; in a tone of mock surprise.</charAction> whoa, how'd she get out of
            that rock.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until the scene cuts back to Zuko rebuking
                Ozai's and the Fire Nation's cruelty.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, we're back. Alright, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And this is, you know, kind of a different-we don't have a lot of scenes where it's
            just two characters standing around talking. It doesn't happen too,
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> too much in Avatar, but...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>This kind of reminds me of when Zuko faced Zhao in <charAction>Mike affirms
                intermittently.</charAction> 103, where they were-there was just a tense scene, lot
            of dialogue.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I really like-yeah, I really like those tense moments, and-and uh, both Dante
            Basco, who plays Zuko, and Mark Hamill, who plays Ozai, did-did a great job with uh, the
            acting and the emotions.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, for me, you know, just as a viewer of Avatar, um... it's just great having
            been with Zuko through so many ups and downs, and then... you know, <charAction>Refers
                to Zuko disgusted tone as he states how he, through his time away from Ozai, has
                learned the Fire Nation's supremacist justifications for starting the war have
                engendered nothing but hate and misery in the world.</charAction> you really believe
            what he's saying and you feel the emotion behind it. He really earned these, uh,
            revelations that he's had, you know... which is, again, it's a really important theme
            for us is that people aren't just given things in Avatar, hopefully they, they earned
            them, like powers, or you know, knowledge, or respect.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to Zuko proudly saying his new outlook is due to
                Iroh's influence.</charAction> Little-little nod to Uncle there, with his influence
            on Zuko. <charAction>Refers to the sequence of Aang, Sokka, and Toph trying to catch a
                powerless Azula, with the Dai Li blocking or helping Azula evade their
                attacks.</charAction> So, this begins a crazy action sequence that Joaquim Dos
            Santos, the director, boarded. I remember when he pitched this to us, we were just like
                <charAction>Bryan chuckles.</charAction> blown away by it. He's-he's a really great
            action choreographer and storyboarder.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, he also did the fight-he storyboarded the fight in 217, which was the other
            underground fight with the Dai Li. <charAction>Mike gives an affirming
                murmur.</charAction> So, he had some, some moves to riff off of.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>And he did a lot of stuff, uh, with Azula, <charAction>Refers to Azula evading Team
                Avatar's attacks with acrobatic jumps and leaps, not fighting back at
                all.</charAction> since Azula doesn't have firebending, you know, the idea is she's
            just basically buying time and trying to, she's fighting like-like Aang usually does,
            which is just to avoid the attack and waste time until the eclipse is over. So, I think
            he referenced a lot of like parkour moves, kind of...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Yeah, French <charAction>Mike
                affirms.</charAction> roof jumping. Don't try that at home, by the way.
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs; refers to Azula jumping between the ground, the metal beams and
                the cave walls in the bunker, dodging Aang's airbending.</charAction> That's why
            she's-she's jumping all around here from... wall to wall, and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>That's uh, you know, we had this idea with, um, Ty Lee and Mai is that one of the
            reasons Azula chose them as friends is they had these skills she did not have, and she
            spent, you know, the better part of her adolescence and, um, learning these skills from
            them. <charAction>Refers to Azula not touching the obstacles around her, or Sokka
                underneath her, as she clears a jump through an earth barrier.</charAction> So, here
            we get to see, uh, what she's learned from Ty Lee, and how agile a gymnast she's become.
                <charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> She's always like ten steps ahead of everybody
            in her, <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> in her thinking and manipulations.
                <charAction>Refers to the Dai Li agent sending his rock gloves at Toph at
                point-blank range, only for Toph to break them apart before they
                connect.</charAction> So, there we see uh, it's kinda hard to see, but the Dai Li
            guy shoots those little rock gloves at Toph, but she breaks 'em. <charAction>Brief
                pause; refers to Azula mocking Team Avatar's attempts to catch her, switching from a
                patronizing complimentary tone, to a belittlingly smug one.</charAction> Like Grey
            DeLisle did an amazing job. I mean she's always great, but these reads are so good for
            Azula.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary as Azula lets Toph know she's rolling her eyes
                at her, with Toph retorting she'll roll Azula's whole head.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>I think Azula and Toph are such a great match, <charAction>Laughs.</charAction>
            'cause they're so comfortable in themselves, you know, <charAction>Mike
                affirms.</charAction> or assumingly, and they... two huge personalities.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs; refers to Azula provoking Sokka by mentioning how she imprisoned
                Suki.</charAction> I just realized there's a lot of, lot of season two finally comes
            back in this episode. <charAction>Bryan chuckles.</charAction> 'Cause a lot of people
            were like, "where's-what happened to Suki?" <charAction>Bryan affirms.</charAction> and
            they, you know, they had a big figh-she had a big fight with Azula, and all that kinda
            stuff comes back, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Azula covertly bringing out a knife from her sleeve as Sokka
                charges at her, one which has the same design as Mai's.</charAction> And there we
            see Azula with one of Mai's daggers, so, it's-really picking up skills from her
            friends.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> She wasn't going to do anything bad with that
            dagger though, right? She was just holding it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Oh yeah, I think she was just going to <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> trim
            her fingernails.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> She-I think she was going to reflect some
            light in his eye, <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Blind him, and...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>Interjects.</charAction> make him blink and trip and
            possibly...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... fall. Safely.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Zuko saying to his father he's going to help Aang defeat
                him.</charAction> That's the moment right there, that we've been waiting for, for
            two and a half seasons. <charAction>Laughs; refers to Ozai luring Zuko back with the
                truth about his mother, buying time while the eclipse ends.</charAction> But now we
            see-we kinda see where Azula gets her, her smarts and her attitude...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> Her smarts?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... from-from her-from her dad. She's got some smarts, <charAction>Bryan
                chuckles.</charAction> some street-smarts. But he's kind of doing a similar thing
            where he's, he, by bringing up his mom, he's-he's kind of keeping Zuko around a little
            bit longer, 'til...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> Pushing-pushing these buttons.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... 'til the eclipse is over, yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Baiting him. <charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> See that everybody sort of has a
            weakness, you know, some sore spot. <charAction>Brief pause; refers to the faint echoes
                on Ozai and Zuko's voices.</charAction> Thought Tom did a great job mixing this, I
            love the, the reverb in this chamber.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. So, now we...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Ozai recounting how Ursa committed treasonous actions in order
                to save Zuko from Ozai and Azulon's punishment.</charAction> Another season two
            thing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Another callback to season two, uh, where we saw the flashback to when Fire Lord
            Azulon passed away. We see that Ozai and Zuko's mom did have a little pact to uh, save,
            she kind of saved Zuko's life by doing something not very nice to <charAction>Bryan and
                Mike chuckle.</charAction> Fire Lord Azulon. Uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the scene dissolving from Azula withholding the truth about
                Suki from Sokka, to Ozai telling the truth about Ursa to Zuko, both of them using
                their leverage to stall for time.</charAction> Now that's a nice little
            cross-dissolve there to show how similar father and daughter are.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I like that parallel. Visual parallel.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the color palette in the scene changing to turquoise hues as
                Ozai swiftly bends a bolt of lightning at Zuko.</charAction> So, I thought the color
            sh-shift coming up here worked really well. MOI Animation did a really nice
            job.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the cut from the extreme closeup shot of Ozai, his eyes
                closed, to the darkened shadow on the sun moving to expose the light underneath,
                back to Ozai who opens his eye.</charAction> So, we see that he's feeling the
            wi-eclipse coming, or ending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Zuko guiding the bent lightning through his body, as he's sent
                back several feet.</charAction> Boom. And...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects; refers to Zuko using Iroh's lightning redirection technique
                in practice for the first time.</charAction> Uncle, another callback...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> Another one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... to season two, <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> Uncle taught Zuko how to
            do this. <charAction>Refers to Zuko redirecting the lightning ahead of Ozai's
                podium.</charAction> So, Zuko just blows up the stage in front of Ozai.
                <charAction>Refers to Zuko being gone from the bunker as Ozai picks himself up from
                the ground; in a mock dramatic tone.</charAction> And he's gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until Azula, having freed herself from Team
                Avatar's bindings with her bending, gives them an series of confusing directions to
                where Ozai supposedly is, involving going a hallway and a secret
                stairway.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> I was wondering, how were they going to find the
            secret stairway...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> If it's secret?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> if it's secret. And what hall? There's like
            four halls. I guess she really doesn't want them to find it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>Another brief pause in commentary until Sokka and Toph convince Aang to
                abandon the search for Ozai, and instead regroup with the invasion
                force.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, yeah, any fans who were reading the premise of the show, and then, they're like,
                <charAction>In a curious tone.</charAction> "is he really going to face the Fire
            Lord in episode eleven?" <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Nope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>They probably figured it out that it wasn't going to work. <charAction>Mike gives an
                affirming murmur; refers to the invasion force wearing their eclipse glasses after
                the eclipse has ended.</charAction> And uh, we did not test out if these glasses are
            sufficient protection for <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction> looking at an eclipse,
            so kids, please don't do that, listen to your science teachers.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to the Fire Nation war balloons and airships rising
                into the air.</charAction> And now comes the big, big reveal. <charAction>Refers to
                the mechanist despairing over his inventions being co-opted by the Fire Nation
                again.</charAction> Yeah, see, now he feels bad. <charAction>Bryan
                laughs.</charAction> He's like, "why did I make those things?" <charAction>Laughs;
                refers to the airships.</charAction> So, these have a cool-these are the-the, these
            giant airships are 3D CG models, um... the...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Aldina Dias and I designed them. She did a
            fantastic job.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to Steve Ziolkowski.</charAction> And a guy named Steve Z built
            them. What's his last name?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Well, <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> you'd think with my last name, I would
            know. I would take the <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> time...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> He goes by Steve Z.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I can't pronounce his <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> last name. I can't
            remember.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Uh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> It's like Ziolwowski, you know, it's one of
            those, it's like my name.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the figureheads on the bows of the airships.</charAction> Oh,
            that's cool, what-on, so, on the front of those airships, there's like a big kind of
            face, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Loo-looks like a big uh, sort of Chinese lion... slash dragon head.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I'm really, really happy with them. Uh, Aldina did a cool-she did a bunch of
            concepts for the silhouette, and she had one where the middle was sort of scooped out.
                <charAction>Refers to the upturned pointed prow of the airships.</charAction> And
            uh, we wanted it to have similar, uh, bow like-like the Fire Nation ships, so it has
            that same horn. Just a recognizable silhouette. Sort of like the komodo rhinos that they
            ride. <charAction>Refers to the sequence of Aang and Katara trying to take down the
                balloons airships, only to get forced back by the numerous firebenders on the ship's
                exterior catwalks.</charAction> Some great storyboarding by Lauren Montgomery.
                <charAction>Brief pause; laughs.</charAction> I like-I like that little sequence,
            it's like our mini... mini, mini <description>Star Wars</description>. You know, it's
            like...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the background.</charAction> Oh, yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... tiny little... splinter of what <charAction>Laughs.</charAction>
            <description>Star Wars</description> does, and just crazy laser blasts everywhere, and
            flying in and out of it. <charAction>Brief pause; refers to Zuko arriving at Iroh's
                prison, with the structure damaged and pockmarked, the guards either knocked
                unconscious or cowering in fear, and Iroh gone, his cell bars blown
                open.</charAction> Again, uh, now we see what Uncle was working towards, and
            he...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Why...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... <charAction>Interjects.</charAction> did some crazy qigong, and just bent the
            metal.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>... why he was getting all buff in episode four. He knew, he knew something was
            coming. <charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> He's got other plans, that we don't know
            about right now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause; refers to the low-pitched conveyor belt sound as the
                airships pass over the invasion force.</charAction> Ben Wynn did some cool sound
            design for these airships.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until, after everyone realizes the airships
                will destroy the submarines, the invasion force's only method of escape besides
                Appa, Hakoda tells the youngest members of the invasion force to escape on the
                bison, while the rest of them stay behind and surrender.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>So, this is when we see all is not well, the plan didn't really work. They're barely
            just going to scrape by.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>You know, we kind of, just for the series and stuff, we kinda needed the kids to be
            alone again. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Like we couldn't have-couldn't be tracking
            like Hakoda and all these, all these other characters. so, um...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> It's also you want there to be a price for,
                <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> for their failure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Totally. So, we wanted the-the kids to get away, and all the-all the adults get
            captured.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>It's just-it's cool too, because it then puts the uh, puts all the pressure back on
            the kids, <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction> for, you know, really seeing this
            journey through. <charAction>Refers to the large clump of seaweed that the swampbenders
                poke out of.</charAction> That always looks like a really nice plate of spaghetti to
            me, <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction> like spinach, pasta, hamburger...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Well, it is-it is seaweed, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>We are getting close to lunch, huh. <charAction>Mike chuckles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>Another brief pause in commentary until Teo says goodbye to his father as
                he goes with Aang and the rest of the kids.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>It's a very emotional goodbye. But there wa-so, we wanted, you know, we didn't want
            these poor little kids to be in jail, <charAction>Bryan chuckles.</charAction> like
            The-The Duke and stuff, and, but once they, <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> once they
            get away to the Western Air Temple, they kind of feel like they're just-just hanging
            out, <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> like they don't have anything to do
            really.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Or it's vacation, summer vacation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief pause.</charAction> Well, you know, there's the whole spinoff
            we're pitching. What those guys were doing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, the-the <description>The Duke and Haru Chronicles</description>?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, it's gonna be good.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the tone of a dramatic narrator.</charAction> Duke, Haru, Teo. In the
            halls of the temple. <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> They-they basically start up
            a street luging...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Oh, sweet, yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... tournament.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Oh...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Refers to the long take of Appa pulling out from the bottom of the frame
                and flying into the horizon, closely focusing in on the expressions of Sokka and
                Katara before they shrink into the distance.</charAction> I like that, that shot
            came out really...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Yeah, animation and everything just came out
            beautifully on that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Usually when we try crazy animated pullouts like that, like from someone's eye all
            the way to Appa, it usually <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> doesn't work. But that one
            came out good. <charAction>Mike affirms.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <th/>
        <speech>
            <description>A brief pause in commentary until Appa shrinks into the distance, puffy
                white and dark blue clouds dominating the shot.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>These clouds look pretty cool.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. <charAction>Refers to Zuko following Team Avatar on a war
                balloon.</charAction> I love this moment at the end where we see that Zuko's... just
            following them.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>He's like, "does my hair look good? Is it, <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> is
            it... flowing...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interjects.</charAction> Flowing right in the wind, <charAction>Bryan
                affirms.</charAction> so is it beautifully.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>... is it parted in the right place?" So, great job everybody, that one was well
            worth the wait for us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>But was it worth it for the fans? We do not know yet. Hopefully-I think-I think
            that-that would be a, a fan favorite is my prediction.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I don't know what they want. <charAction>Mike laughs.</charAction> I just make
            it. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>We just make-mainly we make what we would want to watch. And then hopefully other
            people would <charAction>Bryan laughs.</charAction> like to watch it too. It's worked
            out so far, so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech>If it was just me, it would be all street luge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Well, good luck with that spin-off series.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the tone of a dramatic narrator.</charAction>
            <description>The Last Street Luger</description>.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Can I be a-a consultant on it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bryan">Bryan</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In the tone of a dramatic narrator.</charAction> You-you shall.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mike">Mike</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you.</speech>
    </p>
</root>
