<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Awakening</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens on board a Fire Nation ship where Aang finally regains
                consciousness. The camera zooms out on his face as he opens his eyes and rises from
                his bed, visibly shaken and in pain, and now with a head full of hair.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What happened? <charAction>Sees the Fire Nation designs and flag and immediately
                assumes he has been captured.</charAction> Oh no!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He leaves his room, carefully creaking open the door and peering outside
                for any sign of Fire Nation soldiers. Using his glider as a crutch, Aang stumbles
                across the hall, occasionally leaning on the wall for support due to being weak. He
                stops at a turn in the hallway upon hearing two guards, who are actually Pipsqueak
                and The Duke, talking to each other.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>You hear something? <charAction>Aang retreats behind the wall, where he dons a
                determined look and quickly steps out to send a weak air blast at them, which only
                ruffles their clothes, and moves past the hallway.</charAction> He's awake!
                <charAction>The two begin chasing Aang, who struggles to escape.</charAction> Stop!
            Wait!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang manages to reach the deck of the ship, however, he stumbles on the
                stairway and drops his staff. It slides over to where Hakoda and Bato, disguised as
                Fire Nation soldiers, are petting Momo.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> Momo?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo runs toward Aang, jumps on his shoulder and licks his face. Toph and
                Katara, standing near the edge of the ship, hear the events.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Twinkle Toes! That's got to be you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, you're awake! <charAction>The two race over to him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Are you sure? <charAction>Rubs eyes.</charAction> I feel like I'm dreaming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hugs Aang.</charAction> You're not dreaming. You're finally
            awake.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hugs Aang; is disguised as a Fire Nation guard.</charAction> Aang, good
            to see you back with the living, buddy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka? <charAction>Breathes heavily, appears to be passing
            out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Uh-oh, somebody catch him, he's going to-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The screen becomes black as Aang collapses to the floor, Katara running
                short of catching him. The shot cuts to the entire group, including Appa,
                surrounding Aang who is now in Katara's arms. Meanwhile, on another ship, Zuko is
                heading toward the Fire Nation. Mai joins him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Aren't you cold?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I've got a lot on my mind. It's been so long, over three years since I was home. I
            wonder what's changed. I wonder how <description>I've</description> changed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Yawns.</charAction> I just asked if you were cold, I didn't ask for your
            whole life story. <charAction>Zuko frowns at her sarcastic response. Mai giggles and
                holds his face in her hands.</charAction> Stop worrying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two kiss. Mai exits, and Zuko stays there with an expression of relief
                on his face. We return to the ship where Team Avatar is on. Aang is awake once
                again. He sits in front of Katara, also sitting, surrounded by Toph and Sokka. Appa
                rests behind them. Aang receives a robe to cover him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Why are we on a Fire Nation ship? Why is everyone dressed this way? And why am I the
            only one who's completely out of it? <charAction>Katara and Aang are left
                alone.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You need to take it easy, okay? You got hurt pretty bad. <charAction>Smiling at
                him.</charAction> I like your hair.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I have hair? <charAction>Feels it.</charAction> How long was I out?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>A few weeks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everything okay?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking away, annoyed. Annoyed tone.</charAction> We're fine,
            Dad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Aang.</charAction> I'm Hakoda, Katara and Sokka's father.
                <charAction>Aang moves to shake his outstretched hand.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Placing her hands on Aang's shoulders stopping him.</charAction> He
            knows who you are. I just called you "Dad", didn't I?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>I guess you're right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Removing Katara's hand he shakes Hakoda's hand.</charAction> Nice to
            officially meet you, Chief Hakoda.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>It's an honor to meet you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Great, great, so now you guys have finally met. So would you mind giving us a little
            privacy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Of course. <charAction>Walks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Are you mad at your dad or something? <charAction>Katara looks at Hakoda leave with
                an expression of annoyance on her face.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused look.</charAction> What, not at all. Why would you say
            that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang shrugs and murmurs as if to say "I don't know." but gasps in
                pain.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe we should go upstairs. <charAction>Helping Aang up.</charAction> You need a
            healing session.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in Aang's room on the ship. Katara bends some water onto the scar left
                by Azula's lightning attack.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Tell me where the pain feels most intense.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Mmm, a little higher. Uhhh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang briefly flashes back to the battle at Old Ba Sing Se where he rose
                into the Avatar State, then back to reality.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, you're definitely in the right area there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can feel a lot of energy twisted up around there. <charAction>Begins to remove the
                water.</charAction> Let me just see if I can-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Katara bends the water from Aang's scar, he suddenly jerks backward and
                again flashes back to the battle at Old Ba Sing Se, to the moment where he was shot
                by Azula's lightning. The flashback scene then changes to Katara is tearfully
                looking over Aang, looking comatose, flying on top of Appa as they flee Ba Sing Se.
                After that, he snaps back to reality.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I went down! I didn't just get hurt, did I? It was worse than that. I was
                gone! But you brought me back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I just used the spirit water from the North Pole. I don't know what I did
            exactly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to look at her.</charAction> You saved me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Placing a hand on the side of his face.</charAction> You need to
            rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to the Fire Nation Capital, Li and Lo addressing a crowd
                below.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Li">Li</speaker>
        <speech>Your Princess Azula, clever and beautiful, disguised herself as the enemy and
            entered the Earth Kingdom's Capital. In Ba Sing Se, she found her brother Zuko, and
            together they faced the Avatar ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lo and Li">Lo and Li</speaker>
        <speech>And the Avatar fell! And the Earth Kingdom fell!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Li">Li</speaker>
        <speech>Azula's agents quickly overtook the entire city. They went to Ba Sing Se's great
            walls ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lo and Li">Lo and Li</speaker>
        <speech>And brought them down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Li">Li</speaker>
        <speech>The armies of the Fire Nation surged through the walls and swarmed over Ba Sing Se,
            securing our victory.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A flashback shows the Dai Li taking down Ba Sing Se's walls and the Fire
                Nation troops entering the city as Earth Kingdom citizens look on with fear. Tanks
                are seen approaching the Ba Sing Se's royal palace before flashing back to Li and Lo
                with Azula approaching between them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lo and Li">Lo and Li</speaker>
        <speech>Now the heroes have returned home!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lo">Lo</speaker>
        <speech>Your princess, Azula ... <charAction>Crowd cheers.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Li">Li</speaker>
        <speech>And after three long years, your prince has returned ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lo and Li">Lo and Li</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko approaches with a worried expression. Crowd cheers. We now go back to
                Team Avatar's ship. Sokka sits on a crate with a map with the others surrounding him
                as he narrates past events.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>After what happened at Ba Sing Se, we had to get you to safety. We flew back to
            Chameleon Bay where we found my father and the other Water Tribe men.
                <charAction>Flashback preparing to leave by taking off his Earth King robes
                revealing traveling robes beneath.</charAction> The Earth King decided he wanted to
            travel the world in disguise, so he set off alone. <charAction>Bosco is shown taking off
                his own attire and hat before Kuei jumps on Bosco and they set off.</charAction>
            Well, not completely alone. <charAction>Cut back to Sokka continuing the
                story.</charAction> Soon, the bay was overrun by Fire Nation ships. Rather than
            fight them all, we captured a single ship and made it our disguise. Since then we've
            been traveling west. We crossed through the Serpent's Pass a few days ago. We've seen a
            few Fire Nation ships, but none have bothered us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So what now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>We've been working on a modified version of the invasion plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sharply.</charAction> It's <description>Sokka's</description> invasion
            plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, Sokka's plan. We won't be able to mount a massive invasion without the Earth
            King's armies, but the solar eclipse will still leave the Fire Nation
            vulnerable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So we're planning a smaller invasion. Just a ragtag team of our friends and allies
            from around the Earth Kingdom. We already ran into Pipsqueak and The Duke.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eating noodles with The Duke on his shoulder.</charAction> Good to see
            you again, Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And the best part is, the eclipse isn't even our biggest advantage!
                <charAction>Whispers.</charAction> We have a secret... <charAction>Looks at both of
                his sides.</charAction> You!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yep, the whole world thinks you're dead! Isn't that great? <charAction>Stands up and
                raises both of his fists triumphantly.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang is shocked. Cut to Aang looking out to the water from a side of the
                boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The world thinks I'm dead? How is that good news? That's terrible!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Aang.</charAction> No, it's great! It means the Fire Nation
            won't be hunting us anymore! And even better, they won't be expecting you on the Day of
            Black Sun!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, no, no, no, no. You have no idea. This is so messed up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Another Fire Nation ship approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll handle this. The Avatar is back. <charAction>Opens glider and grunts in
                pain.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Aang.</charAction> Aang, wait! Remember, they don't know
            we're not Fire Nation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sweating, Aang puts his glider away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone just stay calm. <charAction>He and Bato put their helmets on.</charAction>
            Bato and I will take care of this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pipsqueak and The Duke cover Appa and Momo, while Aang, Toph, Sokka and
                Katara hide in a square hole.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I hate not being able to do anything.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hopefully, you won't need to.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Crew from the other ship boards Team Avatar's ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Navy officer">Fire Navy officer</speaker>
        <speech>Commander, why are you off course? All Western Fleet ships are supposed to be moving
            toward Ba Sing Se to support the occupation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, we're from the Eastern Fleet. We have orders to deliver some
            cargo.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Navy officer">Fire Navy officer</speaker>
        <speech>Ahhh ... Eastern Fleet. Well, nice of Admiral Chan to let us know he was sending one
            of his ships our way.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bato">Bato</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sure Admiral Chan meant no disrespect, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Navy officer">Fire Navy officer</speaker>
        <speech>I mean, how hard is it to write a quick note and send a hawk our way?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Next time, we'll send <charAction>Bato and Hakoda glance at each other.</charAction>
            two hawks to make sure you get the message.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two bow to each other, and Hakoda and Bato exit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Sir ... Admiral Chan has been on leave for two months at Ember Island.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Navy officer">Fire Navy officer</speaker>
        <speech>What? Why doesn't anyone ever tell me anything? Something's not right; they should
            have known that. I think this is a captured ship. <charAction>Whispering.</charAction>
            Just stay quiet until we're safely across the ramp. Then we'll sink this ship.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph, hearing this, emerges.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>They know!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She metalbends the bridge between the ships off. The captain and his guards
                fall into the water. Katara creates a large wave which separates the other ship from
                theirs. Team Avatar's ship departs quickly. The captain and his guards from the
                other ship climbs back on board theirs by rope ladder. Meanwhile, back at the Fire
                Nation Capital, Zuko feeds turtle ducks in a lake with some bread. Azula joins
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>You seem so downcast. Has Mai gotten to you already? Though actually, Mai has been
            in a strangely good mood lately.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I haven't seen Dad yet. I haven't seen him in three years, since I was
            banished.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>So what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>So, I didn't capture the Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Who cares? The Avatar is dead ... <charAction>Zuko looks away.</charAction> unless
            you think he somehow miraculously survived.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko flashes back to when Katara explained about her vial of spirit water
                in the Crystal Catacombs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>During flashback.</charAction> This is water from the spirit oasis at
            the north pole. It has special properties so I've been saving it for something
            important.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back to the present.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>No. There's no way he could have survived. <charAction>They glare at each
                other.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Well, then I'm sure you have nothing to worry about.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the ocean. The second ship begins firing at Team Avatar's. Toph
                takes an earthbending stance while The Duke stands behind her to guide
                her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Load the Toph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pipsqueak drops a boulder in front of Toph who begins earthbending it at
                the attacking ship. It hits a catapult as another fires. others try to fight back
                with a series of rocks that Toph earthbends at the other ship. With The Duke's
                guidance, Toph earthbends another piece of rock and sends it to intercept the
                oncoming fireball. Aang, inside the ship with Sokka, makes a move to help but is
                stopped by Sokka. In frustration he bangs his head against his staff. The other ship
                fires a harpoon, piercing a hole in Team Avatar's ship's bottom. As water flows in,
                Katara, noticing this, freezes the water below to plug the hole.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm gonna give us some cover!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She brings up vapor from the water to create a fog screen. However, a
                fireball makes its way through and destroys the rocks that Toph had been
                using.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Aang and Sokka in the ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I just can't stand by and do nothing! <charAction>Runs out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Following.</charAction> Aang, no! <charAction>Grabs the
                staff.</charAction> You're still hurt, and you have to stay secret! Just let us
            handle this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Fine. <charAction>Grabs his staff and walks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Two fireballs hit the ship causing a fire. Katara quickly extinguishes it
                with waterbending.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>How are we doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Things couldn't get much worse. <charAction>A serpent rises from the water near
                their ship. Sokka turns around and looks at it in despar. Yelling.</charAction> The
            universe just loves proving me wrong, doesn't it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You make it too easy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The serpent is hit by a fireball from the other ship. In anger, it wraps
                itself around the other ship, allowing Team Avatar's ship to escape.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you, the universe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar's ship arrives a port in a town. Aang is alone in his room,
                until the rest of the gang enter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, Aang! We're going into town to find some dinner.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Clutching his stomach.</charAction> Well, I am pretty hungry. Maybe
            dinner's a good idea.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Here, <charAction>Offering a Fire Nation bandana.</charAction> tie this around your
            head. It will cover your arrow.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not going out if I can't wear my arrow proudly! <charAction>He lies back
                down.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, come on. Be practical.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Placing a hand on Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> You guys go ahead
            without us. We'll catch up to you. <charAction>Toph and Sokka exit. Katara sits on
                Aang's bed, placing a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> I think I understand why
            being a secret bothers you so much. You don't want people to think you failed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're right, I don't. But the problem is, I did fail!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, that's not true.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Getting up.</charAction> It is true. I was in
            Ba Sing Se. I was there! But I lost. And now the Earth Kingdom is fallen for
            good.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's not for good. <charAction>Getting up too.</charAction> Remember, there's still
            a plan. The invasion!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>And I hate the invasion plan, too! <charAction>Rips down the Fire Nation flag
                covering his staff.</charAction> I don't want you or anyone else risking your lives
            to fix my mistakes! I've always known that I would have to face the Fire Lord. But now I
            know I need to do it alone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Moving to comfort him.</charAction> Aang ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, please! Just go ... please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exiting.</charAction> Is there anything you need?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I need to redeem myself. I need my honor back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the Fire Nation Capital, Zuko returns to the royal palace and
                prepares to face his father, Ozai. He breathes deeply and enters. We briefly see
                Ozai before cutting back to Team Avatar's ship. Katara returns to Aang's
                room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I brought you some food! <charAction>Notices Aang has gone missing.</charAction> Oh
            no ... <charAction>Drops the food tray and runs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang, flying on his glider. Back at the Royal Palace, Zuko bows
                before Ozai.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>You've been away for a long time. I see the weight of your travels has changed you.
            You have redeemed yourself, my son. <charAction>Approaches Zuko; the camera pans up to
                view Ozai's full face for the first time.</charAction> Welcome home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang struggles to remain in flight against his injuries. Back on the ship,
                Katara runs toward Bato and Hakoda. She is in tears.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bato">Bato</speaker>
        <speech>I'll leave you two alone. <charAction>Exits.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>What's wrong, Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He left.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang. He just took his glider and disappeared. He has this ridiculous notion that he
            has to save the world alone, that it's all his responsibility.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe that's his way of being brave.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's not brave, it's selfish and stupid! We could be helping him and I know the
            world needs him, but doesn't he know how much we need him, too? How can he just leave us
            behind?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>You're talking about me too, aren't you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How could you leave us, Dad? <charAction>She attempts to wipe away the
                tears.</charAction> I mean, I know we had Gran-Gran, and she loved us, but we were
            just so lost without you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hakoda moves to comfort her as she turns away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>I'm so sorry, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Embraces Hakoda.</charAction> I understand why you left. I really do,
            and I know that you had to go, so why do I still feel this way? I'm so sad and angry and
            hurt!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>I love you more than anything. You and your brother are my entire world. I thought
            about you every day when I was gone and every night when I went to sleep, I would lie
            awake missing you so much it would ache.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to the Royal Palace.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>I am proud of you, Prince Zuko. I am proud because you and your sister conquered Ba
            Sing Se. I am proud because when your loyalty was tested by your treacherous uncle, you
            did the right thing and captured the traitor. And I am proudest of all of your most
            legendary accomplishment: you slayed the Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> What did you hear?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>Azula told me everything. She said she was amazed and impressed at your power and
            ferocity at the moment of truth.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes back to Aang continuing his flight, struggling. He comes
                upon a Fire Nation blockade.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>A blockade.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He takes a deep breath and swims under it. Upon emerging, he finds a tree
                bark and rides it like a surfboard through the water. A storm turns the seas very
                choppy. He falls off and into the water and his staff flies away. Back to the
                palace, Azula is asleep when Zuko enters her room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Why'd you do it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling, with her eyes still shut.</charAction> You're going to have to
            be a little more specific.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Why did you tell Father that I was the one who killed the Avatar?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Can't this wait until the morning?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It. Can't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs and opens her eyes.</charAction> Fine. You seemed so worried about
            how Father would treat you because you hadn't captured the Avatar. I figured if I gave
            you the credit, you'd have nothing to worry about.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>But why?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Getting out of bed.</charAction> Call it a generous gesture. I wanted to
            thank you for your help and I was happy to share the glory.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You're lying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking past Zuko.</charAction> If you say so ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You have another motive for doing this, I just haven't figured out what it
            is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Please Zuko, what ulterior motive could I have? What could I possibly gain by
            letting you get all the glory for defeating the Avatar? <charAction>Approaching close to
                Zuko she places a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> Unless, somehow, the Avatar was
            actually alive. All that glory would suddenly turn to shame and foolishness. But you
            said it yourself, that was impossible. <charAction>Zuko begins to leave.</charAction>
            Sleep well, Zuzu.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in the sea, Aang struggles to stay above water or reach his glider.
                After letting out a scream, a wave overcomes him and he falls into the water. He
                re-emerges after a brief time.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not gonna make it. I failed. <charAction>Within the lightning strikes, the
                spirit of Roku appears before Aang.</charAction> Roku?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Roku">Roku</speaker>
        <speech>You haven't failed, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But everyone thinks I'm dead again. They think I've abandoned them, and I'm losing
            this war. I'm letting the whole world down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Roku">Roku</speaker>
        <speech>If anyone is to blame for the state of the world, it is me. I should have seen this
            war coming and prevented it. You inherited my problems and my mistakes. But I believe
            you are destined to redeem me and save the world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Moonlight shines onto Aang as Yue's spirit appears above.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>You already saved the world. And you'll save the world again, but you can't give
            up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The storm ends. The spirit of Roku disappears, while Yue's spirit descends
                toward Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> You're right. I won't give up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He creates a wave and surfs it with the tree bark. Yue's spirit watches him
                leave and ascends back to the moon. Aang is washed up at the base of a volcano, on
                the same crescent island where Roku's temple once was. Later, Momo finds him and
                licks his face, waking him up. Katara, Sokka, and Toph find him, reaching him via
                Appa. Katara runs to hug him, her worried look changing to happiness.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're okay!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They all, including Momo and Appa, come together for a group
                hug.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I have so much to do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I know, but you'll have our help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You didn't think you could get out of training just by coming to the Fire Nation,
            did you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What about the invasion?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We'll join up with my dad and the invasion force the day of the eclipse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Notices Aang's damaged staff has washed ashore.</charAction> Hey! What's
            ... oh, it's your glider.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay. If someone saw it, it would give away my identity. It's better for now
            that no one knows I'm alive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Flies up and sticks it in the volcano's lava trails, causing it to catch
                fire as they depart. Scene fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
