<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Deserter</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens in a forest while Momo suddenly appears, jumping from a
                tree to another tree. A mysterious figure is seen following him, and Momo lands on a
                roadside kiosk, while Team Avatar is arriving at it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking toward a poster on the kiosk, present in the middle of a
                crossroad.</charAction> This should give us a good idea of what's around
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Flips a small pouch to find it empty aside from a few
                crumbs.</charAction> See if you can find a menu, I'm starving! <charAction>Wipes his
                mouth.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I bet we'll find something to eat here, <charAction>Pointing at the
                poster.</charAction> the Fire Day's Festival. <charAction>Momo jumps down. Aang
                begins reading-out the poster.</charAction> Fire Nation cultural exhibits, jugglers,
            benders, magicians ... <charAction>Turns to Katara.</charAction> This would be a great
            place for me to study some real firebenders.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at another poster on the other side of the kiosk;
                seriously.</charAction> You might wanna rethink that. Look at this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Comes over to at the poster.</charAction> Hey, a poster of me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>A wanted poster! This is bad. <charAction>Aang removes the poster from the wall and
                starts reading it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stares at the wanted poster.</charAction> I think we better keep
            moving.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at Katara.</charAction> I have to learn firebending at some
            point and this could be my only chance to watch a master's up close.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Swayed by Aang; while her head is bowed.</charAction> I guess we could
            go check it out. <charAction>Aang begins rejoicing.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Moves in front of Katara; in an opposing tone.</charAction> What? You
            wanna walk into a Fire Nation town where they're all fired-up with their ... you know,
            fire? <charAction>Aang becomes serious again.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Starts walking toward Appa and is followed by Aang.</charAction> We'll
            wear disguises and if it looks like trouble, we'll leave.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Not convinced; sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah! Because we always leave
            before we get into trouble.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Appa and Momo.</charAction> You guys stay out of sight here while we
            go to the festival. <charAction>To Katara and Sokka.</charAction> Ready
            disguises!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka and Katara put on their black cloaks while Aang pulls his orange
                shawl over his head with a smile on his face making him look
                ridiculous.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically at Aang's goofy disguise.</charAction> It's like you're a
            whole different person ... <charAction>Katara giggles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Let's go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The gang looks around seeing everyone in masks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I think we need some new disguises.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Where are we gonna get masks like that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mask dealer">Mask dealer</speaker>
        <speech>Get your genuine Fire Festival masks here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That was surprisingly easy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The gang chooses three masks. Katara chooses a lady with makeup, Sokka a
                blue smiling mask with petals around the rim, and Aang who chooses a red mask with a
                frown on it. Katara removes Sokka's mask, revealing him to be frowning, and Aang's
                mask, revealing him to be the one smiling. She places Sokka's original mask over
                Aang's face and Aang's over Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, there's some food.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Finally! <charAction>To the shop keeper.</charAction> What do you have?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Shop keeper">Shop keeper</speaker>
        <speech>Flaming fire flakes! Best in town.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'll take'em!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka gobbles down the fire flakes, but has a spasm from the
                spiciness.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aaahhh! Hot! Hot!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> "Flaming fire flakes", hot? What do you
            know?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, look at this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Puppet Fire Lord">Puppet Fire Lord</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry loyal citizens! No one can surprise the Fire Lord!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation kids">Fire Nation kids</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>As an Earth Kingdom general puppet pops up behind the Fire Lord's
                puppet, with a rock ready to attack.</charAction> Oh no! Look out! <charAction>The
                puppet breaths fire, burning the other puppet.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, hold on! Where are we going?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know, but there's a big crowd so it must be good.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Knowing the Fire Nation, it's probably an
            execution.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I gotta learn that trick!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Malu">Malu</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you! For my next trick I need a volunteer from the audience!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waving his hand up in the air all around childishly.</charAction> Oh!
            Oh! Me! Me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a stern tone while pulling his arm down.</charAction> What do you
            think you're doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I want to get a closer look.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's better that we don't attract any attention to ourselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Malu">Malu</speaker>
        <speech>How about you, little lady?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While backing away.</charAction> Uh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Malu">Malu</speaker>
        <speech>Awww, she's shy. Leeet's give her some encouragement, folks!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a jealous tone while folding his arms.</charAction> Awww! That
            could've been me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Malu">Malu</speaker>
        <speech>This next trick is called "Taming the Dragon." <charAction>While sitting her down in
                a chair and tying her to it.</charAction> You will be my captured princess! Don't
            worry, young maiden! I will tame this fiery beast! It's too strong, I can't hold
            it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We gotta help her!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, we don't want to make a scene!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Malu">Malu</speaker>
        <speech>The rope, it's breaking! <charAction>Aang saves Katara with his airbending,
                dispersing the flames is a ray of colors while he loses his mask in the
                process.</charAction> Hey, you tryin' to upstage me, kid?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang starts doing a goofy dance as everyone boos at him for ruining the
                trick.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Citizen">Citizen</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! That kid's the Avatar! <charAction>Aang stops dancing and
            runs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I think it's time to go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>Follow me! I can get you outta here! <charAction>The kids follow
            Chey.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>There they are!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Chey throws a series of explosives at the Fire Nation soldiers that are
                chasing them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Over there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm calling Appa. <charAction>Aang blows his whistle.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I hope he can really hear that bison whistle!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Making a sharp turn down one of the several alleys.</charAction> This
            way! <charAction>Comes running back.</charAction> Okay! Not this way!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They make another turn, but the way they came is blocked by guards. Chey
                throws another smoke bomb and runs past them into another alley. They group comes
                across another dead end where there is an enormous supply of fireworks. Cut to an
                overhead shot that reveals Appa has arrived in the nick of time.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Appa! Down here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa lands between the kids and the guards, with his backside facing the
                guards. Appa airbends a gale force wind which results in the guards getting blown
                out of sight. As the guards run back into the alley, Appa has already taken off. Cut
                to Chey, he bites the top off a bomb to light it. He throws it at the fireworks
                supply and it blows up creating a beautiful display of fireworks. Cut to Chey
                removing his hood as they cruise away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Nice touch setting off the fireworks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Impressed.</charAction> You really know your explosives ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>I'm familiar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're a Fire Nation Soldier!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech><description>Was.</description> My name's Chey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The group lands and makes camp.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>I serve a man. More than a man really, he's a myth, but he's real, a living legend,
            Jeong Jeong the Deserter. He was a Fire Nation general, or wait, was he an
            admiral?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Not amused.</charAction> He was very highly ranked, we get it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah! Way up there! But he couldn't take the madness any more. He's the first person
            ever to leave the army - and live. I'm the second, but you don't get to be a legend for
            that. That's okay though. Jeong Jeong's a firebending genius. Some say he's mad - but
            he's not! He's enlightened.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You mean there's a firebender out here who's not with the Fire Lord?
                <charAction>Gets up in excitement.</charAction> We've gotta go see him! He can train
            me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Snaps at Aang.</charAction> We're not gonna go find some crazy
            firebender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed; Stands up to gesture.</charAction> He's not crazy! He's a
            genius! And he's the perfect person to train the Avatar! That's why I followed you into
            the festival.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Look, thanks for the help, but we're leaving for the North Pole in the
            morning.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, this could be my only chance to meet a firebending master who would actually
            be willing to teach me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It can't hurt just to talk to him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Very annoyed.</charAction> That's what you said about going to the
            festival! Why doesn't anyone ever listen to me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Sokka turns to pout, he almost runs right into a spear. In a flash, they
                are surrounded by men wearing straw hats, light armor, wearing tribal make up, and
                wielding spears.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lin Yee">Lin Yee</speaker>
        <speech>Don't move!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The tribal folks escort them to their settlement.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lin Yee">Lin Yee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angry.</charAction> Jeong Jeong told you not to look for
            Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hold on, you know these guys?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>Oh yeh! Lin Yee's an old buddy! Right, Lin Yee?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lin Yee">Lin Yee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Not amused with Chey.</charAction> Shut up! Keep moving.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Down the hill, there is a little cottage with leaves and
                logs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lin Yee">Lin Yee</speaker>
        <speech>Go on. He sees you only.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>Oh that's okay, we can chat later.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Is that where Jeong Jeong is? I need to talk to him right away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang tries to move forward, but it stopped by a spear shaft.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lin Yee">Lin Yee</speaker>
        <speech>No! You wait there. <charAction>Pushes Chey forward.</charAction> Go now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry! Everything'll be fine. He's a great man, great man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Chey walks toward Jeong Jeong's cottage. Back in the Fire Days Festival in
                the now deserted central square of the town where some guards are being interrogated
                by Admiral Zhao who is accompanied by a few guards himself.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>So, the Avatar was here and you let him slip away?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard captain">Guard captain</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Anxiously.</charAction> Yes, sir, but other than that the festival went
            off without a hitch! <charAction>A huge piece of burning planks of wood falls in the
                background with a massive crash making the guards twitch.</charAction> No fights.
            Theft was way down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> I don't care about your local crime rates! Which
            way did they go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard captain">Guard captain</speaker>
        <speech>They headed into the forest, up the river I suspect.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Ready the river boats. We're going after the Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back in the settlement, Chey exits Jeong Jeong's cottage. He arrives back
                where Aang and the others are fast asleep. Everyone wakes up instantly as Chey
                approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What happened? Can I see Jeong Jeong now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking downcast.</charAction> He won't see you. He's very angry that I
            brought you here. He wants you to leave immediately.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Finally! Let's hit the road. <charAction>He stretches back out
            again.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Why won't he see me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>He says you're not ready. Says you haven't mastered waterbending and earthbending
            yet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Wait, how does he know that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech>He saw the way you walked into camp. He could tell.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm going in, anyway!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang walks to Jeong Jeong's cottage. He takes a deep breath, parts the
                curtain, and walks into the darkness. Cut to a dark figure seated cross legged
                amidst a semicircle of candles, his back to Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Get out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Master, I need to learn firebending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Only a fool seeks his own destruction.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Jeong Jeong.</charAction> I'm the Avatar, it's my destiny to—
                <charAction>Gets interrupted.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Destiny? What would a boy know of destiny? If a fish lives its whole life in this
            river, does he know the river's destiny? No! Only that it runs on and on out of his
            control! He may follow where it flows, but he cannot see the end. He cannot imagine the
            ocean.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, but it's the Avatar's duty to master all of the bending disciplines.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>To master the bending disciplines, you must first master discipline itself. But you
            have no interest in this, so I have no interest in you! Now, get out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Please, I have to learn. This could be my only chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Are you deaf? How can I teach you if you refuse to listen? Before learning
            firebending you must learn water and earth. Water is cool and soothing, earth is steady
            and stable, but fire, fire is alive! It breathes, it grows. Without the bender, a rock
            will not throw itself! But fire will spread and destroy everything in its path if one
            does not have the will to control it! That is its destiny! You are not ready! You are
            too weak!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At this final gesture the candles around Jeong Jeong violently flame up to
                illuminate the entire hut before quickly going out. A vision in front of Jeong Jeong
                begins, as one candle is seen lit in front of the firebender. A tree is in the
                background behind the Deserter. In front of him, stands Avatar Roku.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Roku">Roku</speaker>
        <speech>You think I am weak?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Avatar Roku! No, No! I did not mean that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Roku">Roku</speaker>
        <speech>I have mastered the elements a thousand times in a thousand lifetimes. Now, I must
            do it once again. You will teach the Avatar <charAction>He raises his hand and ignites
                the tree behind Jeong Jeong.</charAction> firebending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, yes, I will teach you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Really? That's great! <charAction>Raises his hands happily; Jeong Jeong groans in
                dismay fearing this may not end well.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In the morning outside of Jeong Jeong's cottage. Sokka is sitting on a
                boulder by the river, fishing. The screen pans up the river where Katara is
                practicing waterbending before switching to Aang and Jeong Jeong in front of the
                cottage. Aang stands, bandy legged, on a flat stone in the river. Jeong Jeong stands
                a foot or two away on the bank in front of his cottage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Widen your stance. Wider! Bend your knees. Now, concentrate. <charAction>Aang
                expresses his concentration.</charAction> Good, good!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! What do I do now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns around.</charAction> Silence! Talking is not concentrating! Look
            at your friend, is she talking? <charAction>Points at Sokka.</charAction> Even that oaf
            knows to concentrate on what he's doing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction>
            Hey!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But what am I concentrating on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Feel the heat of the sun. It is the greatest source of fire. Yet, it is in complete
            balance with nature!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So when do I get to make some fire?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Concentrate!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang breathes and is embarrassed as his friends laugh at him from behind.
                He turns to look at them, but they stop instantly, as he tries to innocent. Cut to a
                long shot of the figures in the distance climbing the slope of a mountain. Cut to a
                close-up shot of Aang and Jeong Jeong walking up the path to the mountain's
                summit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Are we coming up here so I don't burn anything with my fire blasts?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>No fire yet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Power in firebending comes from the breath. That is why you must master proper
            breath control.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You brought me up here to breathe?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Assume your stance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang assumes the proper stance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Faces the opposite direction of Aang.</charAction> Wider.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're not even look— <charAction>Interrupted by Jeong Jeong.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech><description>Wider!</description> Now, inhale through the nose and exhale through
            the mouth - without talking. Good. Keep going.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jeong Jeong walks down the path and out of the frame as Aang continues to
                breathe, a look of fierce concentration on his face. Cut to a view of Aang's lower
                body as he parts the curtain into Jeong Jeong's cottage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing here? I did not tell you to stop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I've been breathing for hours!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>You want to stop breathing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I want you to stop wasting my time! I already know how to squat and breathe and feel
            the sun! <charAction>Wiggles fingers to the ceiling to gesture this.</charAction> I
            wanna know how to shoot fire out of my fingertips!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs gruffly.</charAction> I had a pupil once who had no interest in
            learning discipline. He was only concerned with the power of fire - how he could use it
            to destroy his opponents and wipe out the obstacles in his path, but fire is a horrible
            burden to bear. Its nature is to consume and without control it destroys everything
            around it. <charAction>While he was speaking, the camera cuts to Zhao on his boat;
                several men attack him, but he fends them off easily, leaving a fire in his wake.
                Cuts back to Jeong Jeong.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Learn restraint, or risk destroying yourself and everything you love.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>After several hours Jeong Jeong finds Aang in front of the hut
                meditating.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I thought about what you said, I promise I'll be more patient.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>We're going to work with fire now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh yeah! <charAction>Aang gets excited and airbends himself into the air. He quickly
                gets serious again.</charAction> I mean, let us begin.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jeong Jeong grabs a falling leaf and burns the center.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Concentrate on the fire. I want you to keep the flame from reaching the edges of the
            leaf for as long as you can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tribal man">Tribal man</speaker>
        <speech>Master! There is trouble.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's going on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Concentrate on your leaf!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> This is the <description>worst
            </description>firebending instruction ever! All he does is leave me for hours to
            concentrate or breathe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sure there's a good reason.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But I'm ready to do so much more.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang remembers to concentrate on his leaf and gets into a stance and
                breaths. Moments later, the leaf burns up creating a small flame.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excited.</charAction> I did it! I made fire!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, that's great, but you should take it slow.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang starts playing with it by tossing it back and forth from in front to
                behind himself. He makes a blast go in the opposite direction.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Now <description>that's</description> some firebending!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, you'll hurt yourself!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I wonder how that juggler did it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang tosses it into the air and spreads his arms out. For a second, he has
                a smile on his face, but it vanishes as he accidentally burns Katara's hands. Katara
                shrieks in pain.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara! I'm so sorry!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka comes running to Katara's side.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Katara, what's wrong?
                <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What did you do?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It was an accident! I was, uh... Katara, I'm so--</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka tackles Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I told you we shouldn't mess around with this! Look what you did! <description>You
                burned my sister</description>! <charAction>Katara runs away.</charAction> You
            burned my sister! <charAction>As Jeong Jeong walks in.</charAction> This is all your
            fault!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>I know! Now pack your things. You must leave immediately.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara runs off.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry, I didn't ... <charAction>Sokka runs off.</charAction> I'm sorry!
                <charAction>Jeong Jeong looks at Aang, displeased.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to Katara who is sulking by a creek due to the pain of her
                burns. She dips her hands in; they glow briefly, and a few seconds later her hands
                are healed.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>You have healing abilities. The great benders of the Water Tribe sometimes have this
            ability. I've always wished I were blessed like you - free from this burning
            curse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But you're a great master. You have powers that I will never know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Water brings healing and life. But fire brings only destruction and pain. It forces
            those of us burdened with its care to walk a razor's edge between humanity and savagery.
            Eventually, we are torn apart.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly the water is front of them is blasted with flames. Jeong Jeong
                gets up and gets into a defensive bending stance and breaks the flames that wash
                over him and Katara. The screen changes to a frontal shot of Zhao's riverboats
                coming toward them before switching back to Katara and Jeong Jeong.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>Go get your friends and flee! Do not come back here or you will all be destroyed.
            Hurry!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jeong Jeong faces the boats that land harmlessly around him. The screen
                shows Zhao looking ahead through a telescope from the main deck of his ship. He
                lowers it and smiles. The screen goes back to Jeong Jeong produces a large wall of
                fire in front of the ships. An overhead shot of the ships is shown; the boats turn
                to land on the beach. The screen goes back to the front of the beach. Zhao comes
                into view.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, men. My old teacher gave up fighting a long time ago. <charAction>The
                screen pans to Jeong Jeong. Suddenly, Zhao parts through the wall.</charAction>
            Haven't you, Master Jeong Jeong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <charAction>The screen goes for a close of Jeong Jeong's face, and a wide shot as he
                drops the wall of fire. Cut to Katara running up to where Sokka is preparing Appa to
                leave.</charAction>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Katara! Are you all right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm fine, we've got to get out of here. Where's Aang? <charAction>Sokka gestures to
                the cottage.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara enters the cottage to find Aang sulking.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Jeong Jeong tried to tell me that I wasn't ready. I wouldn't listen. I'm never going
            to firebend again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You'll have to eventually.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, never again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay, Aang. I'm healed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What? How?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'll explain later. But right now, we have to get out here. Zhao and his soldiers
            are attacking!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets on his feet.</charAction> Where?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>By the river. They captured Jeong Jeong.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I have to help him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <charAction>The screen switches to an overhead shot of the beach. Zhao and his men stand
                against Jeong Jeong, before cutting to a closer shot.</charAction>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Look at you. You were once so great. I can't believe my former master has become
            nothing more than a simple savage.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>It is you who have embraced savagery, Zhao.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>It's Admiral Zhao, now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>That title will not help you against the Avatar. Do not try to fight him! You are no
            match!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> I think I can handle a child.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jeong Jeong">Jeong Jeong</speaker>
        <speech>I have never seen such raw power ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Jeong Jeong!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>We'll see. Men! Take the deserter!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to overhead shot of Jeong Jeong surrounded by five firebenders. Aang
                tops short in horror as they close in. Jeong Jeong smirks and wraps himself in a
                ball of flames. When the flames completely dissipates Jeong Jeong is nowhere to be
                seen.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angry.</charAction> It's a trick! He's run off into the woods. Find him!
                <charAction>Faces Aang.</charAction> Let's find out what my old master has taught
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You were Jeong Jeong's student?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Until I got bored.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zhao throws a fireball at Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>I see he taught you how to duck and run like a coward. But I doubt he showed you
            what a firebender is truly capable of! <charAction>Throws another intense
                fireball.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Whoa! Wild shot!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Roars with rage.</charAction> I'll show you
                wild!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang looks over to the side where Zhao just burned.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No self-control ... <charAction>Gets an idea.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Stand and fight, Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> Oh, were we fighting? I thought you were just
            getting warmed up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Burns in anger at the remark.</charAction> I was ... <charAction>Shoots
                another fireball.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zhao fires many more fireballs which all miss.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Is that all you got? Man, they'll make anyone an admiral these days!
                <charAction>Nearly gets blasted.</charAction>
            <charAction>Aang cups his hands over his to sound louder.</charAction> Ahoy!
                <charAction>Moons Zhao with pants up.</charAction> I'm Admiral Zhao!
                <charAction>Zhao gets even angrier and Aang nearly gets blasted again.</charAction>
            I don't know why, but I thought you'd be better than Zuko. <charAction>Aang looks
                disappointed when he says this. His eyes go wide and he lies down on the deck fast
                enough to avoid being burnt. Mocking Zhao's firebending.</charAction> Sloppy. Very
            sloppy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Nowhere to run now, you little smart mouth!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Having dodged a series of blasts from Zhao on several
                ships.</charAction> You've lost this battle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enraged disbelief.</charAction> Are you crazy? You haven't thrown a
            single blow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, but you have. <charAction>He gestures around, all the boats are on fire and
                sinking.</charAction> Jeong Jeong said you had no restraint. <charAction>Jumps in
                the water.</charAction> Have a nice walk home!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, come on! Let's go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut a shot from behind Aang, who is now looking at the river bank beach.
                Aang hops on Appa and they fly away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! Where's Jeong Jeong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He disappeared. They all did.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chey">Chey</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks into the now abandoned village; not amused.</charAction> Hey,
            where did everybody go? <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Very funny guys</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, you're burned! Let me help you. <charAction>Katara heals the burn on Aang's
                arm.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, that's good water.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>When did you learn that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I guess I always knew.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh ... Well then thanks for all the first
            aid over the years. Like when I fell into the greaseberry bramble.
                <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Or that time I had two fishhooks in my
            thumb!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Two?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> He tried to get the first fishhook out with another
            fishhook.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Still being sarcastic.</charAction> Oh, and the time that mink snake bit
            me! Thanks for healing that up. That was great. Really helpful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
