<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Painted Lady</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens with Appa, the gang in his saddle, slogging his way down
                the course of the sludge-infested river Jang Hui in the Fire Nation. Aang and Momo
                are frolicking in the putrescent water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Momo! <charAction>Dives into the water.</charAction> Oh Momo! <charAction>Dives
                again and Momo flies to Aang.</charAction> Hahahahaha! You found me, buddy!
                <charAction>Looks down at the water in distaste and airbends up to Appa's saddle,
                where he stands dripping in sludge.</charAction> Hey guys, I think this river's
            polluted. <charAction>Airbends mud off himself, splattering the rest of Team Avatar with
                mud, which causes them to cry out in disgust.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tastes mud on her mouth, and spits.</charAction> Pah! Plegh!
                <charAction>Aang airbends again, blowing the rest of the mud back into the river and
                messing up their hair.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well that explains why I can't catch a fish around here, because normally my fishing
            skills are off the hook! <charAction>Holds up a fishing hook. The gang is unamused as
                Aang sits back down.</charAction> Get it? Like a fishing hook?
                <charAction>Grinning.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Countering.</charAction> Too bad your skills aren't on the
            hook.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph, Aang, and Katara laugh as Sokka makes a disgruntled
                face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It looks like we'll need to go somewhere else to get food, <charAction>Unrolls a
                long scroll in front of her.</charAction> assuming that'll fit into Sokka's master
            schedule.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hmmm ... It's doable. But that means only two potty breaks today.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, maybe we can get food there! <charAction>Points at a village in the middle of
                the river.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms to the village and fades to Appa as Aang hides him under a
                mat of grass.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Now you look just like a little hill with horns! Bye, buddy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa groans as Momo briefly reveals himself under some more grass nearby.
                Scene changes to the Jang Hui River, while Toph, Katara, Aang, and Sokka approach
                the river.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I don't feel anything. Where is the village?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's in the middle of the river! <charAction>Pointing at the
            village.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera pans down to show a man standing on a ferry.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Sure is! My name's Dock. Mind if I ask who you are?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We're um ... from the Earth Kingdom colonies.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Wow ... Colonials. Hop on, I give you ride in the town.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to the river, while Dock paddles the boat
                across.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why do you guys live on the river? <charAction>Looking at the
            village.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns his paddle to the right side, pointing at the Fire Nation
                factory.</charAction> Because we're a fishing town. At least that's how it was
            before the factory moved in. <charAction>Closer shot of the Fire Nation factory and pans
                down.</charAction> Army makes their metal there. Moved in a few years ago and
            started gunking up our river. <charAction>Shot changes back to the ferry. Aang and
                Katara glance sadly at each other.</charAction> Now our little village is struggling
            to survive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans downs to the villagers, showing their conditions of poverty
                and starvation. Team Avatar gets off the ferry boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks for the ride! <charAction>Waves his hand to Dock, who waves
                back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to three villagers sitting on a porch.</charAction> Look at this
            place. <charAction>Cut to two other villagers, an old man and a young boy.</charAction>
            It's so sad. <charAction>Cut back to Katara looking down.</charAction> We have to do
            something to help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, we can't waste our time here. We have a bigger mission that we need to stay
            focused on. These people are on their own.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Chases Sokka and grabs his shoulder.</charAction> These people are
            starving! But you'd turn your back on them? <charAction>Puts her hands on her
                hips.</charAction> How can you be so cold and heartless?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot changes to show their argument from the river as a barrel bobs up
                and down.</charAction> I'm not turning my back, I'm just being realistic. We can't
            go around helping every rinky-dink town we wander into. We'll be helping them all by
            taking out the Fire Lord. <charAction>Aang guides Toph toward the arguing
                siblings.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Covering Sokka's mouth with her hand.</charAction> Hey, loud mouths!
            Maybe we should be a little quieter when we talk about 
                <charAction>Quietly.</charAction> "taking out the Fire Lord."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, Katara, be reasonable about this. You know our mission has to come
            first.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reluctantly.</charAction> I guess so. <charAction>Looks
                annoyed.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Let's just get what we need and go. <charAction>Smiling to Katara, who smiles
                back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an aerial view of the village. The shot changes to show the counter
                of an outdoor market stall. As Team Avatar walks up to it, they notice a man who
                looks like Dock, but wearing a different hat, bowed behind the
                counter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, Dock. You work here too?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not Dock. I'm Xu! Dock's my brother.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar looks confused.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But we just saw you. You're even wearing the same clothes. <charAction>Close-up of
                his hat.</charAction> The only difference is your hat.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera zooms out to Xu talking.</charAction> Dock works on the docks.
            That's why we call him, "Dock", and I work in the shop, that's why they call me,
            "Xu"!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't get it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech>Me neither. <charAction>Jumps down behind the counter and pulls out a crate filled
                with rancid gray seafood.</charAction> What I can getcha? <charAction>Katara, Aang,
                and Sokka look disgusted.</charAction> Hey, I'll give you a special deal. If you buy
            three fish, I'll give you a clam for free. <charAction>Sokka pushes a clam, and mucus
                splashes out from it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara both recoil, muttering in disgust.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Picks up three fish. Carefully.</charAction> We'll just take the fish.
                <charAction>Xu takes the fish.</charAction> Mind telling your brother we need a ride
            back to shore? <charAction>Xu jumps down behind the counter and jumps up wearing Dock's
                hat.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, colonials! My brother says you need a lift. <charAction>Jumps over the counter,
                and walks to the dock.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar follows Dock to the dock. A little boy stops
                Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little boy">Little boy</speaker>
        <speech>Can you spare some food?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Touched.</charAction> I wish I could help more. <charAction>Gives the
                boy a fish, and the boy bows to her and leaves to give the fish to his sick
                mother.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to nighttime, as the camera shows an aerial view of Team Avatar's
                camp. Shot changes to show a barrel of polluted water. Aang lifts the water with
                waterbending and Toph separates the pollutants from the water with earthbending.
                Aang passes the water to Katara, who boils it in a crock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Our detour into town today has completely thrown off our schedule. It's gonna take
            some serious finagling to get us back on track.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Finagle away, oh schedule master.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, for starters, it looks like we'll need to wake up forty-three minutes earlier
            every day.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Forty<description>-three</description> minutes?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing to various spots on his schedule.</charAction> Look, we only
            have a few weeks to get to the Fire Lord in time for the invasion and the eclipse,
            which, by the way, only lasts for eight minutes. And we just lost a whole day. So if we
            want to make up the time and stay on schedule, we have to wake up early!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Well <description>I'm</description> not waking up early.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Or we could just cut out all of our eating breaks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No way!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Forget it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets a sly look on his face.</charAction> I got it, how's this from now
            on, we'll take food breaks and potty breaks at the same time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara, Toph, and Aang express their disgust at this idea with Aang doing a
                spit take.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, it might be gross, but it's efficient. Either way, we have to leave here first
            thing tomorrow morning.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Close-up of Katara's face, who looks distraught at Sokka's words. Cut to an
                aerial view of the village the following morning and cut to the campsite. Appa lies
                on his side, groaning, while Katara ministers to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's the matter Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I think Appa's sick.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Panicking.</charAction> What? Appa's sick? That's awful!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, Sokka, I didn't realize you cared so much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Of course I care. I might as well just throw our schedule away now.
                <charAction>Pulls out his schedule. He stops and looks at the group. Cut to a shot
                of the rest of the gang giving him the evil eye, and he quickly changes his tone,
                rushing solicitously to Appa's side.</charAction> And I'm concerned because my big,
            furry friend doesn't feel well.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>He must have gotten sick from being in the polluted water.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>He doesn't look sick. You okay, buddy? <charAction>Appa groans and Aang pulls out
                Appa's purple tongue.</charAction> His tongue is purple! That can't be good. Katara,
            can you heal him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It looks like he needs some medicine. Maybe we can find the right herbs in
            town.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo arrives and attempts to lick Appa's tongue before being pulled off by
                Aang. Cut to the village, which is bustling and lively. One villager pole vaults
                from one house to another.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Is it just me, or does this place seem different?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, are the people ... happier?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The little boy from the previous day runs by, bouncing a ball, and Katara
                smiles to herself. The kids walk up to Xu/Dock's market.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, Xu, what's going on with everyone today?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Drinks from a ladle.</charAction> Ah, something amazing happened last
            night. Food was delivered to our village by a mysterious and wonderful person ... the
            Painted Lady.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>The Painted who now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech>The Painted Lady. <charAction>He places a miniature statuette of the spirit down on
                the counter.</charAction> She's part of our town's lore. They say she's a river
            spirit who watches over our town in times of need. I always thought she was just a
            legend. Until now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>See, we don't need to help these people, they already have someone to help them. All
            we need is medicine for our sick friend.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech>Medicine? Sorry, all the medicine we have goes to the factory. That's why there's so
            many sick people in our village.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Looks like we need to stay another night so Appa can rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> I guess you're right. You got any more food to
            sell?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Goes under the counter and emerges holding a fish in each
                hand.</charAction> Would you like the one-headed fish, or the two-headed fish?
                <charAction>He turns the fish on the left sideways to show the second
                head.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Ponders.</charAction> Two-headed! <charAction>The rest of the group
                lowers their heads and small sweat drops appear.</charAction> What? You get more for
            your money that way! <charAction>Holds up the polluted fish.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The rest of the group get even bigger exaggerated sweat drops as they
                express their disgust and run away from Sokka who follows behind with the polluted
                fish. </description>
            <description>Fade to the village, late that night. A figure resembling the Painted Lady
                glides over the water on a carpet of fog and enters the village. She steps into a
                hut where several people are sleeping on the floor, and bends over each of them in
                turn, healing them with a blue glow. Her last patient is the mother of the little
                boy seen earlier, her son sleeping at her side. He wakes as the Painted Lady turns
                to go and silently follows her out the door.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little boy">Little boy</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you, Painted Lady.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The lady stops and nods her head before disappearing into the water. Cut to
                the village, the next day. Dock polishes his figurine with a rag as Sokka steps up
                to the counter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hi, Dock. Is Xu around?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock/Xu">Dock/Xu</speaker>
        <speech>Let me check ... <charAction>He runs around the shop and ducks beneath the counter
                to switch hats.</charAction> Hey there! Back again, are ya?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pushes Sokka away.</charAction> We need more food. <charAction>Slams the
                money on the counter.</charAction> Our friend is still sick and we can't leave until
            he's better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Xu obligingly presents them with a platter of polluted clams. The camera
                pans in on the clams. Sokka comically slides in behind them and gives silent chuckle
                along with a comical annoyed symbol on his forehead. It appears he has an idea
                brewing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, well, that's too bad. Maybe if you guys are lucky, the Painted Lady will visit
            you in the night, and heal your friend.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Picks up the clams. Sarcastically.</charAction> And maybe she'll cook us
            a midnight snack, and we'll all have a sing-along.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xu">Xu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Not getting the sarcasm. Sokka looks annoyed now.</charAction> Yeah,
            maybe! You know, last night she visited us again. Healed most of our sick
            folks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Is that why this place seems so festive?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A villagers raises a large statue of the Painted Lady in the town square,
                everyone cheers and applause.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Yep, it's all because of the Painted Lady.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Can you believe how much an entire village can be affected by one lady I mean ...
            spirit?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I hope she returns every night. Otherwise this place would go right back to
            the way it was.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets annoyed.</charAction> Why would you say that? Look how much better
            off these people are.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, now, but without her they wouldn't be able to fend for themselves. If she
            really wanted to help, she would use her spirit magic to blow up that factory.
                <charAction>He makes mocking gestures to indicate explosive spirit magic. He crosses
                his arms with a smile. Katara gets even more annoyed. The screen pans to the right
                to show Aang who has his arms crossed not impressed.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Spirit magic doesn't work that way, Sokka. It's more like ... <charAction>He waves
                his body with arms in the air making similar gestures to indicate spirit magic.
                Katara storms away from the two.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang and Sokka">Aang and Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sokka wraps and arm over Aang's shoulder and the two combined their
                little imitation but far more ridiculous.</charAction> Wooooooooo ...
                <charAction>Sokka chuckles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Katara on the edge of a dock looking out toward the factory. Cut to
                the campsite, that night. Katara slips out of her sleeping bag and stuffs dried
                grass into it to disguise her absence. She dons a makeshift Painted Lady costume,
                wrapping a ragged gown around her. Katara bends the water to make a mirror so she
                can apply the markings. She puts on a wide conical hat similar to the Painted
                Lady's, but with a diaphanous white veil covering her face. She glides away toward
                the village, but not quietly enough; she wakes Momo, and he wakes Aang by jumping on
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's the matter, buddy? <charAction>Katara leaves Team Avatar.</charAction> It's
            her! <charAction>Excited, waves his hand to Katara and puts on his
                headband.</charAction> Hello, Painted Lady Spirit!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara shocked, quickly flees from Aang. Meanwhile, Aang uses his
                airbending to accelerate his run. The camera moves to a hill as Katara climbs up and
                continues on as Aang easily keeps up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Jumps up the hill.</charAction> Excuse me, I don't mean to bother you,
            but my friend's sick and we're on kind of a tight schedule. <charAction>Continues to
                follow her down the hill as she crosses the river.</charAction> Wait! But I'm a
            great bridge between your world and mine! <charAction>Aang freezes some water to form
                stepping stones to cross the river.</charAction> I know Hei Bai! We're close
            personal friends! <charAction>Katara moves faster, and Aang jumps on a wooden bridge.
                Katara runs out of the river onto the docks and notices Aang's reflection in the
                water. She looks up and sees Aang running across a roof.</charAction> Heeey!
                <charAction>He suddenly hits a pole, Katara flinches and feels sorry for him but
                continues on across the river to the other side. She stops to look out at the
                village thinking she is safe but Aang drops in front of her.</charAction> My name's
            Aang. I'm the Avatar. <charAction>Lifts his headband and points at his
                arrow.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Using a disguised voice.</charAction> Well, hello Avatar. I wish I could
            talk, but I am very busy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, me too. I hate that. <charAction>Looks at Katara's face from behind the
                veil.</charAction> You know, you're really pretty, for a spirit. I don't meet too
            many spirits, but the ones I do meet, not very attractive. <charAction>Looks at Katara
                suspiciously. Tries to look under the hat.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Giggles nervously.</charAction> Thank you, but-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You seem familiar too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>A lot of people say that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Suspicious.</charAction> No, you really seem familiar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Look, I really should get going. <charAction>Covers her face and runs, but Aang uses
                his airbending and blasts her hat up into the air, exposing
            her.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Guiltily.</charAction> Hi, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You're the Painted Lady? <charAction>Pointing at
                Katara.</charAction> But how?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I wasn't her at first, I was just trying to help the village. <charAction>Takes her
                hat off.</charAction> But since everyone thought that's who I was anyway, I guess I
            just kinda became her. <charAction>Drops her hat on the ground.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So you've been sneaking out at night? Wait, is Appa even sick?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He might be sick of the purple berries I've been feeding him, but other than that
            he's fine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe you lied to everyone, so you could help these people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry, I know I shouldn't have ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> No, I think it's great! You're like a secret
            hero!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, if you wanna help, there's one more thing I have to do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang gives her a curious look. Cut to the Fire Nation factory. Aang and
                Katara run along the river's edge toward it. Aang looks at the polluted
                water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You wanna destroy this factory?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Yes. Sokka was just kidding, but he was right. Getting rid of this factory is the
            only way to help these people permanently.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara enter and move to different sides of the factory. Katara
                uses waterbending to cut the metal hooks that hang barrels of a magma. Aang, with
                protective gloves on, overturns bigger hanging barrels, smiling at his work. Aang
                uses earthbending to break apart the pipe system in the factory. Katara bends a huge
                wave of water through the windows and floods the factory. The scene cuts to outside
                as the factory explodes from within and muck stops flowing from the pipes. Cut to
                Aang and Katara walking back to their campsite. Aang laughs and makes explosion
                noises.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Shhh! <charAction>Quietly.</charAction> We don't wanna wake Sokka. <charAction>She
                turns and sees that Sokka and Toph are awake.</charAction> Hi, Sokka, we were just
            out on a morning walk!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily and disappointed.</charAction> Oh, really? A morning walk?
                <charAction>Dumps the hay out of Katara's sleeping bag.</charAction> I know you're
            the Painted Lady, I know you've been sneaking out at night, and I know you've been lying
            about Appa and been feeding him <charAction>Sticks out his own tongue.</charAction>
            purpleising tongue berries! <charAction>Toph sticks out her tongue and shows that it is
                purple and holds up a bag of berries which Momo starts eating.</charAction> Katara,
            what you did put our whole mission in jeopardy. We're leaving right now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara walks past Sokka sadly. Sokka confronts Aang as he
                follows.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And how long did you know about this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Defensively.</charAction> Hey, I just found out this morning!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang sprints away with airbending. The scene changes to the Fire Nation
                factory where a man can be seen coming out of the smoke and looking angrily toward
                the town. Cut to Team Avatar packing, but they pause when they hear buzzing. The
                factory workers are shown headed for the town on jet skis. Cut to the gang on a
                cliff looking down at the river below.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching and kneeling down with the others.</charAction> What's going
            on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Fire Nation soldiers are heading toward the village!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Katara.</charAction> What did you do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I kind of destroyed their factory.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Defensively.</charAction> It was your idea!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I was joking! I also said to use spirit magic and made funny noises!
                <charAction>Slaps his forehead.</charAction> Did you even think this through? The
            army is gonna blame the villagers! They're headed there right now to get
            revenge!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, what was I supposed to do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Leave! Do nothing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> No, I will never, ever turn my back on people who
            need me! <charAction>Gets up.</charAction> I'm going down to that village, and I am
            gonna do whatever I can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Katara walks away, Sokka stops her by putting his hand on her
                shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! I'm coming, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I thought you didn't want to help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You need me, and I will never turn my back on you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, you really do have a heart. <charAction>The two hug.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wiping away tears.</charAction> He really does have a heart, doesn't
            he?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang turns to Toph for confirmation. Toph, however, elbows him and he falls
                off camera with a thump. Cut to the Fire Nation soldiers on jet skis. Cut to Team
                Avatar looking at the village. Cut to Mung and his soldiers standing on the
                dock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mung">Mung</speaker>
        <speech>I thought we could live as neighbors, in peace. But I guess I was wrong. You steal
            our food, our medicine ... and then you destroy our factory.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock/Xu">Dock/Xu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pops out of the crowd wearing Dock hat.</charAction> We didn't do any of
            that. <charAction>Pops out in a different place wearing his Xu hat.</charAction> Yeah,
            the Painted Lady brought us food. She's the one that healed our sick, not your
            medicine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mung">Mung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holding a statuette.</charAction> Oh, right, the mysterious Painted Lady
            did it. And I suppose she drew the army emblem on your containers, too.
                <charAction>Throws the statuette at the container, smashing it. The crowd
                gasps.</charAction> This is a town of thieves and liars! <charAction>Firebends a
                blast at a house. Mockingly.</charAction> Where's your Painted Lady now? We're going
            to cure the world of this wretched village.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The soldiers begin demolishing the town. A jet ski, with two soldiers, goes
                past a dock as a soldier sends a hook and chain toward it. The chain wraps around a
                log holding up a house and it breaks as the jet ski drives away. The house crumbles
                into the water. Cut to two soldiers who light a large flammable ball perched on a
                buoy in the river, but a mysterious gust of wind blows out the fire,
                twice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mung">Mung</speaker>
        <speech>Light it again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They follow Mung's command, and it is blown out again. Eerie flute music
                begins floating over the water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female Fire Nation soldier">Female Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>Look at that! Where's it coming from?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a heavy fog rapidly pouring in.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male Fire Nation soldier">Male Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know. Something strange is going on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>An ominous growling noise echoes over the river.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little boy">Little boy</speaker>
        <speech>It's the Painted Lady. <charAction>Grins slyly. Ominous tone.</charAction> She's
            coming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mung">Mung</speaker>
        <speech>There is no Painted Lady!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A repetitive thudding noise, as of giant footsteps, has begun. Pan over the
                river to the further bank where we see that the thudding is caused by Toph elevating
                and dropping a large boulder, while Appa provides the growling. Sokka mans the
                flute, producing eerie noises.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female Fire Nation soldier">Female Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>What is that sound?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male Fire Nation soldier">Male Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe it is her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The fog parts dramatically to reveal Katara in full Painted Lady regalia.
                She pauses a moment and rushes toward the soldiers with a burst of waterbending. She
                alights on the dock and slowly approaches them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mung">Mung</speaker>
        <speech>Do something! <charAction>Pushes his soldiers forward. As they timidly draw near,
                they are rattled by a blast of airbending. Aang is shown hiding beneath the dock.
                The two soldiers run off. To the remaining soldiers.</charAction> Stand your ground!
                <charAction>Katara waterbends two jet skis into a nearby cliff. As she raises her
                hand to wreak further damage, the soldiers jump into the remaining jet skis and
                speed off, leaving Mung.</charAction> I'll take care of you myself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He bends an arc of fire at Katara, we see it advance toward her in slow
                motion. Aang, still concealed beneath the dock, sends Katara flying into the sky on
                a column of air; the flame passes harmlessly beneath her. Aang rends the dock in two
                with a blast of wind, sending Mung flying into the river. As he flounders, Katara
                rises out of the polluted water before him and raises her arms
                threateningly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Leave this village and never come back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He swims desperately away from her. A stray jet ski passes by and he
                clambers into it; the ski buzzes off. Sokka and Toph row toward the village as the
                people applaud Katara as she returns to the dock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little boy">Little boy</speaker>
        <speech>I knew you'd come.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager #1">Villager #1</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager #2">Villager #2</speaker>
        <speech>Painted Lady, you're the best!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Me and my brothers really owe you a lot. <charAction>Looking at her and her faded
                Painted Lady marks.</charAction> Hey, wait a minute! I know you! You're not the
            Painted Lady, you're that colonial girl!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara places a hand on her face and realizes her make-up is
                smudged.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little boy">Little boy</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, you're the lady that gave me a fish.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You've been tricking us. You're a
            waterbender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager #3">Villager #3</speaker>
        <speech>She's a waterbender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager #4">Villager #4</speaker>
        <speech>How dare you act like our Painted Lady!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The crowd surges forward in anger. Sokka runs forward to
                intervene.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe she is a waterbender, but she was just trying to help you. Because of her,
            that factory won't be polluting your river, and the army is gone. You should be down on
            your knees thanking her!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, it's okay. <charAction>She steps forward and moves Sokka back. To the
                villagers.</charAction> I shouldn't have acted like someone I wasn't, and I
            shouldn't have tricked you. But I felt like I had to do something. It doesn't matter if
            the Painted Lady is real or not. Because your problems are real, and this river is real.
            You can't wait around for someone to help you. You have to help yourself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>She's right, but what should we do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pops out from behind the little boy's mother and uses a lower
                voice.</charAction> Maybe we can clean the river!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, we can clean the river! <charAction>The crowd cheers.</charAction> Thank you.
            You know, you're not so bad for a waterbender.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You wouldn't mind keeping that a secret, by the way, would you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>No problem. Keeping my mouth shut is a personal specialty. My brother Xu, on the
            other hand, ohh, he's a blabbermouth. <charAction>Sokka facepalms.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So, Dock, are you gonna help us clean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>No, ma'am. I'm going to get my other brother, Bushi. He loves cleaning rivers.
                <charAction>Dock brazenly switches hats right in front of them.</charAction> All
            right, I'm Bushi! Let's get some river cleaning done!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Aha, I knew it! I knew you were the same guy. You're the shop owner and the boat
            guy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, you must be talking about my brothers, Dock and Xu.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> No, I just saw you! You switched hats and called
            yourself a different name!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Dock">Dock</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Oh, you know who does that? My brother, Dock.
                <charAction>Conspiratorial whisper.</charAction> He's crazy. <charAction>Goes off
                chuckling.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang fumes in annoyance. Cut to an aerial view of the village with boats in
                the surrounding river. The shot changes to the boats on the river as the villagers
                spread clean out the pollutants. Katara bends the water into a large vat while Aang
                and Toph separate the pollutants using earthbending and putting it in a large boat.
                Cut to an aerial view of the village as the day passes by and the river becomes
                cleaner. Cut to Team Avatar's campsite at night. Katara sits on an overlook of the
                river when suddenly clouds of fog appear and the real Painted Lady
                emerges.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Painted Lady">Painted Lady</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you. <charAction>Slowly disappears.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara is first shocked, but she smiles. Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
