[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Bryan Konietzko, co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>This is Mike DiMartino, the other co-creator.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa Garagarza
</th>
<td>And this is Elsa Garagarza, I am the background/layout supervisor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Hi Elsa, thanks for coming.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Thank you for inviting me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>You're like the background design supervisor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>The background design supervisor, yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, which means when we have a script, um, a new script, we sit down and talk about on id-ideas about like the locations, and um, since <i>Avatar</i> is sort of like a travel show, we don't have a lot of reused locations, so every episode we have to draw all new designs for the... the backgrounds are the-like the places, the insides are the buildings, and fields, campsites, whatever. So, uh, Elsa heads up, um, a couple great artists. Uh, do you want to tell them about the artists you work with?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Yeah... yeah, I have two wonderful people that I work with, excellent professionals. They are Jevon Bue and Enzo Baldi, they have been helping me out since season two, since the end of season one-no season two. And uh, we have been-they've been doing a fantastic job, uh, we have been doing all these wonderful designs for all these locations, as-that Bryan has said, and sometimes even if we're re-revised new locations, we add up to... to all these new places that we go to and revisit. It's always interesting 'cause we-there's always sometimes even if you revisit, there all these new extra little places that we, uh, redesign, and yeah. It's all so full of surprises.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we sometimes take an opportunity to improve upon a, uh, past design if we do see it again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And this, uh, this episode was especially challenging, and this whole location Ba-of Ba Sing Se, because we knew we were going to spend multiple episodes at this place, and it had to really feel like a real, real city, and which is, I think when you see it, that's what comes across to me, is like how real this place feels, like all the different, you know, rings where they go in, the Lower, Middle, and Upper Rings and, and all the great houses and landscapes and everything, so, great job Elsa on all the awesome background designs.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Well...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the man who sits in between Sokka and Toph on the train.</i>] By-by the way, the guy with the corn was a little tribute to uh... <i>Invader Zim</i>, and if you know the episode, then you get a cookie. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Well, it was pretty interesting beginning with Ba Sing Se, um, I was dreading it a lot for a longest time, I knew it was going to be a lot of work, and it was a lot of design involved, but I think it was a fantastic experience.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the train station Team Avatar arrives at.</i>] This was fun to do things like subway cars and train stations that didn't feel too contemporary or, um, or even futuristic, um... you know, its-its, I like-I like the inclusion of like the rooftops on the subway cars, like their little buildings, and even the inside, I mean it feels like a New York subway, and it's-it's familiar, but obviously the ancient <i>Avatar</i> version.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Here...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to Joo Dee.</i>] And this character's... [<i>Laughs.</i>] were you going to say that?  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, I was gonna say, uh, we, we-sometimes we model characters after people we know, and uh, Joo Dee is based on our production manager, er-uh, Miken Wong.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I think she's our line producer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Er, I mean our line producer, sorry Miken.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And Mike and I have been working with Miken for a long time. She was my first producer in LA. So, she's always happy. Happy, happy, happy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And we're like Sokka, going, "No, but, but you didn't hear what we had to say," [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] and she's like, "No, it's okay, don't worry,".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And we're like, "But we-we can't finish the episode on that day," [<i>Elsa laughs.</i>] so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the establishing shot of the Lower Ring.</i>] So, this is the Lower Ring, as Joo Dee just said.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And uh, the color supervisor Hye-Jung Kim and I talked about how we could, you know, Elsa... distinguished the different rings architecturally, and then uh, Hye-Jung and I decided, you know, we'd have a different color rooftop scheme and like building scheme for each. So, the-the Lower Ring was um, a lot grittier, a lot more monochromatic, not very you know, not very colorful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>It was a lot of fun to design the Lower Ring, because it had a lot of flavor of, uh, we were uh, inspired by many towns in-in China, uh, Yangtze and uh, the one that's specially, uh... Yangtze province, the um, the central part of it was a big inspiration for all these marketplace areas, and it was very colorful and nice, and [<i>Refers to the extreme longshot of the marketplace road Zuko and Iroh are walking on.</i>] we-especially this background particularly, that's what we wanted to capture, the flavor. 'Cause it's, it is a, a low, rundown place, but it's also has so-has some charm to identify it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we wanted the, in the Lower Ring, since it's uh, where they keep the refugees an-and the-the poorer working class people, they wanted to have less trees, like it's overpopulated, and you know, the rich people, as you go up in the rings, less buildings, more trees, more parks and rivers, and um, so they sort of force all these lower class people to live on top of each other and the streets are... kind of organically windy and you know, just... just haphazard and as we go up into these districts you start to see more organization, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So uh, Tim Hedrick who's supposed to be here today, he's the writer of this episode. Unfortunately, he's not here, but uh, he and the other writers and-and Aaron, our head writer, did a great job kind of establishing this new city, you know, we-we knew we were gonna go to Ba Sing Se, we knew this was going to be a big location in season two, but we hadn't worked out all the political, you know, intrigue and everything that ends up going on in Ba Sing Se, so they-they played a, a big part in-in shaping that, and kind of coming up with this, you know, <i>1984</i> sort of utopian, seemingly utopian society that turns out to be a little, little creepy under the surface.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we knew, Mike and I, early on knew... that, it-there was always going to be something wrong with this city, you-you'd think that, oh, they're the good guys, they're on their side in the war, and they'll definitely help them. We knew we wanted it to be that when the-the kids showed up that somehow or another, they would end up being enemies of this place, um. So often the case in the real world, there's just a lot of shades of grey, and, and uh, everything's not so cut and dry. [<i>Refers to the Upper Ring.</i>] So, here you can see in-in the Upper Ring it's just beautiful, idyllic, it's like pastures and parks, and... [<i>Refers to the palace gate the Dai Li are standing under.</i>] this is based on the uh, the South Gate to uh, the Forbidden City in uh, Beijing where Mike and I got to go... uh, I think a year, year and a half ago.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, we even based, I think the doors on that were, there's only like certain doors that the emperor can go through, and the aside doors are where everyone else has to go through, so later on in the party, I think we have the, the uh, the guests of the party they're entering cer-through a certain, uh, side door, not the main one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar's house in the Upper Ring.</i>] This was a really important location, um, 'cause it's, it's where the kids would be living for several episodes, which was very weird, it's very unlike <i>Avatar</i> to have like a apartment, you know, that we keep coming back to. It's almost like a sitcom.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Even if we revisited it, we visited different rooms of that same place, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Joo Dee describing the house as nice.</i>] It is pretty nice. I wouldn't mind...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... I wouldn't mind something like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Me neither. [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, after them, you know, camping out for two seasons, it's kinda cool that they get to [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] settle down and hang out in a place.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>But it was fun to, when we were doing the storyboards inside this location, you know, these-these are sort of worldly, earthy kids who don't have parents or teachers around, so it was fun to like come up with staging ideas where they're just, Aang's laying on the bannister and Sokka's has his feet on the painting, and stuff like that, like... [<i>Refers to the cat owl.</i>] There's that weird cat owl, [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] you know. I think that's voiced by my neighbor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Is it... Jason Miller?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I'm not sure, you might be right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I-I think [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] that was Jason Miller. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] Hi Jason!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Uh, also, I-mention Lauren MacMullan, who directed this episode, um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Fantastic job.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah, great job with the, making-again, making this place feel like a real place. I mean a lot of the shots in this, cinematography of the whole location really came out beautifully.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And Chris Graham, uh, was one of the board artists, did a really great job on a lot of these shots. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] So, the other two board artists on this episode were, uh, Kenji Ono and Dean Kelly, both, uh, classmates of mine at the Rhode Island School of Design.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A pause in the commentary occurs until Katara asks the team's new neighbor, Pong, who he would get in trouble with for talking to them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So this guy, Pong... [<i>Laughs.</i>] as their wacky neighbor was, we had kinda wrote him into some subsequent episodes, but he ended up-kept, he kept getting cut out, [<i>Laughs.</i>] 'cause he was just kind of like extra weight that we didn't end up needing. But he became kind of an inside joke with the-all the writers, Pong their wacky old neighbor. [<i>Refers to Jet spying on Iroh and Zuko in their apartment.</i>] So, this little subplot with uh, Zuko and Jet is definitely one of my favorites of-of, this is a continuation kind of from the uh, previous two episodes where Jet met Zuko, and-and Zuko didn't want to be in his gang, and Jet's taking that very personally at this point, and-and trying to prove that Zuko is in fact a firebender.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Jet's one of those guys who, you know, he was around in our place in time would always be into conspiracy theories and, you know, everyone's against him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, and he was a good character to kind of, uh, play into this whole, um, utopian/dystopian plot, and have him be the one who, you know, got-got captured and got brainwashed and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Kind of the rock star rebel. [<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Bryan; refers to the team discussing what kind of bear the Earth Kingdom has.</i>] So, this little joke here about, our little inside joke about... ordinary animals, 'cause all the animals in <i>Avatar</i> are hybrids obviously and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Momo poking out from underneath the fallen curtain while the rest of the team is talking.</i>] I never noticed Momo is already hanging out under the curtain there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; in a mock serious tone.</i>] Yeah, he's right there...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Isn't that him?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... in a moment he will pop up, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] at-as Lord Momo of the Momo dynasty.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph flicking her booger at the ceiling offscreen.</i>] So, here's this, the little booger joke, I'm pretty proud of this. [<i>Mike and Elsa laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Toph burps in response to Katara critiquing her manners.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That burp. Was that-did Jessie do that burb?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think she did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Jessie's the voice of, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] Jessie Flower's the voice of Toph. Okay, here it comes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah, here it is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the booger on the ceiling, and Toph's outstretched finger pointing toward it.</i>] Point, then he... I don't know if you noticed, but it's hanging on the ceiling right above Sokka's head, throughout the rest of this scene.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Waiting to fall.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah, she shot it in his general direction, but it, it planted on the ceiling. [<i>Refers to Momo poking his head out of the curtain.</i>] See, wow, see Mo-that was a nice hookup.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Good job Lauren, or Kenji, or... [<i>Refers to Aang and Sokka exaggerated bowing to one another.</i>] I think Kenji did this crazy bowing stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the various paintings on the apartment walls.</i>] Hey Bryan, maybe, do you want to talk about like the uh, paintings that you see in the show, 'cause a lot of people always comment like, oh that screen or that painting in the background is really cool, was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the booger falling from the ceiling onto Sokka's head.</i>] Mmm, there's the booger. [Mike and Elsa laugh.] Um, I don't want to talk about...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background; laughs.</i>] Alright.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... those paintings, because um... I just don't. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Alright, well they're very nice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Thanks. Sometimes, sometimes they're from uh, uh, Oh Seung-Hyun, one of our-our supervising director. He's from Korea, and he has this amazing collection of beautiful paintings, uh, originals that he owns, and sometimes we put those in the show. [<i>Refers to Momo walking past Aang and Sokka, the curtain he was previously under now wrapped around him like a cape.</i>] Ah, I love this joke.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Momo, Super Momo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to the crescendo in the theme as Jet is distracted by Smellerbee and Longshot.</i>] I like that, the music that, uh, Jeremy and Ben did, the Track Team, that moment was really cool for Jet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, Jeremy, like master of many instruments, pulled out the cello and did these like extended techniques for all that kind of 1970s psychological thriller score stuff for Jet. Just something wrong with Jet, something deep in his brain, that-that theme of his, we flex that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Those-those musical themes make my hair stand on point. [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] Ver-very successful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Um, Elsa do you find Jet handsome?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Absolutely, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] absolutely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He divides people.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's-there's two types of women, the ones who [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] think Jet is very handsome, and the ones who think, you know, he's no good...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Oh please.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>]... he's trouble, they can see right through him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Mike...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>They're lying.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... that's a little bit of a generalization, there might be a third type [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] of woman who really doesn't care.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Doesn't care? Al-alright, maybe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to Jet confronting Zuko and Iroh.</i>] So, I, I love this uh, this showdown between Zuko and Jet, some of my favorite animation in the series.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] And uh, it was Dean Kelly who boarded this, uh, action scene I believe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Bryan.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Elsa.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Did a great job. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] But this-what I like about Jet's story is like, he's going crazy but he is actually telling the truth, [<i>Laughs.</i>] so you kind of feel bad for him, 'cause, you know, he-Zuko is a firebender, he's not totally crazy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the sequence where Jet and Zuko duel each other in the tea shop, using the tables and chairs as weapons and footing.</i>] So some of the choreography here was... the fight choreography, we were inspired by just the classic uh, Hong Kong kung fu movies where they really make use of like props and things that are, you know, in the room, and jumping up on the table, and then maybe someone cuts that in half, and then you have to balance on it, you know. Just trying to um... trying to like use the environment for, to-to make the fight unique. [<i>Refers to the clothing worn by the party attendees.</i>] Uh, love to mention, uh, Angela Mueller, who did, uh, character design on this episode, I-all of these, um, costumes, these fancy costumes are just amazing, I think they came out really great. [<i>Refers to Long Feng.</i>] This is Long Feng, voiced by Clancy Brown. He's a fantastic actor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, Long Feng ended up being a really cool villain for season two, I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's just his voice acting, it just brings such a [<i>In a deep, throaty voice.</i>] gravitas to the series.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Elsa laughs as Katara and Toph enter the party with Long Feng, sticking their tongues out at the guard who refused to let them in. The scene then cuts to a high angle view of the party inside the Earth King's palace, colored lanterns hanging down from the ceiling, and the nobility mill about on the ground.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like that, those drawings are good.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Bosco.</i>] Oh, and this is the first time we see Bosco, the king's bear who, again, this kind of just ended up being a little joke in the script, but we loved it so much that we kept putting Bosco in all the subsequent shows and we see him later with-with the king and stuff, so. It's just nice that the king has a, you know, a little pet to keep him company.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's sort of... it-it's a good character, uh, building thing for the king. He's, he's a good guy, but he's just sort of innocent, naïve, so it made sense that he just had a big... kind of dumb pet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>And who wouldn't want a bear?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Exactly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, do you-what do you like to design more, Elsa? Like interior and building stuff, or like, more organic campsites and landscapes and stuff like that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>I like to design downtowns, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] uh, uh, Lower, uh-like the Lower Ring-like the Lower Ring for me was fantastic to design. It was, uh, very interesting, I like nuances and flavors, and it-but I do like exteriors more than interiors. Landscapes are fine though, but sometimes [<i>Bryan gives affirming murmurs intermittently.</i>] even they're harder to pull through... to make 'em real, them real. [<i>Refers to the street outside the teashop, set during nighttime.</i>] This area here was beautiful, this teashop area was, to me, was lovely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Then I think, uh, the nighttime BGs by um, Bryan Evans and Hye-Jung Kim really came out cool. This is some of my favorite color in the whole season.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the slow motion shot of Zuko slicing the straw in Jet's mouth.</i>] That's my favorite moment when Zuko cuts Jet's straw, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] it's just so symbolic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to the sequence of Aang and Sokka sneaking around the party.</i>] Yeah, Lauren MacMullan did a great on this, she boarded this section.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Momo's tail poking out out from behind Aang's hat.</i>] And notice Momo's little tail squirming around.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The idea is sort of that, it looks a bit like the uh, queue hairstyle that the Ba Sing Se people have.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the party attendees.</i>] Look at all those costumes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, they're amazing. JM Animation did a great job drawing all those costumes, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] it-it was a lot to ask of them, but they, they did it, gre-great job. [<i>Refers to Toph and Katara's high society apparel.</i>] So, I think uh, Katara and Toph's makeup was a lot more successful in this episode than in, [<i>Laughs.</i>] 215. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I guess the joke in 215 was that... it was very garish.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, they got the extra treatment [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] on that one. This was, yeah, this was their own subtle makeup.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the embarrassed expression on Aang and the awed expression on the noble Aang just airbent.</i>] I really love how Lauren's style came through in all these expressions, sort of mixed with JM's animation style.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Nice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Really funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, this is like this society party where everyone's all impressed 'cause the Avatar's shown up, but... [<i>Refers to Momo scurrying underneath and into Aang's discarded hat.</i>] I like Momo running, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] running out there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the theme that plays as Aang entertains the party.</i>] Nice goofy Aang music by Jeremy Zuckerman.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Bosco starts getting excited at Aang waterbending different colors of tea, to which Bryan laughs.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>And he's entertained.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko and Jet dueling while they're back-to-back with one another.</i>] So, Sifu Kisu and I did this choreography out in the uh, courtyard of Nickelodeon. Someone was running around us as we were swordfighting, it was pretty crazy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Anybody get hurt?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I usually get hurt [<i>Elsa and Mike laugh.</i>] in those situations.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>A lot of those are pretty-[<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] with all the swords and everything?  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Don't try that at home kids. [<i>Brief pause; refers to Iroh blushing at being called the finest teamaker in the city.</i>] I love that Uncle blushes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, this really kind of really starts the, the whole Uncle subplot of uh, starting-you know, working at a teashop, and then he eventually ends up getting his own teashop, so. It was cool to give them jobs kind of, and have them...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Again...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... employed. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... very un-<i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Dai Li binding Jet with their rock gloves.</i>] It's also the first time we see the Dai Li's, uh, rock gloves, which was uh... the idea was earthbending, up to this point, has been very big and brutal and, you know, noisy and we wanted these guys to be a lot sneakier, and um, have a more delicate, stealth-stealthy kind of earthbending, so I came up with this idea that they have little rock tiles that sort of magnetize to their hands, and then they can shoot them off and still control them, so they can seize people and turn them into handcuffs and stuff. So, they just sort of, it's almost like clay, they ju-I mean, the-the rocks are hard, but they fuse them together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Momo trying to flee from the Dai Li while still under the hat.</i>] Oh Momo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] He really thought he was gonna get away with that. [<i>Mike affirms; refers to Long Feng saying he'll meet Team Avatar in the library.</i>] I think the library is one of my favorite, uh, background designs from this episode. You want to talk about your influence on that, Elsa?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Oh, well actually this background was done by Jevon. He did a fantastic job with it, and we were really working on that fireplace, 'cause it was an important focal point, and look at all the drama that, um, all-a great focal point. So, uh, he did a fantastic job. He's great with libraries.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, that's so true, we had the, he and Enzo did the crazy spirit library in...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Absolutely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... 210. [<i>Refers to the fireplace emanating green light on the room and the characters.</i>] So, the idea here, if you're wondering about this fire, um, generally for Earth Kingdom locations, uh, for light sources we don't use torches or lamps, anything with fire. We tend to use these phosphorescent crystals, um, but for the dramatic lighting and, I don't know, the sort of ominous presence of a fire, we thought it'd be-be cool to have a fire, so I thought, well hey, maybe there's some sort of weird rare crystal that's actually flammable, and um, kind of like, you know, one of those artificial logs that lasts longer, [<i>Laughs.</i>] you know, so?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yep, makes sense to me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, then we just made them, the fire green, which is a more Earth Nation, Ear-Earth Kingdom color, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of Long Feng's speech, interspersed with Jet's brainwashing.</i>] So, I love this, just this whole sequence at the end where it crosscuts between Long Feng describing the-what's going on in the city, and seeing Jet, you know, being-starting the brainwashing process. I think it just-it was very effective of setting up how kind of two-sided this city is, like the, the utopian side and then the very creepy, underground, mysterious side of the city.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Very dramatic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to Toph closing her eyes in response to Long Feng's words.</i>] I love Toph's expression there. This is so painful to her. [<i>Brief pause; refers to Long Feng threatening Aang's search for Appa.</i>] So, there's, a little hint there, a little foreshadowing. [<i>Refers to the new Joo Dee.</i>] That's not...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; in mock realization.</i>] That's not Joo Dee! That's not Joo Dee at all.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Oh Mike, we've been spending too much time together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I know, I know. Alright, great creepy ending to a fabulous episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Thanks Tim, thanks Aaron, thanks Lauren.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Thanks Elsa, for designing and-Ba Sing Se.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Su... supervising.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>A lot of work.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] With all your folks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Thank you. No, a lot of work, but it-great work. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, you guys did a great-I, I was dreading it myself, but then uh... you guys knocked it out of the park, it looked great, and um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Thank you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Dreading it because it was going to be a lot of work, but it was certainly worth...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Very, very worth it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>... all the experiences. Thank you very much.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] And it was worth it too, 'cause we, we ended up spending, you know, the rest of the season there, so it was, it was great that it-that it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... came out as good as it did, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Awesome. Thanks guys!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Elsa
</th>
<td>Awesome.  
</td></tr></tbody></table>]