<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Bryan Konietzko, co-creator, co-executive producer, and art director of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim Hedrick
</th>
<td>Hi, I'm Tim Hedrick, I'm a writer on <i>Avatar</i>, I wrote this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>And this is Mike DiMartino, I'm uh, the other co-creator and executive producer of <i>Avatar</i>. And uh, so, Tim is here joining us today. Tim has written uh, such classics eps-uh, <i>Avatar</i> episodes such as "The Deserter".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Mmhmm, that was a classic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh... yes. [<i>Tim laughs.</i>] "The Swamp".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Another one, another-all the hits.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh, I believe, uh, the first-for the first episode where we were-arrived in Ba Sing Se.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>That's right, after the 214.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Um... yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>And then this, this gem.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Kind of which actually is linked to 214, and the conspiracy theory.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's kind of the end of that storyline. And we see more of the lovely Jet, in this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes. I feel like you can never get enough of Jet. [<i>Tim laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Until you do, [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] and then, then he's, and then he's all done.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Tim.</i>] Yeah. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, so, this is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background; refers to the Dai Li arresting Jet.</i>] Cripes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... kind of a-an important episode to wr-uh, kind of wrap up the, the whole Jet storyline that we uh, you know, kind of started in season one, and continued in Ba Sing Se in season two.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>And we see more of the Dai Li. I don't know if you guys hit on this, but the Dai Li were named after the secret police of Chiang Kai-shek. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] So, and they are the secret police of Ba Sing Se, so that... history of oppression lives on, and-and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the low-detail drawings of Appa.</i>] Oh, here's a-here's good, these drawings of Appa right there, done by another writer, John O'Bryan.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>My office mate.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes. So, John became the official uh, artist of Sokka's style.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>I've been encouraging him to sell those at Comic-Con. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I don't know if he's going to do it or not...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I think people would totally be into that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>I-I know I would bid on 'em.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the detailed drawing of Appa.</i>] I did the uh, the other Appa poster.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Tim laugh.</i>] You mean the one that is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] The one that looks like Appa [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]?  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. Although I did not write the Chinese, that was S. L. Lee. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] I-what's amazing is that John was able to tap into like seven different children's styles.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, he does.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Where he...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>They all... it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] They're all like accurately, authentically a child's drawing that like seven different children worked on...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>It's exa-that's exactly what it's like sharing an office with John, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] is like with seven different children.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] So, this was also, you know, we needed an episode where finally, uh, Zuko finds out that uh, Aang is in the city, and he's close. He's-he's been trying to have this normal life, trying to accept, uh, you know, settling down in Ba Sing Se, and then uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Although he's pretty conflicted about it, and this sort of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... this sort of... spurns him to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, this-I, this begins the Zuko becoming a happy teamaker arc, that ends tragically for him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yes... yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh quitting his job to get his own teashop; laughs.</i>] And it gives you an inside look on the tea business, which I think is important for kids to know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Franchise.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, have you talked about <i>Avatar</i> franchising like this?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Opening some teashops maybe?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Mike and I are, you know, we're looking into it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Starbucks can't handle it all.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh handing his now former boss, Pao, the teapot, and the latter's distraught reaction.</i>] I always figured... was Pao reacting to the hot teapot that he just dropped in his hand?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh... I think it's a combination of he burned his hands and he was just upset that Iroh got taken away from him. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Not until this moment, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] Iroh-Iroh's a pretty considerate guy, but that was a pretty...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Tim laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... in-inconsiderate way to [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] hand a teapot to someone.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, I wanna say, uh, this episode was directed by Lauren MacMullan, uh, another great, uh, director on our team of <i>Avatar</i> folks. And uh, animation directed by uh, director Kim of uh, MOI Animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Kim Sang-Jin.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Zuko staring out at the Lower Ring housing.</i>] Yeah, this was great, it was really exciting to see the Ba Sing Se designs come to life, 'cause it's an awesome looking city.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, it definitely feels like a real place.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The-the concept of the, the rings really worked out well with like a different architectural style, and sort of a different level of, like a class system, you know, realized in architecture. [<i>Refers to Joo Dee.</i>] And that's based on Miken Wong, our, uh, production manager.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Who is just as smiley.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Line-wait, line producer? Line producer, I'm sorry. Sorry Miken. [<i>Tim chuckles.</i>] Yes, we based uh, Miken is always happy, even when she's telling you, uh, the show's in trouble, or... [<i>Tim laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>You're behind schedule.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... behind schedule. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Deliver any bad news with a smile. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We love Miken. [<i>Tim chuckles.</i>] Miken-Mike and I worked with Miken... s-uh, starting like eight or-well for me, about eight years ago, Mike about ten years ago. [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] We've been working together on various shows around town. And she's still happy somehow. [<i>Tim laughs.</i>] So, we had her do some acting reference in the video... footage.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Gives an affirming murmur; refers to Aang's physically exaggerated reaction to Joo Dee trying to stop the team's search for Appa.</i>] I love this moment too where Aang freaks out. I think...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Kenji.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... [<i>Simultaneously with Bryan.</i>] Kenji, uh, Kenji Ono, our storyboard artists did some great drawings in the storyboard and... the animators took that and ran with it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph celebrating the team's flaunting of the rules by blowing open part of the house with her bending.</i>] I think this moment just came out of the [<i>Tim laughs.</i>] storyboard meeting that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, that's a really great addition.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the long shot of Team Avatar exiting the house.</i>] What's funny is they-they blew a whole in the building, but they use the door still. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] We just had this idea that they-I think in the script, she broke a pot, or just like a vase, but we were like, let's just have her blow half the house apart. And then when you see it in the subsequent episode, there's like scaffolding, [<i>Laughs.</i>] they're trying to fix it up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>I did want to mention that next door to them in the house, [<i>Mike and Tim laugh.</i>] is-was a neighbor named Pong...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... that I put into many scripts in Ba Sing Se that just, he never made it on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. Well we saw-we did see him in-in, in the, the first episode where they're in Ba Sing Se.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Oh, that's right, they talk to him very briefly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>They... Sokka talks to him, but uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] At one point he-didn't he end up in the prison?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, he was in the prison, and yeah, the Dai Li was tracking him, they grabbed him out of his house. He had a whole backstory.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he was like a major character [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] for a while, and then.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] No offense Tim, but I don't miss it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] Well, [<i>Laughs.</i>] I think I might be the only one whose-has a hankering for more Pong.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to the fireplace emanating green light on the room and the characters.</i>] So, the idea with this green fire, I'm not sure if we've touched on this, is that usually we just use uh, in the Earth Kingdom, we use these phosphorescent crystals for a light source. Um, they don't use fire that much, sort of a prejudice against firebenders and whatnot. Um, but the ide-we had this idea that, I don't know, there was some rare crystal that was, um, maybe fused with some kind of gaseous substance, and it could-it could burn. It's like a really long-lasting artificial log or something. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] And it has a green flame because of the gaseous... releases.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>But I imagine it being very fragrant as well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Like an evergreen scent.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... it's like a potpourri-yeah, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] it's evergreen. It's a-it's lime mint, is what it is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to Iroh asking what Zuko to consider what he wants his life to be like.</i>] That's some classic Uncle advice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, Tim, when you write a script, and then, you know, often there's like a long gap before you see the final, you know, product.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Uh-huh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Are you ever surprised at the end, you're like, "Ah, I had no idea that was gonna come out like that," or, or...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yes, all the time. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] Almost always there's something in there that's, usually there are always like some visual jokes [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] that aren't in the script. [<i>Refers to Toph gluing a poster on the wall backwards, and thinking it's upside-down.</i>] Although this was in the script, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] where she puts it on backwards. But uh, yeah, I mean especially-or like battle scenes, you never really know how that blocking is going to work out, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] when-when you see that in the end, and this has a great fight scene in it. That-all that stuff [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] is, is always amazing to see for the first time. [<i>Brief pause; refers to Jet approaching Katara.</i>] There's our man.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, so this is the first time Katara's seen Jet since uh, season one, when he... broke her heart.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So to speak.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara attacking Jet.</i>] They had a loving relationship.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah... yeah. This is-this is a woman scorned right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] She...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] But I really-what I like about Jet's character is like, he was, he's always been kind of... troubled, you know. [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] He's-he's-he's, he's... he had good intentions, but [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] kinda went about the wrong way to, to-to solve problems I guess.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the tense theme that plays during Jet's closeup shot.</i>] Ooh. Yeah, Jet has the kind of classic, on the edge, between good and evil, he means to fight the Fire Nation but he goes too far, and it raises questions about, you know, the difference between the Freedom Fighters and terrorists, and, that's-there's some really deep thematic stuff [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] that goes on with Jet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Jet was designed by uh, Ryu Ki Hyun, who's a great animator and designer we met, uh, at JM Animation. And uh, we, we just loved his drawings, and, um, when episode 110 came into production, we, we gave him the assignment of designing Jet and the whole gang of, uh, Freedom Fighters.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph checking to see if Jet is lying.</i>] And this, t-right, this is the first time we see Toph with her lie detecting ability.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, this is the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] With her heartbeat, which is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] The idea that she sees with vibration, so, she can sense... she's kind of like a polygraph, she can sense a change in-if everything's quiet enough, and-and she's concentrating, she can sense a, a change in someone's heartbeat, and... kind of biorhythms.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Old Sweepy.</i>] Here comes Old Sweepy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>This is, this is a reoccurring theme in uh, Tim's scripts.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Tim is great at writing old men.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>They're kind of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Old-old blowhards.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>]... crazy old men
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>They're always, they don't use, like, instead of, "the army", they're like, [<i>In a crotchety, old man voice.</i>] "army makes the stuff here", [<i>Mike and Tim laugh.</i>] you know, just-just, they jump right into the sentence.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think he comes straight from New Palestine, Indiana, [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] 'cause these are my roots expressing themselves on film here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka pointing out Whaletail Island on the map.</i>] And also, Whaletail Island was named after that specific island on the map, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>That's right...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] You guys were looking at it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... it looked like a whale tail. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Although no one in the <i>Avatar</i> world would know that, like, would they?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Well...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] They have whales, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... eh, you know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] If...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... Avatars have been flying around, for years.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I guess somebody made that map and saw.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>They probably have, uh... bison whales, I don't know, [<i>Tim laughs.</i>] something.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>No, they've got whales. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I take it back, they would know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Toph says she can tell Katara's lying about Jet being her boyfriend.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Toph...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I love that moment.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... hanging off her power with a joke, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] by the way. I love that. [<i>Brief pause; refers to Toph calling Ba Sing Se the worst city ever.</i>] That's a great comment honestly, [<i>Tim and Mike laugh.</i>] for a character on the show that our city is the worst.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] I think that was what was kinda cool about Ba Sing Se, is like we had set it up as this like Shangri-La, great place that, you know, the kids really wanted to get to, and all their problems would be solved once they got there, and they get there and they discover this crazy conspiracy, and like, just dark underside to the Earth Kingdom, which is cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Just, just continuing the line of disappointments [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] that are characters get all the time, [<i>Laughs.</i>] it never works out for these guys.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Well, yeah...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That-that goes along with, you know, we tend not to... play people like, just good versus evil, [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] you know, it's the multifaceted nature of politics and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, well the great thing about Ba Sing Se...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>In the background.</i>] just societies.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... is that's how they see themselves, is this Shangri-La, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] this perfect society, and everything's on total lockdown, but they just can't keep a lid on the war anymore.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of Zuko baiting and capturing a Dai Li agent, while disguised as the Blue Spirit.</i>] This sequence came out really cool, with the... spirit...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Blue Spirit's back!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the Dai Li agent bending his rock glove, turning it into a clenched fist like his hand.</i>] There you see the nice detail of how the Dai Li can remotely control these little stone hands, like a puppet master.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Blue Spirit scarecrow.</i>] I just like the idea that Zuko is in his apartment stitching up this little Blue Spirit stuffed mask. [<i>Tim and Bryan laugh.</i>] He's-he's pretty good with the craft.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>He's quite a seamstress. [<i>Mike affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He found one backstage at a, at an opera house. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] That's a-'cause the Blue Spirit mask is an opera, Chinese opera mask for like a-a wizard. [<i>Refers to Aang's negative reaction to the idea of Katara kissing Jet.</i>] See a little Aang jealousy here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>For the shippers.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He... he [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] doesn't like that. I think it did...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar's efforts to trigger Jet's traumatic memories.</i>] Yeah, now we're getting this, the whole brainwashing of Jet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka sticking a stalk of straw in Jet's mouth, with a pop sound effect.</i>] Great sound design by Ben Wynn there, when Sokka sticks the... hay into his mouth.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he did some great stuff here when Jet goes into his, his kinda tripped out mind thing here. [<i>Refers to the piercing, echoey sound effects that accompany Jet's flashbacks.</i>] Is kinda surreal sound design and stuff, which is really cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Rough Rhino leader, Colonel Mongke, appearing in Jet's memories.</i>] We-we see a little uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh right, this was the big moment where we reveal the Rough Rhinos were b-behind the uh, destruction of Jet's town when he was a kid.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The idea was that the Rough Rhinos sort of were the, the group that would go in first before the army would come, and they would sort of raze the village and set it on fire, and just kind of cause mayhem.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>In addition to their singing performances, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] which they rehearse.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Of course...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah. They usually sing first, then, then raze the villages.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the team talking about Lake Laogai.</i>] Now, we were talking before that Laogai means prison in Chinese, and so it's essentially Prison Lake.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>A little on the nose.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yes. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] It might take some of the surprise out of... for the fans in the Asian...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Toph earthbends the entrance to Lake Laogai from underneath the water.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Toph always handy for some underground sight.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the underground Lake Laogai architecture.</i>] So, I was really happy with uh, a lot of the background designs and paintings for this, uh, kind of catacomb like space, uh. I have a really cool book that shows um, empty spaces in Paris, and they have these... like catacomb sewer systems that look a lot like these. So we use those as inspiration.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Is this...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the sequence of the Joo Dees being hypnotized by the Dai Li.</i>] This is-this is one of my [<i>Laughs.</i>] favorite sequences in <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's kind of Stepf-<i>Stepford Wives</i>-esque scene, where they're all being brainwashed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>A Joo Dee factory.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, they're plenty [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] of Joo Dees to go around.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the color palette on the characters being greener colors.</i>] So, here we see the phosphorescent crystals that we normally use, um. We kept them kind of a cool color to keep it creepy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shot of an imprisoned Appa, followed by a reverse shot of the Blue Spirit entering his cell.</i>] Yeah, that was-that's one of my favorite, like kinda cuts to that we've [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] done on the show, just the mislead of, [<i>In a mock anticipatory tone.</i>] you think it's the kids! Aw, it's the Blue Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, and this is, how long has Appa been gone now? For like six episodes?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>He would've been gone since episode...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] The end of 10.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of Team Avatar fighting Long Feng and the Dai Li.</i>] Ah, this is a great uh, sequence, uh, this action sequence was storyboarded by Joaquim Dos Santos, uh, who later became a director on <i>Avatar</i> after Lauren left. One of my favorite action sequences.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah... yeah, it's definitely a challenge, I think to board multiple people fighting, and keep it clear as to what's going on, you know. If you have one-on-one, it's-it's... it's, it's difficult, but it's I think, uh, much harder to keep track of a bunch of different characters all fighting at the same time. [<i>Refers to the Dai Li using their unique earthbending against Team Avatar.</i>] There's some great moments of seeing the Dai Li grabbing people, and creating these rock pillars, and running up the walls, and all this stuff, it's great. Very exciting.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long take of Toph fighting off four Dai Li agents, taking them down with earthbending in quick, near simultaneous succession as they try to flank her from either side on rock pillars.</i>] This-this shot's one of my favorites right here. The symmetry of Toph taking out those [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] two guys.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, and the great idea that Toph can't see the fists always [<i>Mike affirms intermittently.</i>] flying at her, you know, 'cause they're flying through the air. [<i>Refers to Jet breaking the rock gloves the Dai Li sends at him.</i>] Some excellent hook sword action. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, she knows the line of action, she can feel someone strike at her, but yeah, it might be hard for her to time, time the fist in the air. [<i>Refers to the room filled with pipes that Aang and Jet confront Long Feng in.</i>] This room came out really well. [<i>Refers to Long Feng trying to bribe Aang with Appa's location.</i>] Clancy Brown, fantastic voice actor, uh, does Long Feng.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Long Feng questions Aang and Jet's belief that he's in a losing position, right he activates Jet's brainwashing.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>And now Jet, turned into the ultimate weapon.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the distorted echo sound effect applied to Long Feng saying Laogai.</i>] Neat-cool little sound design there on... the word Laogai, little echoes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the shot of Appa angrily stomping the ground, whipping up waves of dust.</i>] I love-that animation of Appa is like some of the best, 'cause you just really feel his weight, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] and like how big he is, and uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Very cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... this is difficult to do in... TV sometimes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh frustration at trying to get Zuko to stop blindly following the path his father set him on.</i>] And this is, Uncle just drops the-kind of the ultimate Uncle speech [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] on Zuko here, to just kind of break him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>This is a great one, very emotional. Usually Uncle stays kinda calm, but every once in a while he...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, he can't-can't keep it in anymore.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... like 120, when he's like yelling at Comma-at Zhao, you know that, I really like when... when he gets excited, you know he's serious.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. No, great acting by Mako, who uh, unfortunately passed away, uh, la-last year. Did just a great job bringing Uncle to life.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko's stubborn refusal to abandon his destiny as a prince.</i>] Zuko's teen angst and stubbornness, [<i>Tim laughs.</i>] he just, he knows these things, he just doesn't want to let them through, he's hung up on his ego. Really wants his father's approval, even though he's kind of torn what he thinks about his father.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>It makes you think that maybe if Zuko had a pet like Appa to love, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] that he would've been softened...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Maybe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... as a child.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I think they've sci-scientifically proven that... having pets...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>It's very therapeutic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... very therapeutic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Jet being forced to attack Aang.</i>] I really like just the-the tragedy of, you know, what happens to Jet here, where...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Jet's eternal battle...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... it's just like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... [<i>In the background.</i>] ex-terrorist.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... you know he doesn't want to be doing this, but.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of flashbacks to Jet's interactions with Team Avatar and the Freedom Fighters.</i>] This is a great little sequence that Mike and Jeff Adams, editor, pulled together. Just a little f-flashback.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the flashback of Jet and Katara.</i>] Good times with Katara.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Aw man. [<i>Refers to the sequence where Jet throws one of his hook swords at Long Feng, who then fatally wounds Jet with his earthbending.</i>] This sequence got scripted I think, like ten to twelve different times...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] You're right, it did. I mean...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... based on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... if you're talking about originally...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Nah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... [<i>Laughs.</i>] maybe we shouldn't, but there was a different version we had, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] There are many different ways it went down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like it, I like how it came out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, no, I think this was definitely the best way, and it makes Long Feng... very villainous.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I'm happy with the-the storyboarding sequence too, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] I think it, uh, really came together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph knowing Jet was lying about being okay.</i>] And this is Toph's big lie detector payoff... coming up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>She sees through Jet's heroic downplay of his predicament. [<i>Brief pause; refers to Longshot saying he and Smellerbee will look after Jet.</i>] It's the first time!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Longshot speaks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>First and last time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, many people are wondering, why didn't Katara use the spirit water at this point?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] That's a great question.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] It's a good thing she didn't, 'cause...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] She was saving it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah, no, I think she tested it, she tested the water, she knew she couldn't help him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Spirit water is for series regulars only.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah... yeah. Well, it's also I think we-we determined that spirit water... you gotta have some sort of, uh, spiritual connection to the Spirit World, or something like that to-that to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I think it's that Aang was the Avatar. [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] Had she used it on a normal person, it probably wouldn't have worked.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think it would...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It was just the fact that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... just be like regular water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... yeah, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] the fact that Aang was... the Avatar.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>But could she have used it for Zuko plastic surgery?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>You know, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] but the idea behind that is it's... it wouldn't change the sc-the look of the scar.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Dai Li agents that Aang and Toph bend off the cliff face.</i>] By the way, I did some, uh, ADR on this part, so...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh, did you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... if you hear me, and uh, John O'Bryan, yelling as, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh, are you guys one of the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... as Dai Li agents.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Bryan lets off a mock aggravated yelp to imitate the Dai Li getting thrown into the water.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Dai Li agents that get thrown off? Wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the high angle shot of Long Feng and the Dai Li looking down at the boxed in Team Avatar.</i>] That's a great shot there by...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] See if you can pick out which one's me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... Chris Graham.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa swooping in to save Team Avatar from the Dai Li.</i>] Right... here's the big moment everyone's been waiting for.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Aww.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Woohoo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>I'm tearing up, just, even now.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Appa came back. Yeah, after we, you know, we kind of messed with the audience a few times, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] where you think Appa's going to come back, and then he doesn't, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the screaming Dai Li agents.</i>] I-there was you, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Yeah. That was us right there!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... John. [<i>Laughs.</i>] Got it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, I think this was very-very satisfying...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa and Long Feng.</i>] Long Feng gets his comeuppance.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... reuniting. Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa dominating the shot in the background, as Long Feng takes up comparably less space in the foreground.</i>] That's a great shot, with the telephoto. [<i>Refers to Long Feng trying to launch a rock pillar at Appa.</i>] So, you see Long Feng did start to earthbend there, but Appa intercepted him. [<i>Refers to Appa throwing Long Feng into the lake like a skipping stone, with only the water splashes making any sound.</i>] I like how quiet it is when he skips across the water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] He skips. It's very peaceful, like maybe Appa would just be doing that on a sunny day by himself, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] just skipping people across the pond.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa spitting Long Feng's shoe out of his mouth, having chomped down on the latter's foot.</i>] So, Long Feng's foot is not inside that shoe. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] It's just the shoe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the closeup shots on Aang and Appa emotional reunion.</i>] That's a sweet moment.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Aww.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yay.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara crying as she looks down on Lake Laogai.</i>] And then Katara is mourning here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Team Avatar having a group hug on Appa's saddle.</i>] They're all family again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko.</i>] Zuko at this crossroads.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I like this little tag. I think in the animatic, we had-we, we didn't have this little end scene [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] and we added it afterwards 'cause I think it wasn't totally clear that if we knew...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] What happened.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... if Zuko was the one who freed Appa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>'Cause if you showed it, then that gave away the surprise of... [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] of Appa showing up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to final shot of the episode where the Blue Spirit masks sinks underwater.</i>] But I love that last shot too of the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] The Blue Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Blue Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Is he gone for good? [<i>Gives a questioning murmur.</i>] Maybe?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, pretty much. [<i>Tim laughs; brief pause.</i>] All right, once again, I want to thank everyone who's worked really hard on this show to make it awesome. Thanks Tim for an awesome script for this one...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>Hey, thanks for having me, man...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... once again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... it was a lot of fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Thanks for that yell in the end of the episode, I think that was the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It kinda sealed the deal, didn't it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, it did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>It was the dramatic juice...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I think...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>... that this [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] episode needed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... because you wrote that guy's yell, [<i>Tim affirms.</i>] so something about writing it and then voicing it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>It's, in-in the script, said, parentheses, yells in all caps, end parentheses. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] And-and I got to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] But you knew his motivation I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Tim
</th>
<td>I did. [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] He was scared. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Synergy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] See you next time.  
</td></tr></tbody></table>