[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Mike DiMartino, co-creator and executive producer of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sifu Kisu
</th>
<td>Hi, I'm Kisu, I'm the martial art... consultant for the motion TV show, <i>Avatar</i>. [<i>Kisu and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>Motion TV? I gotta get one of those.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Hey, I got one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>This is Bryan Konietzko, I'm the other co-creator, and co-executive, and whatev-I don't know, [<i>Kisu chuckles.</i>] I do some stuff...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] He does a lot of stuff on this show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... do some stuff on this... this show. So, this is a very special episode of <i>Avatar</i> because after uh, many, many episodes we were waiting for the right character to model after our good friend Sifu Kisu. And um, although many personalities and little anecdotes of characters had been modeled my experiences of being a student of Kisu's, um, we finally-you know, he's like, [<i>Imitates Kisu.</i>] make me, make me someone cool. [<i>Bryan and Mike chuckle; refers to Piandao.</i>] So uh, finally we said this sword master, we...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Couldn't have been any cooler this guy, looks like you stole my soul, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] it's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And then voiced by the great uh, actor, Robert Patrick, who was uh, made famous as T-1000, and uh, [<i>Adopts the accent and cadence of Arnold Schwarzenegger.</i>] T-1000, and uh, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I was very pleased, he's um, a really good choice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, he's a great actor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I gotta say the first time we saw the uh, animation come back, it was a little, little startling to see you, Kisu, in animated form [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] talking to us with a different voice. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>It-it, [<i>Mike laughs intermittently.</i>] oh, it really scared the hell out of me, I-I looked at it and I was like, [<i>In a mock disturbed tone.</i>] oh my god, they've stolen my soul.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Bryan and Mike laugh; refers to soft blue color palette on Team Avatar.</i>] I really like the way the lighting came out for this meteor shower. [<i>Refers to the more vivid blue colors that come from the meteor, as it crashes down in the background.</i>] I like that right there, where the meteor actually lights up the canyon. [<i>Refers to the stark, craggy landscape.</i>] So, this is a-a-another episode, as most of the ones in uh, season three, where the landscape is heavily inspired by uh, some reference photos I took in Iceland, um, these crazy moss covered, uh, volcanic formations. And where the kids are camping, uh, the idea is that the Fire Nation being so in-you know, industrious that they've strip mined a lot of their land for um, minerals so they can smelt metal for their ships and all their war machines. Um, so, originally the idea was that the Fire Nation was gonna be very, uh, industrialized and a lot of strip mines and-and we um, didn't really get that much of it in. [<i>Laughs.</i>] I mean, if you look around through season three, you'll see some factories and stuff, but um, that was, that was the inspiration behind that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh, I was reminded today by Seung Hyun, our supervising director, that this is the Annie combo, uh, episode, where Giancarlo, director, uh, won an Annie award, which is a, uh, animation award, uh, and uh, the animation director Jae, uh, director Yu, in Korea, uh, also won uh, for-for character animation. So, some very talented folks working on this episode, and uh, was written by Tim Hedrick, uh, always adds a great sense of humor to his episodes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Only the best for you, Sifu Kisu. We-we assembled...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah, that's right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... a crack team. [<i>Refers to the sequence of an imprisoned Iroh pretending to be senile, all the while physically training his body.</i>] So, this is a great little um, B-plot that also came from uh, the writing retreat that we took uh, before season three. We had this idea that, you know, we-we meet Uncle's character after his big height of fame and-and glory as a general, um, and he's sort of in retirement, but um, this begins his transformation back to that, uh, fierce general. [<i>Refers to Iroh, after the guard leaves, dropping his act and eating his food from his bowl rather than the floor.</i>] And we see that he's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>It's pretty amazing that, you know, you've touched on <i>The Art of War</i> here, that the whole tactic of, you know, someone, you know, thinks that you're beneath contempt, they don't pay attention to you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And the-<i>The Art of War</i> is an ancient text, right, it's a...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock menacing tone.</i>] It's a manual toward the domination of other human beings. [<i>Kisu and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] It was written, uh, for that purpose, and has since been adopted by uh, corporations all over America. [<i>Bryan and Kisu laugh.</i>] Think that's its' main uh, function now. Hostile takeovers in the corporate world.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Well, it's got-it's got some, um, really interesting stuff based on the <i>Daoza</i>-the <i>Dao</i>, the Way, of um, you know, know your enemy, know yourself, and a thousand battles you will never be defeated. It's interesting to watch Uncle's transformation because, you know, you just think he's this fat old man, but you don't get to be the top general of the Fire Nation and the next person in line for the throne without having something special going on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like how he bides his time too. He's-he's very careful about when he makes his move.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Well that's something we've seen from the beginning with Uncle. He's always been very patient, uh, you know, he's always, you know, created the façade of, you know, gentleness or weakness until just the key moment where action is needed, and then he acts decisively.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, 'cause you really get a sense that he's got tons of power, but we actually haven't shown him... fight that much [<i>Laughs.</i>] really.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, just a few [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] little moments.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Little dashes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang in the aesthetically excessive armor.</i>] Now this tickles me to death because this is... [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Okay, this joke here, we gotta comment on this, [<i>Kisu and Bryan affirm.</i>] 'cause, 'cause uh, you know... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the theme playing during the shot of Aang in his armor.</i>] Music, by the way, Jeremy Zuckerman on the electric guitar there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the Guan Dao weapon that Sokka twirls around.</i>] I love the pizza cutter.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang's armor.</i>] Everything, uh, that Aang is [<i>Laughs.</i>] wearing sort of represents s-stylistic elements that Mike and I don't really care for. [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>] But I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] But...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... yeah, everyone wanted Aang to h-you know, is there any way he could, uh, in the series become twenty-five years old, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] have stubble, um, more bladed weapons, maybe a motorcycle, an eyepatch. [<i>Mike and Bryan chuckle.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sword hanging on display in the weapons shop.</i>] Now, that sword right there is something special. That's uh, actually drawn from something I brought back in, uh, 2001 from China, from the uh, Zhengzhou Wushu Festival. It's one of the commemorative swords that they made, uh, for the fifteen hundred year of the uh, Shaolin Temple in China.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So yeah, not only did we, uh, model, you know, Master Piandao after Sifu Kisu, but we, for the three main swords that we see in this episode are all from his collection. That one that he just mentioned. Um, Piandao's own sword was-is a Qing dynasty sword, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Um, yeah, it's about a, based on a three, maybe even four hundred year old sword.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And then, uh, the one that they forge for Sokka was a really beautiful sword.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>And that was a contemporary piece that uh, I found when we were um, visiting uh, Wudang Mountain, um, Wu-tang Mountain, in China [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] last September.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka steadily increasing his use of the door knockers.</i>] This is a fun little gag here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao's castle.</i>] I love my house, I'll be waiting. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Piandao's servant, Fat, answers the door, with Sokka comically trying to change his startled expression, at which Kisu chuckles.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like that little freak-out. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Fat.</i>] And this guy's based on your servant at home, right, Kisu? [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Absolutely, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] you know, [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] Jeeves is well respected and knows kung fu.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Exactly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Excellent.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to Fat's protruding stomach.</i>] This is the pillow he wears in his robe [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] to... deceive his enemies.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka and Piandao.</i>] I love the setup though that-that you guys did with uh, you know, him presenting himself to the master, and, you know, the master just assumes he's gonna be, you know, one more big mouth, know-it-all.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao's study, the window overlooking the landscape and horizon.</i>] I love this room, this-this came out really nicely. We wanted, you know, this-this Zen feeling for this master that-that's so common in these sorts of stories... that he spends most of his time with meditative practices, and puts a lot of import on those.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Well, it's been, uh, historically documented that, you know, most great generals who've seen like a lot of turmoil, who've seen a lot of, you know, horror, you know, retire and become gardeners or, you know, painters or calligraphers or, you know, you know, artiste musicians.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, like uh, Musashi, [<i>Kisu gives an affirming murmur.</i>] was a poet, actor, painter, sculptor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao.</i>] Now that, just my profile, just [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] chills every time I saw, I was like, oh my god, who's that guy? I'm kind of cute though. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] Little older there though.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Well, we had to age you a bit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka's jubilant expression at being accepted as Piandao's student.</i>] I-I love Sokka's look, you know, right there he's like, [<i>Imitates Sokka.</i>] you will?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the scene cutting to black after Sokka's expresses his joy.</i>] This, this is a rare, uh, structurally this is a, a rare episode for us because the two act breaks end on someone being really happy, like something good's going to happen. Usually it's like, [<i>In a mock grave tone.</i>] you have to fight an army. [<i>Mike and Kisu chuckle; refers to the sequence of Piandao's sword forms.</i>] So, what do you think about this sequence, Sifu?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>This was taken from, um, actually compi-an amalgamation of different sword styles that we practice, uh, in particular <i>Loong Ham Gim</i>, the Walking Dragon swordsmanship. And you guys animated it precisely, it was amazing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Well, we didn't, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] but some great talented people did, [<i>Laughs.</i>] in Korea.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Well, we're a collective effort, from top to bottom.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>True, true. [<i>Refers to the long shot of Aang, Katara and Toph laying on the ground, with Momo running into frame.</i>] I love the way Momo runs in there and flops down. Really reminds me of my dog. [<i>Kisu laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph.</i>] I love the way Toph is picking her nose.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Oh yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Vigorously.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sound effects of Toph's nose picking.</i>] Ben did it, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] uh, Ben or, uh, Aran, the foley artist, I'm not sure, did some great, uh, [<i>Laughs.</i>] sou-sound for her just digging in there, like a wet sponge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph detailing her daily routine.</i>] I like the whole, um, you know, I pick my toes twice. [<i>Everyone laughs.</i>] Nah, just for the pure sensation of picking it, I love that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shot of Team Avatar resting on a strip of barren rock below some cliffs.</i>] So, there you can see the strip mine. [<i>Refers to Iroh's training of doing crunches, while hanging upside down from his cell bars.</i>] So, man, Uncle, he's got his feet on these metal bars. It's pretty intense.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>And also, this is one of the classic trainings of-of hanging upside down, in the Shaolin Temple they do that, and, you know, lock you into these braces, and-because the, you know, waist like a snake is one of the requirements for um, a high-level martial artist.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao tasking Sokka with writing his signature with a calligraphy set.</i>] So, luckily uh, Seung Hyun, our supervising director, um, he's from Korea and he has some experience writing calligraphy, so I mean, Mike and I don't really know the tools involved and the proper way, you know, we-we maybe referenced things from movies. But um, it was great, uh, Greg filmed, Greg, uh, Rankin, our videographer, filmed Seung Hyun doing this whole, um, process of-of setting up the paper and the ink, and... [<i>Kisu gives an affirming murmur; refers to Sokka writing his signature by rubbing his inked face on the paper.</i>] but obviously Sokka just comes in and... [<i>Kisu chuckles.</i>] just uh, like a bull in a teashop. No, china shop? [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] Bull in a something, I don't know. Tea shop, that'd be messy too. [<i>Refers to Piandao's exasperated reaction.</i>] That's a good Kisu moment right there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>That was a good Kisu look for sure.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>There's one coming up that's very, [<i>Laughs; Kisu affirms.</i>] I think we-I think we filmed you... for your reaction.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka and Fat practice dueling, and Sokka running away after being disarmed.</i>] This is classic, I love this. [<i>Imitates Sokka.</i>] Ahhh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Hey...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] That...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... what-what else can you do but run away? It's good self-defense.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, story wise, I thought that was really smart, Tim and Aaron, to come up with like, you know, there's a lot of talking and, and informational stuff in these lessons, but we needed to show like Sokka actually physically progressing and show that he's getting better as a swordsman too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shot of the waterfall, and the river and canyon that are part of it.</i>] So, this is, uh, Gullfoss, which is um, a very famous waterfall in Iceland, and uh, [<i>Kisu gives an appraising murmur.</i>] was from uh, some photos that I took there. And then after this episode was, you know, we, the designers and I, based this-this amazing, uh... waterfall on this, and it was painted fr-you know, referencing the photos, and then the animation came back, and... and then Mike came into work one day, and he's like, "hey, I, I think I saw that uh, waterfall on..." um, Sunrise, was it Sunrise...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] <i>Sunrise Earth</i>, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... <i>Sunrise Earth</i>. You're, I think they painted it so well that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to Piandao's exasperated reaction at Sokka's cartoonish drawing.</i>] That reaction right there, the animation was great, that sigh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That was very much, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I think uh, I've gotten that look from Sifu Kisu [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] a lot of times in class. This uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Uh, oh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>Refers to Piandao telling Sokka to concentrate.</i>] that "concentrating on what you're doing", there's a story behind that, and when uh, Sokka was swinging the-the-the nunchuks around, the two sectioned staff, this actually comes from uh, personal experience. Uh, one day in class, Sifu Kisu turns around and hands me some solid oak nunchuks and says, "here, you're going to learn two section staff now". And I, you know, was very excited, the uh, twelve year old boy in me [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] was like, wow, my own nunchuks. And-but he recognized this look on my face, and he says, "uh-uh, don't, don't think I'm giving t-you these because you're good. I'm giving you these because you have a problem concentrating, and these will train you to be aware of, you know, where the other end is at any moment, and the second you're not aware, it's going to find you".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Expletive.</i>] found you. [<i>Laughs.</i>]  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Five minutes later, I hit myself in the head with these solid oak, uh, nunchuks, and man that hurt. [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I have a tendency to giggle at the wrong moments too, I'm so sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>No, it was a, [<i>Kisu laughs.</i>] but anyways, so um, that line is-is definitely about that, and uh, Sokka does just that when he's uh, at the weapon shop.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>No, you-we did some really amazing stuff with the um, the sword applications, the like, the disarms, um, the footwork, the connecting, the distancing, was all very authentic and um, very um... I-I don't even have a word for it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] This uh, not only was it fun basing this character on, on Sifu Kisu, but, um, I think this was one of the most... fun, yet ch-challenging and vigorous, uh, kung fu reference sessions we've ever had. I mean, there were-there were multiple sessions for this episode. But um, for this whole crazy fight in the end, um, its-you know, and it's not even a fight, it's more of a test that um, that Piandao is putting Sokka through. Um, I mean, I don't think you and I had ever [<i>Laughs.</i>] worked so hard in a session.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I think it's some of the best, uh, two-man combative work we did, except probably for the, uh, Azula and Zuko fight, uh, with the fingernails that we didn't get to use. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] Oops.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the cut to black as Sokka smiles upon hearing he's going to make his own sword.</i>] Another happy act break. [<i>In a mock enthusiastic tone.</i>] I'm happy! So, the crazy thing about, uh, when we were doing this vigorous, um, reference, we-we each had these like foam training swords, and we were in the, the Nickelodeon gym... just battling, and-and there was so much choreography that we, we just improvised a lot of it. And um, and the-the storyboard artists, uh, M-Mike Chang, um, sort of, you know, took pieces of it. But, there we are, I'm standing up on these bleachers, uh, Kisu's down on the ground, we're t-fighting, I got stabbed in the leg, even though it was a foam sword, [<i>Bryan and Kisu laugh.</i>] it hurt really bad, and the door opens up, and Serena Williams walks in to the gym, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] and... she says, "wow, what a, you know, what a great way to uh, what an amazing job you-you s-you know, you-you work so hard and stay in shape". Now, this is Serena Williams, who's just like, has to be one of the most in shape people in the world, and uh, I'm huffing and puffing and sweating and about to faint, [<i>Laughs.</i>] you know, like, she just walked in at a one moment where we were uh, moving around.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Think we've got a picture proof of that one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We do. It was an honor to meet her. She's a big <i>Avatar</i> fan, and-and later uh, did a voice for <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Did she?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>She did. [<i>Kisu gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, she works in the prison.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Ahh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Is friends with, uh, Uncle Iroh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar moving the meteor up to Piandao's castle, with Toph earthbending it.</i>] I love that the kids think they're being sneaky, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] like uh, no one's going to notice they have this giant rock with this huge [<i>Laughs.</i>] trough behind it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>They're all really strong, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] they pushed it really hard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao's blankly looking at the rest of Team Avatar.</i>] And that little look that Piandao is just like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] The earthbender's got a trough.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>Imitating Piandao; in a disbelieving tone.</i>] uh-huh. [<i>Laughs; refers to Piandao's curious expression.</i>] That looks pretty funny too. [<i>Refers to the sequence of Sokka forging his sword.</i>] This was a great sequence storyboarded by Seung Hyun. Um, we normally, sort-fear doing montages, they-they can be either really boring or trite or um, I don't know, but this one, um, we-I'm really happy with it and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, this one came out, tells a story...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... tells a story.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... when they-when they, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I like the whole concept of him having to construct his weapon too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And having to earn it, [<i>Kisu affirms.</i>] and you see some dedication.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the cut to nighttime as Sokka works at the forge.</i>] 'Cause he's got to up late, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] keep the fire going.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>And that's something we've shown all the way through the show is that, you know, none of the bendings, you know, comes automatically, it's not something that just, you know, magically appears, but its, it comes from a series of efforts, of-of, you know, really, uh, sacrificial works [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] that you have to do in order to develop a skill.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao looking at Sokka's progress.</i>] And again, that, like that shot where Piandao is um, watching Sokka, um, and Sokka doesn't know, uh, Seung Hyun put that in, and it, I-it, it's a great example of... everything Piandao does with Sokka is a test or a training sequence, and um, even this big long fight, you know, it's not really a fight, Sokka thinks it's a fight, but at the end he realizes it was sort of his uh, initiation or you know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Well, his whole reason for selecting him as a student was all based on character. That's-that's what it comes down to. There-there's-there's a saying in-in traditional Chinese martial art, uh, in China you pay in character, in the States you pay in cash. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to Piandao praising Sokka's skills and humility.</i>] But, I mean that's, that's a good point that this guy, you know, I'm sure he's trained thousands, you know, I'm sure he was a general and uh... and by this point, he's probably tired of all these, uh, assertive personalities he's run into, and it makes sense that he says, well you know, I have a gift, I'm-I'm a sword master, and who am I going to pass this, you know, who am I going to pass this along to? Just other aggressive, you know, talented people, or someone with character, so, you know... one who...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Someone who will misuse it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... yeah. And, you know, maybe Sokka isn't the, will never be the best swordsman, but, you know, his judgment will help uh... him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I think more importantly too is um, you know, when a-when a master selects someone to pass on something rare, he's really looking for someone that is going to preserve it. Because these arts are getting rarer and rarer all the time. Um, you know, who uses a sword to fight anymore? You don't use a sword to fight, you use a sword to-to develop, you know, your skill, and to develop your-your energy and to move your chi, your life force energy, beyond your hands, through your weapon, into your opponent's weapon, into your opponent. And um, so it's something much greater than, you know, just learning to poke a hole in somebody, it-it-it teaches you self-control, and um, you know, uh, spatial awareness, and, um, it-it raises a spirit. It-it makes you a more enlightened person, it jus-if your mind isn't in the moment every second you have a sword, you're gonna cut yourself really bad.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka and Piandao's duel.</i>] So, here begins some really amazing animation. Um, we're all very proud of this whole sequence, um, every aspect that came out really nice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>And this is based on a series of traditional, very deadly [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] sword applications. Kids...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Do not do this at home.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>... don't do this at home. Don't even play like this. Never point a sword at anyone, it's impolite...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>In a mock serious tone.</i>] and dangerous.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>... and dangerous.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka using vantage points on the courtyard stairs to try and get an edge on Piandao.</i>] So... just imagine, Nickelodeon gym, Kisu chasing me around [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] with a foam sword. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>We did this in a-in a series of different places. [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] We did it on-on the stairs out front of the studio...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] True, that's true.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>... we-the courtyard, um, the bleachers. Um, you know, we pulled out all the stops for this. And um... yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to Sokka, standing on the stair wall over his opponent, pinning down Piandao's sword.</i>] This is about when uh, Serena Williams walked in. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I think we...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Were up on top of the bleachers. [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] He says, "what do we do from here," I say, hey I've got an idea. That's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the heavy slicing sound effects as Sokka and Piandao slash at each other and their surroundings.</i>] This, this has great, uh, I love the sound design that Ben Wynn did in this section. They're like-you really feel like the swords like, the-the-the weight of the swords coming together and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka swiftly cutting the bamboo surrounding him.</i>] This right here, that's so, that was so ninja, [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] so-so, you know, s-that-that, yeah, I just have a sort of classic, you know, martial movie things that I like, and that just totally was an icon of all of that, that was so great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka running and screaming from Piandao.</i>] I like Sokka. We have all [<i>Kisu chuckles.</i>] this great action, and just goofy stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the metallic vibration sound effect as Sokka slides under Piandao's tremoring blade.</i>] Nice sound design there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Sweet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until the closeup shot of Piandao, blinded by some dust Sokka sent at him, scrunches up his eyes after trying to keep them open.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>But that-that was some subtle animation that-that can be very difficult for TV, but came out nicely, showing that, you know, he's got some sand in his eyes, he tries to open them, but it's too painful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Piandao complimenting Sokka's ingenuity throughout their fight.</i>] And the cool thing is even though it looks like he's bent on, you know, really doing Sokka in, he's teaching him the whole time, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] with all his commentary, in all of the angles.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Well, you figure that like this guy is so good that, I assume you've had experiences like this, Kisu, where like, he's obviously in control of every move he does, [<i>Kisu affirms.</i>] he's not gonna do anything that would actually... permanently [<i>Bryan affirms; laughs.</i>] injure Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>No. Being-being a master, if this was a real fight, it would've been over in probably the first second and a half. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>A real sword fight lasts less than one point seven seconds, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] for sure.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It's not-it's not a pretty thing, a sword fight. A sword fight is all about finding the vital point of your opponent, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] and poking it. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Piandao using his fight with Sokka as another test.</i>] So, this is, yeah, again, this was a lesson, this was training.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Kisu chuckles at Piandao's recommendation for Sokka to use an alias like Lee, given that there are a large number of Lees in the Fire Nation.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to large crater in the background behind Piandao's courtyard.</i>] So, that was another cool, in the background behind Piandao that was this crazy formation I saw in Iceland where... the ground had opened up sort of like those pods in <i>Alien</i>, just like, [<i>Makes an eruption sound.</i>] it was crazy. Some volcanic activity. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the exterior shots of Piandao's castle.</i>] Then uh, was a new background team that did these, um, paintings, in Korea, and they just came out so beautifully in this episode. Uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, this feels, I mean, of all the episodes this feels like a place you could go visit, 'cause [<i>Bryan affirms intermittently.</i>] a lot of it is. [<i>Laughs.</i>] Go to Iceland, and visit it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, this is director Kang's team in uh, Seoul.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>I do want to say that I appreciate, out of all the characters that you could've drawn me as, someone who's, you know, so strong and dedicated to the essence of martial virtue. Um, I'm really, you know, honored and-and flattered to be, you know, involved and... a part of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Our pleasure. You know, only took three seasons to find the right character.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Eh, it's okay.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We were going to make you the-the cabbage merchant, but uh, [<i>Mike and Kisu laugh.</i>] just felt he was too tall and imposing. [<i>Refers to Toph metalbending the chunk of meteorite into the Nickeolodeon "splat" logo.</i>] So, it's a little, uh, tribute to the Nick splat that lives [<i>Mike chuckles; Kisu affirms.</i>] in the lower right corner of our screen. [<i>Laughs.</i>] Whenever we're storyboarding, that's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, I remember that was in the script, and I was like, whoa, whoa, we're not going to really do that, are we? And then we did it. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] It's-it's kind of funny, I like it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Came out kind of cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, well thank you, Sifu Kisu, for lending your uh, beautiful likeness to this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Hey, thank you guys, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] I really, you know, you did me justice, I look better than I do in real life. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] It was a fun episode. Thanks to uh, Giancarlo, for doing a great job directing, and all the board artists, and... everyone who worked on it.    
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>And the animation team was just awesome, they just take it to the next level.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Great job as always.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kisu
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Thanks everyone.
</td></tr></tbody></table>]