[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The episode begins at Ozai's home on Ember Island. Cut to overhead shot of a courtyard where Aang and Zuko practice firebending using synchronized fire blasts. Cut to ground-level shot of the two as they create sweeping arcs of fire that dissipate into the ground. They each raise an arm and leg, sending forth streams of fire, before leaning forward and sending forth another stream of fire. Cut to closer shot of Aang and Zuko as they stand upright, assuming a final fighting stance before closing their eyes, relaxing their postures, and taking a deep breath. Toph and Katara are seen in the background, sitting on steps nearby. Zuko and Aang bow to one another, and the latter stretches his arms and walks away. Cut to Katara and Toph, who is lying down on the ground, relaxing.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Doesn't it seem kind of weird that we're hiding from the Fire Lord in his own house?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I told you, [<i>Cut to Zuko sitting on a dry fountain and wiping his head with a cloth.</i>] my father hasn't come here since our family was actually happy. And that was a long time ago. It's the last place anyone would think to look for us.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to wide-view of the courtyard from where Katara and Toph are sitting, their backs to the screen. Sokka and Suki enter on-screen from afar, Sokka holding a rolled-up piece of paper.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You guys are not gonna believe this! There's a play about us.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to close-up of her and Sokka.</i>] We were just in town and we found this poster! [<i>Sokka shows the poster for the play to the team. It depicts Katara, Aang, and Sokka with Zuko's scarred face in the background.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>What? How is that possible?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Listen to this ... [<i>Turns the poster toward him.</i>] "<i>The Boy in the Iceberg</i> is a new production from acclaimed playwright Pu-on Tim, [<i>Cut to a close shot of the poster as the camera pans up.</i>] who scoured the globe gathering information on the Avatar, from the icy South Pole to the heart of Ba Sing Se. [<i>Shot changes to show Team Avatar.</i>] His sources include singing nomads, pirates, prisoners of war, and a surprisingly knowledgeable merchant of cabbage."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>"Brought to you by the critically acclaimed Ember Island Players."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Recalling a memory.</i>] Ugh! My mother used to take us to see them. They butchered <i>Love Amongst the Dragons</i> every year!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Sokka, do you really think it's a good idea for us to attend a play about ourselves?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Persuasively.</i>] Come on, a day at the theater? This is the kind of wacky time-wasting nonsense I've been missing! [<i>He holds up the poster anxiously and smiles sheepishly; Katara looks away, appears nonplussed.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to nighttime at the theater. Cut to inside the theater to show the stage and curtain. The camera zooms out to show the balcony as Toph, Katara, and Aang arrive, with Aang wearing a hat to cover his head tattoos. Toph and Katara sit down; Zuko sits next to Katara as Aang tries to sit next to her. Aang stands back up.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko; points to his seat and tries to act casual.</i>] Hey, uh ... I wanted to sit there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Removing his hood.</i>] Just sit next to me. What's the big deal?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I was just, I wanted to ... okay. [<i>Sits down.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka and Suki sit in the row behind the rest of Team Avatar.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Why are we sitting in the nosebleed section? My feet can't see a thing from up here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Don't worry, I'll tell your feet what's happening.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The curtain rises to reveal a set representative of the South Pole seas. Actress Katara and Actor Sokka are rowing their boat along. Cut to Katara who looks thrilled to see herself onstage, and Sokka grabs her shoulder, pointing at her, himself, and the stage excitedly. Cut to shot of Actress Katara, an older, more robust woman wearing Water Tribe garments.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Sighs.</i>] Sokka, my only brother! We constantly roam these icy South Pole seas, and yet never do we find anything fulfilling!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to Actor Sokka, a thin, lanky man.</i>] All I want is a full feeling in my stomach! I'm starving!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The audience laughs. Cut to Sokka and Katara as their faces fall; they look at each other, confused. Cut to angled shot of the stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>Is food the only thing on your mind?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to shot of the actor.</i>] Well, I'm trying to get it out of my mind and into my mouth! I'm starving! [<i>Audience laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Leans forward in his seat; clearly annoyed.</i>] This is pathetic! My jokes are way funnier than this! [<i>Extends his arm in a dramatic gesture.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughing.</i>] I think he's got you pegged!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to the stage where Actress Katara now stands in the canoe.</i>] Every day, the world awaits a beacon to guide us, yet none appears! [<i>Cut to close-up of the actress who holds her hand out and clasps her hands together dramatically.</i>] Still, we cannot give up hope! For hope, [<i>Begins to cry.</i>] is all we have! And we must never relinquish it, even ... [<i>Sniffs and falls back into a sitting position.</i>] even to our dying breath! [<i>Leans over the side of the canoe and buries her face in her hands, crying.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the team, Suki holding her hand over her mouth to suppress a laugh and Sokka looking over at Katara with an amused smile, while Toph and Zuko are enjoying the play.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>With crossed arms, displeased.</i>] Well, that's just silly. I don't sound like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Elated.</i>] Oh man! This writer's a genius!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actress Katara still slumped over the side of the canoe. An iridescent light suddenly appears from above and she turns her head upward, shocked. Cut to shot of the stage where a model iceberg can be seen, the vague shadow of a figure visible from behind. The two actors stand up in the canoe.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>It appears to be someone frozen in ice, perhaps for a hundred years.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Closer shot of the silhouette swaying from side to side inside the iceberg prop.</i>] But who? Who is the boy in the iceberg?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Aang who smiles and leans forward in his seat. Cut to close-up of the model iceberg where Actress Katara stands before the silhouetted figure, Actor Sokka hosting himself onto the prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>Waterbend! Hi-yah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She performs a karate chop, mimicking waterbending. The silhouette disappears from view and the prop splits in half, sending forth a jet of steam. An actress, meant to portray Aang, leaps up on screen and poses, winking and with one hand on hip. The actress is visibly wearing a flesh-colored cap over her hair to portray herself as bald; the cap also bears the airbending mastery tattoo. She wears an excessive amount of blush on her cheeks and her overall physiognomy and demeanor clearly display her femininity.</i>
<p><i>Cut to shot of the actual Aang who momentarily closes his eyes and cringes in disbelief before leaning forward over the railing even more, eyes bugging out. Cuts back to the actors on stage.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>Who are you, frozen boy?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; in a high-pitched voice.</i>] I'm the Avatar, silly, here to spread joy and fun! [<i>She leans toward Actress Katara, laying a finger on her lips, and also motions toward Actor Sokka before standing upright and spreading her arms out in a cheery gesture.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Wait, is that a woman playing me?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A crude, costumed-version of Appa suddenly bursts up from behind the trio of actors; loud festival music previously heard in the episode "Avatar Day" is presently played. The replica of Appa sways from side to side before leaping off the iceberg prop. Cut to a wide shot of the stage as the three actors wearing the bison costume, only their legs visible, land to the right of the stage, run across to the left side, and finally behind the iceberg prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Gasps.</i>] An airbender! [<i>Clasps her hands to her chest.</i>] My heart is so full of hope, [<i>Drops down on one knee emotionally.</i>] that it's making me tearbend! [<i>Begins to cry and grabs on to Actress Aang's leg. Cut to close-up of Actress Katara who continues to bawl dramatically. Cut back to shot of the entire trio.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>My stomach is so empty, that it's making <i>me</i> tearbend! [<i>Throws his arms up hopelessly before dropping to his knees, clutching on to Actress Aang's other leg, and crying.</i>] I need meat! [<i>Cut to close-up of Actor Sokka.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Stoops down, puts her arm around Actor Sokka's shoulders, and points upward.</i>] But wait! Is that a platter of meaty dumplings? [<i>Cut to actual Aang whose head and arm rest lazily on the railing, unimpressed.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut back to shot of the trio, Actress Aang now sitting down, her legs dangling over the edge of the iceberg prop. Both Actress Katara and Actor Sokka are kneeling down.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Excitedly; shielding his eyes with his hand and turning his head, searching for the alleged dumplings.</i>] Ooh, where, where?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs and swings arm jovially.</i>] Did I mention that I'm an incurable prankster? [<i>Crosses her legs as the audience laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to wide shot of Team Avatar. Aang extends his arm toward the stage, angry with the actress' bad portrayal.</i>] I don't do that! That's not what I'm like! And I'm <i>not</i> a woman! [<i>Throws hands up in frustration.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs and turns to face Aang.</i>] Oh, they nailed you, Twinkle Toes! [<i>Continues to laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to stage where the trio of actors and iceberg prop are no longer present; the scene continues to depict the South Pole seas. A model Fire Nation ship prop glides onto stage from the left; a man portraying Prince Zuko stands at the bow of the ship, garbed in Zuko's outfit from Book One and peering through a telescope. The actor portraying Iroh stands at the helm.</i>
<p><i>Cut to shot of Actor Iroh, a very rotund, round-faced man sporting a slightly exaggerated imitation of the real Iroh's hairstyle, complete with a top-knot, beard, and sideburns.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Looking towards Actor Zuko, at ease.</i>] Prince Zuko, you <i>must</i> try this cake! [<i>Holds up a platter of cake with one slice missing.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actor Zuko looking through the telescope. He wears a headpiece that sports the ponytail Zuko once wore, albeit slightly exaggerated, and Zuko's scar; the replicated scar, while realistic, is worn over the wrong eye.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Determined.</i>] I don't have time to stuff my face! [<i>Lowers his telescope and turns to Actor Iroh.</i>] I must capture the Avatar to regain my honor! [<i>Faces out into the audience, clutching his hand in a fist assertively.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to wide shot of the model ship.</i>] Well, while you do that, [<i>Actor Zuko looks at him, annoyed.</i>] maybe I'll capture another slice. [<i>He holds the cake up higher before bringing it toward his face and proceeding to gobble it down ravenously and noisily.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns his view from Actor Iroh, in disgust.</i>] You sicken me!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to shot of Katara and Zuko in their seats, both with their arms crossed. Zuko appears displeased with his character portrayal while Katara looks at him with a smug smile.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Gestures toward the stage.</i>] They make me look totally stiff and humorless.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Complacently amused.</i>] Actually, I think that actor's pretty spot on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>In protest; holding his arms out.</i>] How could you say that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the bow of the model ship where Actor Zuko has resumed peering through his telescope. Actor Iroh stands behind him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Completely at ease.</i>] Let's forget about the Avatar and get massages!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns toward his uncle, leaning forward menacingly; shouting.</i>] How could you say that?!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Katara and Zuko; the former continues to smile smugly as the latter slumps down in his seat, defeated and dismayed to find her claim accurate.</i>
<p><i>Fade to a background drawing of the Southern Air Temple. The camera pans down to show Actress Aang searching, and finds a tail behind a bush prop.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>Hey look, I think I found something! [<i>Tiptoes to the bush. Actor Sokka scratches his head while Actress Katara shrugs. Actress Aang picks up the Momo prop, a rabbit-monkey puppet.</i>] It's a flying rabbit-monkey! I think I'll name him, Momo! [<i>Laughs; using puppet.</i>] Hi everybody, I love you! [<i>The audience laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Ugh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actress Suki, holding up two fans. She lifts them up. Actor Sokka enters in the Kyoshi Warriors' uniform.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing to his backside.</i>] Does this dress make my butt look fat?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Audience laughs, as does Suki. Sokka gives her an embarrassed look. </i>
<p><i>Cut to Actor Bumi with an Omashu background.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Bumi
</th>
<td>Riddles and challenges you must face, [<i>Camera pans back to show the whole stage.</i>] if you are ever to leave this place! [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Aang dodges a swaying rock while a goat gorilla chases Actor Sokka across stage. Actress Katara stands amidst a jennamite prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Lifting up a piece of the jennamite prop.</i>] Ugh! Oh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara gives a disgusted look and sticks out her tongue. Cut to the stage with a pirate ship background with the Team Avatar players in center stage. The pirates enter the stage from both side holding weapons in the air and attack them. The Team Avatar players slip away, with Actress Katara holding a large scroll. They tiptoe off stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Why did you have to steal that waterbending scroll?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Crying.</i>] It just gave me so much hope! [<i>Katara narrows her eyes.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a stage hand holding a sheet of metal, which he shakes to make a sound effect. Cut to the stage to show Actress Aang tied to a platform guarded by six Fire Nation soldiers. Actor Zuko stands in front of the platform.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>The Avatar is mine! [<i>Looking of stage.</i>] Wait, who's coming?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Blue Spirit
</th>
<td>[<i>Jumps on stage holding two swords and has a large mask.</i>] I'm the Blue Spirit, the scourge of the Fire Nation, here to save the Avatar!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Blue Spirit walks across the stage waving his swords. The guards fall down and Actor Zuko runs around the platform and throws a red strip of paper to symbolize firebending. The Blue Spirit points a sword at Actor Zuko, who runs away.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>My hero! [<i>Jumps on top of the Blue Spirit's large mask.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Blue Spirit walks off stage. Zuko and Aang frown, giving each other an embarrassed look. </i>
<p><i>Fade to a stagehand using a crank to lower the actors. Actress Katara and Actor Jet appear on a small rope platform. Actress Katara cries.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Jet
</th>
<td>Don't cry, baby! Jet will wipe out that nasty town for you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A large blue banner pulled by a stagehand dressed in black crosses the stage. Actress Katara and Actor Jet ascend on their platform.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>Oh Jet, you're <i>so</i> bad.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Both exit. Katara appears embarrassed. Toph laughs. </i>
<p><i>Fade to the team traveling on a large Appa prop with mountains painted in the background.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Gasps.</i>] Look! It's the Great Divide! The biggest canyon in the Earth Kingdom!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Eh, let's keep flying.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a stagehand dropping a bag of fake snow on stage in one spot. Cut to Actor Sokka and Actress Yue with a Northern Water Tribe background painting.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Don't go, Yue! You're the only woman who has taken my mind off of food! [<i>Kisses Yue. Gags.</i>] Wait, did you have pickled fish for dinner?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Yue
</th>
<td>Goodbye, Sokka! I have important moon duties to take care of! [<i>Exits on the moon prop.</i>] And yes, I did have pickled fish!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] You never told me you made out with a Moon Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[Placing a finger on Suki's lips] Shhh! [<i>Tearing up.</i>] I'm trying to watch! [<i>Suki, disgusted by Sokka's act, looks away, and folds her arms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to miniature Fire Nation ships being pulled across the stage by ropes. Actress Aang, wearing a Koizilla costume, stomps on them. She waves a doll of Zhao.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] The Avatar is back to save the day! Yay! [<i>Actress Aang stomps three more miniature ships before tripping over her Koizilla costume and falling.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Curtain drops. The audience cheers and Toph laughs. All the other members of Team Avatar appear disgusted. Zuko puts on his hood.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Ugh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to outside the theater. The camera pans to Team Avatar sitting on a flight of stairs during intermission.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Unimpressed</i>] So far, this intermission is the best part of the play.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks down the stairs holding a bag of flaming fire flakes and sits next to Suki.</i>] Apparently, the playwright thinks I'm an idiot who tells bad jokes about meat all the time!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Hint of sarcasm.</i>] Yeah, you tell bad jokes about plenty of other topics.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Eats a fire flake.</i>] I know!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Angry.</i>] At least the Sokka actor kind of looks like you. [<i>Sokka becomes furious over Aang's remark while Suki gleefully smiles.</i>] That woman playing the Avatar doesn't resemble me at all!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I don't know, you are more in touch with your feminine side than most guys.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Standing up, angrily.</i>] Argh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Relax, Aang. They're not accurate portrayals. It's not like I'm a preachy crybaby who can't resist giving overemotional speeches about hope all the time. [<i>Everyone looks at her.</i>] What?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around and sits down. Sarcastically.</i>] Yeah, that's not you at all.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Listen friends, it's obvious that the playwright did his research. I know it must hurt, but what you're seeing up there on that stage is the truth.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to a painted background with Earth Kingdom buildings. The Team Avatar players stand next to a large rock.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>Well, here we are in the Earth Kingdom!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Opens up her miniature air glider prop.</i>] I'd better have a look around to see if I can find an earthbending teacher! [<i>Jumps up into the air with a cable lifting her up.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>This is it, this must be where I come in!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Aang flies around the theater, over the audience, and returns to the stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>I flew all over town, but I couldn't find a single earthbending master!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Joyfully]</i> Here it comes ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Enters the stage from a trapdoor beneath the rock prop and holds it above his head.</i>] You can't find an earthbending master in the sky, you have to look underground! [<i>Throws away the prop.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang, Sokka, Suki, and Katara laugh. Zuko looks up from a piece of paper and stunned, drops the paper. And Toph is still looking eager.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>Who are you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Spits.</i>] My name's Toph, [<i>Flexes.</i>] because it sounds like tough, and that's just what I am! [<i>Audience laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Wait a minute, [<i>Picks at her ear with her pinky.</i>] [<i>confused]</i> I sound like a guy. A really buff guy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Well Toph, what you hear up there is the truth. It hurts, doesn't it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Are you kidding me? I wouldn't have cast it any other way! [<i>Laughs as Katara looks away in dismay.</i>] At least it's not a flying bald lady! [<i>Camera pans to Aang, who turns toward the stage in annoyance.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>So, you're blind? [<i>Waves hand in front of Actor Toph's eyes.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] I can see you doing that. I see everything that you see, except I don't "see" like you do. I release a sonic wave from my mouth. [<i>Screams very loudly at the Team Avatar players. The audience and Team Avatar grimace at the scream; Aang claps his hands over his ears, Zuko grips the railing in front of him, Suki and Sokka hug each other in terror, and Katara grits her teeth while Toph looks excited.</i>] There. I got a pretty good look at you. [<i>Actress Aang and the audience claps.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a stagehand operating a light. The shot changes to show the Actors Zuko and Iroh.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Iroh
</th>
<td>Zuko, it's time we had a talk ... [<i>Points to Zuko, who now wears a large wig.</i>] about your hair, it's gone too far!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Maybe it's best if we ... split ... up! [<i>Actors Zuko and Iroh walk away from each other.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the Team Avatar players and Actors Zuko and Iroh cornering Actress Azula.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Azula, my sister, what are you doing here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>You caught me. Wait, what's that? [<i>Points in the distance.</i>] I think it's your honor!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Where? [<i>Everybody looks while Actress Azula escapes through a door.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Turning to audience.</i>] She escaped, but <i>how</i>?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to a stagehand sitting on a stool while he rotates a lever. Shot changes to show the a large drill prop which Actress Azula stands on while it drills through a wall that Actress Aang attempts stands on. One stagehands dressed in black clothing shakes the wall while another waves smoke onto the stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>If she continues drilling, this wall will come down for sure!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A stagehand offers Actress Aang a rock prop, which she throws at Actress Azula.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>[<i>Blocks the rock prop.</i>] Haha, yes! Continue drilling! The city of Ba Sing Se can hide no longer!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Aang throws two more rock props at Azula. The shot changes to show members of the audience yawning and falling asleep.</i>
<p><i>Cut to Actor Jet jumping in front of the camera. He wears googly eyes and waves his hook hands around. Camera zooms out to show the Team Avatar players surrounding Actor Jet.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>No, Jet! What did they do to you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Jet
</th>
<td>Must ... serve ... Earth King! [<i>Begins swinging his hook hand wildly at Actress Aang and Actor Sokka.</i>] Must ... destroy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A stage hand is seen throws a hollow rock prop which floats down. Actor Jet falls down so that he lands underneath the prop and crawls all the way under.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Did Jet just ... die?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You know, it was really unclear.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to Actress Katara with the stage background painted as the Crystal Catacombs.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>I have to admit Prince Zuko, I <i>really</i> find you attractive!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Shot changes to show him sitting on a rock bench.</i>] You don't have to make fun of me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>But I mean it! [<i>Sits down with Actor Zuko.</i>] I've had eyes for you since the day you first captured me! [<i>Zuko and Katara inch away from each other, slightly uncomfortable. Aang narrows his eyebrows.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Stands up.</i>] Wait, I thought you were the Avatar's girl! [<i>Aang nods.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] The Avatar? [<i>Stands up and walks toward Actor Zuko.</i>] Why, he's like a little brother to me! [<i>Laughs.</i>] I certainly don't think of him in a romantic way. [<i>Aang grows concerned.</i>] Besides, how could he ever find out about ... this? [<i>Actress Katara and Actor Zuko embrace and hold hands while Actress Katara pops up one leg. Aang gets up.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Whispering.</i>] Oh, you're getting up? [<i>As Aang leaves.</i>] Can you get me some fire flakes? [<i>Puts his arm around Suki, but whispers to Aang again.</i>] Ooh, and fire gummies! [<i>Puts his arm back around Suki, who looks slightly annoyed.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actor Zuko standing between Actor Azula, who has a Fire Nation flag behind her, and Actor Iroh, who has an Earth Kingdom flag behind him. A light shines on Actor Zuko.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>Well, my brother, what's it going to be? Your nation, or a life of treachery?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Stops drinking from a cup.</i>] Choose treachery, it's more fun! [<i>Winks and gives a thumbs up sign.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actor Zuko walks toward Actor Iroh.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>No way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Pushes Actor Iroh over and walks to Actress Azula.</i>] I hate you, Uncle! You smell, and I hate you for all time!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Earth Kingdom flag falls on Actor Iroh as Actress Azula and Actor Iroh exit.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko.</i>] You didn't really say that, did you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I might as well have.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actress Mai, who pulls a sword out of her hair and gives it to a ninja, who takes a guard away. The shot changes to show the stage is set up to resemble the Earth King's throne room. Actress Ty Lee jumps to the other guard, kisses her finger and touches the guard's shoulder, causing him to fall over. Actress Azula jumps behind Actress Ty Lee and they pose. The audience applauds. Actress Aang jumps in from behind the set.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>Avatar State, yip yip!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The stage light shines on Actress Aang, causing her tattoos and eyelids to glow. A stagehand runs across the stage and ties a rope to Actress Aang. Actress Aang closes her eyes while the rope lifts her into the air. Actress Azula jumps on stage from behind the smoke.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>Not if my lightning can help it!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Azula throws a blue streamer at Actress Aang. Actress Aang peeks from behind her closed eye and grabs blue streamer, shaking and screaming in feigned pain. The audience looks at the scene in shock. Actress Aang's limp body is slowly lowered to the stage. Actresses Ty Lee and Mai pose on both sides of Actress Azula, who stands in front of Actress Aang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>The Avatar is no more!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Audience applauds loudly, while Team Avatar again gives disgusted looks. </i>
<p><i>Fade to outside the theater, where everyone except Aang is present for the second intermission.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>It seems like every time there's a big battle, you guys barely make it out alive. I mean, you guys lose a lot!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You're one to talk, Suki. Didn't Azula take you captive? That's right, she did!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks at Sokka seriously.</i>] Are you trying to get on my bad side?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm just saying ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Does anyone know where Aang is?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>He left to get me fire gummies, like, ten minutes ago. And I'm still waiting!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I'm gonna check outside.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Aang standing alone on a balcony. Katara enters and walks up to him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Are you all right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Angered.</i>] No, I'm not! I hate this play! [<i>Yanks his hat off and throws it on the ground.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I know it's upsetting, but it sounds like you're overreacting.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Overreacting? If I hadn't blocked my chakra, I'd probably be in the Avatar State right now!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the rest of Team Avatar inside the building. A kid wearing an Aang costume runs by.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Suki, what are the chances you can get me backstage? I got some jokes I want to give to the actor me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Seriously.</i>] I'm an elite warrior who's trained for many years in the art of stealth. [<i>Smiling.</i>] I think I could get you backstage! [<i>Sokka and Suki leave.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko, after observing everyone's reactions.</i>] Geez, everyone's getting so upset about their characters. Even you seem more down than usual, and that's saying something!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You don't get it, it's different for you. You get a muscly version of yourself, taking down ten bad guys at once, and making sassy remarks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Yeah, that's pretty great!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>But for me, it takes all the mistakes I've made in my life, and shoves them back in my face. My uncle, he's always been on my side, even when things were bad. He was there for me, he taught me so much, and how do I repay him? With a knife in his back. It's my greatest regret, and I may never get to redeem myself.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Sits down next to him.</i>] You have redeemed yourself to your uncle. You don't realize it, but you already have.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>How do you know?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Because I once had a long conversation with the guy, and all he would talk about was you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Yeah, and it was kind of annoying.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Oh, sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>But it was also very sweet. All your uncle wanted was for you to find your own path, and see the light. Now you're here with us. He'd be proud. [<i>Punches Zuko on the shoulder.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Ow! What was that for?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>That's how I show affection.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The same boy with the Aang costume comes by and sees Zuko.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young boy
</th>
<td>Your Zuko costume's pretty good, but your scar's on the wrong side. [<i>Runs off.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>The scar's not on the wrong side! [<i>Covers his face with his hood.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to backstage as the actors talk with each other and prepare their costumes. Sokka and Suki peek backstage and spot Actor Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>He's coming this way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka jumps out in front of Actor Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Can I help you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Actually, I think I can help you. I'm a big Sokka fan, but I don't think you're representing him quite as well as you could be.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Starts walking away.</i>] Aww no, another fan with ideas.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Runs in front of him.</i>] Just hear me out. [<i>Pulls out some cards.</i>] Here's something I think the real Sokka would say. [<i>Clears throat.</i>] What does the cabbage merchant use to fix his cabbages? A cabbage patch!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Suki gives herself a face palm in the background.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Chuckles.</i>] That's actually pretty good! Let me see those! [<i>Takes the cards from Sokka. Reads one and laughs.</i>] "A rocky relationship" ... not bad!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Puts his arm around Actor Sokka's shoulder.</i>] Also, don't be afraid to make up some phrases, especially before an attack. Something like ... "Flying kick-a-pow!". [<i>The two begin to walk away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Who are you, anyway?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm just a guy who likes comedy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the full moon. The shot changes to show Katara and Aang alone on the balcony.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Katara, did you really mean what you said in there?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>In where? What are you talking about?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>On stage, when you said I was just like a ... brother to you, and you didn't have feelings for me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I didn't say that. An actor said that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>But it's true, isn't it? We kissed at the Invasion, and I thought we were gonna be together. But we're not.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang, I don't know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Why don't you know?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Because, we're in the middle of a war, and, we have other things to worry about. This isn't the right time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Well, when is the right time?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang, I'm sorry, but right now I'm just a little confused.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang tries to kiss Katara.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I just said I was confused! I'm going inside. [<i>Exits the balcony.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Ugh, I'm such an idiot! [<i>Puts down his head on the balcony railing.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to back inside the theater. Aang returns to the rest of the group and sits in the back row with Suki and Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Here's what you missed ... we went to the Fire Nation, and you got better, and Katara was the Painted Lady, and I got a sword, and I think Combustion Man died. Oh, look, the Invasion's about to start! Shhh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actresses Katara and Aang standing on one of the submarines.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Katara
</th>
<td>I just wanted to let you know, Aang, that I'll always love you. Like a brother.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Punching the air.</i>] I wouldn't want it any other way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two shake hands. Actress Aang opens his miniature glider and flies up via a rope. Actress Katara waves. Aang curls up and uses his hat to cover his face. Actress Katara and Actors Toph and Sokka looking around on top of the submarine.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>Hey Toph, would you say you and Aang have a "rocky relationship"? [<i>Audience laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs hysterically at Suki and Aang. Lifts up Aang's hat.</i>] I told him to say that!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>I hope everyone's ready for the Invasion! Slap-a-pow! [<i>The audience and Sokka laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The curtain rises, two stagehands clad in black finish pushing the Royal Palace prop and run off stage. Actress Katara and Actors Toph and Sokka enter from the sides of the stage, while Actress Aang is dropped in from above the stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>We finally made it to the Royal Palace, but no one's home!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Enter Actor Zuko, stage right and Actor Sokka raises his boomerang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Actually, I'm home, and I want to join you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Lowers his boomerang.</i>] I guess we have no choice. Come on! [<i>All exit stage left, except for Actress Aang, who is lifted off stage.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Stands up and stretches.</i>] I guess that's it. The play's caught up to the present now.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Wait, the play's not over!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Sits back down.</i>] But it is over, unless ... [<i>Dramatically.</i>] this is the future.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Actor Ozai on stage. The shot changes to show him standing on the Royal Palace prop. An orange lantern held by a small cable with paper flames slowly moves across the stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Ozai
</th>
<td>With the energy harnessed from that comet, no one will be able to stop ... [<i>Lifts his hands in the air.</i>] the Fire Nation!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Azula enters.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>Father, Zuko and the Avatar are at the Palace. They're trying to stop you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Ozai
</th>
<td>You take care of Zuko. I shall face the Avatar myself! [<i>Disappears behind a smokescreen.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actor Zuko jumps on stage and a rope lowers Actress Aang on stage as he holds his miniature glider prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Aang! You find the Fire Lord, I'll hold her off!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The cable lifts Actress Aang off stage.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>You are no longer my brother. You are an enemy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>No! I am the rightful heir to the throne!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>We'll see!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Azula pulls out her blue streamer and snaps it at Zuko who ducks out of the way. Actor Zuko holds two red streamers and jumps to the other side of Actress Azula. He throws his two red streamers at her and Actress Azula jumps over him. Actress Azula raises her hand not holding the blue streamer. Five red paper resembling flames shot from the ground starting at Actress Azula, the last one covering Actor Zuko so that only his silhouette can be seen.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Zuko
</th>
<td>Honor! [<i>He drops off stage through a trapdoor with the flames.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actress Azula bows. The audience cheers. Zuko looks worried and the rest of Team Avatar looks at him. The shot changes to show the stage, which has small paper flames fluttering upstage. Actress Aang walks across the stage and looks around while Actor Ozai sits on his throne beneath the Sozin's Comet prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Ozai
</th>
<td>So, you have mastered all four elements?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing her staff prop at him.</i>] Yeah, and now you're going down!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Ozai
</th>
<td>No! It is <i>you</i> who are going down! [<i>Stands up.</i>] You see, you are too late! The comet is already here, [<i>Actress Aang looks in concern at the audience. Aang widens his eyes.</i>] and I'm unstoppable!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Actor Ozai wields two red streamers. He attacks Actress Aang, who jumps out of the way. Actress Aang opens her glider, which now has two small blue banners pop out. She twirls the weapon. Actor Ozai circles his streamers while Actress Aang jumps over him with the help of a rope. She tries to get close to Actor Ozai, but Actor Ozai makes her back away using his red streamers. Actress Aang jumps over Actor Ozai, who fires a constant stream of red streamers at her. When Actress Aang lands, Actor Ozai sends a large red sheet painted as fire at her. A black clad stagehand lets go of the prop and runs away.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Becomes wrapped in the fire blanket.</i>] Noooo ...! [<i>Falls to the stage with her eyes closed.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actress Azula
</th>
<td>It is over, Father. We've done it!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Actor Ozai
</th>
<td>Yes! We have done it! The dreams of my father, [<i>Large fire sheets rise behind him and a platform lifts him up.</i>] and my father's father, have now been realized! [<i>A Fire Nation flag drops.</i>] The world ... is ... mine!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The audience, except Team Avatar, cheers loudly and gives a standing ovation. Team Avatar is noticeably concerned by the events.</i>
<p><i>Fade to outside the theater, as Team Avatar is walking away, all of them showing annoyed looks.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>That ... wasn't a good play.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I'll say.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>No kidding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Horrible.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>You said it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walking with Suki.</i>] But the effects were decent.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>]