<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Bryan Konietzko, co-creator and executive producer of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hey, this is Mike DiMartino, uh, the other creator and co-executive producer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie Flower
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Jessie Flower, and I play Toph.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack DeSena
</th>
<td>And this is Jack DeSena, I play the voice of Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Cool, thanks for coming, guys.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah! [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, this episode is episode uh, what is it, 317, "The Ember Island Players".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And this is kind of a-the <i>Avatar</i> version of a-of a clip show. [<i>Jack and Jessie chuckle.</i>] I remember when uh, the-the original like impetus for this idea was, was from one of the writers, Tim Hedrick. He pitched this like crazy idea of-of a band of, uh, like performers who were acting out the <i>Avatar</i> story, and at the time, I remember, we were all like, "ah, that's a funny idea, but that-that's a crazy episode, we'll never make that one," but, [<i>Laughs.</i>] later on in the season we-we realized, "wait, that would be the perfect episode for kind of a-a, a lead in to the big finale episode that comes after this."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>So, was the intention to like create a-a situation where people could catch up and like recap the whole series?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Kind of, we wanted-we wanted to like, you know, kinda s-show where we'd been and how far we'd come, but not just do, you know, a typical [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] clip show, so. [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>In season-in season two we had a similar thing with uh, "The Guru" episode, where that was sort of a clips episode too, but again it was like the <i>Avatar</i> version, it was like Aang mediating over these, these past events in his life [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and how they were kinda gumming up his spirituality, and then in this one again, yeah, it's like r-kind of the culmination of everything they've done and how far they've come, and, and uh, it's just kind of a weird thing for them to see their lives played before them, and then to see the Fire Nation's point of view of how it will all end.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka jovially saying that going to see a play is the wacky stuff he's missed doing.</i>] Wait, shh, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] Jack's coming up. [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] Listen. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] So, did you guys have a-have a fun time uh, working on the show and stuff?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Oh, I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... loved it, yeah. It's been absolutely amazing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>It's so fun, just like watching all of the reactions, and-of like the characters when I say stuff. [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>] So, I don't know, sometimes...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, I-I-I've been, I've been a really big fan of the show the entire time, and-and I have a lot of friends, um, who are-are very obsessed with it. Just the-the, I'm-I've been really pleased with how excited like how e-people my age, I'm twenty, and I-I'm in college, and there are like so many people my age who are really, really enthused by it, and I've had friends who I was [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] like friends with for a couple years and who hadn't realized I had, was on the show, and then found out...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... in the-like season three, and I'm just completely freaked out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Ah, that's funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>That happens with me too, and they end up asking me so many questions, and they're just like, "oh my gosh, that's so cool!" [<i>Jessie and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Well, it's been crazy for us 'cause, I mean, we're already old, but you guys, [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] we've-we have been working with you for years, and, I mean, I-I think Jack, we started working with you in 2003.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I mean, for the pilot, [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] or, maybe 2000, yes, 2003.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Jack was eight when he started. [<i>Bryan and Jessie laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] The voice breaks were a lot less forced [<i>Mike, Bryan and Jessie laugh.</i>] then.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And uh, Jessie, I think you first played in uh, chapter 114, right? You were... a different...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, at the beginning of season two, like the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Season one, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, well, your first-you came and did a-a voice for Meng, do you remember her?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] she's so funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was the cute girl that Aang, or she had a crush on Aang in "The Fortuneteller"...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] In 'The Fortuneteller".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>With the pigtails. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And then, yeah, and then when we, when we had the character of Toph, we were like, "we gotta get that girl wi-she was really cute. [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>] With the, had a lot of s-sass to her, you know."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Every-I don't-Mike's usually in the records, and I'm not usually in them, but every time I see Jessie, she's about a foot taller, [<i>Jessie and Jack laugh.</i>] so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>It was fun doing an audition for Toph 'cause the very first script that I did, it was fighting the big Boulder guy in the wrestling match.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>And I was actually in Indiana with my grandparents at the time, and so, I-my grandma was there like doing The Boulder, [<i>Mike, Bryan, and Jack laugh.</i>] and, so, it was really hilarious, she was like, [<i>In a high-pitched threatening tone.</i>] "oh, I'm going to get you!" in a high voice, and it was so funny. It was so fun though.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's funny. So, is it weird see your-your voices coming out of some drawing of a character?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Well, I've gotten used to it now, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] 'cause like every time I see Toph, I'm like, "oh, that's me." [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah, I have this weird sense of recognition with the character where I look at it and it's obviously not me, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] and it's a drawing, and-but, I-I feel like, "oh, that's me, [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] that's what I do."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>You're like, "oh, I was really cold on set that day." [<i>Jessie and Jack affirm; chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the actor performing Sokka in the play.</i>] Who did-uh, did Dee do my-Dee did my voice in this episode, right? In like actor portraying me?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>N-oh, the actor who played-no, that was Scott Menville actually did the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Actor Sokka. [<i>Refers to the some of the various caricatured characters portrayed in the play.</i>] Dee played, uh, Dee Baker, who usually does Appa and the-all the animals, he, he played Jet, I think he played King Bumi, [<i>Jack gives an affirming murmur.</i>] Actor King Bumi, I think, and uh, uh, the Fire Lord at the end, which doesn't sound like him at all, but he did an awesome job with the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] And then uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... the overacting Fire Lord. [<i>Jack affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>Refers to the actress performing Katara in the play.</i>] and Grey DeLisle, who usually [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] does Azula, did actress Katara, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] which is uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Oh really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... which I, actually working on the episode, didn't know. Mike told me a little while later.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the actress performing Aang in the play.</i>] And then uh, actor Aang is played by Rachel Dratch, who you, uh, used to be on <i>Saturday Night Live</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In an excited tone.</i>] Really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In a surprised tone.</i>] Oh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Oh man, I love her. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>She's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Aang in the play being portrayed by a woman.</i>] Why did you choose to like make Aang a girl in the... the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Well...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie.
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background; laughs.</i>] The...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... it's sort of a self-referential joke. Whenever you do a animated show, they usually want to cast, uh, women who are like in their thirties to play boys, [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>] because you never know how long the show is going to go on, and, you know, as Jack mentioned earlier, boys' voices start cracking, but...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... Mike and I were always, uh, we just insisted that the kids had to be kids, and um, you know, that's why we got you guys, and since the sh-the show is, you know, it's a continuous storyline over like about the course of a year, we-we didn't mind if-if people grew up and-and [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] kinda aged 'cause we planned on the characters [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] maturing and stuff. So, um, yeah, so that was kind of a joke is like they would cast [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] Aang as this Sandy Duncan type, [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] uh, [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>] you know, Peter Pan type character, so we just did an extreme caricature of that. [<i>Refers to Momo being a puppet operated by Aang's actor.</i>] And it's every-I mean, everything in this episode is just a, [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] just, we're kind of making fun of ourselves before anyone [<i>Laughs.</i>] else does. [<i>Jack laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>It's so funny. Wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I can't wait for the fans to actually try to put on this play sometime. [<i>Jack and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I know. That would be [<i>Laughs.</i>] amazing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] We-yeah, someone sent us some, some clips online of like... [<i>Sighs.</i>] I just-I don't even know what convention it was, but it was like everybody was in costume, and they were putting on these plays that they had written as the characters that were like... [<i>Jack chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh my gosh, that's so cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... really strange, but here-here's a-a complete, well almost complete, play that they could re-enact.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until the play starts retelling the events of "The Waterbending Scroll", with Jack, Mike, and Jessie laughing as the on-stage Sokka asks Katara's character why she stole the scroll in a comedically whiny voice.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We actually used-worked with Scott, uh, who did Actor Sokka, back, I mean, that was one of the first jobs we did together was on <i>Mission Hill</i>, a WB show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Gives an affirming murmur.</i>] Yeah, I remember that show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He was um, Kevin French.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the caricatured Blue Spirit, the now cartoonish mask large enough to encompass the actor's entire body.</i>] I like how the Blue Spirit suddenly had a giant [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] head. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Easter Island Blue Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He only...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Nice touch.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... faces forward. [<i>Bryan and Jessie laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Blue Spirit actor waving his swords around in the air, as he pantomimes taking down the Fire Nation extras.</i>] And all the like dorky action that happens.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the basic special effects the Ember Island Players use to simulate fantastical elements like bending, namely with colored streamers, props, and wires.</i>] I think one of the, when we were talking with the storyboard artists at the beginning, trying to plan out this episode, uh, you know, we wanted it to feel like it was a real play that these people really could've put on. [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>] So, there's, you know, there's all these kind of practical effects that they use [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] for the, for the fire and the water [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] and stuff like that. [<i>Refers to the painted stylized backdrops that represent the places Team Avatar visited.</i>] And... I think uh, did Aldina Dias design the uh, backdrops and stuff?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, Aldina, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] Aldina and I, um, she designed all these backdrops based on the locations, because [<i>Jessie chuckles intermittently.</i>] we figured, you know, a lot of it was hearsay and, "oh, what it-what does-what does that place look like?" and you know, just their-their idea of what Omashu might look like, or the Northern, you know, the peo-these-these actors in the Fire Nation probably have never been to the North Pole. They just asked some soldier or sailor from the war. [<i>Jack affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Zuko actor's costume.</i>] Yeah, there's funny little details of like that Zuko's scar is actually like a, kind of like a mask that's on the wrong side of his face.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's the Phantom of the Opera type thing. [<i>Mike affirms; refers to the Ember Island Theater.</i>] And uh, Elsa Garagarza did a great job, uh, designing this theatre, I think it-it really feels like a real place, just like a...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Aang's actress, now dressed in an Ocean Spirit "Koizilla" costume, kicking miniature Fire Nation ships, re-enacting the Siege of the North.</i>] And with this like <i>Ultraman</i> [<i>Jessie and Mike chuckle.</i>] giant fish.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>With little toy ships...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>... [<i>Laughs.</i>] going across the stage.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah, there's lots of... [<i>Refers to the little Zhao doll in the Aang actress' hand.</i>] you did notice the little-little toy Zhao...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah, right. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... [<i>Laughs.</i>] in his hand as well. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] So, how did you guys like working with uh, Andrea, the voice director?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Oh, she just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Andrea is so sweet. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] She's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah, and she-I mean, she really knows how to get out of me whatever needs to be gotten, um, especially like as we transitioned towards the end of season one to more dramatic material, um, at the like North Pole and stuff. She definitely was able to... tailor the recording sessions to really get out of me what needed to be gotten, and um, yeah, help me reach the place I needed to be.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, and she knows like the exact words to use when she's trying to get me to say a line like a certain way. And like when you're trying to say something, sometimes it's really hard to like come up with that s-exact word that you need, but she just comes up with it, and then I get it, and it's, she's just great at directing it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>And at this point, three seasons in, she has such a, a di-a strong grasp of what we can do and where our strong points are, [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>] and then helping us get past like-I-I have a very hard time laughing on cue.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, I remember that. [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>And, uh, it's getting easier and easier, and she really knows how to help me through it. Just 'cause in real life, I either have like a huge [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] belly laugh or just a smirk, [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>] I don't have like a small, medium laugh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's what's funny though, is a lot of Sokka's laughs, which kind of are like in-your, you know, har-hard-to laugh on cue sort of laughs, but [<i>Laughs.</i>] they actually turned out really funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Right. They're kind of just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] 'Cause they're...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... when he goes...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Jack spontaneously does an overly pronounced and wacky laugh for a few seconds, similar to the one Sokka does when his actor counterpart on stage reads some of the former's jokes, and causing Mike, Bryan, and Jessie to laugh in turn.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>But I'm getting there, I think I can do it soon.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Don't you guys just wish Andrea had a little bit more energy though? Low...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] What? [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... she's a little low key, right? [<i>Brief pause; in a hushed tone.</i>] Just kidding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was a joke.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Oh yeah. [<i>Jessie and Jack laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>For the audience out there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the play adapting Team Avatar's adventures.</i>] So, as they review all of these adventures, do you guys have any favorite, uh, episodes that you-that you acted in?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I don't, well I like the ones that I'm in, [<i>Mike, Bryan, and Jack laugh.</i>] those are definitely the best.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yeah, I mean, I really liked the-the stuff at the North Pole where I got to try something a little bit more [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] serious was a lot of fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I like that time where the owl was like chasing us, I thought that was really cool 'cause it was like, I don't know, it seemed like all scientific with the whole like underground thing, it was just really cool, and then like an owl, it was just kind of like weird 'cause it was like bigger and, I don't know, it was fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>S-so, that was 210 and 211, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] you-you guys liked...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] So, yeah, we all like the middle... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... the middle of the-middle of the... [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>No-oh, and uh, no, it's season three, uh, when I got to have a huge sword, [<i>Everyone laughs.</i>] very exciting for me, I re-I read just the title of that episode, and knew that I was getting a huge sword, [<i>Bryan and Jessie laugh.</i>] and I'm so sad...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] A space sword.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Yes, a huge asteroid... sword.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary as the play re-enacts the events of "The Drill", with Aang's actress throwing down prop rocks at Azula's actress and the Fire Nation drill prop.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>You guys get really excited when you're like the main character in the episode?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yes. [<i>Mike, Jack and Jessie laugh.</i>] You can say a lot of stuff...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, sorry...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>... it's fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... sorry Jessie, you didn't-Toph didn't get too many like full episodes this season...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh, no...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... she only had like a couple.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>... it was fun. [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>] I'm...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>I like-I like, it-it goes back and forth for me, I mean, I like the episode where Sokka's kind of the A-story and there's a lot of-driving him, but a lot of the really fun stuff for me came when I was just the B-story, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and it was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... just Sokka goofing off.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Oh yeah, we-the one we, the commentary we just did with uh, Dante and-and Andrea was uh, 316, one right before this, and it's um, really serious Katara-Zuko story, but-it's-it's probably the most serious story we ever did, but it has some of the funniest Sokka stuff in it where you wanted to borrow Momo, and where you were in-you were in the tent [<i>Jack affirms intermittently.</i>] waiting-waiting [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] for Suki, and Zuko comes in. [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] That was very fun to do the uh, ADR for, just to fill in all the little sounds of my anticipation and excitement waiting in the tent. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A pause in commentary until Katara questions if the reimagined depiction of "The Crossroads of Destiny", namely Zuko's joining with Azula and betrayal of Iroh, and his actor yelling at Iroh's that he hates him for all time, was what actually happened, to which Zuko ashamedly says it might as well have.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>See, I think this is-this is a fun episode because that's-as goofy as all of that was, then, you know, you, you've gone along with these characters, and-and to see Zuko's reaction, it, [<i>Jack affirms.</i>] I don't know, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] it's really serious, you-you kind of understand the weight of it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary as the actress playing Ty Lee, after kissing her fingers, pokes an Earth Kingdom soldier extra, causing him to pretend to comically seize up and fall as though he were paralyzed, to which Bryan chuckles.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That was the little Vulcan death grip [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] from Ty Lee, no one really understood [<i>Jessie affirms intermittently.</i>] how it worked in the, [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] in the play. [<i>Refers to Actress Aang "activating" the Avatar State, closing her eyes, with her eyelids glowing as the stage lighting shuts off.</i>] So, Mike actually did this, this-this thing where her eyelids are painted with glow-in-the-dark...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, that's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... paint. Yeah, Mike did that for Halloween one year, [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] you-you dressed up as Aang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I remember that. [<i>Mike chuckles; Bryan affirms.</i>] I walked through the little thing, and I thought it was like a, I thought you were fake, and then we walked closer... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh, I remember, I heard his voice through, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] I heard his voice through the haunted house, he goes-he's like, "hi Jessie," and you were like. [<i>Gives a mock scream of horror.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I was like, [<i>Mike laughs; in a mock tone of surprise.</i>] "wah! What the heck!"
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah, I forgot I scared you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>And-yeah, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] you did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>She thought you were a statue.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, I thought you were like a mannequin [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] that had glow-in-the-dark paint on. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] This was a great read, Jack. Ah, this cracked me up every time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>What is it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>The line Bryan was referring to plays, as after Suki jokingly mentions all the times Team Avatar have lost in the play, Sokka sarcastically retorts by bringing up Suki's own loss and capture to Azula, causing Suki to coldly frown at him, making all the commentators laugh.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That sort of reminds me of my relationship with my girlfriend. [<i>Jack, Jessie and Mike laugh; refers to Katara going to check on a distraught Aang.</i>] And again, just seeing, you know, it's-it's all goofy and fun and recounting all the, the tales, but it, I really like seeing how it affects... [<i>Jack and Jessie affirm.</i>] the kids.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Right, I think that it's a really well, well written story.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>It's cool to see how it-what the feelings of the characters are, like of themselves.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's one fun thing about <i>Avatar</i>, coming from like sitcom animated shows, no one really has any feelings, [<i>Bryan, Jack, and Jessie laugh.</i>] it's all just a joke...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Ah-that's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... so, it's, I mean, it's fun to do comedy, but, but, I don't know, it just, it-it has more weight to me when you actually believe that they're people with feelings and stuff. [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>That-and that's my-my favorite thing about this show. When-when I was growing up on cartoons, I can't remember a show where-that had to have a "Previously On" [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] in order to watch it, [<i>Bryan laughs intermittently.</i>] and it's so exciting to me to be part of something that's so serial and tells such a story.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>The whole... all of the seasons is such a great story. It's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Thank you. [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] I feel like-I feel very weird whenever like people compliment me on the show and say like, "I really love your show," I always have to say, "me too". [<i>Mike, Jessie and Bryan laugh.</i>] I, like I feel so, like it's so much out of my hands...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Well, I mean...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... there's such a beautiful story being told, and I-I just pop in with little silly sounds, [<i>Mike and Jessie chuckle.</i>] and I feel like way more of a fan of the show than a... participant.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>But, you know, I-it took, and it's still taking so many people, and-and the talents and hard work and dedication of so many people, and it's um, you know, everybody's just doing a great job, and we have great actors, great voice direction, great writing, and just all the way down the line. And-and, so, I mean, even though Mike and I created this, and this all came out of our heads six years ago, it's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] About time. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... we're-we're fans of it too, and we're just along for the ride in the same time...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Jessie laughs as Toph affectionately punches Zuko in the arm after their talk about Iroh's love for his nephew.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... so, it's um, it's ki-it's kinda nice to be able to just step outside of it and enjoy it, which was always our goal, was to make something that we liked.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Right. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Zuko angrily tries to rebuke another play attendee for saying his scar is on the wrong side of his face, to which Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That-I feel like, I feel like Zuko there when I'm at the conventions, and people ask some question [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] and they get really angry, and they're telling-like trying to correct me on <i>Avatar</i>, and I'm like, [<i>In a mock enraged tone.</i>] "hey!" [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Another brief pause in commentary until Sokka, in a rapid movement, moves behind the actor portraying himself.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like Sokka's zippy movements here. [<i>Makes a sound akin to air rushing.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yes. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>The commentary pauses again as Sokka gives some of his personal comedic material for his actor counterpart to work with, Suki facepalming in the background as Sokka deliver his cabbage-related punchline.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock exasperated tone.</i>] Oh Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] I want to pull my collar when I do it. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh; makes a buzzing noise.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] You do sometimes wonder what Suki sees in him, [<i>Jack laughs; Jessie affirms.</i>] you know, a little bit. [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>What happened? [<i>Jessie and Bryan laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Suki.</i>] She's got very nice hair. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, she does. She's good with the fan. [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Katara and Aang's conversation about their relationship.</i>] I like this, this scene breaks my heart. Poor Aang. So, are-so, which uh, side are you guys on, are you for the Aang-Katara or Aan-uh, Katara-Zuko... relationship?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Hmm...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>I don't know, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] that's hard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>I-I, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It divides nations. [<i>Jack affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yes, it does. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>And I've, you know, read the script, so I know, I feel like now I've already, I can't state an opinion. [<i>Mike and Bryan chuckle.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] But both Aang and Zuko are-have so different personalities, it's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That's where the drama...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>... it's-you have to choose which one, [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] I know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... lies. [<i>Refers to Aang kissing Katara after she just said she was confused about the developments in their relationship.</i>] Oh, Aang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>I think-I think Jet's still alive in a lake somewhere, [<i>Mike and Bryan chuckle; Jessie affirms.</i>] he's back in...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] See, there-there's a third-there's an independent party. [<i>Jessie affirms; Jack chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's the uh, that's the-one of the fake endings we made was Jet and Katara get together. [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Man, we're having [<i>Mike laughs intermittently.</i>] trouble just finishing the real ending. [<i>Bryan and Jessie laugh.</i>] We don't have any time or energy for a fake ending. [<i>Refers to Sokka summarizing the parts of the play Aang missed when he was outside, namely when the portrayed Sokka got his sword.</i>] There, you got your sword. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Oh, I did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, got his sword.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Everyone chuckles as Sokka shushes everyone and horizontally slides out of frame.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang's actress cheerfully saying to Katara's character that she wouldn't have their relationship, which Katara's actor compares to siblings, be any other way.</i>] This is a really great Rachel Dratch line here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yes. [<i>Everyone laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the enthusiastic handshake Aang and Katara's actresses perform.</i>] We talked about that handshake a lot in the uh, I think we did a specific acting reference for it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Aang's actress' tiny, improperly proportioned glider that she uses to fly around.</i>] Oh, another funny little detail I just remembered was that that little-Aang's little prop glider [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>] that he flies around with, I-I believe uh, Ben Wynn, our sound designer, actually recorded the sound of a-of the-there's a toy Aang glider that came out a few years ago...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Uh-huh. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... he actually recorded [<i>Laughs.</i>] like the sound effects of it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>When you-when you swing it around, it's like, [<i>Makes a "phwoo" sound of air gently rushing by; Mike and Jessie affirm.</i>] it does like a whole like kung fu and glider sounds.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, we wanted it to sound kinda like wimpy and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's a lot of stuff like that. [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Bryan chuckles as Aang's actress questions why no one is in the Fire Nation royal palace, enunciating every word.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko's actor.</i>] And that voice is uh, is Dante's brother, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, it is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>That's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Awesome.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Derek Basco.</i>] Another Basco brother, who I... sorry, I can't remember his first name right [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] at this moment, but...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the extra-terrestrial theme, shot tilt, and lighting change that occur as Sokka wonders if the play is depicting the future.</i>] This is a little reference to, man, what episode [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] was that? 104 or 106, where he was like, [<i>Imitates Sokka.</i>] "food eats people!". [<i>Mike and Jessie laugh.</i>] Like, what was that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Ozai's actor being illuminated by the stage lighting, the dark shadow on him coloring in as he comes into relief.</i>] So, I love, the first time I saw this animation starting when the Fire Lord comes out, I was just blown away, 'cause it's like... just seems like so real and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, it wa-some parts of it seem so cheese that you're like, "oh yeah, this is fake," but then some parts of it actually are [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] kind of seem... like it's the real.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Man, I wish I could remember that animator's name.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, [<i>Jessie chuckles.</i>] it was a...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Korean...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... woman-woman an-animator in Korea.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>At JM Animation. I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Who did all this s-stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... I would do-I would try to say her name, but I think it would [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] probably do more damage than good. [<i>Jack chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence where the portrayed Zuko and Azula, then Aang and Ozai, fight each other, using colored streamers to simulate their bending.</i>] She did this whole end section, right? With those...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, she did all the key animation, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] with just the acting...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Just this fight is just great, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>She did...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] And that was cool, we wanted the end, even though it was this cheesy play the whole time, we wanted the end to still be kind of powerful [<i>Jessie affirms intermittently.</i>] and not feel t-totally [<i>Laughs.</i>] lame. And uh, I think it... with the animation and the staging and everything, it-it did come out that way, and it... [<i>Jack and Jessie affirm.</i>] it feels...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko's distressed reaction to his actor counterpart being "defeated" by Actress Azula.</i>] I think Zuko-Zuko's reaction there is great. [<i>Mike and Jessie affirm.</i>] We um, yeah, a lot of this was sort of inspired, not-not directly, just-just the, the mood, um, from like uh, <i>Shaolin: Wheel of Life</i>, which was a, a stage show that the Shaolin monks put on with a, [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>] a London production company. And then um, and then Mike and I, when were in Beijing, we saw a really cool-we saw two, uh, we saw like a, a Shaolin stage show, and then we a really good, uh, Chinese acrobatics show. So, it was like, you know, even...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Is that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... even without fire and stuff, we knew we could make it really cool. [<i>Jack and Jessie affirm; laughs.</i>] Like this stuff's great. So, we actually...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Awesome.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... you know, [<i>Refers to Aang's actress twirling around her glider, and Ozai whipping his red streamers around.</i>] we had footage of me and Kisu swinging these... props around. [<i>Jessie and Jack laugh.</i>] I remember Sh-Sheri Wheeler, like I gave her this whole prop list, like, "get me all kinds of satin and little party streamers [<i>Jack chuckles.</i>] that we can throw around the gym," and, and um, we actually did a lot of the kung fu with these props. [<i>Refers to Aang's actress' long and drawn-out "no" after she was draped in the Fire Lord actor's "fire".</i>] Another great Rachel Dratch [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] read. [<i>Jack and Jessie laugh.</i>] Twenty-five second "no". [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Those are always fun. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the Fire Lord actor's victory speech.</i>] That's Dee, so-ri-right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>I-I'm-I'm-I'm such a big fan of his. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] I brought-I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Dee is, he's superhuman.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>... I brought in friends when I knew he was going to be doing ADR and doing Appa and Momo, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] I've had them just come and just watch, 'cause I-ah, he's amazing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar saying how awful the play was, with the exception of Sokka, who says the special effects were decent.</i>] And then, I'm not sure, but I feel like the writers might have thrown this reference in for... the uh, M. Night movie that's coming up. [<i>Jessie gives an affirming murmur; Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] That the effects were decent. Not that we don't think it's going to be awesome, but, I don't know, [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] I think that was their little jab [<i>Jack laughs.</i>] at the movie.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, well, thanks guys, thanks for...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Thank you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Thank you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... doing this whole journey with us, and uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... it's been...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It's great talking to you guys. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... several years, and hope we get to work together in the future.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah, definitely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Oh, we've had a long-that. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>That would be great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Other than, beyond the little bit of ADR that's left.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Jessie laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Two more of those. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Like another project kind of thing. [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] Yeah, cool. Thanks guys...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] But I mean, those should be great too, let's not, [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>] those last two [<i>Jessie affirms.</i>] recording sessions are going to be out of control.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>A lot of grunts. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Special.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>A lot of m-uh, uh, moaning.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>A lot of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Jack makes several grunting and moaning sounds, akin to the ones Sokka makes when he's mocking the Fire Lord's fight with Aang. Jessie also jumps in by doing a mock scream of shock.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, you, you guys are running and falling a lot, so. [<i>Bryan affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock disappointed tone.</i>] Oh, cool. [<i>Jack and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And all your actions together, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>Good.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock frustrated tone.</i>] Good!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Thanks guys.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jack
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Jessie.</i>] Thank you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Jack.</i>] Thank you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, thanks, bye!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Jessie
</th>
<td>Bye.
</td></tr></tbody></table>