[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Scene opens with the camera zoomed out showing Appa flying in above the mountains with a few viewable trees, carrying Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Momo.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Aang is pacing around on Appa's saddle, breathing heavily.</i>] Would you sit down? [<i>Turns around from his perch on Appa's head.</i>] If we hit a bump, you'll go flying off. What's bugging you anyway?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Worriedly.</i>] It's what Avatar Roku said. I'm supposed to master all four elements before that comet arrives.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>In a sarcastic, amused tone while facing Aang.</i>] Well, let's see. You pretty much mastered airbending and that only took you a hundred and twelve years. I'm sure you can master three more elements by next summer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frightfully.</i>] I haven't even started waterbending and we're still weeks away from the North Pole. What am I gonna do?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Grabs Aang's arm.</i>] Calm down, it's going to be okay. [<i>Aang sits down in front of her.</i>] If you want, I can try to teach you some of the stuff I know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiling.</i>] You'd do that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Nods and looks over the side of Appa's saddle.</i>] We'll need to find a good source of water first.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Grinning; sarcastically.</i>] Maybe we can find a puddle for you to splash in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Momo standing in front of a large waterfall and river.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frowning beside Aang and Katara's ecstatic faces.</i>] Nice puddle.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa flies down into the river and creates a huge splash that soaks and almost knocks Momo of the rock he is standing on, turns over, and floats on his back.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Takes off his shirt, smiling.</i>] Yeah! Don't start without me, boy! [<i>Begins to run toward the water.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Somewhat blankly.</i>] Remember the reason we're here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Stops short and looks at Katara.</i>] Oh right. Time to practice waterbending. [<i>Puts his clothes back on.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Great. So what am I supposed to do?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>You could ... clean the gunk out of Appa's toes. [<i>Hands Sokka a branch with a bushel of leaves at the end.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frowns and crosses his arms.</i>] So, while you guys are playing in the water, I'm supposed to be hard at work picking mud out of a giant bison's feet?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiles; somewhat cheerfully.</i>] Mud and bugs!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Okay. [<i>Takes stick and walks over to Appa who is floating in the water.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Scene changes to Zuko's ship in the ocean. On the deck, Zuko is practicing firebending with his  Lieutenant Lee when the boat turns and they are thrown to one side on their backs.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up of his face; he glares at the tower.</i>] Someone's changing our course.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to a crew member steering the ship at the top of the boat.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Storming in, yelling.</i>] What is the meaning of this mutiny? No one told you to change course! [<i>Shows Iroh and the rest of the crew playing Pai Sho behind them.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>Actually, someone did. I assure you, it is a matter of utmost importance, Prince Zuko. [<i>Scratches beard.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Hopefully.</i>] Is it something to do with the Avatar?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>Even more urgent. It seems, I- [<i>Rubs forehead in stress.</i>] -I have lost my lotus tile. [<i>Moves a piece of his across the Pai Sho board.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Confused.</i>] Lotus tile?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>For my Pai Sho game. Most people think the lotus tile insignificant, but it is essential for the unusual strategy that I employ.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>In disbelief.</i>] You've changed our course for a stupid lotus tile?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>See, you, like most people, underestimate it's value. Just give me ten minutes to check the merchants at this port of call. [<i>Excitedly.</i>] Hopefully, they will have the lotus tile in stock and I can get on with my life. [<i>Zuko breathes fire up at the ceiling in anger and Iroh smiles.</i>] I'm lucky to have such an understanding nephew.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The room fills with smoke of Zuko's outburst, clouding the scene from view.</i>
<p><i>Cut to a scene of a content Appa floating in the river while Sokka stands on his stomach and brushes in between his toes with the branch.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah, don't get too happy. You've got to do <i>me</i> next. [<i>Appa moans happily.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Shows Katara and Aang by the shore.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>This is a pretty basic move, but it still took me months to perfect. So don't get frustrated if you don't get it right away. [<i>She moves her hands back and forth and makes small waves in the water, while Aang looks up, smiling.</i>] Just push and pull the water like this. The key is getting the wrist movement right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Stands up.</i>] Like this? [<i>Does the hand movements Katara is doing, but nothing is happening yet.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Kindly.</i>] That's almost right. If you keep practicing I'm sure eventually—
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Hey, I'm bending it already! [<i>Shows Aang making much bigger waves than Katara's on his first try.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Surprised.</i>] Wow, I can't believe you got that so quickly. It took me two months to learn that move.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Shrugs shoulders.</i>] Well, you had to figure it all on your own. I'm lucky enough to have a great teacher.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiles.</i>] Thanks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>So, what's next?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>This is a more difficult move. I call it streaming the water. [<i>She moves her hands and raises a stream of water from the river into the air and moves it around.</i>] It's harder than it looks, so don't be disappointed if- [<i>Shows Aang already controlling a stream of water, moving it around and above his body and neatly coiling it back into the river, much to Katara's dismay.</i>] Nice work. [<i>She frowns.</i>] Though the over-the-head flare was unnecessary.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Sorry. [<i>Excited.</i>] Well, don't stop now! Keep 'em coming!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks up sadly.</i>] Well I kind of know this one other move, but it's pretty hard. I haven't even totally figured it out yet. The idea is to create a big, powerful wave. [<i>She moves her hands up, shaking, and starts to get a big mass of water to rise out of the river, but it pops before forming into anything substantial.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>So, like this? [<i>He raises his hands and creates a massive wave that towers over their heads.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Still working on cleaning up Appa, he looks up and stares at Aang's wave crashing toward him in fear.</i>] Aang?! [<i>The wave throws Sokka off into the water and his head slowly rises out, annoyed.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiling.</i>] Looks like I got the hang of that move! What else do you got?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angry at Aang's quick success.</i>] That's enough practicing for today.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Head still sticking out of the water.</i>] Yeah, I'll say! [<i>Points to the left.</i>] You just "practiced" our supplies down the river. [<i>Shows a group of bags floating away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Looking guilty.</i>] Uh, sorry. [<i>Smiles worriedly.</i>] I'm sure we can find somewhere to replace all this stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>My life was hard enough when you were just an airbender. [<i>Sinks back underwater.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to Katara, Sokka, and Aang walking through the streets of a city market and port. Shows many armed men staring at the trio. Sokka and Katara look nervous while Aang looks around in wonder.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walking back from alleyway with a bag over his shoulders.</i>] We've got exactly three copper pieces left from the money that King Bumi gave us. Let's spend it wisely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Uh, make that two copper pieces, Sokka. I couldn't say no to this whistle! [<i>Pulls out a white whistle that looks like a bison, takes a huge breath and blows into it, but it barely makes a sound.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Pulls out fingers over his ears after expecting a loud noise.</i>] It doesn't even work. [<i>Aang stops blowing when Momo squawks at him.</i>] See? Even Momo thinks it's a piece of junk.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>No offense Aang, but I'll hold the money from now on. [<i>Aang hands her the two copper coins.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to the other side of the port where a man is talking in front of his boat docked in the water.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>[<i>Moving hands and shouting excitedly.</i>] Earth Nation! Fire Nation! Water Nation! So long as bargains are your inclination, you're welcome here! Don't be shy, come on by! [<i>Sokka, Katara, and Aang walk by and he runs up to them.</i>] Oh! You there, I can see from your clothing that you're world-traveling types. Perhaps I can interest you in some exotic curios?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks back to the man.</i>] Sure! What are curios?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks confused and thinks.</i>] I'm not entirely sure. But we got 'em! [<i>Puts his hand on Aang's shoulder and smiles, walking him into the ship.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to the inside of the boat where strange collectibles are lined up on shelves on the walls. Aang, Katara, and Sokka walk in.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks up close at an item on a shelf, confused.</i>] Huh?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara stares at an ornate monkey statue on one of the shelves eerily.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>Standing in a dark doorway as Aang passes by with Momo on his back.</i>] I've never seen such a fine specimen of lemur. [<i>Walks into the light, an iguana parrot on his shoulder.</i>] That beast would fetch me a hefty sum if you'd be interested in bartering. [<i>The iguana parrot squawks at them.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Grabbing Momo.</i>] Momo's not for sale.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Shows Katara walking over to a shelf where a number of scrolls are kept. She grabs one with the waterbending symbol on it and opens it to see lines of waterbending diagrams and writing.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiling.</i>] Look at this, Aang. It's a waterbending scroll! [<i>Aang walks over.</i>] Check out these crazy moves.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns to the captain, excited.</i>] Where did you get a waterbending scroll?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>Slams his hand onto the scroll and pulls it away.</i>] Let's just say I got it up North, at a most reasonable price, free. [<i>Rolls the scroll back up and puts it away back in its shelf.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around and looks at the captain from the other side of the room.</i>] Wait a minute ... Sea loving traders, with suspiciously acquired merchandise, [<i>Raises eyebrows, almost yelling.</i>] and pet reptile birds? [<i>Turns around to Oh, almost spitting in his face.</i>] You guys are pirates!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>[<i>Puts his arm around a terrified Sokka's shoulders.</i>] We prefer to think of ourselves as "high risk traders."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to Katara holding their two copper pieces next to Aang, with the captain on the other side of the counter they are leaning on.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>So, how much for the, uh, <i>traded</i> scroll?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>I've already got a buyer, a nobleman in the Earth Kingdom. [<i>Voice turns less serious.</i>] Unless of course, you kids have two hundred gold pieces on you right now.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around and whispers to Katara.</i>] I know how to deal with these guys, Katara. Pirates love to haggle. [<i>Katara drops the final coins in his hand.</i>] Watch and learn. [<i>Walks over to the counter, leans against it, and talks in a pirate voice.</i>] Let's say to the price of, one copper piece! [<i>Smiles, and dramatically presents the single coin.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs hysterically.</i>] The price is two hundred gold pieces. I don't haggle on items this rare.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Still smirking and talking like a pirate.</i>] Okay, two copper pieces!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>Aggravated.</i>] It's not as amusing the second time, boy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Whispering.</i>] Aang, can we get out of here? I feel like we're getting weird looks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Aye, we be casting off now! [<i>Walks away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts back to outside, Aang, Katara, and Sokka are walking off the boat and back down the street.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>What was that all about, Katara?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah, I was just starting to browse through their boomerang collection.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Worried, holding her arms.</i>] I'll just feel a lot better once we get away from here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts back to the pirate ship. Oh is running across the deck looking for them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>Hey you! Get back here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Calmly turns around.</i>] Well, well. Look who's come to their senses. Told you the haggling would pay off.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Suddenly, the group of armed pirates jump out of the boat and run to Aang, Katara, and Sokka, whispering menacingly and swinging their weapons.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Scared.</i>] I don't think these pirates are here to trade with us. [<i>Turns around and runs, Aang and Sokka follow and the pirates chase behind them. Half of the group runs down one street while the other goes down the one next to it.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>This way. Let's cut 'em off!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Turning a corner with Aang and Katara.</i>] Whoa! [<i>Katara freezes a puddle behind them that a pirate slips on.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to peaceful scene of the cabbage merchant with his cart of cabbages in an alleyway. Sokka, Katara, and Aang run past him and almost knock his cart over. Aang sends a blast of wind that throws the cart into the group of pirates behind them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Cabbage merchant
</th>
<td>[<i>Angry.</i>] My cabbages! This place is worse than Omashu!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Group of pirates jump out of another street and chase Aang, Sokka, Katara, and Momo.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate
</th>
<td>I hope that lemur of yours has nine lives!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>[<i>Him and the pirates corner them in the dead end of a street.</i>] Now, who gets to taste the steel of my blade first?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>No thanks. [<i>Spins and hurls a blast of air at the pirates that send them backward, and runs toward them with his glider out.</i>] Grab on tight!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang! I thought we were running <i>away</i> from the pirates! [<i>Jumps on to Aang's glider with Sokka and they lift off into the air.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Just hang on! [<i>Flies over the pirates' heads and into the distance.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts back to their camp by the river, where Aang, Sokka, and Katara stand by the shore.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Putting his glider away.</i>] I used to kind of look up to pirates, but those guys are terrible.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Mischievously.</i>] I know. That's why I took this. [<i>Holds out the waterbending scroll they saw in the shop.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Surprised.</i>] No way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Excited.</i>] Isn't it great?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No wonder they were trying to hack us up! You stole their waterbending scroll!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Jokingly.</i>] I prefer to think of it as high risk trading.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Good one, Katara.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Sokka, where do you think <i>they</i> got it? They stole it from a waterbender!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>It doesn't matter. You put all of our lives in danger just so you could learn some stupid, fancy splashes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>These are <i>real</i> waterbending forms. You know how crucial it is for Aang to learn waterbending!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks away.</i>] Whatever.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Well, what's done is done. We have it, we might as well learn from it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene cuts to show Zuko and Iroh standing in the market place.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>I've checked all the shops on this pier. Not a lotus tile in the entire marketplace.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>It's good to know this trip was a complete waste of time <i>for everyone</i>!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>Quite the contrary. I always say, the only thing better than finding something you are looking for [<i>Crew members begin to walk past carrying Iroh's purchases.</i>] is finding something you weren't looking for at a great bargain! [<i>A crew member walks past the two playing a tsungi horn.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You bought a tsungi horn?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>For music night on the ship. Now, if we only had some woodwinds. [<i>Pointing to the ship.</i>] Oh, this place looks promising! [<i>The monkey statue is shown again.</i>] Oh, that is handsome! Wouldn't it look magnificent in the galley?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>[<i>To pirate captain.</i>] We lost the Water Tribe girl and the little bald monk she was traveling with.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Turning.</i>] This monk, did he have an arrow on his head? [<i>Iroh turns around, making a face similar to the monkey's.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera cuts show Katara looking at the scroll.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I just want to try this one move first and then it's all yours. [<i>Gives it to Aang.</i>] Here, hold it open for me. The single water whip. Looks doable. [<i>Attempts the move, but ends up hitting herself in the forehead.</i>] Ow!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Ha, ha, ha!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Glaring at Sokka.</i>] What's so funny?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm sorry, but you deserved that. [<i>To Aang.</i>] You've been duped; she's only interested in teaching herself.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] Aang will get his turn once I figure out the water whip. [<i>She tries again, but hits Momo instead, who screeches.</i>] Ugh, why can't I get this stupid move?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>You'll get it. [<i>Katara glares at him.</i>] You just gotta shift your weight through the stances. [<i>He tries and does it perfectly on the first try.</i>] There, see, the key to bending is—
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Screaming.</i>] Will you please shut your air hole? Believe it or not your infinite wisdom gets a little old sometimes! Why don't we just throw the scroll away since you're so naturally gifted! [<i>Sokka glares at her.</i>] What? [<i>She looks back at Aang, who has tears in his eyes.</i>] Oh my gosh, Aang, I am so sorry, I don't know what came over me. But you know what, it won't happen again. [<i>She gives the scroll to Aang.</i>] Here, this is yours. I don't want to have anything to do with it anymore.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>It's okay Katara.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What about Momo? He's the real victim here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Bends down to pet Momo as he rubs his hind end.</i>] I'm sorry, Momo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>And what about me? There was that time you—
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>No more apologies!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera fades to show a much smaller boat being launched out of Zuko's ship. The camera fades again to show the boat and the pirate ship sailing down a river.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>Shouldn't we stop to search the woods?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>We don't need to stop. They stole a waterbending scroll, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>Mm-hm.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Then they'll be on the water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene fades to show Katara, Sokka, and Aang sleeping by the campfire. Katara quietly takes the scroll and sneaks away from the camp. However, when she turns around she comes face-to-face with Momo, who starts chattering.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Whispering.</i>] Shhh, Momo! Go back to sleep. Shh! [<i>The camera fades to show her standing by the river, attempting but failing to perfect the water whip, frustrated.</i>] Ugh, ugh, ugh! Shoot! Come on water, work with me here! Okay, what if I just, ow! Stupid scroll! [<i>The pirate captain and Zuko are shown hearing her.</i>] Okay Katara, shift your weight through the stances. [<i>She drops the water again and hears the ship pulling up onto the river bank. She peaks through the bushes to see what the noise was, and gasps upon seeing the pirates. She turns to run, but it grabbed by a pirate.</i>] No! Let go of me! [<i>She bends water up into the pirate's face, and he releases her, she runs but is grabbed again on the wrists by Zuko.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>He glares at her as she looks frightfully at him.</i>] I'll save you from the pirates.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene cuts to show Katara tied to a tree with Zuko standing in front of her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Tell me where he is and I won't hurt you or your brother.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Furiously.</i>] Go jump in the river!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Try to understand. I need to capture him to restore something I've lost, my honor. [<i>Katara jerks her head away from Zuko.</i>] Perhaps in exchange I can restore something you've lost. [<i>He holds her mother's necklace up to her neck.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>My mother's necklace! How did you get that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I didn't steal it, if that's what you're wondering. <i>Tell me</i> where he is. [<i>Points at Katara.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>No!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>Enough of this necklace garbage! You promised a scroll!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I wonder how much this is worth ... [<i>The pirates gasp as he takes it out and holds it over a fire in his hand.</i>] A lot, apparently. Now you help me find what I want, you'll get this back, and everyone goes home happy. Search the woods for the boy and meet back here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>Fine.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene cuts to the campsite, where Sokka is waking up.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Notices Katara's missing.</i>] Huh? Where did she go? [<i>Looks through the bag.</i>] I don't believe it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Yawns.</i>] What's wrong?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>She took the scroll! She's obsessed with that thing. It's just a matter of time before she gets us all in deep- [<i>Yells as a pirate throws a rope around his arms and drags him forward. He rolls away and charges at the pirate while another pirate captures Aang in a net and drags him away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate
</th>
<td>I got him, come on!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Oh, what? I'm not good enough to kidnap? Ah! [<i>The pirate shoots another net at Sokka and drags him away too.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts back to the place where Zuko and the pirates are gathered. The pirates are holding Aang and Sokka, who are tied up. Sokka is struggling with the ropes.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Nice work.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang, this is all <i>my</i> fault.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>No Katara, it isn't.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>Yeah, it kind of is. [<i>Katara glares at Iroh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>To the pirate captain.</i>] Give me the boy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td><i>You</i> give <i>us</i> the scroll.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You're really gonna hand over <i>the Avatar</i> for a stupid piece of parchment?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Don't listen to him, he's trying to turn us against each other!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns to Aang.</i>] Your friend is the Avatar?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Sure is, and I'll bet he'll fetch a lot more on the black market than that fancy scroll.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Shut your mouth, you Water Tribe peasant!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Yeah, Sokka, you really should shut your mouth.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm just sayin' it's bad business sense. Think how much the Fire Lord would pay for the Avatar. You guys would be set for life.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko.</i>] Keep the scroll; we can buy a hundred with the reward we'll get for the kid. [<i>The pirates turn to leave.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You'll regret breaking a deal with me. [<i>He and two of his soldiers send a blast of fire at the pirates. The pirates jump back and Oh runs out, throwing smoke bombs and jumping into the cloud as the fight ensues. Some of the soldiers run out to Sokka and Aang, who are struggling with their ropes, but are stopped by several pirates. Momo runs down the tree and frees Katara.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Thanks, Momo. I owe you a bushel of apples. [<i>She runs to join the fight. Aang is shown lost in the smoke, a thrown knife narrowly misses him and cuts through his ropes. Zuko finds his way out of the smoke cloud and hides the scroll behind his back, but the pirate captain sees him and the two begin to fight. The scroll flies into the air and his caught by Momo, the iguana parrot sees him and hits Momo. The scroll flies back down to the ground. A knife narrowly misses Sokka's head, and he uses it to cuts the ropes on his hands.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Shouting.</i>] Aang, are you there?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I'm over here! Follow my voice!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Where? I can't find you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I'm right here! [<i>Airbends the dust away, revealing the pirates surrounding him, and immediately airbends it back around himself.</i>] Uh, never mind! I'll find you! [<i>Sokka climbs out of the dust cloud on his hands and knees. Aang vaults over him in a full sprint.</i>] Run! [<i>They find Katara, who is trying to push the pirate boat back into the water.</i>] Katara, you're okay!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Help me get this boat back in the water so we can get outta here. [<i>They join her in trying to push the boat, but can't.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We'd need a team of rhinos to budge this ship.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>A team of rhinos, or two waterbenders.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to Aang and Katara pushing and pulling the water until the boat rises up.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Everybody in!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to show Iroh breaking up the fight between the pirate captain and Zuko.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>Are you so busy fighting you cannot see your own ship has set sail?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>We have no time for your proverbs, Uncle!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>It's no proverb! [<i>Points to Team Avatar who has hijacked the pirate ship.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Pirate captain
</th>
<td>Bleeding hog monkeys! [<i>Zuko laughs while pointing at him. His laughter dissipates as the pirates hijack his own boat. The pirates taunt him and the screen pans to a steaming Zuko.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] Hey! That's <i>my</i> boat! [<i>Goes chasing after the hijacked boat.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Pondering.</i>] Maybe it should be a proverb ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Off camera.</i>] C'mon, Uncle! [<i>Iroh runs after Zuko.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Sokka, can't you make it go any faster?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I don't know how. This thing wasn't made by the Water Tribe!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Several of the pirates jump onto the ship, but are quickly swept away by Aang's waterbending. Determined, Katara performs a perfect water whip to throw the last pirate off.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Hey, you did the water whip!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I couldn't have done it without your help.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka is shown being held in place by two pirates.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Would you two quit congratulating each other and help me out?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Momo is shown still being chased by the iguana parrot; he flies up to the top mast and entangles the bird in the ship's flag. Sokka is shown being thrown by one of the pirates.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Oh
</th>
<td>That's good ... [<i>Aang lands behind him and airbends him and the other pirate off the ship before jumping down to Sokka.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing.</i>] Aang, look! [<i>The ship is shown headed toward a huge waterfall.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Oh no ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Oh comes up behind him with a knife, Aang turns and blows the bison whistle. Oh stands confused while Sokka comes up behind him and pushes him off the ship.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Have you lost your mind? This is no time for flute practice! [<i>Katara and Aang stare in horror at the approaching waterfall.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>We can stop the boat! Aang, together, push and pull the water! [<i>They create a small Whirlpool that stops the boat.</i>] It's working, it's slowing down! We're doing it!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>But we have another problem. [<i>Zuko's boat is shown sailing straight toward their ship. The boat rams into the ship and Sokka, Aang, and Katara are forced to jump as the boat goes over the falls.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Together
</th>
<td>Jump! [<i>Appa is shown flying toward them. They land on him and fly to safety.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Holding up the whistle.</i>] I knew a bison whistle would come in handy! Thanks Appa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah, we owe you one. [<i>Appa roars and the scene cuts to show Zuko running to the cliff in horror at the fact that his boat has gone over the falls.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>My boat!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Iroh
</th>
<td>[<i>Chuckles.</i>] Prince Zuko, you're really going to get a kick out of this. That lotus tile was in my sleeve the whole time! [<i>Has a big smile on his face.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko snatches the lotus tile and furiously throws it down the waterfall.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts back to Appa flying through the clouds.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang, I still owe you an apology. You were just so good at waterbending without really trying. I got so competitive that I put us all in danger, I'm sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>That's okay Katara.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Besides, who needs that stupid scroll anyway?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Holding the scroll. Sarcastically.</i>] Is that really how you feel?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>The scroll!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Puts his hand in front to keep Katara from grabbing it.</i>] First, what did you learn?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Stealing is wrong. [<i>Snatches scroll.</i>] Unless it's from pirates.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughing.</i>] Good one, Katara.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fades to credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>]