<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Mike DiMartino, co-creator and co-EP of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John O'Bryan
</th>
<td>And this is John O'Bryan, I'm the writer of the episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim Dos Santos
</th>
<td>And this is Joaquim Dos Santos, I am-was a storyboard artist on this episode, and current director on season three of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>John wrote this episode. Uh, John is also the uh, genius artist behind the style of Sokka. Uh, whenever you see Sokka's drawings, uh, you s-it's John.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>I don't mean to brag or nothing, but...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah. When you do those drawings...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... those're great drawing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... do you, what are-what're you thinking about, what's your motivation when you're-when you're...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Well, I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... creating those artistic, genius moments?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... I don't think I've drawn anything since I was in second grade. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]  So, m-my style hasn't evolved. [<i>John and Joaquim laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Excellent. So, this is another episode we kind of... the end of season two is really very continuous and a nice story arc in Ba Sing Se, and this is like "The Earth King" episode where the kids finally, finally make it to their goal of talking to the Earth King. And um, kind of culminates this uh, conspiracy storyline we began a few episodes, and stuff like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's tough to follow that last episode, the-the 217 I think is one of the best episodes in the series, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Wow, I'll tell Tim.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>This one's pretty good too. [<i>Mike and John laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>This is definitely something I have to live up to.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. I think what was kind of different about this one too, uh, Joaquim, you could talk about the storyboarding a little bit, is like act one we knew was going to be-usually act three's the big action scene or whatever, yeah...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right, this one started out with a huge bang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, 'cause we wanted the kids to really earn their way to get to talk to the king, and-and, you know, now that they, as Sokka says, now that they don't have any, uh, Long Feng doesn't have Appa to blackmail 'em anymore, they can-they can bust through.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Bust loose, and just kinda go right at them, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>I-I don't want to embarrass Joaquim or nothing, but he-he is a Brazilian jiu-jitsu practitioner... [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh, geez, please.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... and I don't know if that influences his fighting scenes [<i>John and Joaquim chuckle.</i>] and all...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh, does he?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] For those of you who are interested in that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's... do you bring any of your knowledge of martial arts to when you storyboard, Joaquim?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Uh, there's not too much grappling in <i>Avatar</i>...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>That's true.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... which jiu-jitsu kind of contains a lot of, but I think it's just a general love for all things that kick butt. [<i>Mike laughs; brief pause.</i>] So yeah, started-you know, when we started on this, or when I s-personally started on this show, it was kind of a-a-a breath of fresh air to just be able to unleash and just go, go wild as far as martial arts goes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Mike and I don't know how to do anything. [<i>Mike and John laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>You could do...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I can do a couple moves...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Could get our...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... I could probably take you down, I think...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... [<i>Laughs.</i>] I'd just go...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... if I had to I probably could.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I've seen Mike kick a little butt. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>I'd just give up my wallet. [<i>Joaquim chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh, this episode was directed by Ethan Spaulding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Who's a magnificent director.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Gives an affirming murmur; refers to Team Avatar flying off to the Earth King's palace.</i>] So, here begins the insanity. [<i>John affirms.</i>] I believe this is where you started, Joa-Joa-Joaquim, this is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>This-this... [<i>Refers to Team Avatar debating whether they should leave Ba Sing Se or not.</i>] I did a little bit of the first part there [<i>Mike affirms intermittently.</i>] with the dialogue, but this is where it all kind of starts comes together with the action. And I remember talking about this in the start-up meetings and, and it sort of being the idea that there's just multiple waves after waves of, uh, of soldiers to come to-to stop them, they gotta get through it.  [<i>Refers to the surface-to-air rock that nearly hits Appa.</i>] Whoa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, and great, uh, animation, uh, by animation director Jae Myung Yu.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Absolutely. Um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, that's awesome.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... really, [<i>Refers to the giant rocks that the teams of palace soldiers bend.</i>] I mean, look at that, that's-there's so much weight to those-those, you know huge stones that they're flinging up at 'em.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to Team Avatar taking on the Earth Kingdom soldiers.</i>] I think what's good about this action scene too is that, kinda shows how far the kids have come in their training too. Like, a lot of times we don't have-we always want to show like training scenes and the kids getting better at the martial arts and stuff, but sometimes the story's just, you know, story's got to keep moving, so we don't have time to show all that stuff, but in sequences like this, you can see, really see how they've... progressed as-individually and together like as a team, I think, which is cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Absolutely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yeah, we were, we were pitching this out, I think the idea was just that the-they're-they're superheroes by this point, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and these guys are just disposable peons that they're... [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... knocking out of the way.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long take of Aang and Toph fighting back to back, applying earthbending in a variety of different ways to ward off incoming fire.</i>] And let me just bring to light how much animation was in that scene [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] specifically. Uh, overlapping action, just, they-they really, really pulled through for us, the animation studio did, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and did a kick butt job. [<i>Refers to Toph earthbending the walkway tiles, flipping them over, and pressing down the palace soldiers struggling underneath.</i>] I think our first cut of that, the guys looked like they were dead underneath the rocks, [<i>John laughs.</i>] the first uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Well, they got totally squashed...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... they would not have had any legs. Now they're okay, they're just a little bruised.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang and Toph earthbending a dome out of the walkway tiles, forming it around the team to block an incoming rock statue.</i>] This was a cool concept, I think. Both you and Bryan had come up with it in the pitch, that they formed this kind of cocoon. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yeah, I like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, I always ask the writers this, John, when they come in, is like, you know, you guys write the scripts, you haven't seen it for a long time, it come-comes back in color. Are you always like... surprised to see the outcome of-of, you know, a script that you've written and stuff, and see it visualized, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Y-y...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Do you enjoy that process?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... yeah, yeah. I mean, there's, uh, I don't know, I'm pretty bad at watching animatics, so [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I feel like there's even a lot that I've missed in the animatic, 'cause I can't always decipher drawings, but uh, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] yeah, when the-when the finished, colored product comes back, it's, yeah, it's always very impressive, and... full-lots of surprises, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa fanning his tail in the air while on the platform.</i>] And... a little small detail here is that Appa is actually helping them up with the uh, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] with the elevator there by kind of fluttering his tail.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh, I didn't know that, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] interesting. You know, a-from a-I'm sure you guys have talked about this, from-from a writing standpoint, one of the hardest things to [<i>Laughs.</i>] do is figure out what to do with Appa. You cannot-you don't always have somewhere to put him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Absolutely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>And uh, I think you'll see on the train, when they're on the train later, he's just kind of floating [<i>John and Mike laugh.</i>] outside the window 'cause we didn't know where else to put him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Joaquim laughs at Sokka opening one of the palace doors, startling the woman inside.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>There are so many stories we thought of in the old days where, and somebody would just say, "oh man, they can't, they're-what about Appa?" They would-they would...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] They could totally just fly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... just fly there. [<i>Laughs.</i>] Right, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Well, that's definitely one of our boarding notes too, we're always like, where's Appa, and where's Momo?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And Momo often disappears for a while, but [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] we always find good little nuggets for him to do.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko deliriously falling to the ground in his apartment.</i>] This was a great scene boarded by, uh, Mike Chang. That-and that animation on that fall [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] was just, just something of beauty. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the rubble that Sokka climbs over.</i>] Tons of rubble. [<i>Refers to Sokka giving a flying kick to the doors leading to the Earth King.</i>] This was a great gag we came up with in the pitch, [<i>Joaquim and John laugh.</i>] where just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Referring to Sokka falling from the door he just tried to kick down, Joaquim imitates the deflating sound effect that accompanies Sokka's fall, with both him and John laughing afterward.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... and initially, this scene was, I don't know if you remember, was extended, [<i>Refers to the team entering the Earth King's throne room.</i>] and this was a huge fight scene in this enormous round room we come up with.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's right, you did even more boards...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, I mean there was like a double board here, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... then-then we ended up with.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... yeah, time kind of cut it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Well, I think-I think, I was satisfied with that action.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I get it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] I think they earned their way in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Absolutely. I don't know how many more intermediaries we might have possibly killed, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] quite a bit more.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Earth King.</i>] And the, I like how the-the, sort of how the Earth King turned out. You know, he's... he's not, uh, too cartoony and he's like, seems like a real guy, you know. I think the kids had a lot of expectations of what this guy was going to turn out [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] to be like, and you kind of realize he's just like a normal guy who's been sheltered all his life. [<i>John affirms.</i>] Which, you know, is based on, on real, real stuff in China and st-and things, where the emperor there, you know, often wouldn't leave the Forbidden City in China for years and years, and they-they led a very isolated existence in a way.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Right. He sort of personifies the, uh, "ignorance is bliss".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>He means well, he's not a bad guy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>No, no...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Exactly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... not at all.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Out of the loop.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar trying to inform the King about Long Feng's deceptions.</i>] But that's what I like about this story too, is how the kids come into his palace, and stuff kind of wakes him up, [<i>John affirms.</i>] from-from what's been going on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Earth King's glasses.</i>] Nice touch with the uh, uh, <i>pince-nez</i>, by the way, the little glasses on his face. [<i>John and Mike laugh; refers to Bosco.</i>] Oh, Bosco.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Oh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Very funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... good old Bosco.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, Bosco became, he-he appeared first in, uh, 214 I think, and then, we just all decided we liked Bosco so much that he was going-going to hang out with the king.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Aang starts detailing Long Feng's capture of Appa to the king, casually breaking out of the rock glove bindings the Dai Li put on him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Sort of great here too that Aang pretty much showed everybody that he could get away if he wanted to. [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] But he's-he's choosing to do this diplomatically.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Aang's good like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>He is good like that. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Aang-Aang really cares what people think about him, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think you're right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Long Feng trying to convince the king that the kids are enemies.</i>] What a no-good liar. [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Scoundrel.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>But he's-Long Feng was a good, good season two villain. [<i>Joaquim gives an affirming murmur.</i>] I really liked his character.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>And this was really one of the first, you know, besides the-the episode right before this is where we really got to see what the Dai Li agents' jobs were, and-and, and get a feel that they're his minions.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there were kind of two factions, it was like, Long Feng and the Dai Li, and then the king and all his guards and soldiers and generals and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>After a brief pause, Mike and Joaquim chuckle at Aang airbending Long Feng's robes, revealing the bite mark on his exposed leg by Appa.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh, I remember, it took us a long time to figure out how they could prove that, [<i>Mike laughs,</i>] that he had met Appa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was a good way. [<i>Refers to the two shots of Aang sliding into frame, enthusiastically pointing at Appa's teeth in the first shot, then Long Feng's bite mark in the second.</i>] Ah, I love this...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Look at...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... this animation coming up here with, [<i>Mike, John and Joaquim laugh.</i>] Aang, where he's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>He just slides out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... so low. Think Ethan storyboarded that part.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>He did, he did. Yeah, that was great. [<i>Refers to Team Avatar cheerful, then disappointed, then accepting reactions to the Earth King coming around to their explanations.</i>] This is awesome acting too here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Mike imitates the kids going "aww" after the king clarifies that just because Long Feng met Appa does not prove their claims about the rest of the Dai Li's conspiracy. A brief pause in commentary until the king says he'll look into the matter, to which the kids give satisfied affirmations.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Joaquim and John laugh; imitating the kids.</i>] He says we'll take it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until the scene transitions to Iroh taking care of Zuko's fever.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I like the idea with this little B-story of Zuko was, was we knew we were gonna have him kind of go through this transformation and-and, kind of lean toward the good side. And, uh, wanted a kind of simple story where we're, Zuko is literally going through this feverish transformation. S...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, it's, I sort of got to do all the episodes with crazy dreams, I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Did you? [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Uh, the, the one in third season, which everyone will see.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh, yeah. Don't ruin it for anyone.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh, I'm not, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I'm not saying a word. [<i>Mike and Joaquim laugh; refers to the Earth King on the train.</i>] It's his first time on the train.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joachim
</th>
<td>His first time out of the, out of the palace.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh, that's right, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Toph tries to earthbend the entrance to Lake Laogai from underneath the water, only to bring up bits of rubble.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, that is actually an identical shot to the last episode that we did, where Toph raised the secret [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] entrance to the Lake Laogai headquarters, and now it's all broken up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the Earth King.</i>] Is that Phil LaMarr, as the Earth King?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah, he-I was going to mention that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Is it? Is it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah, he did the-he was the voice of the Earth King, and he does a lot of... animation voices, and [<i>John affirms.</i>] just a great actor. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] And, you know, it's always funny with the, the voice recording stuff, is like rarely do all the ch-are all the characters in the room together, you know, you think like [<i>John affirms.</i>] everyone's there acting together, but, you know, sometimes we'll have like Katara and Sokka together or something, but, you know, the-the kid who plays Aang, uh, Zach Tyler Eisen, lives in New York. He's always recording by himself, [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] you know, sometimes Zuko is, uh, recording by himself, so. But-but Andrea, the voice director, uh, Andrea Romano, always brings, you know, her direction style and stuff can really blend them all together very nicely and-and make it very cohesive.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>And the interesting thing from a boarding point of view is a lot of the time that we get the tracks, it only has certain actors on it. Until we'll go to a pitch, we'll kind of leave, you know, say Katara hasn't been on the track yet, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] we'll just leave her kind of really ambiguous what her acting is, and at a later date we'll end up getting her-her track, and then plugging the-the acting later.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Gives an affirming murmur; refers to Zuko's dream, his face unscarred, on the throne as the Fire Lord, being tempted by two dragons.</i>] So, did you ever have a dream like this, John, when you were writing this? [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>My dreams don't ever actually make any sense. [<i>Mike laughs intermittently.</i>] They're-they're never this cool, and I can usually barely remember them, unless I write them down when I first wake up. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] But yeah, it's usually just, you know, I'm going grocery shopping, except I'm at the post office. [<i>Mike and John laugh.</i>] Just something really mundane like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko.</i>] This was really cool [<i>John affirms.</i>] to see though, Zuko, without the scar on his face.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Sort of what he should've looked like had he not had such a horrible father.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and John laugh; refers to the blue dragon in Zuko's dream baring its mouth, the blackness within encompassing the shot, with Ursa fading in.</i>] We see a little glimpse of Zuko's mom right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>And if I can remember that correctly, I remember at one point the boarding had Zuko's mom actually getting swallowed by the dragon.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>She was in the mouth...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] She was in the mouth...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... it's just, I was-it was a little too scary...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... it was a little much.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... even for me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I was scared looking at the board.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>I-I was scared.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] So, we changed that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>That's true, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the top-down shot of the Fire Nation drill, still stuck in the Outer Wall, and surrounded by three other smaller ones.</i>] So, and there we see the drill, which w-you know, was in the episode of-called the "The Drill". [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] Still in-in, and you see that, I think Bryan had the idea of like, that there were the-the earthbenders kinda constructed these...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; laughs.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... other walls around it to, you know, 'cause they were trying to disrepair it and-and get it out of there, but they needed some protection still, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>It looks like some kind of little Jersey barrier, [<i>Joaquim laughs.</i>] or something like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Long Feng's attempts to explain the drill to the king.</i>] So, this is here, this is where Long Feng's lies all kind of finally crumble. [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Kids, lies will always do that to you. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Can't keep control forever.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Earth King ordering the Dai Li to arrest their leader, Long Feng; in a mock dramatic tone.</i>] Oh, the tangled web! [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yes. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the closeup shot that pans horizontally between the two Dai Li agents, as they look at each other, ruminating on which side to pick.</i>] This was a great scene that I remember came together in the pitch, where both Dai Li agents look at each other, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] for a moment, where it's, should I do this?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the metal handcuffs the Dai Li send out of their sleeves, imprisoning Long Feng.</i>] They have separate metal handcuffs.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>They do.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Because-because they can't use the rock ones on him obviously.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's right, yeah. They have to create a new kind of handcuff. Well, not new, I mean, metal handcuffs have been around for a while, but.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Joaquim and John chuckle.</i>] A new kind of [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] <i>Avatar</i> metal, newfangled handcuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Team Avatar telling the king about the Day of Black Sun.</i>] So, this is kind of-this is the scene too, that kids have been waiting... to tell the kid-the king about the eclipse since like, "The Library" episode, I think, which when they first found out about it. [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] Which John also wrote, by the way.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Isn't there-isn't there a callback to that in one of these episodes, is somebody says something about... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] About?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... Professor Zei, from the university?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah, [<i>John laughs.</i>] when they-when they first come to Ba Sing Se, they're, they talk about how they met a professor from Ba Sing Se University. But uh, yeah, he went down with the library.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yes. [<i>Refers to the Earth King.</i>] I can remember being so frustrated, having read the script at this point, with the king when he said "I am the king of fools", I was like, [<i>In a mock insulting tone.</i>] yes, you are the king of fools!  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and John laugh; brief pause.</i>] So, how was it, Joaquim, coming in, 'cause uh, you know a lot of the crew had been around since the beginning, like coming into a-to a show that was like halfway, you know, in the middle of the season and-and jumping in and stuff, how...?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>It was, I mean it was-it was a great experience, uh, as far as dealing with everybody, 'cause everybody was just so, you know, so-so friendly and-and there wasn't really that mentality where, you know, a lot of crews you go onto, you know, "this is our team", and, you know, you're kind of an outsider, everybody. I remember I had lunch with you guys my first or second day and, you know, it just-everything really flowed really smoothly, and I think this show particularly kind of caters to what I enjoy about, you know, film and-and... so, I think I, I took to it really, really easily.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Now, were you a fan of before you started working on it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I was a big fan of it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] You were, alright, that's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... I can remember my-my-my girlfriend at the time, my fiancé now, was uh, watching TV, and-and this show kinda made the rounds, uh, just rumor wise in all of animation, [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] we're kind of hearing about this <i>Avatar</i> show, and she happened to catch it on Nickelodeon, and she TiVo'd it, and she had said, "you gotta come home, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] you gotta watch this show now". And the show that I was on at the time was coming to an end, and everything just seemed to work out really, really well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh, that's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Did it-did you seek out <i>Avatar</i>...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... after seeing the show?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I, I-I called up as soon...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... as I heard that there was a position open, and I said, [<i>In a mock desperate tone.</i>] "I want in, let me in", and uh, I remember for a while not being able to-to take the test to uh, get in, just 'cause of work instruments, and then it worked out, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>That's right. Lauren MacMullan had left to work on a movie based on a Fox animated [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] show that we can't give you the name of.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Right. I think I was taking... was I taking Justin's place? Had Justin just left?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, our Justin Ridge, our s-storyboard artist from... who had been there since the beginning. [<i>Joaquim affirms.</i>] But um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>There was definitely, you know, some big shoes to fill though. I mean, I-I-I studied all of Justin's boards, and was abs-absolutely just amazed by them. So, there was-there was, there...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] You filled the shoes...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... [<i>In a mock frustrated tone.</i>] I was intimidated, man!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... you filled them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Well thank you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Iroh telling Zuko that after his metamorphosis, he will become a beautiful prince, the person he was always meant to be.</i>] He's going to be a butterfly, [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur.</i>] when he comes out of it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yes. That line actually made me cringe when I read it, the "beautiful prince" line. [<i>Mike, John and Joaquim laugh.</i>] But then when I saw it in the-in the-in the show, it worked out really well. I was like, beautiful? [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Sokka questions if Guru Pathik is some kind of poisonous blowfish.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] That's a great one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, we're kind of, this-this act three stuff also is... was used to kind of set up the next couple of episodes where the kids split up and have to go their separate ways. [<i>Refers to Sokka and Katara learning where their father is.</i>] And also that, you know, the news that they find out where their dad is, is like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Huge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... something we've been setting up since, you know, s-early season one where we found out that their dad left their tribe to fight in the war.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Long Feng's secret files on everyone in Ba Sing Se.</i>] That's a lot of uh, legwork if they have files on everybody in the city. He-Long Feng must have a lot of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] He...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... government employees for...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Well, it was before the internet, so it was harder to, [<i>Joaquim laughs.</i>] you know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Right, right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... keep track of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] None of that intranets. [<i>John laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>They have really, uh, good filing clerks though [<i>John laughs.</i>] I think in-in Ba Sing Se. Really good library science, uh... books...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Hey, I was thinking they stored a lot of them in the library that went down in the desert. [<i>John laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>That's what, uh, that's where paperbenders come in. [<i>Mike and Joaquim laugh.</i>] Which we don't go into in this show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>We didn't-we haven't seen those yet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>The useless art of paper. [<i>Mike and John laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Aang trying to confess his feelings to Katara before they leave.</i>] Uh-oh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>A brief pause in commentary until Sokka interrupts Aang's confession, to which Joaquim and Mike chuckle at.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Oh, fellas all understand that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Joaquim.</i>] Yep. [<i>Mike and Joaquim laugh.</i>] We've all been there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Another brief pause in commentary until Sokka falls off of Appa after hearing the Earth King mention the Kyoshi Warriors.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] This is great. D'oh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Aw man, he would've totally... [<i>John chuckles.</i>] broken his back there. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yeah, that's definitely a compound, uh, fracture of some sort.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Sokka praising the Kyoshi Warriors to the Earth King.</i>] That's why you have to be really careful who you give a uh, recommendation for. [<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur; Joaquim laughs.</i>] Because it can come back [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] and hurt you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang, Katara, and Toph forcing Sokka into a group hug.</i>] This is great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>John and Joaquim chuckle.</i>] Sokka doesn't hug. Not a hugging guy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>No.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of Zuko dreaming he has an arrow tattoo on his head and no scar, only to wake up and find he still has his trademark burn.</i>] Oh, this is my favorite part I think, in the episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, this was staged really nicely, I think, Mike Chang...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yeah, very well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>This was Mike Chang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... also did this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>The...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Just the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>The way I knew this scene...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>As Zuko reacts in horror to his new face, Mike gives off a mock yell in fight, chucking afterward.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... played really well was... that it, you know, we'd seen it all the way from the beginning from the-the rough stages all through the storyboards, and it still shocked me when we got the footage back, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] s-still thrown by it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to Sokka joyously recounting the team's achievements, including beating Long Feng.</i>] I love that he's so happy that he got Long Feng arrested.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Joaquim laugh.</i>] Me too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to Aang saying their love interests are waiting for them when they get back.</i>] I like Aang's line too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah. [<i>Simultaneously with Joaquim.</i>] "Girls are waiting for us."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with John.</i>] "Girls are waiting for us."  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka saying everything from then on would be perfect; John and Joaquim laugh.</i>] He couldn't set that up any better, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] could he.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Might've been overreaching a bit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Perhaps. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause; refers to the sterile lighting on the Dai Li agent outside of Long Feng's cell.</i>] Did a lot of great diffusion on that scene, which-which-which I think works out really well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I love the-the scenes in the cell looked really nice, and creepy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Cool, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph getting kidnapped by Xin Fu and Yu.</i>] Then we have the [<i>Clears throat.</i>] Toph kidnapping, which, you know, as we recall...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, we haven't seen...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Xin Fu and Master Yu, they haven't been around for uh, many an episode, but.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>... yeah, I hope people remembered [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] who they were, that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock confused tone.</i>] Who're these dudes?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>John and Mike laugh.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] But I think, uh, I really love the ending of this episode, 'cause you do get that kind of feeling of like, yeah, things are going good, we could get a little complacent, and then, [<i>Refers to Azula, Mai, and Ty Lee, disguised as Kyoshi Warriors.</i>] bam! [<i>John and Joaquim affirm.</i>] Oh, it's... Azula.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td><i>Avatar</i> is great at disappointing [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] kids, with its e-endings.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>I definitely...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I feel like those make the best stories. [<i>John and Joaquim affirm.</i>] If you end with a happy ending every time, what are you going to do next?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Boy, some kids were so mad [<i>John and Mike laugh.</i>] about the ending to season two. [<i>Joaquim laughs; Mike affirms.</i>] It was... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Tune in for Bryan and my commentary on s... [<i>John laughs.</i>] the last episode of season two [<i>Joaquim laughs.</i>] for more of that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Yay.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>This was a ball to work on though, this-this-this one in particular from, uh, from season two was, was a lot of fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>Season two as a whole is, is pretty solid. [<i>Joaquim gives an affirming murmur.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I would say so. I mean the fact that we get to do, you know a, a political conspiracy thriller for children... is, you know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] No doubt, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Nothing wrong with that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... it's exciting. Thanks again everyone who worked so hard on this-this episode in the series.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>Yep. And thank you for...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Thank you guys for joining us.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>John
</th>
<td>For buying the DVDs. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joaquim
</th>
<td>... thank you having us.
</td></tr></tbody></table>