<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hey, this is Mike DiMartino, co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>This is Bryan Konietzko, the other co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron Ehasz
</th>
<td>And this is Aaron Ehasz, head writer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, this is the main title of the show, which, uh, took a lot of work and effort by a lot of different artists.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I was driving back and forth between the Burbank Studio, uh, Titmouse's studio, and Hollywood, and my friend, Andy Dill's house, where he was working on the digital stuff and compositing in some other part of LA and everyday hitting all three, and it was pretty rough, but it came out cool. We're happy with it. That last shot I really like. I like the way the perspective shifts.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, this is the... kind of the first in the trilogy of, uh, Northern Water Tribe episodes, where they finally get to the Northern Water Tribe. And actually, uh, I wrote this episode, so it was kind of... I was really into it and, unlike most of the episodes from the first season, like, this was a story that we, Bryan and I, had from the beginning almost, like, we wanted to have... we knew that when they got to the Northern Water Tribe that Katara would, uh, you know, finally think that she realized her vision of becoming a waterbender and be shut down by the... the old waterbending master.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>No commentary for a short period of time until Katara states the identity of the approaching men as waterbenders.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And, you know, there was a lot of build up all season to get to this point, so it was, uh... it was very exciting to finally get to this... this story and be able to do this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I kind of like the... the way the season wraps up with some familiar things. Zhao in this tent, sort of planning this big attack on the Northern Water Tribe really reminds me of episode 103, when, uh, he first learns that the Avatar is back, uh, with Zuko, and I think it's kind of a neat bookend, um... bookends for the... for the season.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Another thing about, uh, this guy, Admiral Zhao, uh, he was voiced by Jason Isaacs, who was in a bunch of things. He was in <i>The Patriot</i>, and he was in, uh, the <i>Harry Potter</i> movies; he's Lucius Malfoy, and he's just a really great... great actor and a great villain overall.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That... we were very lucky to get him. I remember Mike kept saying to the casting department, "Can we just get someone like Jason Isaacs?" And they finally said, "How about we get Jason Isaacs." So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I was like, "Yeah, that's cool. We'll take him."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] We got really lucky.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he was... he was a great actor and, you know, as you will see in the later episodes, unfortunately he is... he's... he's dead, but...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Not Jason Isaacs.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] No. Yeah, the character.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] The character.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yes, Mr. and Mrs. Isaacs, your son is okay. [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>] Not to worry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Uh, it took a lot of discussion in the boardroom to figure out these water lock systems, and unfortunately a lot of the scenes got cut, but it came out pretty cool, and I think you get the idea that this culture has built their... their whole... they built their whole culture around, uh, water, and it's kind of like these veins going through the city and cascading down, uh, from the... the chief's palace all the way down to the lower snowfields. That's a great character design by Angela Mulder on, uh, Princess Yue. And Aaron was adamant that she have, silvery hair because he knew pretty early on that she was gonna be tied in with the moon, so. I remember you were... [<i>Aaron makes an inaudible remark.</i>] you like grabbed me in the hallway and you were like, [<i>Imitates Aaron.</i>] "I saw a drawing where her hair was dark; it's gotta be white."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yes, there are very few visual things that I actually care...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It's true, it's true.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... enough and bicker about, or whatever, but... [<i>Speaking simultaneously with Bryan.</i>] or am interested in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Speaking simultaneously with Aaron.</i>] When someone is that passionate about it, I just say okay. [<i>Both laugh</i>] No and, uh, it was great; it really made her stand out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>We gotta, we gotta mention uncle's song here 'cause, uh, uncle, who's voiced by Mako - great, great actor - uh, he hates singing, but he's really good at it, so we keep giving him songs to do, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] but every time he's like, [<i>Imitates Mako.</i>] "No don't make me sing another song. I don't want to do it."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>But I think he was on Broadway.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's what I heard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>No, he was great, so, uh... we, we love to have uncle sing. It's very hilarious, and I think that was the... that was the first official song we had him do.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, so if you... if you haven't noticed before that... that love theme that he sings becomes the theme for Sokka and Yue's love story in... in this trilogy of episodes, so, um, you'll hear that melody woven into the score by Jeremy Zuckerman throughout, uh... eighteen, nineteen, and twenty.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh another good actor note, this is, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects</i>] Jon Polito.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, Jon Polito does the chief's voice, and uh... he's, you know, he was in the Coen brothers movies, and he's just a great character actor
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I... I was starstruck for the first time when I... when I got to meet him. That was really cool. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, being a Coen brothers' disciple in art school definitely...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, and it's... it's, you know, in our show, it's kinda hard to find... actors who can really bring like a realism to it, but also be funny and dramatic and all the things you need to be to be a great actor, and uh, you know, we try to balance it out with, with actors who can... can bring a lot to the table. So like, Jack DeSena does a great job with Sokka and Mae Whitman, Mae Whitman is Katara; she's really wonderful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>There's some great animation by, uh... animation director Yoo Jang Young, and uh... from JM Animation. He just, he... ever since the pilot, he has taken to Sokka so well, just like Jack has, and um... the two of them together just make a great, lively combination. I really like this uh... that background; the lighting's really cool and that kinda glowing fountain, but the characters are in shadow, I thought that was nice. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] Pakku, this character, is one of our favorites. He just came out really well. If you'll notice, he is the first character in the, um, ope-, the main title sequence; the waterbending character in the red silhouette is Pakku, so... like Mike said, we had plans for him very early on, so we put that design in. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] I just love any scene between Zuko and Zhao; it's just awesome. These guys are... their egos are sooo big and, uh, so much tension, and they both kinda want the same thing; they both want the Fire Lord's approval and... it's just a great clashing of... of egos.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>This is like the first moment where, [<i>Clears throat.</i>] Zhao recognizes that Zuko is the Blue Spirit.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I really was happy with that, the color correction in those flashback scenes. I thought it looked pretty... pretty cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Pause in the commentary until Zhao hands Iroh the broadsword.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That was a really hard move to do in the acting reference, to flip the sword over and catch it. I didn't know if I could do it [<i>Mike laughs.</i>], but actually I got it the first time. The second time I dropped the sword and it bounced all over the room, which was pretty scary, but... I should've just stuck to the first take.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, do you ever see yourself in these, uh, in the animation, 'cause I... 'cause a lot of times you do the reference for the act-...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I do
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... for the acting or the... or the kung fu, do you ever see your...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Oh, definitely. I think you can recognize the hands most...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... um, and I definitely recognize Sifu Kisu, our martial arts consultant, in a lot of the... the action. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] That... just great character animation on Pakku. Got really, really lucky on that one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Pause in commentary until Katara approaches and confronts Pakku about not teaching her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I love this part [<i>Refers to when Katara says that she did not travel the distance just to be told know and waits for Pakku to respond "No". All laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he's just a... he's not a nice guy. [<i>Chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Great... [<i>Begins, but interjects to add to Mike's comment.</i>] jerk.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Jerk is a good word.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Great voice acting. Who... who was the voice actor?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh, Victor Brandt did the voice of this, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Fantastic, it just matched with the character design so well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Pause in commentary until Katara runs after Aang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like those little spirit animal heads on the... it's sort of a motif throughout the city. There's like totem poles with the various animal heads.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's a lot of details like that that are in the background designs and stuff that... you know, are in the backgrounds if you look closely, so there's a lot of great... great detail and kind of stuff that has been thought through by the background designers and... and Bryan in the art direction, so...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>A lot of moon motifs for the Water Tribe, um, the idea that the moon moves the tides and is sorta the first waterbender, which Yue talks about later. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] I think Bobby Rubio had storyboarded most of the romance stuff in this...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... Right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He did a great job. A lot of personality in his drawings.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I'd like to observe that the canals and... and sort of gondola-like sequences are, uh, based on my recent trip to [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>], uh, Italy and that, uh, is a note directed at the IRS, so...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh, wow.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, there you go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Alright, here's a little... little fun fact for you, the... the, uh, pirate barker that we just saw biting the gold is actually, uh, Bryan's voice, and he is, uh... another tidbit, is the, uh, all the pirates are based off... our character design is based off the, uh, animators in Korea, a lot of the animators we work with, so it was fun. They first appeared in, uh, "The Waterbending Scroll" episode, and uh, are reapp-, are reappearing here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Kids are always so cute on Avatar, that's another note... [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>There are a lot of very cute...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... Especially Water Tribe kids.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>An-... another batch of great character designs by Angela Mulder. She did a great job on all the Water... Water Tribe kids; they're really cute. Some great drawings by Chris Graham, the storyboard artist here. He handled most of this Pakku-Aang stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>What... what was Pakku just slurping?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We thought instead of just noodles, he'd have some like tentacles mixed in there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>K
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, they're like octopus/squid tentacles, or something.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Pause in the commentary until Yagoda states her recognition of Katara's necklace.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Famous voice actor there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Lucille Bliss. She was, uh, she's Smurfette...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I think so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... I believe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>No kidding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>She is classic... classic. Very nice lady.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>This... what's happening right here is something that I love about <i>Avatar</i>, which is that this necklace that we've known about for so long and that sort of had its own kind of mini-plot where it got lost and Zuko had it, now we're finding out kinda this deeper history behind it, and like, there are so many things in this show that... that, uh, start off seemingly so innocently that pay off with such depth and... and, uh that's one of my...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's true, even what... the class that, um, Yagoda's teaching is a healing class...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects affirmatively.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... of waterbending and that... that plays a really important roll... even in before that sequence and... and, uh you know, much... a lot after... after that sequence in other episodes, um, and basically she's... she's moving the water along the, uh, acupressure points in the body.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So this is another... this is one of my favorite sequences, I think we've done is... it just came out great. It's great staging.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I love that rope noise...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... by Ben. That was great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Um, the pirates again are back. [<i>Refers to Oh voicing the caution to be taken while handling the blasting jelly.</i>] So, that was Bryan right there. [<i>Laughs with Bryan.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Terri-... terrible voice acting. It was really hard to im-... imitate my friend Seung Hyun [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>] <b>and</b> whisper. That was difficult.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Nah, it's just really great to do sequences where there's, you know, as much as we like to write jokes and do great dramatic scenes and stuff, to do stuff that we can rely on the animation and the acting and the staging and stuff to sell the story and this was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, great... great storyboard by Chris Graham here. I love this ominous bird with the glowing eyes. [<i>Brief pause while Zuko's ship explodes.</i>] A lot of shots of this ship blowing up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, we wanted to kind of... or Chris had the idea I think, to kind of stage it like... like a live action explosion, where they shoot it from a bunch of different angles and then we edited it all together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>All the coverage.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That probably comes from the fact that it... it costs a lot of money [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] to get all those cameras because you can only blow up the prop one time, so...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... That's probably why [<i>Mike laughs again.</i>], the... the directors are like [<i>Imitates a director simultaneously with Aaron.</i>] "We gotta put... we gotta put more shots in there."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Imitates a director.</i>] "We gotta get it. We gotta get it."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. I love... I love coming out of that really dramatic, you know, intense scene to this romance scene that at first seems innocuous, and then has its own drama.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Commenting on Sokka's self-whittled fish.</i>] I love this little thing he made for her. [<i>Chuckles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>This was, uh... I remember writing this joke and thinking, "I don't know if this is gonna work." [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>] But then in the storyboard, I think it was Bobby...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td>... Rubio did the storyboard, and he drew that... the... the bad little...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Jumps in.</i>]... fish bear.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... fish bear design, and we're like, "That's the design. Do not change it at all. That's... it's gotta be exactly that." He just captured the... the terrible Sokka carving.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I hope that will be coming to stores.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Bryan and Mike snicker.</i>] Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Oh Sokka. [<i>Mike laughs</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I love... I love when Katara, this little bit of acting, how her hood flops over her head. I thought that was nice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>No commentary for a brief period of time until Katara stands and begins speaking.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's so cute how Momo tries to pay attention to what people are saying. [<i>All chuckle.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I love how quickly Katara dismisses Sokka's... [<i>Laughter from Mike and Bryan.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Referring to the scene in which Aang is teaching Katara waterbending.</i>] I love this background.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Adding to Bryan's comment.</i>] This is what... really beautiful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The... the reflected... the reflected light on that wall is just gorgeous. Beautiful. The... everything... the stairs kinda fading into the water. It was really cool. It really feels like moonlight on a... luminous, reflective surface, really cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>And also, if you notice, the phase of the moon in the background, that was carefully...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Adding on.</i>]... planned out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... planned.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Discussing the background design of the next scene.</i>] That's a cool design. I think Dean Kelly, a storyboard artist, did some background design on this. I think he did that alter piece thing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think, uh... Giancarlo Volpe storyboarded this part, and he also directed this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I love this scene. [<i>Pauses in commentary until Pakku instigates Katara.</i>] Ooh, too far. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I love the cracks. They look really beautiful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And this kinda calls back to episode, uh... one where she was getting all mad at Sokka for being... [<i>Chuckles.</i>] being a little sexist about his attitudes, and she bre-... ended up breaking the iceberg that eventually freed Aang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Maybe that's why Sokka says "Yeah I think she did." He remembers. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Addressing the scene involving Iroh and Zhao conversing about the incident with Zuko.</i>] This is a cool scene too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's a lot of great, dramatic tension and stuff. It's just really great that we can do funny scenes and then we can have a scene like this where it's all, dramatic tension between two dudes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's great because, uncle knows... they're both lying right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Uncle knows Zuko isn't dead and he kno... he knows Zhao did it, but he's lying and pretending the pirates did it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... And Zhao thinks that Zuko's dead and knows, because he set it up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's just a cool scene with a lot of underlying... [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] motivations.  [<i>Referring to the fight between Katara and Pakku.</i>] Love this fight. It came out really great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this is really the first time we see how... how much passion Katara has with her waterbending and... and seeing how... how much raw talent she has kind of and, you know, after this episode she begins to hone that more, but.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, a lot of care went into, with the... the Kung...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>In response to Katara waterwhipping Paku.</i>] Boom. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... the Kung Fu reference with Sifu Kisu. We wanted to make Paku look refined, like he had trained a style, a specific style, and that Katara was just kind of like a street fighter. Just raw and passion talent, but unrefined in her... skills. [<i>Referring to Sokka's getting blasted by waterbending.</i>] Sokka's always... [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>] we figure he has really bad karma because he's always getting... knocked around. [<i>Aaron mentions something.</i>] This is cool, great animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Referring to Katara as she secures her footing with waterbending.</i>] I love that move, just... stabilizing herself. It's so simple.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Kind of the key to Kung Fu is just, rooting... rooting yourself. [<i>Addressing the melee portion of the duel.</i>] This is cool. Chris Graham storyboarded this fight. [<i>Commenting about Paku's facial expression.</i>] Look it, so smug. What a jerk. [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>] What a... you just en...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I love the little kids who are, like, see her doing her Kung Fu and start cheering.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's kind of influenced by all my seven nephews who, get so pumped [<i>Aaron chuckles.</i>] watching <i>Avatar</i> and [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] start jumping around the living room.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>No, it's great to see that, like, kids are actually learning, like, Kung Fu moves from the show because they're... they're watching over and over and over and over again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>My [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>]... my nephew, Ryan, has a perfect horse stance...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... and he learned it from the opening.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>It's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>My favorite shot, coming up right here. [<i>Referring to Katara.</i>] This wave that she sends out. Oh, I love it. My favorite shot, and it's like eight... [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] eighteen frames long. [<i>Aaron chuckles. Bryan comments on Paku's waterbending.</i>] This is really cool too. You see that he freezes it... as he's coming down in the air.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara's disheveled hair.</i>] Oh, this is also the, the uh, first time we see Katara's hair down I believe, which was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] This was popular...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... with the crew. [<i>Mike laughs; refers to Katara stubbornly trying to break out of the ice shards Pakku trapped her in.</i>] I love that she's still defiant, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think this, this ice cage thing, I was kind of inspired by-I think we had just seen <i>House of Flying Daggers</i>, and there was like a...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah. The bamboo...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... the bamboo cage that they formed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Beautiful movie. [<i>Refers to the ice shards melting away.] And then, it melts, [In a mockingly dramatic tone.</i>] right when his heart melts [<i>Dramatically sighs.</i>].
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, [<i>Laughs.</i>] that was intentional. So poignant.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the establishing shot of the Fire Nation ships at dock.</i>] That's a cool shot. We always try to show the Fire Nation, just a militaristic organization, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko taking off his stolen armor faceplate.</i>] You have no idea what Zuko had to do to get that uh, [<i>Bryan and Mike chuckle.</i>] that uniform helmet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the multiple new scars Zuko has on his face.</i>] I like, uh, I'm pretty happy with the... battle-damaged Zuko. I like the sp-the specificity...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah, yeah, it's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... of the scars.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>It looks cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the explosion scene earlier in the episode.</i>] If you... like toggle through the uh, explosion scene with Zuko in the ship, you'll see that moments before the explosion reaches him, he forms a protective fire shield around himself, and uh, it's kinda-kinda fights fire with fire, and, and that's how he was able to survive, and so. He and the bubble of fire are pushed out of the ship through the window... in case you were wo-in case you thought it was a stretch.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; brief pause until the long shot of Yue and Sokka on the bridge at night.</i>] Took Sokka all night to [<i>Bryan and Aaron laugh.</i>] find her.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>To find her, on the same bridge [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] that he met her on both times. I was gonna say that, and I thought it was a little, a little negative, but uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] It was a late-it was late in the day though in that last scene.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td>Brief pause until Sokka states he knows he can't interact with Yue given their different social standings.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I also like his glove mittens [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>], I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] They're his article...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] That came from snowboarding, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Snowboarding?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, it was just influenced by, [<i>Aaron gives an affirming murmur.</i>] when you, when you have to get into your bindings and... [<i>Mike whistles at Sokka and Yue's kiss.</i>] you got those split mittens, it's a lot easier. But keeps your fingers a little warmer. The, sort of the backstory, some stuff that we didn't get as much time to deal with um, is that the, the Southern Water Tribe is-was hit harder in the war than the Northern Tribe was, uh. They were closer to the Fire Nation, and, just through some battles and... strategic things, um, they really took the brunt of the attacks, so... their culture was sort of wiped out, um. That's why when we see them, they're... a little bit more um, just smaller family units, and um, more like rudimentary camps and stuff. Whereas the Northern Tribe, uh, was able to, maybe because of the landscape or the way they'd fortified themselves, were able to preserve their culture a little bit more. So ... that's sort of the, the contrast, where Sokka thinks he's from this um... I don't know, less cultured community.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>In, in comparison to Yue. [<i>Refers to the tilt shot where the size of the fleet that Zhao has gathered is slowly revealed.</i>] This is a cool shot, I love how it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... takes its time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Just... just a good...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Good job.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... cliff-hanger.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Good job, Mike and Aaron. [<i>Mike chuckles; refers to the credits starting to roll.</i>] Do we talk over this part? [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Sure, why not.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>'Kay. I should say my two year old son Paul loves the closing [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] credit theme...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh yeah, he like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... that he will dance to it for the entire... jump up and down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's awesome.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>It is awesome. [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] You should try, you the listener should try [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] dancing to this right now, enj-enjoy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the music playing in the credits.</i>] Yeah, I, I think Ben mentioned before, but this is Kecak. It's a uh, Balinese monkey chant, it's really amazing. Just kind of group, uh, music, and Ben studied this in school.
</td></tr></tbody></table>