<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Scene fades to an exterior shot of Team Avatar's house. Shot cuts to a mirror, in front of which, Aang, whose head is covered with shaving cream, shaves his head with his shaving tool. Camera pans left to show Sokka in the mirror to show he has little facial hair, which he cuts off using the end of his machete. He clicks his tongue. Camera pans left again to show Katara in the mirror as she fixes together her hair loopies. Once they are placed, she smiles and the shot cuts back to show the whole room, with them all in front of the mirror. Scene changes to a dark room, where Toph lies on her bed, her blanket sloppily lying over her and her hair in a mess. Light cuts through the darkness as the door opens, and Katara enters the room and gasps at the sight.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Toph! Aren't you gonna get ready for the day?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Toph gets up, causing her messy hair to fly around. She spits on a nearby vessel which spins upon impact. Cut to Katara's face as she looks shocked, before cutting back to Toph as she gets to her feet and brushes a large amount of dust off her sleeping dress.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I'm ready.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>You're not gonna wash up? You've got a little dirt on your ... everywhere, actually.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>You call it dirt, I call it a healthy coating of earth!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Hmm ... [<i>Thinking.</i>] You know what we need? A girl's day out!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Do I have to?!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>It'll be fun!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the outside of a large building, where Toph and Katara stand near the entrance. Two women in robes walk out and smile at each other.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>The Fancy Lady Day Spa? [<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Sounds like my kinda place.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Are you ready for some <i>serious</i> pampering?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Sure, Katara, whatever you say. As long as they don't touch my feet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two girls walk inside the building. Cut to inside of the building, where Katara sits smiling, having her feet scrubbed. Shot cuts again to a close-up of Toph's dirt-filled foot as the attendant tries to scrape the massive amounts of dirt off her feet. Shot cuts to a close-up of Toph's angry face.</i>
<p><i>Cut to a shot of a hallway inside the spa as suddenly an explosion erupts from one of the doorways, due to which, the frame becomes crumpled. An attendant flies out and hits the opposite wall, Toph having earthbent out of annoyance. Scene changes to Toph and Katara taking mud baths. An attendant with arms full of fresh towels walks over to Toph. Cut to Toph's face as she inhales air, and exhales, earthbending the mud on her face, creating a scary appearance, which scares the attendant, who runs away. Katara and Toph laugh, as the mud around Toph's mouth forms a large smile.</i>
</p><p><i>Scene changes to a pile of rocks in a sauna which Toph and Katara are occupying. Toph kicks the ground, bending another rock from another pile, making it fly onto the pile of hot rocks. Katara, using waterbending, splashes the hot rocks with some water creating steam. They both sigh in relief. Scene changes to Toph, who has a lot of make-up on her face walking through the streets of Ba Sing Se.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Well, that wasn't so bad. I'm not usually into that stuff but I actually feel ... girly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I'm glad. It's about time we did something fun together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a shot of the two crossing a bridge over a creek. As they do, they pass three girls going the other direction. Shot cuts to Katara and Toph from behind the girls.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Girl with umbrella
</th>
<td>Wow, great make-up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Thanks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Girl with umbrella
</th>
<td>For a clown!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The three girls laugh, Toph's smile is replaced by a frown as she and Katara stop walking. Katara puts her arm over Toph's shoulder, attempting to console her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Don't listen to them, let's just keep walking.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Shot cuts to the face of Star, who is one of the three girls.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Star
</th>
<td>I think she looks cute. Like that time we put a sweater on your pet poodle monkey.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Third girl
</th>
<td>Good one, Star.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] Let's go, Toph.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] No, no, that <i>was</i> a good one. Like your poodle monkey. [<i>She laughs.</i>] You know what else is a good one? [<i>She earthbends the bridge, removing a circular part above which the three girls are standing, causing the girls to fall into the creek below. Cut to Katara's face from the hole.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Now <i>that</i> was funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara waterbends a wave that sweeps the girls as they scream. Cut to a shot of Toph walking away from the bridge as Katara jogs to catch up.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Those girls don't know what they're talking about.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>It's okay. One of the good things about being blind, is I don't have to waste my time worrying about appearance. [<i>Cut to a close-up of Toph's face.</i>] I don't care what I look like. I'm not looking for anyone's approval. I know who I am. [<i>She stops walking, and she cries a bit.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>That's what I really admire about you, Toph. You're so strong, and confident, and self-assured. [<i>Toph sniffs.</i>] And I know it doesn't matter, but ... [<i>Keeps her palm on Toph's shoulder.</i>] You're really pretty.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Turning to Katara, smiling.</i>] I am?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Yeah, you are.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Shot cuts to show both of them walking.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I'd return the compliment, but I've no idea how you look like. [<i>Katara laughs.</i>] Thank you, Katara. [<i>She punches Katara's shoulder, her way of showing affection.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Ow!
</td></tr></tbody></table>