[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hey, this is Mike DiMartino, co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Joshua Hamilton
</th>
<td>My name is Josh Hamilton, I'm the writer of this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo Volpe
</th>
<td>And I'm Giancarlo Volpe, I'm the director of this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>And... we're watching the intro.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Josh, Giancarlo, and Mike laugh.</i>] Yes, so this, this episode is called "The Chase". Uh, I think this was kind of a... Western-y inspired episode, wasn't it Josh? Like kind of a...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah, we watched a lot of Westerns. I think we saw <i>The Good, Bad and the Ugly</i>, and um, a show called <i>Shane</i>, and we were in a big-a Western mode when we wrote this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, right before this was the "Zuko Alone" episode, where he's like wandering the plains and... desolate areas and stuff, and this was kind of a continuation of that sort of thing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Is that an intentional thing? Like are, do you research the Westerns, because you want to get that feel, or do you just happen to be watching Westerns at that point in your life?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Well Aaron uh, Aaron went in to research 'em, I guess, but um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think in this case, it was like, we wanted that sort of feel and, so we were like, just checking out some movies to see... how they handled it, an-and stuff like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shot from "Zuko Alone" where Zuko is walking away from the camera toward the looming setting sun.</i>] Ooh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... that's a nice shot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh.</i>] <i>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly</i> comes into play especially in the third act though, we-we'll talk about that later.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Shhh, not yet, not yet. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. This was also really, if you want to talk about it, Josh, the, kind of the-this was the first episode where we have Toph...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, as...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... as part of the group, and-and how that changes the dynamic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah, I thought it was awesome that she was like new. I remem-you wrote 206 and uh, and I loved her attitude, she was so like um, just quick and, and kind of-kind of a jerk, kind of um, Sokka's... a version of Sokka that's a girl, I don't know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>I loved-I love writing her, it was hilarious.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>This was another great episode uh, animated by, um, MOI Animation in Korea, and Kim Sang-Jin is the director over there. He did-added some great, hilarious touches to it. I don't know, what do you think Giancarlo? When you-'cause you directed this episode, and then you send it off to Korea, and then-are you always surprised when you see some of this stuff that they add from, from what you've put in there, or?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah, I mean that-I think that's always kind of a... you know, a thing about... doing half the show in America, and then sending it to Korea, like there's always going to be kind of an X-factor of-of what you're going to expect, of what you-what comes back. But I do remember, specifically on this episode, I was really pleased with how it came back, I just really thought that it they really got the gist of, kind of what I was going for in-in the episode. It was-it turned out really well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Momo giving Katara some berries.</i>] Oh, Momo. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>There's one thing I really liked about this episode writing-wise was um, it starts out almost... I wanna say like a filler, almost like a-I, but I don't mean that in a bad way, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] because it's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. In a faux outraged tone.</i>] What!?  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... it's kind of a character development thing where, you see-you kind of see that Toph and Katara are-are having these problems, and, you sort of just assume that, "Oh okay... they're gonna resolve it somehow by the end of the episode,". But what it kinda does, for me anyways, is it almost kinda lets your guard down, because you don't expect it to take the crazy turns that it does, like a lot later. And I think that that, that was really kind of my feeling when I first read the script, was that, you-you're not really sure where it's gonna go, and that-it was really, it made it a good-a good read, [<i>Mike and Josh give affirming murmurs.</i>] which is always a good sign, you know, when I'm starting a new episode, like, man, if this script is a page turner, then you want to, you get really excited about starting to draw it. And what I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Have you ever had a script that wasn't a page turner?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Not...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. Imitating Giancarlo, in a mock disappointed tone.</i>] Like, aw man, I gotta dire-direct this?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Not on <i>Avatar</i>. [<i>Josh laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh, okay, that's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I'll leave it at that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>What I like about this one, what you-like what you were saying Giancarlo, it's-what-what, it's about our characters are the only characters in it, you know, like our main cast. We don't have-they don't go to a town...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... that's like, they meet someone new, it's like, we've met all the-these characters before, and we just get to see them, like with each other in this situation being tired, like-like they are now, and... how this affects them, I thought that was really fun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the main cast being physically haggard from travelling awake through the night.</i>] Yeah, they're-speaking of them being tired, I just kind of saw that we had painted these like dark circles under their eyes as kind of a, you know, a sign of exhaustion. [<i>Refers to the closeup shot of Toph.</i>] You see that [<i>Josh chuckles.</i>] on Toph right there, and uh, I was always k-I was a little worried, like how that was gonna turn out, but it-it, it actually really works. I think it's just subtle enough, and it, it adds to the whole like building exhaustion that's supposed to be happening to these characters over the course of the episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, they really feel like they-they get more and more tired, which is cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>It's a good, like stress builder.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the scene of Katara fuming in anger, after Toph defiantly refuses to help setup camp.</i>] Hmm, I love this animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this was some good com-hilarious... funny animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Josh snickers at Katara's indignant pronunciation of "sugar queen!?".</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So who-did you come up with the sugar queen line, Josh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I did...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... where did that come from?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Josh and Mike laugh.</i>] I don't know where it came from, [<i>Giancarlo makes an inaudible remark.</i>] but I can remember writing the line, and thinking like, this is that line that's going to get cut somewhere along the line, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] someone's going to have a note, and it made it past, you know, you-the different versions of, you know, the-it wasn't in the outline, but the first draft, and it made it past the table draft, and it made it past through core draft, and I don't know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I like it! [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... I think yeah, we started her... saying twinkle toes, and then I think we needed some alternates for people, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Now she's-says all sorts of stuff about... insulting people. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah, that's really...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara mocking Toph for not being able to see the stars.</i>] Katara just said one of like her meanest lines ever.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, that-that was another line too [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] I thought was going to get cut at one point...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... because there was like [<i>In a mock concerned tone.</i>] "there's no-she can't make fun of her blind, that seems too"...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Right. [<i>Josh and Giancarlo laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>...  but I feel like it's okay, 'cause Toph then kicks her butt with the earthbending, so, [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] they're-they're kind of equally jerky to each other.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>I also kind of feel like when-when brothers and sisters argue, which-I mean know Katara and Toph aren't related, but it's that type of relationship, you go for the throat, [<i>Mike and Josh laugh intermittently.</i>] you know, you-you're not politically correct when you're trying to insult your brother or your sister, like you-you try to find something that's wrong with them, and... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] That's correct. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... really hone in on that, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Aaron must have had a great childhood, that was his line that-and, uh, yeah, that was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Was it? [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... another one I thought wasn't going to make it. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] Of course, now Toph jokes about her blindness all the time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to Sokka inchworming in his sleeping bag.</i>] I like this little animation of Sokka, he's like a little worm...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... moving over there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Josh and Giancarlo snicker at Katara snide comments on Toph's unwillingness to help setup camp.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>I notice that, like, subconsciously working on this episode, because it was so much about them getting progressively more and more tired, I-I felt like it was kind of affecting me personally [<i>Mike and Josh snicker.</i>] when I was working on it. I mean, every episode does kind of wear you out by the time you're-get to the end to it-end of it, but this one especially, I was like, man that was just-yawning a lot. [<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] <i>I</i> had the little circles under my eyes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Wow, that's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Josh snickers again at Katara saying that, unlike Zuko, Sokka is fun and perky. Followed by a brief pause in commentary until Sokka gives an enunciated "Shush" to the rest of the group, as he tries to get some sleep.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Jack's read of that line was really fun. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think it was-it was written as, just a regular "shhh".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Okay, right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>He, yeah Jack DeSena who plays Sokka always comes up with...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... kind of, funny [<i>Laughs.</i>] variations on things.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Giancarlo and Josh laugh.</i>] I believe for the record, Andrea was like, "What... what is that, what did you just do?", and he's like, "Sure, you know, I'm you know, changing it up a little." [<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Refers to the approaching tank train.</i>] Someone had mentioned at some point, in a board meeting or something that Lo and Li were driving the tank train.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Oh right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was, that is our little secret, so-idea.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. In a playfully devious tone</i>] I thought I'd divulge that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. You never see them, but Lo and Li, Azula's teachers from uh, the first episode...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] The old ladies.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... of season two, we just imagine they're in there in with their goggles, [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] just like driving the, the-the tank train, 'cause we're wondering, there's no... [<i>Josh and Giancarlo chuckle.</i>] we don't see anyone, how is it getting around?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the mongoose lizards that Azula, Mai and Ty Lee are riding.</i>] What do, what's those lizards called?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>We're debating what the name of these things [<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh.</i>] are. We think they're mongoose lizards, or mongoose dragons.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Might've been...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... some fancy name for them, I forget.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Azula, Mai and Ty Lee.</i>] I remember kind of, i-in a very geek fashion, like-like daydreaming why they were riding on these instead of the rhinos, and it was like, well it's, they're, it's they're-they're the all-terrain um, mounts in the Fire Nation, [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] whereas the rhinos are kind of more like the tanks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah totally...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... they're-they're, they're faster.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the mongoose lizards jumping over the rock pillars Toph bends up at them.</i>] Look at them, look at them...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah see, there you go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... jumping over the rocks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Rhino couldn't...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Case in point, right there! [<i>Josh laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... no rhino could jump over the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] And, [<i>Dramatically clears throat. In a mock judgmental tone.</i>] I believe they run on water, Giancarlo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] Well that was, that was kind of the reason we needed a new creature, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That you wouldn't think would be able to run on water, but later on they-they needed to, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] I actually found reference for that lizard running on water stuff online, I mean we-we actually pull a lot of reference off the Internet, but just, you know, anything from like, a color scheme for a cloud, you know for the-for the sky or something, to, you know, animation of a-of a horse running or something, and somehow try to turn that into a... into an <i>Avatar</i> animal. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh. Refers to Sokka freaking out over not getting any sleep.</i>] I like this animation of Sokka...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] This is great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... is hilarious too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the previous shot of the characters, where Sokka's arm was swaying in the air.</i>] I like that dangle that his little arm did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Refers to the low angle shot of Sokka.</i>] Yeah. I love the angle too, it like... [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the tank train.</i>] And... duh, Ben and Jeremy do the sound and music, did a great job with this episode with the-Ben did all the tank train... sounds and stuff, and um, Jeremy does the-the scoring and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the cut to Zuko. In an enthusiastic tone.</i>] Zuko's in this episode!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In an enthusiastic tone.</i>] Yeah, Zuko! [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] What's kind of funny...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. In a fawning tone.</i>] He's so handsome!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... is-oh, he is. I always forget like, that this is the episode where the-the kids don't even know who Azula is yet, like we, when we were writing it, it's like, you kind of have to remind yourself like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... like, you know who you-who they are, and the audience knows who she is, but, these kids have no idea who's been...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... tracking them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause in commentary until the group realizes that Appa fell asleep while in flight.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Refers to the profile shot of Appa, with Aang crawling down his face, their features fluttering as they rapidly freefall.</i>] This shot right here, I can remember uh, Bryan drawing on the outline. He like drew, you know, just in freehand...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... and it was, eh, I think I still have it. I'ma sell it on eBay.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence of Appa trying to fly again, sailing through the treetops, and the multiple closeup shots of the group being flung around in his saddle.</i>] Awesome falling.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Just kidding. [<i>Josh and Giancarlo laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>The-yeah, where Aang is... ju...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Upside down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... upside down on the saddle, right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Josh and Giancarlo laugh.</i>] Kinda drew it in...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to everyone's sluggish disembarking from Appa.</i>] Yeah, all the animation of everyone being really tired is funny-like Sokka's walk cycle here is [<i>Laughs.</i>] really.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>It's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the little needles stuck in Sokka and Katara's hair.</i>] Think they also have like little, um, for tree...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... needles in their... [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] clothes and hair. Yeah, it's so funny, funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause in commentary until Toph angrily asks Katara what she means by the former's "issues".</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this just feels like a bunch of kids, who... just have not slept, [<i>Laughs.</i>] and... everyone's on edge, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... just kind of-in a way, it's very realistic, it's like, this is what would happen when, bunch of kids... running around the world together, not sleeping.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Giancarlo.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Josh.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] They'd break, eventually.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Refers to Katara confirming she blames their lack of sleep on Toph.</i>] She's cracking.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>I love how like she-Katara is just poking her, [<i>Imitating Katara.</i>] "Come on!", [<i>Mike laughs intermittently.</i>] "Bring it on!". [<i>Brief pause.</i>] The uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. Refers to Aang angrily defending Appa from Toph's accusations.</i>] Aang gets very defensive of Appa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>That's his-that's his soft spot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Josh.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Yeah. I think he...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] You ever want to... make A-Aang mad... [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah, mentioning of...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... tied up Appa...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Or steal him. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa's shedding.</i>] The Appa-the Appa shedding, I just remembered is, in-was an idea from like the first season. Mike, do you remember that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh, I think...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Someone came in with the idea of like, Zuko finding them because of Appa?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, that was a really old idea, [<i>Josh agrees intermittently.</i>] that may have even been... from development, like, the idea that they could-that Zuko could...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Follow them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... track them with Appa, 'cause he's shedding [<i>Josh affirms.</i>] 'cause it's hot out, and it's hot out and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah, it was great for the springtime, you know...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... just show, like the seasons changing, and [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] how it affects him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, there's stuff like that, ideals like that we've... have been there kind of since the beginning, or get pitched and we...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... they're great ideas, but sometimes we don't have, they just don't work into the stories we're-we're doing now, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, we always end up kind of finding a place for 'em eventually.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>It's craz-neat how they all work together, like the Appa shedding and then, you know, them ending up chased relentlessly, and they just kind of fit together like puzzle pieces, and they...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka drinking from a cup of water.</i>] I always kind of think that Sokka's drinking coffee here, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I think that was sort of the, [<i>Josh laughs.</i>] the-the idea. I mean, he probably isn't, but it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... it just looks [<i>Josh and Mike chuckle.</i>] like he's having an espresso to kind of perk him up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, he's just-I think it's just water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the theme playing as Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Momo wash Appa's coat.</i>] I like this uh, washing Appa music. [<i>Mike and Josh chuckle. Refers to Sokka getting hit by Aang's waterbending.</i>] And Sokka gets wet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Classic. [<i>Giancarlo and Josh laugh. Brief pause until the cut to a medium closeup shot of Appa's head, his fur still wet and dangly.</i>] Yeah, I like wet Appa too. He's been wet and droopy a couple times. He looks cute.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Appa breaking up the treetops as he flies up.</i>] Uh-oh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>That's trouble.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Appa made a big mistake right there. They would have been fine if Appa hadn't hit the trees. [<i>Giancarlo laughs. Brief pause.</i>] So...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] This coming up was uh... you know, when you-she sees Uncle, they don't know each other, you know, one's on the good side, one's on the bad side, or Un-you know, Uncle's whatever, but, it was great. It was-was a perfect opportunity to like have them talk to each other, and... not know who they are.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah, that's a really nice, uh... moment in this episode coming up, when the two of them share the tea.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I remember reading that and just loving that scene, so then I... ended up storyboarding it...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] You did?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>]...  'cause I loved it so much, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>That's a very rare occasion when Mike or Bryan will actually kind of, request to storyboard a section, usually 'cause they're just so busy. And uh, Mike just came into my office one day, and said, "Hey, you mind if I do the uh, [<i>Mike chuckles.</i>] the scene with Toph and Uncle?", and I was like, "Hmm, that's less work for me,".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Josh and Mike laugh.</i>] Mmm, alright.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] You storyboarded the whole fight in the end, which is crazy, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Oh yeah, the three-way fight.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause in the commentary until the scene fades in from black, and Aang soars through the sky on his glider.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the previous scene of Mai and Ty Lee finding the right term for clumps of hair.</i>] This scene that just passed, I remember we did a rewrite on it after we saw the animatic, and Aaron said that he wanted to put in, um-maybe you also did too Mike, but, have Mai and Ty Lee talk more. Because I don't think we've heard from them since show 203...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Two... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... which was "Return to Omashu".
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the sequence of Aang walking through a deserted, ruined Earth Kingdom town.</i>] This part's so Western-y, it's great, just like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] That looks great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... quiet man in the deserted town.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>These are storyboards by Ian Graham, I think.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shot of a house's front shutters bouncing in the wind, and a low angle shot of the torn up overhang of another house.</i>] He did... some nice like atmospheric shots.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I really like kind of the... contrast and the art direction that th-Bryan did, and the, um, background painters did in this episode...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Oh yeah, like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shadows looming off the town's buildings.</i>]... just like the dark shadows, and... really got that sunset-ty feel.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>This is great like a western, you know, you're being chased, and now it's time to like, now, you're ready, you're going to face 'em...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... I don't-I love that, it's so great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the warmer color palette on Momo and Sokka.</i>] Nice sunset colors there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Josh imitates Momo hissing at Mai and Ty Lee.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, that's a crazy Momo screech.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Imitating Katara's distress at being pursued.</i>] How did they find us? [<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] There's al-there's occasionally lines like-like Josh was just talking about that get added sort of later and-and um... I had to do like a, a temp track I guess for Katara saying "How did they find us?", and it-and I-I tried to imitate Mae, [<i>Josh snickers.</i>] and I always kind of feel bad that she heard that, [<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] and-and was, you know, hugely insulted by it or something.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I always enjoy your... performances Giancarlo. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>It is when-it's funny when you hear an animatic, and out of nowhere you hear Giancarlo's voice. [<i>Mike and Josh laugh. In a mock surprised tone.</i>] Oh!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>It's a little scarring, 'cause every time...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. Refers to the scene of the mongoose lizards running across the river.</i>] There they go! They're-they're-they're running on the water!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Oh yeah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] So they do, they really do run like that too, don't they...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[In the background.] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... with their arms like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, they kind of... [<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] flail their arms.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Josh.</i>]... flailing around, like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>When I was a kid and I saw that, I laughed so hard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Giancarlo and Mike laugh. Refers to the slicing sound effect on Katara's water disk attacks.</i>] I notice there's like a slight kind of scissors noise when Katara's like throwing those water... blasts at Ty Lee there. It's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I think those are kind of like water disks...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... like sharper.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shot of Ty Lee somersaulting, jumping into the air, and then falling back into the camera.</i>] That's awesome.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>It's a little shot that I added in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka fighting Ty Lee, even as she incapacitates his limbs.</i>] Yeah, I love this part. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>This is great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, she's chi, [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>] chi-blocking him. [<i>Josh laughs at Ty Lee wincing at hitting Sokka's head.</i>] Which, really for Sokka that just means he loses sensation in his limbs. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Since he doesn't have any bending abilities.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>I like that, that, we're kind of seeing there's-maybe there's no chi in his head.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Or his head's just so dense.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] The fighting scenes are always really difficult to write. We usually, the-we just usually write a generic version of it, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] sometimes-sometimes not, sometimes not, but like, you know, we didn't have that goofy arm thing, which turns out hilarious, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's a lot of stuff we'll work out in the storyboard meetings with the-the storyboard artists and the directors and... kind of come up with funny actions, or with Kisu...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... for-for the action scenes and stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Fights sometimes almost... kind of have a mind of their own when you're working on it, because it's-when you're working on them, 'cause you um, you kind of get characters back into a corner or whatever, and then you're suddenly, wait, how are they going to get out of this corner, and... they, they just, it's like this organic process.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>I'm glad I don't have to think about that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh. Refers to Azula imitating Zuko by covering up her left eye.</i>] That was another joke too I didn't think we'd...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... get-get through, but I love it, that's... when she imitates Zuko. [<i>Laughs.</i>] It's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That's her first time, yeah, that's... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And that is totally like-like you were saying earlier, Giancarlo, like that's totally the brother-sister thing too, [<i>Giancarlo murmurs in agreement.</i>] like.. only she will just [<i>Giancarlo chuckles.</i>] make fun of his scar to his face. [<i>Refers to Iroh and Toph.</i>] So, yeah this is the, the beautiful Uncle-Toph moment, where he's making her tea.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>There's kind of a little, there's subtle stuff going on here too that may not be um... completely obvious. He's kind of... he's kind of like, testing to see if-looking she had-when he hands her that tea, [<i>Josh murmurs in agreement.</i>] he's testing to see like how aware she is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... 'cause you can-it's like he can kind of tell she's blind, but.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause in commentary until Toph tells Iroh she knows that people think she's weak just because she's blind.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's always nice when, we have the opportunity to have characters get together who'd normally... you don't see together...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. </i>]... in-in the episodes, or they're the enemies 'cause they're chasing each other, and... and, yeah, that's what I, I think that's, I just, I love the, the meaning of this scene about like having, letting people who love you help you, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... and, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh correcting his statement to Toph about helping the people he loves, clarifying he's only just met her. Giancarlo and Josh laugh.</i>] I like that read. [<i>In a deep, guttural tone.</i>] Ohhh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, we-Mako is such a great voice actor, and this year we were sorry that he-he passed away to cancer, but um, he was such a great-he brought so much to the role of Uncle and, and we just, we'll always remember him, and, and honor him in our... with our show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I'm sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... with our show. Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] Yeah, like this ha-you know, this is perfect, this is just the great opportunity to like, before they knew who ea-you know, before the season continues and they know who each other are, they can talk to each other and just like strangers.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike gives an affirming murmur. Refers to Iroh saying he's been keeping up with Zuko in case he needs help.</i>] And you get the idea too that like Uncle, even though he let Zuko go, he like, he's still worried about him, so he's... been tracking him down, and just kinda-kinda staying on the sidelines until he needs, he needs Uncle, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah. He's been tracking Zuko, who's been tracking Azula, [<i>Mike and Josh chuckles.</i>] who's been tracking Aang, as a kid is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Girl is just... tracking everyone.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the showdown between Aang, Azula and Zuko at the town.</i>]... and it all sort of, comes down to this point.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep. [<i>Refers to Zuko's ostrich horse.</i>] You can't really tell, but Zuko's ostrich horse ran through really fast. [<i>Josh and Giancarlo laugh.</i>] And then we always, weird joke, that he and the mongoose lizard are fighting somewhere.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike, Josh and Giancarlo laugh. Refers to Zuko, Azula, and Aang all adopting fighting stances, as each of them waits for the other to make the first move.</i>] So this is where we start the kind of <i>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly</i>...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... um, Mexican standoff, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] they call it, where uh, who's going to shoot first?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the wide shot of Aang, Zuko, and Azula, with the camera slowly panning from Aang on the right to Zuko and Azula on the left.</i>] That's great buildup.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>That's fine.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>I-I think that this sequence was about twice as long in the original animatic, but unfortunately it has to get... every show has to fit within twenty-two minutes, so. It was a, a little shortened, but I think it still works.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Azula attacking Zuko first.</i>] And the big surprise of course is that Azula, given the choice between capturing the Avatar or attacking her own brother, [<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] would rather go after her brother.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah, I love how she shoots him first, it's so great, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] so telling.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>So, doing a three-way fight is... is not something that I look forward to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... doing again. I mean it was very, it was exciting hearing about it-like reading about it, but, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] I, the-the kind of logistics of keeping track of the characters and everything is just, it's a lot of work.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I always think... well, there's always exceptions to the rule, but usually the... the best fights are usually the one-on-one stuff, but, I don't know, you did such a great job with this I'd like, [<i>In a mock enthusiastic tone.</i>] let's do some more [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>] three-way fights that Giancarlo can direct. [<i>Josh laughs. Refers to Azula's firebending at the buildings Aang is jumping on.</i>] I love this little touch too that you added where, she shoots...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Shoots the building.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Azula shoots blue fire, but when it then catches something on fire, it turns to regular red fire.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Just a cool little touch.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>In an enthusiastic tone.</i>] Just trying to keep it scientific!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Azula encircling the room Aang and her are in with her blue flames, that quickly change to orange hues.</i>] Yes, there, did it again, yeah. Like the idea was like Azula's flames burn hotter or something, and then, but you know, when it catches something on fire, it cools down [<i>Laughs.</i>] to regular fire temperature I guess. [<i>Giancarlo laughs.</i>] Scientifically speaking.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs. Refers to Sokka ambushing Azula as she exits out of the building.</i>] Sokka, jumping around the corner.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara, Sokka, Iroh and Toph joining the fight.</i>] Well, now it becomes more than three-way, there's like, eight people fighting or something. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>A lot of it had to be handled by cutting away from the action...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs in the background.</i>] They got away.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... like you, you just do it, a little shot, like there's a crazy one like this where you sort of see all four of them, but... it's like you gain more by what you don't see.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Toph asking Aang, Katara and Sokka if they needed some help fighting Azula.</i>] That was Toph's way of apologizing...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh. Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... sort of been apologizing to each other, just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects. Refers to Iroh knocking Azula off-balance by running into her with his belly.</i>] I love too-did you, was that the storyboard you came up for the, Uncle just bellying, hitting her with her belly-his belly?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Giancarlo and Josh laugh.</i>] I think that might have been a Kisu suggestion, [<i>Mike affirms intermittently.</i>] he always kind of thought that Uncle would fight with his belly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Josh laugh.</i>] Yeah. That's awesome. [<i>Refers to the point-of-view shot where Iroh focuses in on Toph, then on Katara, Aang and Sokka.</i>] So this is...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] They didn't...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... the moment right here where he recognizes that... she's part of the group, [<i>Refers to Azula sudden attack on Iroh.</i>] and Azula takes advantage of that moment of weakness.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the shot of Zuko, Toph, Aang, Katara and Sokka attacking Azula with a simultaneous attack of firebending, earthbending, airbending, waterbending and Sokka's boomerang.</i>] This shot right here, I've seen on the internet a thousand times, I think people really kind of liked the idea of all four elements combining to attack, you know, the forces of evil.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shot of Zuko, ashamed and distraught, kneeling behind a fallen Iroh, as the town burns in the background.</i>] This is my favorite shot in the episode right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah, I... I remember like posing out the-the Zuko... I, as close as I could get to him crying...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... over Uncle's, you know, condition, but. Obviously, he doesn't, he doesn't cry, but he's having a hard time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>For the ending, I remember writing some ending where like, uh, Toph and Katara are about to argue, and then they stop, [<i>Refers to the final shot of the episode where all the protagonists are asleep on Appa's saddle.</i>] but Aaron came up with this, they just go to sleep, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and I'm like, it's the perfect...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects and laughs.</i>] Yeah, it's totally the perfect ending...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... you forget that they still haven't slept that whole time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, thanks to everyone who did a... everyone on the crew who did a great job with this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>Yeah, my board artists Bobby Rubio, Ian Graham, and Oreste Canestrelli.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the credits.</i>] And... those people there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yes, and everyone else. I'll just try to read the credits as fast as I can. [<i>Josh laughs. In a quicker tempo.</i>] Kathy Gilmore [<i>Giancarlo and Josh laugh.</i>]!  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Thanks guys for doing the commentary, good times.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>Same, thanks Mike...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Thanks for having us.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... Giancarlo...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Good work people.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>]... and Freddie... for reals.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>I'm incidentally working on another Josh script as we speak.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>I believe it also has a little uh, Toph-Katara argument...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Mike and Giancarlo laugh in the background.</i>] Oh, yeah, that's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Josh
</th>
<td>... here and there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>We're just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Don't tell anyone though. [<i>Josh laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Giancarlo
</th>
<td>... we're just repeating ourselves. [<i>Josh laughs.</i>]
</td></tr></tbody></table>]