<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>No commentary until the episode title card appears.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Here we are at part two, of the big Book One finale. Uh, this was written by Aaron, and uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron Ehasz
</th>
<td>Mmm.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzo
</th>
<td>Who's sitting right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Great episode. Uh, do you want to talk a little about the writing process Aaron, 'cause there...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I'd be glad to.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Alright, there's a lot of great stuff that goes on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>It's funny that you mention [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] that the episode was written by me...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[Interjects.] Yeah, I know it is isn't it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>...because at the end of every episode, you usually see "Written by so and so". Anyway, [<i>Claps hands together.</i>] uh, basically this is just, uh, when you see a writer at the end, that's the leas-sort of the lead writer on the episode, in-person who writes the script, but I guess in general, we're extremely collaborative on this show, about the way that we develop every story, um, and the way that we kind of write and rewrite the episodes. So, there's a lot of contributions coming from, um, a lot of different places. In the case of the part one of this and the part two of this for example, we like pitched out for I think an entire week, we worked out every detail of the story of both so that they would all kind of flow together and connect and work so well, um. I should probably mention some of the other members of the writing staff while I have a chance. Um, there's John O'Bryan, and Tim Hedrick, and Elizabeth Welch Ehasz, who's my wife, and uh, we also have Josh Hamilton, who is uh, our superb writing assistant...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, all...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>]... writer's assistant.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In a playfully enthusiastic tone.</i>]... great, talented folks, and uh, it's a pleasure to write with you all. [<i>Aaron chuckles; refers to the <a href="/wiki/Baboon_spirit" title="Baboon spirit">baboon spirit</a> that Aang talks to.</i>] We like this odd spirit guy who's very funny creation...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Who's voiced by Mark Hamill.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes. Mark Hamill, also the voice of the Fire Lord, you may or may not know that, and uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Aang is voiced by...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Finishes Bryan's sentence after a brief pause.</i>] Zach Tyler Eisen.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In a mock serious tone.</i>] That's right, I was waiting for you to fill it in [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]. I thought you weren't s...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>No, he's a great, he's an amazing twelve year old young actor, and uh, just has brought so much life and vitality to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects, in a mock serious tone.</i>] A consummate professional!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Aang's character. Yeah, just, just more professional than I am [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] at my age, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Zuko, a man of few words, but well-acted words.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, uh, Dante Basco does his voice, and uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects</i>] Yeah, he's pretty...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>]... just a great, another great actor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>When we were casting Zuko, we said, we wanted someone who could say one word, but suggest like a lifetime of tension, and uh, Dante just did such a great job.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I remember also, that my middle name is Dante. [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] I remember seeing his name on the, the CD of auditions, and his name was Dante Basco, and I was like "Ah, that's the guy, right there, I know!". [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] Of course, I hadn't heard his voice at all, but actually turned out that he was, he was good. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] James Garrett did uh, Roku. He's a really cool actor.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, great voice quality. Zach, the voice of Aang, was um, what's incredible is he's a master at ADR, which is Additional Dialogue Recording. I think that's what it stands for, and um, it's where you have to match your voice to the picture, so you have to go in and match the animation. It's really difficult, and um, even for adult actors, it's, it's pretty trying, and Zach is just incredible, he's done entire episodes that way when, when we had to do that, and um... he's, he's a trooper. And he's also, what's great is he's such a normal kid. He and Justin Brinsfield are uh, recording engineer, I remember them just like rocking out on the bass, on his first trip out here to LA. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko talking to Aang about the struggles he's gone through with his father and sister.</i>] This is a cool scene, 'cause it, this is probably the most Zuko has talked in one, in one stretch, [<i>Laughs.</i>] the whole, whole season.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Because he thinks no one's listening. [<i>Aaron and Mike laugh; refers to the warm light from the campfire hitting Aang.</i>] I like that uh, color correction there, we had to suggest that that campfire was there and looks cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the next scene, where the Fire Nation has resumed their assault on the Northern Water Tribe.</i>] And...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[Interjects.] The big epic battle.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... this was definitely a challenge, 'cause we wanted to, you know, suggest the enormity of this battle, but due to time and resources and limitations, uh, we obviously can't show every part of the battle, so...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, this is, you know, really hard to do on, in TV.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>But um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I think it comes across.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... I think we really pulled it off.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, you get, you know, shots like this, where you see a lo-see things mixed in with, you know, the details, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Fire Nation tundra tanks and cruisers.</i>] Great tanks design by Aldina Dias, and um, these ships too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think all the ships and the tanks are CG in the show, computer generated, and composited in with the animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Hahn dramatically revealing himself to Zhao, flipping his hair as he removes his disguise.</i>] Hahn's there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>There he is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So we shot reference in Dean flipping his hair around for that, for that scene.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>This is a great, Aaron had had this idea. We had totally forgot about Hahn and this mission that he was supposed to be on, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] and Aaron pitched this idea, "Like, what if, what if he just, Zhao just tosses him overboard. I know it's kinda crazy", and I thought it was hilarious.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh shaking his head in pity after Hahn's failed attempt.</i>] I love that Uncle has the empathy to shake his head...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... and pity.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Bye-bye, Hahn.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the library that Zhao found the secret of the Ocean and Moon spirits in.</i>] So this, remember this library, because it will show up again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the close up shot of the classic Chinese characters that Zhao reads.</i>] And the calligraphy by S. L. Lee, who's our um, calligraphy expert, and does all of our translation, all o-early on, we decided all the writing would be in... classic Chinese. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] I found, I think I searched Chinese calligraphy on the internet. His website came up first, clicked on it, sent him an email, and an hour later, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] he called me. I just got really lucky. [<i>Refers to the sound effects that play in the background of the Spirit World scenes.</i>] I love the sound design in the Spirit World. Um, Ben Wynn did a really cool treatment, and a lot of reversed sounds, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, what did you like most about the Spirit World, Aaron? 'Cause you wrote the Spirit World episode...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>In background.</i>] Oh yeah...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... in episode 107 as well. I feel that you have a special affinity.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I do. I think I enjoy... the sense of discovery and ancientness, [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] and I don't know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Lots of odd possibilities...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... in the Spirit World.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Brief pause until Aang walks down the staircase into Koh's lair.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Aaron created this really creepy character, Koh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this whole sequence, the purpose was to be very scary. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>David Filoni directed this episode, and I, he storyboarded this sequence. [<i>Refers to the extreme closeup shot of Koh's Noh face smiling.</i>] I love that shot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>We got the perfect actor to pay it, play Koh too, Erik Todd Dellums, who is uh, played a villain on a popular television crime show that I enjoy. [<i>Bryan chuckles.</i>] Very amazing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this is definitely... I think if I was 8 years old, and saw this guy, I would probably have nightmares, [<i>Bryan chuckles intermittently.</i>] so, sorry kids if you had nightmares.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Fear is a healthy...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yes, yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... natural emotion.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>But I just love, you know, again, it's like... not only is it a scary moment, but it's like, you're kind of feeling for Aang, 'cause he has to like, put on this brave face and not show any emotion during this scene, which was a great device, I think, that Aaron used to like, add drama to the scene, so... you know, you're, you're, you're waiting for that moment when you know Aang is going to show some emotion or...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang taking a breath in the Spirit World, and cutting to him doing the same in the physical world.</i>] I love how it affects him in the real world too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the blizzard snows falling outside.</i>] I love all the snow in this scene...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... it looks really cool. You really feel like it's a... [<i>Adopts a dramatically humorous tone.</i>] blizzard, blizzardy tundra.   
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, weather, a really hard thing to pull off on TV animation, and this one definitely came out...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... successful. [<i>Refers to the dark, shifting clouds behind Yue and Katara.</i>] I like that shot too, the sky is really cool. [<i>Refers to Sokka saying that Zuko knows how to survive.</i>] Interesting hearing Sokka, [<i>Laughs.</i>] sort of complimenting Zuko.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah, be like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Recognizes, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Bryan.</i>]... congratulates him, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause until Koh starts telling Aang about Tui and La, scuttling and twining around him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Really creepy sounds Ben Wynn did for Koh's... movements.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>Brief pause until Koh changes faces, from an old man to an ogre.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Like all the different faces we see of Koh too. It's like...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's a great...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>]... kinda monster faces and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... people, and animals.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>There were even more.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We just couldn't [<i>Bryan, Mike and Aaron laugh.</i>] fit them all in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Koh has quite a collection.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I think we may hear more from Koh at some point in the future. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Brief pause until Aang makes the connection that Tui and La are the koi fish in the Spirit Oasis.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, I like it, yes, so here's the moment where he realizes the importance of the koi fish that we saw earlier.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Koh swinging around to face Aang, who switched back to his expressionless face between cuts.</i>] Almost caught him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the emotionless farewell that Aang gives to Koh.</i>] I love that read that Zach did for, for Aang, [<i>Aaron gives an affirming murmur.</i>] it's totally deadpan.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Brief pause until Aang greets Hei Bai.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Hei Bai returns from, he was in the Spirit World episode, 107, the panda guy. [<i>Refers to the Fire Nation destructive advancing into the Northern Water Tribe at night.</i>] So, here's some more, more battle. Fire Nation is, is, you know, on the winning side, until...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] It's the moon!  
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the full moon rising behind the Fire Nation ships.</i>]...we see the moon.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So, yeah, back to that idea that uh, natural phenomenon accentuates... the bending. [<i>Refers to the sound of waterbent icicles piercing Fire Nation shields.</i>] I love the sound design there, it was great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Pakku facing down multiple opponents with his enhanced waterbending.</i>] We get to see Pakku really... show his masterful skills here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause.</i>] This is cool. This, this idea of this, kind of, like waterbending serpent uh, was from one of the earliest concept sketches that we did, I believe for the development of the show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>It's kinda what Aang does a little bit in uh, 102, [<i>Bryan gives affirming murmurs intermittently.</i>] where he comes out of the water in that water spiral.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause until Aang is sent out of the Spirit World by Hei Bai.</i>] And... Miyuki boarded this part, she wa-she's great with the animals and kind of, the fanciful elements of the show. [<i>Refers to the Hei Bai attacking the baboon spirit, and changing back into his panda form.</i>] So much just happened in the last 5 seconds, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] there's no way to commentate on it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shot of the Northern Water Tribe, as Aang's spirit flies through the sky.</i>] I really like that shot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes it, I mean that's, you know, story thing that we struggle with every episode really, is like to, we have these really complex stories sometimes that we have to cram into, you know, twenty-two and a half minutes, so. It's certainly hard to get everything in, but somehow we always manage to do it, so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang airbending Zuko while roped up, and escaping from the cave.</i>] It's a great little uh, comedic moment...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... with some fantastic animation by JM Animation. Love that Aang does this huge airbending move, and then can only inchworm, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] his face in the snow. [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh; refers to the scene where Zuko throws Aang to the side as he readies to fight Katara again.</i>] I love how Zuko just dismisses him. [<i>Refers to the shot where Katara swiftly counters Zuko's firebending, traps and suspends him in a tower of ice, then shatters it, depositing him on the ground.</i>] This is a great shot. Dean Kelly did this part. So now, with the full moon, Katara's got the upper hand on Zuko. [<i>Refers to Sokka breaking Aang out of his rope bindings, and letting them go as they flit around in the air.</i>] Great animation on that little bit of rope.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, that... the little details like that, I just love.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We're just so lucky to have little flourishes like that in TV animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's great, 'cause the, the studios in Korea that do the animation, uh, what's great is that, you know, we've set up a system where they are able to add and kind of augment uh, the storyboards that we send them. So they'll, they'll often add great little acting moments, or little, little flourishes like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the scenes where Aang saves Zuko from freezing out in the blizzard, and Zhao capturing the Moon Spirit.</i>] I love the contrast of Aang's altruism, and then [<i>Deepens voice.</i>] Zhao's evil.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So I think act three was kind of a challenge, 'cause it was all this, couple, just very monochromatic tones. There was the red section, and then the black and white section later. Was that difficult art direction wise, Bryan?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It was, there was a like, okay, because red, and then there's a transition where the sky goes black, and you lose the moon, so, do we see the stars, do we not see the stars? And um, yeah, you, you think it might be easy just having one color, but then we have fire flashes, uh, where there's a little bit of color.  [<i>Refers to Yue's flashback sequence, where the colors are slightly muted.</i>] I'm actuall—speaking of color, I'm really happy with how this uh, flashback sequence came out, um. Hye-Jung Kim, color supervisor just did a fantastic job. I love doing these monochromatic scenes, but you know, they're not totally monochromatic, they're just limited palettes usually. Little, little hints of color. [<i>Refers to the close up shot of Yue as an infant, partially submerged in water that ripples out from her.</i>] Great water animations. [<i>Refers to the scene of Arnook and his wife holding a now white-haired Yue.</i>] See the younger Pakku in... those scenes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zhao's speech on his accomplishments, just before Momo attacks him.</i>] This is a great moment for Zhao.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And just when he's getting too pompous.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Momo takes him down. [<i>Refers to Zhao's exaggerated facial animation.</i>] This is where I definitely see some acting reference from my so-called performance. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] Yeah, it's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's interesting, because bad acting often translates to good animation. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] Gotta do this like soap opera acting. [<i>Refers to the theme playing in the background.</i>] Love the music here by Jeremy Zuckerman.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Brief pause until Aang starts describing to Zhao what destroying the Moon Spirit will do to the world and Zhao.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Destiny's a real recurring theme on <i>Avatar</i>, and we approach that theme a couple times over the course of the series.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I'm glad that we, I'm glad that we often talk about... the choice that's involved with destiny, and th-and that, you know, Zhao could choose to, um, not destroy [<i>Laughs.</i>] the moon here, and um. I think that kind of ties in with the, the bending abilities too, that they're not... purely magic, you know, it's still coming from something physical. It's like the destiny is there for the character to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's definitely a message, like in, uh, "The Fortuneteller", that destin-your destiny is something you have the power to shape yourself.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>'Cause yeah, no mat-I think no matter what you think about the concept of destiny, people, people have certain situations they're born into, and they're constantly living up to it, or fighting it. [<i>Refers to Iroh's firebending changing the color palette on Zhao and his soldiers from black and white to warmer colors.</i>] There was a scene that was difficult with the flashes of fire.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. I like, what I love about that is seeing Uncle, you know, beat up some guys. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] 'Cause he, he's usually very peaceful and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[Interjects.] Yeah, we only hear about his former days as the general.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah that, moments like that, you know that he's, he's not one to be messed with, so. [<i>Refers to the sound of Aang's voice in the Avatar State, now echoed and layered with much deeper voices.</i>] Oh, so that's a cool sound effect that, that Ben has put together, that combines multiple voices, uh, as kind of this idea that Aang is speaking with the voice of all these former Avatars.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Simultaneously.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, in his former lives.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Great sequence by Dave Filoni here. [<i>Refers to the shot of Aang suddenly sinking into the waters of the Spirit Oasis.</i>] That came out great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, love that moment.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shots of the Northern Water Tribe turning from grey to glowing blue.</i>] You should see Dave's storyboards for this, with all the marker renderings of this lighting effect spreading out through the city, it's really incredible.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, what did we... Dave was a big uh, Godzilla fan, [<i>Refers to the giant Ocean Spirit monster Aang is controlling.</i>] so I think we ended up calling this guy Koizilla [<i>Mike and Aaron laugh.</i>].
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, it's true, the design says Koizilla.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the colors on the Water Tribe and Fire Nation soldiers turning from monochrome to a bluer palette as the light from the Ocean Spirit hits them.</i>] Another pretty tricky color correction, adding these glows and... following his path through the city.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang manipulating the spirit from within using waterbending forms.</i>] But, it's cool 'cause we see Aang do the kung fu. Uh, he's kinda doing waterbending inside this thing, and then we see the, the Koizilla do the move after him, so you get this idea that Aang's controlling it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I really liked the effect that Dave got, um, in his storyboards with the marker renderings. So when I did the character design of the Koizilla, I started with these smaller drawings using design markers, and blew them u-blew them up, and then sort of traced the patterns that I'd made. It gave it a real, kind of liquid yet energy... feeling, and it took forever, [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] and I commend JM for [<i>Laughs.</i>] pulling off the animation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko and Zhao beginning their fight.</i>] I love this, this face-off.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>This is a rematch we've been waiting for, for seventeen...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... episodes, I think?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Since episode...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] 103.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... the third episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's nice to see Zuko's a little more cavalier now. He was a little tentative in the 103 fight, staying, staying back at first.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Iroh noticing that Yue has some of the Moon Spirit's life inside her.</i>] Here, Uncle's... showing his ability to see... see more than the oth—a normal person could see.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And if you noti...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] The more you know about Uncle.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the closeup shot of Yue, with her eyes retaining their blue color, compared to everyone else's colorless ones.</i>] If you notice, Yue's eyes are blue, despite the rest of the black and white.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Because the Moon Spirit is in her.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's right, that's right. [<i>Mike affirms.</i>] She's got a little bit of the... otherworldly energy in her.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Yue healing the Moon Spirit at the cost of her own life.</i>] Yeah, this is just a great dramatic...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the sound effects from Yue's healing.</i>] Great sound design.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... moment. [<i>Refers to Sokka catching Yue's body.</i>] We actually get to see Sokka being tender and emotional, which doesn't happen too often. [<i>Simultaneously with Bryan.</i>] Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Oh yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Great animation on her...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... [<i>Laughs.</i>] lifeless body. That's pretty good.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, I was just gonna say, you know, to see Sokka... like that is, is cool, 'cause every, you know, what we try to do is like, even though Sokka's the goofball a lot, you get to see this other side of him, and, you know, all the characters are like that, where we, we show different sides of them at different, depending on the story, and like, what's going on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the multiple shots of Fire Nation ships, who were designed by Steve Ziolkowski.</i>] Great uh, 3D models of the ships and tanks by Steve Z. I wish I could pronounce his name, but it's more complicated than mine, so, sorry Steve. [<i>Refers to the long shot of the Fire Nation ships backing away from the Northern Water Tribe, as the Ocean Spirit moves into the foreground.</i>] Again, we have to imply a much bigger battle than we have the resources to show, but I think it came out pretty great. [<i>Refers to the awestruck expressions on Katara, Iroh and Sokka's faces as they see the Moon Spirit become Yue.</i>] It's great, I really feel like you can sense the characters know they're in the presence of something... otherworldly, it's really cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Brief pause until Yue's spirit says she will always be with Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sound effect applied to Yue's voice.</i>] Kind of a cool backwards... sound...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, we, we re...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... treatment on her voice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Classic trick of reversing the sound, applying reverb, and then reversing that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the moon reappearing in the background, and the usual color palettes of the backgrounds and characters being restored.</i>] And the moon is back [<i>Bryan snickers.</i>].
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, so now that you see that yeah, the moon is back, the Ocean Spirit is calmed down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the closeup shot of the Ocean Spirit's head as it looks up to the moon.</i>] Yeah, I love that moment where the Ocean Spirit looks up at the moon, you see that his, his counterpart is restored, so he's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the sequence where the Ocean Spirit drops Aang off on a wall, before it drags Zhao into the water.</i>] And what's interesting is, you notice he drops off Aang at the outer wall there, so this moment where uh, kinda comes in and, and grabs Zhao is, is really more the ocean, the wrath of the ocean coming to get Zhao.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we wanted to be sure that it wasn't Aang...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... taking this revenge. But...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to Zuko reaching out and trying to save Zhao from the Ocean Spirit's grasp.</i>] Then you even get to see Zuko here, you know, his kind of nobler side.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zhao's refusal to take Zuko's hand.</i>] Zhao can't do it, he can't...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep [<i>Laughs.</i>].
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Concurrently with Aaron.</i>] Zhao does not...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Concurrently with Bryan.</i>]... too proud.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Zhao doesn't have a noble side [<i>Bryan and Aaron laugh.</i>].
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the fade to white as the scene transitions.</i>] Flash.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The epilogue. [<i>Refers to color palette of the backgrounds of the Northern Water Tribe.</i>] I really li- I really like the color in this, I like the kind of Max, Maxfield Parrish light.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>All of the ground has this soft cyan blue, and then the sky is like really desaturated, I think it's cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Pakku's statements on journeying to the Southern Water Tribe.</i>] I always wondered what would happen when Pakku shows up, to Gran-Gran's house.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's not going to be...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] She's gonna slap him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Kanna's going to [<i>Mike laughs.</i>]... have a word with him. Yeah, he thought it was hard fighting Katara, but yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Uh... just wanted to mention uh, Andrea Romano, who directs all these voices on our show, and does a great job.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the scene where Arnook and Sokka discuss Yue becoming the Moon Spirit.</i>] Such a great job that my sister cried when she saw this scene.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>She called me to [<i>Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>] tell me she cried right after, in the finale. Yeah, Andrea's just an incredible talent, so much energy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the scene where Iroh tells Zuko he needs some rest.</i>] That's a comeback to... second episode, I guess?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Concurrently with Bryan.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Concurrently with Mike.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Again, their relationship is just... great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, just the, the way Book One ends is really great. It's just, leaves everyone off at this... kind of pivotal, pivotal moment, and a great place to pick up for season two.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's a moment where we, you know, we just try to rely on the... storyboarding. It's well written, but it's also, it leaves room to convey the action with just the images, convey the feeling.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Subliminal.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Just using the...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers to the closeup shot of the Fire Lord's head from the back.</i>] One of the few glimpses we get of the Fire Lord in season one, but definitely a formidable presence. [<i>Refers to the closeup shot of Azula's face as raises her head.</i>] And there she is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>There she is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Azula. Who will...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Who plays a big role in Season Two.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep. [<i>Refers to the initial credit slide, with Aaron having the episodic writer and head writer credit.</i>] Written, man your name's all over this credit here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That's, that's the other Aaron Ehasz, [<i>Mike and Aaron laugh.</i>] on the show. That's the other one.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>We like to...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; reading the credits.</i>] Miken Wong!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Miken Wong!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Miken Wong!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Our line producer, and all these great artists on this episode and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects; refers back to Miken Lee Wong.</i>] The nicest, most considerate, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] thorough human being you could ever hope to work with. And we'd really like to thank, uh, Jenna Luttrell and Eric Coleman who uh, championed this series from its inception.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Um, thanks for Nick, for Nickelodeon, for uh, putting on this show, [<i>Mike and Bryan snicker.</i>] week after week. We're still amazed we get to make it, but uh, very, very proud of it and uh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, they've been supportive of it since...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... the get go, so... lucky.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Thanks Nickelodeon!
</td></tr></tbody></table>