<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The episode opens to morning at the Western Air Temple. Cuts to overhead shot of the team's campsite, the camera panning downward slightly, showing their sleeping bags all arranged in a circular form. Cuts to overhead shot of Suki and Chit Sang sleeping, Chit Sang snoring. The camera pans to the right to reveal Hakoda asleep next to Chit Sang. Cuts to ground-level shot of Teo asleep, The Duke and Zuko in the background also in a slumber.</i>
<p><i>Cuts to shot of Aang asleep on Appa as he wakes up, yawning and rubs his eyes. Cuts to shot of the nearby fountain from the view of their campsite, several birds fluttering about. The birds suddenly fly away as a bomb is launched their way, splashing through the waterfall fountain. Cuts to Aang, who grows suddenly alert, before switching to shot of Appa as the Avatar rises and uses his glider to airbend the bomb away. Cuts to overhead shot of the temple as the bomb explodes. Two more bombs pelt the building. Cuts to campsite, where everyone is now fully awake.</i>
</p><p><i>Cuts to shot of Aang, his back to the camera, as he races toward the edge of the building, glider in hand. The camera zooms in past his figure to a shot of a Fire Nation airship coming into view. Cuts to side-view of the bow of the airship, which launches another bomb that sails through the air and crashes into a nearby bridge. Cuts to Aang, who runs back to the campsite, Appa following close behind, and uses airbending to force the large, ceiling-high metal doors surrounding their site to close. Several bombs continue to assail the temple. Cuts to shot of a portion of the ceiling roof, as it begins to crumble and finally caves in. Cuts to overhead shot of Katara standing directly beneath the crumbling ceiling. She looks up, alarmed, only to be pushed out of the way by Zuko.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>As he runs and pushes her out of harm's way.</i>] Watch out!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to shot of the two as they roll across the floor, the debris from the ceiling crashing several feet away from them. They finally settle on the ground.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] What are you doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Calmly.</i>] Keeping rocks from crushing you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Okay, I'm not crushed. You can get off me now!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara rushes out from under Zuko and exits off screen.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I'll take that as a thank you. [<i>Rises.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to a section of the wall where a hole is bored through. The camera zooms out to show Toph and Haru, who have created the exit way using earthbending.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing to the exit.</i>] Come on! We can get out through here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to overhead shot of the tunnel as everyone begins entering the passageway. Aang stays behind, trying to get Appa to leave with him by pulling on the bison's reins. The camera zooms out, as he spots Zuko standing, facing the airships.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko.</i>] What are you doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Go ahead! I'll hold them off. I think this is a family visit. [<i>Runs off.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background, Sokka and Katara run up to him.</i>] Zuko! No!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Come on! We've gotta get out of here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang, Katara, and Sokka begin pulling on the reins together in an attempt to budge Appa. Cuts to shot of the doors of the building, which continue to be destroyed. Debris continues to fall to the ground as Zuko races toward the doors and leaps over to the other side just as another piece of the door falls and shatters. Cuts to shot of Zuko running toward the airships. One bomb is launched and lands several feet before him where it detonates. Thick gray plumes of smoke rise; after a brief moment, Zuko emerges from the smoke cover, unharmed.</i>
<p><i>He firebends a large blast from his hand. Cuts to shot of an airship, as it receives the blow. Cuts to shot of Zuko standing near the edge of the temple, looking at the airships. A podium-like devise suddenly rises; standing atop it is Azula. Cuts to shot of the princess, who has an evil, maniacal grin on her face.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>What are you doing here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Azula
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiling.</i>] You mean it's not obvious yet? I am about to celebrate becoming an only child!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Azula kicks a large blast of flame at her brother. Zuko dodges and runs backward into the temple, but falls. Several blasts are sent his way as the temple begins to fall apart. He runs toward the airships. As he jumps toward the ship, he sends several shots toward Azula, but fails to hit her and jumps onto the airship. He falls down into the misty floor below.</i>
<p><i>Aang and the group are seen trying to get Appa into the tunnel unsuccessfully.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I can't get him to go in there! Appa hates tunnels!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Aang, there's no way we can fly out of here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>We'll have to find a way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We need to split up. [<i>To the others.</i>] Take the tunnel and get to the stolen airship.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around and suddenly grows angry.</i>] No! [<i>Walks up to her father.</i>] The Fire Nation can't separate our family again!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Hakoda
</th>
<td>It'll be okay. It's not forever.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara hesitates before hugging her dad and running back to Aang. Sokka and Hakoda hug also as Sokka takes Suki and runs with the others. The two groups go their separate ways. Toph is seen touching a wall.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I can clear that away and we can fly out through there!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Um, there's an awful lot of fire in that general direction ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>We'll get through. Let's go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa flies through to the outside of the temple, covered by a shield of rock in front. Azula tries to bring him down, only for the shield to absorb the blasts. Appa escapes and the shield disintegrates. Behind Azula, a second airship rises, revealing Zuko survived his fall by getting onto another airship.</i>
<p><i>Zuko and Azula face off. Zuko makes the first move. He jumps toward Azula, who sends columns of fire at him, which he responds to with more blasts. The two attack each other several times.</i>
</p><p><i>Scene changes to Appa, dodging fire blasts, as Katara deflects several large whips of fire with her waterbending. The group rises above the airship to avoid more fire.</i>
</p><p><i>Back on the airship. Azula and Zuko are evenly matched until they both hit each other with fire-packed punches, launching them both off the airship. Zuko is caught by Katara, but Azula is left falling.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>She's ... not gonna make it ... [<i>Azula uses her firebending to propel herself toward the wall, stopping her fall with her hair pin and saving herself.</i>] Of course she did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to shot of Azula, who stands on the side of the cliff, smiling evilly. Cuts to shot of her watching as the team escapes, her back to the camera. The scene switches to where the gang is camping outside.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Wow, camping ... it really seems like old times again, doesn't it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Jokingly.</i>] If you really want it to feel like old times, I could, uh ... chase you around a while and try to capture you. [<i>He smiles and the rest of the group laughs, except for Katara.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Ha, ha.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Holding up his cup.</i>] To Zuko! Who knew after all those times he tried to snuff us out, today he'd be our hero?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Team Avatar
</th>
<td>[<i>Everybody except Katara holds up their cups.</i>] Hear! Hear! [<i>Aang nudges him with his elbow, before Toph lightly punches him.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiling.</i>] I'm touched. [<i>Stops smiling.</i>] I don't deserve this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] Yeah, no kidding. [<i>Walks away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What's with her?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I wish I knew. [<i>Follows her.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to shot of the entire campsite.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] What's with him?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to shot of a waxing gibbous moon, partially obscured by the clouds. Cuts to a shot of Katara sitting on a rock and overlooking a rocky cliff, Zuko approaching her from behind. She catches sight of him, immediately grows antagonistic, and rises to walk farther away toward the cliff.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>This isn't fair! Everyone else seems to trust me now! What is it with you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around; furiously.</i>] Oh, everyone trusts you now! I was the first person to trust you! [<i>Places her left hand on her heart.</i>] Remember, back in Ba Sing Se. [<i>Points to the ocean.</i>] And you turned around and betrayed me, betrayed all of us!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Closes eyes in resentment.</i>] What can I do to make it up to you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cuts to shot of her and Zuko standing on the cliff as she approaches him while snapping at him angrily.</i>] You really want to know? Hmm, maybe you could reconquer Ba Sing Se in the name of the Earth King. [<i>Cuts to side-view of her and Zuko.</i>] Or, I know! You could bring my mother back!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara storms away, slightly hitting his left shoulder with her right one as she passes Zuko, leaving him disappointed. Cuts to shot of entire cliff side, the waves crashing against the rocky wall. The scene switches to the campsite where Zuko accidentally runs into Suki on his way to confront Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Embarrassed.</i>] Oops, wrong tent!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Sorry, do you need to talk to Sokka, too?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Nope, not me! [<i>Walks away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko enters the tent, a look of disbelief spreading across his face.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Holding a rose in his mouth, surrounded by lit candles.</i>] Well, hello ... [<i>Surprised to find Zuko in his tent, destroying the rose in his mouth.</i>] Uh, Zuko! Yes, why would I be expecting anyone different? [<i>Painfully swallows rose petals and thorns.</i>] So what's on your mind?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Your sister. She hates me! And I don't know why, but I do care what she thinks of me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Nah, she doesn't hate you. Katara doesn't <i>hate</i> anyone. Except maybe some people in the Fire Nation. [<i>His eyes widen as he realizes his mistake.</i>] No, I mean, uh, not people who are good, but used to be bad. I mean, bad people. Fire Nation people who are still bad, who've never been good and probably won't be, ever!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Interrupting him.</i>] Stop. Okay, listen. I know this may seem out of nowhere, but I want you to tell me what happened to your mother.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Slightly taken aback.</i>] What? Why would you want to know that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Katara mentioned it before when we were imprisoned together in Ba Sing Se, and again just now when she was yelling at me. I think somehow she's connected her anger at that to her anger at me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Sadly.</i>] It's not a day I like to remember.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A flashback is shown of a younger Katara having a snowball fight with her brother. Sokka peers over a snow wall and prepares to throw a snowball at his sister only to be hit by a snowball thrown by a younger Katara, off-screen. Cuts to shot of Katara, who giggles joyfully. Cuts to shot of Sokka, who climbs over the snow wall, carrying an exceptionally large snowball. He drops it, however, upon witnessing blackened snow falling from the sky.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>I'm going to find Mom! [<i>Runs off.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] Many of the warriors had seen the black snow before and they knew what it meant: a Fire Nation raid. [<i>A battle scene is depicted of Water Tribe Warriors and Fire Nation soldiers charging and attacking one another.</i>] We were badly outnumbered, but somehow, we managed to drive them off. As quickly as they came, they just left.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cuts to shot of Sokka tossing his boomerang toward the retreating soldiers. The scene switches back to present day.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I was so relieved when it was over, but that's because I didn't know yet what had happened. I didn't know we had lost our mother.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Wait. Can you remember any details about the soldiers who raided your village? Like what the lead ship looked like?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah ... sea ravens. [<i>Scene shows flashback of three red flags waving in the breeze, bearing sea ravens.</i>] The main ship had flags with sea ravens on them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>The symbol of the Southern Raiders. Thanks, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Urging Zuko hurriedly out of the tent.</i>] No problem. Thanks for stopping by! [<i>Zuko leaves.</i>] I'd thought he'd never leave. [<i>Peaks head out excitedly and whispers.</i>] Suki!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Unfortunately for him, Zuko has barely taken two steps away from the tent and is looking curiously at Sokka. Sokka pretends to be completely oblivious and whistles. The next day, Katara emerges from her tent to find Zuko waiting outside, sitting on a rock.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] You look terrible.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I waited out here all night.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Brushing her hair.</i>] What do you want?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I know who killed your mother, [<i>She abruptly stops.</i>] and I'm going to help you find him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara casts him a look of shock, which soon turns to a look of anger.</i>
<p><i>The scene changes to later in the day where Aang is feeding Appa hay. Sokka fiddles around with a flower necklace. Katara and Zuko approach the bison, Zuko carrying a sack slung over his shoulder.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I need to borrow Appa.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Jokingly.</i>] Why? Is it your turn to take a little field trip with Zuko?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Yes, it is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Slightly surprised.</i>] Oh. What's going on?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>We're going to find the man who took my mother from me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka pauses and stands up, surprised.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Sokka told me the story of what happened. I know who did it and I know how to find him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Um ... and what exactly do you think this will accomplish?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Shakes her head in dismay.</i>] Ugh, I knew you wouldn't understand. [<i>Begins to walk away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Wait! Stop! I do understand. You're feeling unbelievable pain and rage. How do think I felt about the sandbenders when they stole Appa? How do you think I felt about the Fire Nation when I found out what happened to my people?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>She needs this, Aang. This is about getting closure and justice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I don't think so. I think it's about getting revenge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily.</i>] Fine, maybe it is! Maybe that's what I need! Maybe that's what he deserves!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Katara, you sound like Jet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>It's not the same! Jet attacked the innocent. This man, he's a monster.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Katara, she was my mother, too, but I think Aang might be right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Then you didn't love her the way I did!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Hurt.</i>] Katara!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>The monks used to say that revenge is like a two-headed rat viper. While you watch your enemy go down, you're being poisoned yourself.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>That's cute, but this isn't air temple preschool. It's the real world.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Now that I know he's out there ... now that I know we can find him, I feel like I have no choice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Katara, you do have a choice: forgiveness.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>That's the same as doing nothing!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>No, it's not. It's easy to do nothing, but it's hard to forgive.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>It's not just hard, it's impossible. [<i>Cuts to overhead shot of the field as she walks away, Zuko following behind.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene changes to later that night where Katara is seen dressed in a black cloak, tying her hair in a ponytail. Aang and Sokka watch her from behind a rock before emerging from behind it.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>So you were just gonna take Appa anyway?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>It's okay, because I forgive you. [<i>Pauses.</i>] That give you any ideas?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Don't try to stop us.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I wasn't planning to. This is a journey you need to take. You need to face this man. [<i>Katara situates herself on Appa's head.</i>] But when you do, please don't choose revenge. Let your anger out, and then let it go. Forgive him.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Okay, we'll be sure to do that, guru goody-goody. [<i>Climbs aboard Appa.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Thanks for understanding, Aang. Yip-yip. [<i>Appa takes flight; Aang and Sokka look up at the departing bison, their backs facing the camera.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You know, you're pretty wise for a kid.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Thanks, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cuts to shot of the two standing together looking up.</i>] Usually it's annoying, but right now, I'm impressed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I appreciate that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So, can I borrow Momo for a week?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Surprised.</i>] Why do you need Momo?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka simply shrugs.</i>
<p><i>The scene changes to Zuko and Katara flying on Appa, heading straight for the camera.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>We need to find the Fire Navy communication tower. All the navy's movements are coordinated by messenger hawk. And every tower has to be up to date on where everyone is deployed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cuts to shot of the communication tower situated on an island in the middle of the ocean; off-camera.</i>] So once we find the communication tower, we bust in and take the information we need.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] Not exactly. We need to be stealthy and make sure no one spots us, [<i>Cuts to shot of the communication tower, the camera panning downward.</i>] otherwise they'll warn the Southern Raiders long before we reach them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene switches to where Zuko and Katara run out from behind a mass of large rocks. Using waterbending, Katara creates a raft of ice for her and Zuko to ride on to the communication tower. The scene cuts to a corridor of tower where the two are crouched in a corner, watching two guards walk out a door. After the guards have passed, they stealthily run through the open door. The scene cuts to a female guard sitting at a writing desk. The duo peers at her from overhead gratings. Katara waterbends the ink onto the guard's hands. She rises from the desk and walks away. Katara and Zuko use the time to comb through the files stored in the drawers.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Okay, Southern Raiders. [<i>Opens a scroll.</i>] Bam. [<i>Points to location on map; off-camera.</i>] On patrol near Whaletail Island.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cuts to shot of Zuko and Katara looking at the map.</i>] Whaletail Island, here we come.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene changes to the next morning. Zuko arises from his sleep and looks at Katara steering Appa. She has dark circles under her eyes from lack of sleep.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You should get some rest. We'll be there in a few hours. You'll need all your strength.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Oh, don't you worry about my strength. I have plenty. I'm not the helpless little girl I was when they came.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene fades into a flashback of the Southern Raiders' attack.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>I'm going to find Mom.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She runs nervously past her brother. Several Water Tribe warriors are shown running about in a frantic motion. The camera focuses on Katara again, who arrives at their igloo and pushes back the curtain.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>Mom!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She runs in to discover her mother seated on the floor, a man towering over her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Just let her go and I'll give you the information you want.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>You heard your mother. Get out of here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>Mommy, I'm scared.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Go find your dad, sweetie. I'll handle this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara gazes into the menacing eyes of the Southern Raiders commander and runs off. The scene changes to her sprinting across the snowy battlefield.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] I ran as fast as I could.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Arrives to where her father is battling Fire Nation soldiers.</i>] Dad, Dad! Please, I think Mom's in trouble! There's a man in our house!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Hakoda
</th>
<td>Kya!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two run to their house frantically. Hakoda pushes back the blue drapes before the scene fades to white back to present day.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>But we were too late. When we got there, the man was gone. [<i>Voice begins breaking.</i>] And so was she.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Your mother was a brave woman.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Clutches her necklace.</i>] I know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene changes to later that night, where Zuko has taken command of Appa and Katara is sleeping on Appa's saddle. Zuko is looking through a telescope.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>There! [<i>Katara looks up.</i>] See those sea raven flags? [<i>Tosses the telescope to Katara.</i>] It's the Southern Raiders.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Determined.</i>] Let's do this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa submerges underwater, Katara waterbending an air bubble around his head so they can breathe. The camera cuts to a shot of a group of Fire Nation soldiers having a conversation on the deck of the ship.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Soldier
</th>
<td>So there I was, and I was like, 'You know ...'
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>He yells as a large water whip emerges from the surface and coils around his body, dragging him off the ship. The other soldiers run to the source of the incident in shock. Appa surfaces and Katara waterbends two huge waves at the ship. The others turn around to see the torrent of water flood the ship, washing them overboard. Appa lands on the deck. One soldier, who has managed to stay aboard the ship, attacks Katara, who pushes him away with a gush of water. She and Zuko make their way through the corridors of the ship, Katara's arms covered in water for defense. One soldier bursts from his cabin, a sword in hand only to be attacked and locked back inside by Zuko. Katara follows him to a large doorway, where they abruptly halt.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>This is it, Katara. Are you ready to face him?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara pulls down her face mask and lets out a cry as she sends a powerful stream of water toward the door. The scene changes to the inside of the room, the door having been knocked down by the impact of the water. The Southern Raiders commander attempts to attack Zuko, who only deflects his firebending attacks.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Southern Raiders commander
</th>
<td>Who are you?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You don't remember her? You will soon, trust me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Southern Raiders commander prepares to strike once more, however, his hand fails to move and begins trembling.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Southern Raiders commander
</th>
<td>What's ... [<i>He attempts to control his arm which bends about uncontrollably.</i>] happening to me?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera focuses on Katara using bloodbending on him. With swift motions, she forces him to the ground. Zuko looks on at her, momentarily stunned before turning his attention back to the commander.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Think back. Think back to your last raid on the Southern Water Tribe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Southern Raiders commander
</th>
<td>[<i>Helplessly subdued.</i>] I don't know what you're talking about. Please, I don't know!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Bending down closer to the commander.</i>] Don't lie! You look her in the eye and you tell me you don't remember what you did.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara bloodbends him, fixing him into a position where the Southern Raiders commander looks right into her eyes. She gives him a cold, hard stare. The camera closes up on one of the commander's eyes before cutting to where Katara's face has changed from one of hate to one of shock.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>It's not him. [<i>She frees him from her grip.</i>] He's not the man.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>What? What do you mean he's not? He's the leader of the Southern Raiders! He has to be the guy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara remains silent and begins walking away. Zuko grabs the weak commander and pins him to the wall.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>If you're not the man we're looking for, who is?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Southern Raiders commander
</th>
<td>You must be looking for Yon Rha. He retired four years ago.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera focuses on Katara, whose eyes are filled with tears. The scene changes to a shot of the ground where an anonymous character rakes the soil with a trough. Cuts to a side-view shot of a house where a man is tending to his garden. The sky is dark and gray with storm clouds. An elderly woman walks up to the open door of the house behind him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha's mother
</th>
<td>Yon Rha! You lazy piece of work, I need something.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Stops his work and attempts to placate.</i>] Yes, Mother. What is it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha's mother
</th>
<td>The tomato-carrots from your garden are too hard for my gums. I need something soft and juicy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>Would you like something else from the garden? I would be happy to ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha's mother
</th>
<td>[<i>Angrily. Her fists clench as she interrupts.</i>] Forget your stupid garden! [<i>Cut to a close-up of her as she yells at him; irritatingly.</i>] Get your grimy hind to the market and buy me some real food!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the flower bed as Yon Rha stands up. Cut to the back view of Yon Rha as he walks toward the town's entrance. Cut to some vegetables on display at a stall. The scene changes to where Yon Rha is walking to the marketplace of the village, the place almost desolate. Yon Rha enters the screen. He begins to buy vegetables from a stand. A wind chime tinkles from one of the other stands. Yon Rha sharply turns around to view the suspicious activity. The camera view changes to someone ducking behind the stand.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Suspiciously.</i>] Hello? [<i>To stand owner.</i>] Did you see someone?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The stand owner shakes his head. Yon Rha is later seen walking back to house down some steps. He stops again and looks up.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>Hello? [<i>Camera view shifts to show someone hiding.</i>] Is someone there?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>He resumes walking again. Katara and Zuko appear from their hiding place.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>That was him. That was the monster.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene cuts to where Yon Rha is walking, rain beginning to fall. He turns and stops once more.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>Nobody sneaks up on me without getting burned! [<i>Drops basket of vegetables and firebends at a nearby bush.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sensing no one, he picks up the fallen vegetables and continues on his way. He unknowingly steps on a thin wire, causing him to fall into the mud. He tries to get up only to see a fire blast coming his way which he quickly avoids. Zuko appears before him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>We weren't behind the bush. [<i>Cut to a side view of the confrontation as Zuko takes a step forward to threaten Yon Rha.</i>] And I wouldn't try firebending again!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to Yon Rha on the ground with his arm shielding his face. Frightened.</i>] Whoever you are, take my money. Take whatever you want. I'll cooperate.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara walks up to Yon Rha and pulls down her face mask.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Do you know who I am?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>No. I'm not sure.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Oh, you better remember me like your life depends on it! Why don't you take a closer look? [<i>Camera focuses on front view of her face.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Camera focuses on him.</i>] Yes, yes, I remember you now. [<i>Focuses on Katara again.</i>] You're that little Water Tribe girl.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Lightning strikes, darkening the screen and flashing back to the incident in the igloo with the young Katara, her mother and Yon Rha.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Just let her go and [<i>Camera zooms out to show Kya kneeling on the floor in front of Yon Rha.</i>] I'll give you the information you want.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>You heard your mother. Get out of here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Young Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Holds her hands together.</i>] Mommy, I'm scared.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Go find your dad, sweetie. I'll handle this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Young Katara leaves the igloo. Yon Rha faces Kya again.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>Now tell me, who is it? Who's the waterbender?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>There are no waterbenders here. The Fire Nation took them all away a long time ago.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>You're lying. My source says there's one waterbender left in the Southern Water Tribe. We're not leaving until we find the waterbender!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>If I tell you, do you promise [<i>She lowers her head and closes her eyes to make a decision.</i>] to leave the rest of the village alone? [<i>Cut to a side view of Yon Rha who nods.</i>] It's me. [<i>Cut to Kya who looks up.</i>] Take me as your prisoner.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to a close-up of Yon Rha who smiles evilly.</i>] I'm afraid I'm not taking prisoners today ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to present day Yon Rha who gulps in terror as the flashback ends. Lightning strikes in the background.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>She lied to you! [<i>Cut to a close-up of Katara who turns away from Yon Rha as she closes her eyes sadly.</i>] She was protecting the last waterbender!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Shocked.</i>] What? Who?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut back to Katara who turns to face him again as she opens her eyes and looks back furiously.</i>] Me!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She holds both her arms out, halting the falling raindrops and creating a shield above the three of them. After a few moments, she sends a forceful stream of water at Yon Rha, transforming the stream into a flurry of ice daggers midway through her attack. Yon Rha crouches in fear, preparing to be hit. When he does not feel harmed, he looks up to see the ice daggers floating in midair. Katara's expression softens and she allows for the daggers to liquefy and drop to the ground.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Falls to his knees.</i>] I did a bad thing! I know I did and you deserve revenge, so why don't you take <i>my</i> mother? That would be fair! [<i>Attempts to smile weakly.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Sorrowfully.</i>] I always wondered what kind of person could do such a thing, but now that I see you, I think I understand. There's just nothing inside you, nothing at all. You're pathetic and sad and empty.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Yon Rha
</th>
<td>[<i>Humbly.</i>] Please, spare me! [<i>Cries.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>But as much as I hate you ... I just can't do it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Katara closes her eyes and lowers her head. Cut to Yon Rha, a hint of a smile gracing his lips upon realizing he will be spared. Without saying another word, Katara turns around and walks away; Zuko looks from Katara to Yon Rha, shooting the latter a last dirty look, and follows her. Yon Rha continues crying and shivering in the rain. The scene cuts to a boardwalk overlooking the water. It is later that day. Scene cuts to Katara, who is sitting on the edge of the dock, her eyes closed, paddling the water with her feet. She opens her eyes sadly as Aang and Zuko approach her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Katara? Are you okay?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I'm doing fine.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Zuko told me what you did. Or what you didn't do, I guess. I'm proud of you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>I wanted to do it. I wanted to take out all my anger at him, but I couldn't. I don't know if it's because I'm too weak to do it or because I'm strong enough not to.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>You did the right thing. Forgiveness is the first step you have to take to begin healing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Rises from boardwalk.</i>] But I didn't forgive him. I'll never forgive him. [<i>Smiles at Zuko and walks up to him.</i>] But I am ready to forgive you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two hug and Katara begins walking away.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You were right about what Katara needed. Violence wasn't the answer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>It never is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Then I have a question for you. [<i>Turns to look at him.</i>] What are you gonna do when you face my father?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Camera focuses on Aang, who now has a worried expression on his face. Fades to credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>