<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The episode begins with a view of the mountains. The camera pans down to show a back shot of Aang sitting in cross legged in a prairie on the ground looking over a vast open savanna landscape. The landscape is mostly barren save for small shoots of grass which bend in the breeze. A range of mountains can be seen in the distance. The ground in front of Aang is littered with holes.</i>
<p><i>Cut to a shot of the group from the front of Appa, Sokka, Toph, Katara, and Momo standing behind Aang. The Avatar is holding a thin wooden flute in both hands.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What's out here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Shot changes to show Appa, Sokka, Toph, Katara, and Momo standing behind Aang, who holds a flute.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Puts her hand on the ground.</i>] A lot, actually. There's hundreds of little ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns around and silences Toph.</i>] Shh! I know you can see underground, but don't ruin the surprise. Just watch. [<i>Blows a note on the flute. A groundhog-type creature pops out of a hole in the ground and mimics the note.</i>] Yeah! [<i>Plays another note and another groundhog mimics it.</i>] I'm putting an orchestra together.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Makes hand motions while looking on with annoyance.</i>] Orchestra, huh? Well, la-di-da.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Three groundhogs pop out of the ground and sing descending notes. Momo jumps into a hole and comes out the middle one, trying to catch the groundhogs. The shot shows all of the holes in the ground. Aang plays four notes and Momo tries to catch the groundhogs that pop up. Katara giggles as she watches the amusing sight. Aang plays another note as Sokka runs up to Aang and plugs the flute with his finger, causing nothing to play. As Aang's cheeks swell with air, the Avatar looks at Sokka with a sad expression.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Annoyed.</i>] This is great and all, but don't we have more important things to worry about? We should be making plans.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>We <i>did</i> make plans. We're all picking mini-vacations.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>There's no time for vacations.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I'm learning the elements as fast as I can. I practice hard every day with Toph and Katara. I've been training my arrow off!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks next to Aang.</i>] Yeah, what's wrong with having a little fun in our down time?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Even if you do master all of the elements, then what? It's not like we have a map of the Fire Nation. [<i>Gestures to the side, sarcastically.</i>] Should we just head west until we reach the Fire Lord's house? [<i>Knocking on an imaginary door.</i>] Knock, knock. Hello, Fire Lord? Anybody home? I don't think so. We need some intelligence if we're going to win this war.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang plays a note on the flute and a groundhog pops up underneath Sokka and sings the note.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Giggles.</i>] All right, we'll finish our vacations and [<i>Mockingly.</i>] then we'll look for Sokka's intelligence. [<i>Aang laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Opening a map and shows it to Katara.</i>] Your turn, Katara. Where would you like to go on your mini-vacation?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing at the map.</i>] How about the Misty Palms Oasis? That sounds refreshing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Oh, yeah, I've been there. It's a pristine natural ice spring. And I usually don't use the word "pristine". [<i>Cut to the symbol on the map.</i>] It's one of nature's wonders.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The close-up of the map's illustration fades to the Misty Palm Oasis, which has a small ice spring in the center. Cut to a shot of Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Toph stare at the oasis in disappointment.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Must've changed ownership since I was here. [<i>Laughs sheepishly.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They walk through the entrance and the hanging sign falls down. Fade to Team Avatar walking past the small ice spring. They walk into the bar and pass five sandbenders hanging around outside. One sandbender spits at Sokka's feet. Sokka looks at the man angrily. The man utters a raspy groan, slurps, and chuckles. Katara grabs Sokka and pulls him into the bar, which is filled with weary travelers.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>To the bartender.</i>] One mango, please.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The bartender uses two swords to slice a bowl from a large chunk of ice. He cuts down some mangos from the overhanging fruit and dices them up. He chops up a piece of fruit and pours a jug of milk into the bowl, still using the swords. He throws a decorative umbrella and straw into the bowl and serves it to Zei, who gives the bartender a coin.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I don't see anything wrong with having one of those fruity beverages while we plan our strategy. [<i>Runs up to the bartender.</i>] Excuse me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zei bumps into Aang and spills his drink onto the airbender.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>No worries, I clean up easy. [<i>Airbends the drink off of his clothes.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Gasps.</i>] You're a living relic.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Shrugs.</i>] Thanks, I try.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>An Air Nomad, right in front of me. [<i>Shot changes to show Katara holding an icy bowl.</i>] Professor Zei, head of anthropology at Ba Sing Se University. [<i>Grabs Aang's arm and points at his arrow tattoo. Camera pans to Aang's face.</i>] Tell me, which of the air temples do you hail from?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>The Southern Temple.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Measures Aang's head with a pair of calipers and speaking excitedly.</i>] Oh, splendid! Now tell me- what was the primary agricultural product of your people?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Nervously.</i>] Uh, are fruit pies an agricultural product?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Oh, truly fascinating. That is one for the journal. [<i>While Sokka speaks, Zei writes in his journal.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So Professor, you're obviously a well-traveled guy. Do you have a more current map? Ours seems to be a little dated.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Certainly.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka unrolls a map on a table and examines. Toph sips her drink and props her legs on another chair.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What, no Fire Nation? [<i>Straightening his back.</i>] Doesn't anybody have a good map of that place?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Examines the map while the camera pans across it.</i>] You've made a lot of trips into the desert.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>All in vain, I'm afraid. I've found lost civilizations all over the Earth Kingdom, [<i>Raises his fist slightly.</i>] but I haven't managed to find the crown jewel: Wan Shi Tong's Library. [<i>Cut to a shot of Toph laying down. Her feet are closest to the camera, showing her dirt-stained soles.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>In disbelief.</i>] You spent years walking through the desert to find some guy's library?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>This library is more valuable than gold, little lady. It is said to contain a vast collection of knowledge, and knowledge is priceless.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Hmm, sounds like good times.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Oh, it is. According to legend, it was built by the great Knowledge Spirit, Wan Shi Tong, with the help of his "foxy" knowledge seekers.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Intrigued.</i>] Oh, so this spirit has attractive assistants, huh?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Puts her hand on the side of Sokka's face to stop him from talking.</i>] I think he means they look like actual foxes, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>You're both right. [<i>Katara and Sokka turn to him in surprise. Cut to Zei.</i>] Handsome little creatures. [<i>Takes out a drawing of the library and places it on the table.</i>] Wan Shi Tong and his knowledge seekers collected books from all over the world, and put them on display for mankind to read, so that we might better ourselves.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>If this place has books from all over the world, [<i>Aang walks over to look at the maps while he sips his drink.</i>] do you think they've got info on the Fire Nation? A map, maybe?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>I wouldn't know. But if such a thing exists, it's in Wan Shi Tong's Library.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Then it's settled. Aang, I do believe it's my turn. I'd like to spend my vacation [<i>Cut to a shot of Sokka as he points his finger into the air dramatically. The background changes to a rushing one.</i>] at the library! [<i>Sokka's voice echoes. Zoom back to a group shot, with Sokka still having his finger raised in the air.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Waving her hand to gain the others attention.</i>] Uh, hey, what about me? When do I get to pick?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You gotta work here a little longer before you qualify for vacation time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Hmph! [<i>Slams her drink on the table and folds her arms. Cut to a shot of Zei.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Of course, there's the matter of finding it. I've made several trips into the Si Wong Desert and almost died each time. [<i>In a depressed voice.</i>] I'm afraid that desert's impossible to cross.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Professor, would you like to see our sky bison?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>A sky bison?! You actually have one?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Appa retreating from four sandbenders, as he growls.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Runs toward the sandbenders.</i>] Sandbenders, shoo, away from the bison!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The sandbenders run away and get into two sand-sailers. They drive the sailers by creating a small tornado of sand near the sail. Cut to a ground view of Appa flying across the sky. Cut to Appa's saddle and pan from Katara and Toph leaning against the sides to Sokka who grabs a telescope and looks over the side. The shot changes to Momo, Zei, and Aang on Appa's head. Zei leans over Appa's head.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Tell me, sky bison, are you the last of your breed? [<i>Appa growls and Zei responds enthusiastically.</i>] Delightful! I only wish I spoke his tongue. [<i>Scratches Appa's head.</i>] Oh, the stories this beast could tell. [<i>Momo crawls up to Zei's side and starts chittering.</i>] Shush, chatty monkey.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Examines the picture of the library.</i>] Wow, shouldn't be too hard to find a place like this out here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa flies away from the camera. Cut back to the saddle.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Groans in frustration.</i>] Does this place even exist?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Some say it doesn't.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Eyes widen in surprise before narrowing.</i>] Shouldn't you have mentioned that before? [<i>Collapses on the saddle, putting her feet over the side.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to an aerial view of Appa flying. Cut to Zei, who writes in his journal and pans to Toph.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Pointing over the side of the saddle with excitement.</i>] There it is! [<i>Everybody on Appa looks to where Toph is pointing, but they can only see sand dunes. Aang, Katara, and Sokka glare at Toph in annoyance for tricking them. Cut back to the shot of Toph.</i>] That's what it will sound like when one of you spots it. [<i>Waves her hand in front of her face with a blank grin to remind them of the fact that she is blind. She quickly goes back to clutching the saddle.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Appa flying and shows a closer shot of Aang driving Appa while Momo sleeps on Aang's head. Sokka and Katara search for the library on Appa's saddle.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>It shouldn't be this hard to spot a giant, ornate building from the air.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks through his telescope and spots a tower. Pointing.</i>] Down there, what's that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Momo wakes up. Cut to the tower and Appa flies down next to it.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Holding the illustrations.</i>] Forget it. It's obviously not what we're looking for. [<i>Side shot.</i>] The building in this drawing is enormous.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They see a sparkle in the distance and a fox holding a scroll with its mouth walking over a dune.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zei.</i>] What kind of animal is that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The fox runs up the tower. Shot changes to a window at the top of the tower through which the fox enters.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>I think that was one of the Knowledge Seekers. [<i>Frontal shot.</i>] Oh, we must be close to the library!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Looking at the illustration Katara is holding.</i>] No, this is the library- look! [<i>Camera pans down from the tower to the illustration.</i>] It's completely buried.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a zoom out shot of the spire from far away.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Further shot of the top of library. The camera pans up from the sand to the top of the library.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Shouting dramatically.</i>] The library is buried?! [<i>Cut to a shot of the group standing in front of the spire. Zei runs forward. Depressed.</i>] My life's ambition is now full of sand. [<i>Collapses. Smiling, he lifts his head and reveals a small shovel in hand. Excitedly.</i>] Well, time to start excavating. [<i>He attempts to unearth the library using the tiny shovel. Cut to a close-up of the spire's surface as Toph places her palm against it.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut a small part of the library which Toph puts her hand on.</i>] Actually, that won't be necessary. The inside seems to be completely intact. [<i>Aerial shot.</i>] And it's huge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>That fox thingy went in through a window. I say we climb up there and give it a look.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I say you guys go ahead without me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>You got something against libraries?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I've held books before. And I gotta tell you, they don't exactly do it for me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Sheepishly.</i>] Oh, right. Sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Let me know if they have something you can listen to.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the window at the top of the tower. A boomerang with a rope tied to it is thrown into the window. At the bottom of the tower, Sokka starts scaling the rope and the camera pans to Aang, Appa, and Toph.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>To Appa.</i>] Don't worry, buddy. I'm not making you go underground ever again. You can stay out here with Toph. [<i>Walks off camera.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa makes a low, rumbling growl.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Awkwardly.</i>] What's up?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to overhead shot Katara, Sokka, Aang, and Zei scaling the rope inside the library. The shot changes to a closer view as Zei, Aang, Sokka, and Katara climb down and Momo flies down. The shot changes to show the library's ceiling dome.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Oh, it's breathtaking! [<i>Shot changes to show Zei, Aang, and Sokka climb down the rope with owl arches in the background.</i>] The spirit spared no expense in designing this place. [<i>Pointing.</i>] Look at those beautiful buttresses! [<i>Cut to an above shot of Sokka, Aang, and Zei, who are hanging from the rope. Sokka and Aang giggle at the word.</i>] What's funny?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Nothing. We just like architecture.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut back to a smiling Zei.</i>] As do I.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They slide off the rope onto a bridge and Momo lands on Aang's shoulder.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>My word! [<i>Examines an owl mosaic above two pillars.</i>] The exquisite mosaic handiwork of this tile-rendered avian symbol ... [<i>Sokka, Katara, and Aang look at Zei quizzically.</i>] Eh, nice owl.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They hear rustling noises. Sokka and Katara run behind a pillar. Aang grabs Zei and they hide behind another pillar. Wan Shi Tong, an owl spirit, walks over the bridge and examines the rope. Aang cranes his head around the pillar.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns his head around.</i>] I know you're back there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang gasps and hides again.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiles and walks from behind the pillar and up to Wan Shi Tong.</i>] Hello, I'm Professor Zei, head of anthropology at Ba Sing Se University.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>You should leave the way you came. [<i>Looks to the side.</i>] Unless you want to become a <i>stuffed</i> head of anthropology.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera pans to three stuffed animal heads on a pillar. Frontal shot of Zei, as he moans and clutches his neck. Katara, Sokka, and Aang walk out from behind their pillars and up to Wan Shi Tong.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Are you the spirit who brought this library to the physical world?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>Indeed, I am Wan Shi Tong, "He Who Knows Ten Thousand Things." And you are obviously humans, which, by the way, are no longer permitted in my study.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>What do you have against humans?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>Hm! Humans only bother learning things to get the edge on other humans. [<i>Cut to Zhao, studying scrolls in the library. Voice-over.</i>] Like that firebender who came to this place a few years ago, looking to destroy his enemy. [<i>Scene changes to the present.</i>] So ... [<i>Leans toward a sweating Sokka.</i>] who are you trying to destroy?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to his reflection in Wan Shi Tong's eye.</i>] What? No-no-no-no destroying. We're not into that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Blinks.</i>] Then why have you come here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Um ... knowledge for knowledge's sake?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Shot changes to him leaning toward Sokka.</i>] If you're going to lie to an all-knowing spirit being, you should at least put some effort into it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm not lying, I'm here with the Avatar, [<i>Grabs Aang and puts him into the shot.</i>] and he's the bridge between our worlds. He'll vouch for me. [<i>Nudges Aang.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Ow. [<i>Frontal shot.</i>] Uh, yeah, I'll vouch. We will not abuse the knowledge in your library, good spirit. [<i>Side shot.</i>] You have my word. [<i>They bow to Wan Shi Tong.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>Hmm, very well. I'll let you peruse my vast collection [<i>Shot changes to Zei, Aang, Katara, and Sokka looking hopefully.</i>] on one condition. [<i>They look at the spirit a little worriedly. Further overhead shot.</i>] To prove your worth as scholars, you have to contribute some worthwhile knowledge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks up to Wan Shi Tong holding a book and kneels down.</i>] Please accept this tome as a donation to your library.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal shot.</i>] First edition, very nice. [<i>Grabs the book with his wing.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Camera pans up to show her holding the waterbending scroll.</i>] I have an authentic waterbending scroll.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal shot.</i>] Ooh, these illustrations are quite stylish. [<i>Grabs the scroll.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to him.</i>] Uh ... oh, I know! [<i>Grabs his wanted poster out of his shirt and shows it to Wan Shi Tong.</i>] Hah!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>I suppose that counts. [<i>Takes the poster.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Side shot of him walking forward.</i>] Oh, great spirit, [<i>Frontal shot of him holding a piece of string.</i>] check this out. [<i>Ties the string into a butterfly knot and shows it to Wan Shi Tong.</i>] Ta-da! [<i>Aang, Katara, and Zei look at Sokka with uncertainty. Shot of Wan Shi Tong just looking at him in silence.</i>] It's a special knot. That counts as knowledge!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal shot.</i>] You're not very bright, are you? [<i>Sokka grunts as Wan Shi Tong takes the knot.</i>] Enjoy the library. [<i>Jumps off the bridge and flies down to lower levels of the library.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Team Avatar and Zei walk toward the library.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Narrows his eyes.</i>] Bright enough to fool you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to an overhead view of the desert outside the library, where Appa and Toph rest in the shade. The shot changes to a closer view of Appa and Toph.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>To Appa.</i>] So ... you like ... flying? [<i>Appa purrs deeply and scratches his ear.</i>] Of course, I'm more comfortable on the ground where I can see. Well, I don't <i>see</i> the way you do. I feel the vibrations in the ground with my feet. [<i>Closer shot of the two. Toph picks up a handful of sand and lets it fall.</i>] But this sand is so loose and shifty, it makes everything look fuzzy. [<i>Appa makes a rumbling groan with a further shot.</i>] Not that there's anything wrong with fuzzy. [<i>Appa grunts.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a large room full of books and the camera pans down to show the Knowledge Seeker, Team Avatar, and Zei at a bookshelf. In a closer shot, the Knowledge Seeker deposits its scroll on a shelf and the camera pans to the right to Team Avatar and Zei. Closer shot of Aang, as he flips a page on his book. He finds an illustration of a person talking to a lion turtle with two more lion turtles in the background.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Holds the illustration up to show Sokka and Katara.</i>] Hey, look at these weird lion turtle things.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Pulls a book off the bookshelf with the symbols 子白 on the cover.</i>] Eh, I've seen weirder.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks up to Aang, carrying a book.</i>] Aang, did you know in a past life, you were left-handed?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I always knew I was special.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Sokka and Zei. While Zei takes books off of bookshelves and adds them to his stack, Sokka takes a scroll from a shelf, reads it, and puts it in his purse. Back shot of Sokka walking up to a podium. He sees the burnt piece of parchment framed on the podium with the characters 培治龍年七月九日烈火國最黑暗的一天.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Reading from the parchment.</i>] "The darkest day in Fire Nation history." It's got a date at the top, but it doesn't say anything else. [<i>He looks around, making sure no one is watching, before prying open the frame with his sword and taking the parchment.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks in with Katara and Zei.</i>] Sokka, where are you going?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Running down a section of a library.</i>] I want to know what happened to the Fire Nation on their darkest day. This could be promising. [<i>Aang, Katara, and Zei follow him.</i>] The information on the Fire Nation should be right up here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Looking at a room full of ashes.</i>] Firebenders.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>They destroyed everything having to do with the Fire Nation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>That's so unfair! Just when I think I'm one step ahead of the Fire Nation, it turns out they beat us here a long time ago. [<i>Collapses on his knees.</i>] I need to know what happened on the darkest day. [<i>Hears whimpering and looks at the entrance to see the Knowledge Seeker standing on its hind legs.</i>] Hello, little weird fox guy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Knowledge Seeker gets on its four legs and points outside the room.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>Seems it's trying to assist you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Um, sure, I guess I'll follow you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They follow the Knowledge Seeker to a large round door with a texture lining the bottom sides of the wall. The Knowledge Seeker enters a small door in the texture. The large door opens showing the Knowledge Seeker standing behind it. Team Avatar and Zei walk toward the center of the room. The Knowledge Seeker pushes a lever beside the calendar wheel and the domed ceiling changes from day to night.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>This room is a true marvel, a mechanical wonder. It's a planetarium that shows the heavens moving.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The domed ceiling changes back into day.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Uh, this is beautiful, but how is it helpful?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Maybe these dials represent dates and times. Sokka, try entering that date from that parchment you took.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Mock whispering.</i>] Shh, Katara, not in front of the fox, he's with the owl.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Knowledge Seeker whimpers. Sokka glances at the parchment and changes four of the calendar wheels. He pushes the lever and the domed ceiling changes from day to night.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Wow, I got to hand it to you, Sokka. You picked the best mini-vacation for sure.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The ceiling changes from night to day and the planetarium suddenly grows dark.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Hey, wait. What happened to the sun?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Narrows his eyes.</i>] Great, you must have broken it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks next to Aang.</i>] It's not broken. [<i>Shot changes to show the sun piece of the planetarium covered by the moon piece.</i>] The sun is behind the moon. It's a solar eclipse! It's literally the darkest day in Fire Nation history. Now I get it. [<i>Grabs Aang's shoulders and shakes him.</i>] Something awful happened on that day. I don't know what, but I do know why. Firebenders lose their bending during a solar eclipse. [<i>Pushes Aang back.</i>] Sorry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>That makes sense. I mean, think what the lunar eclipse at the North Pole did to the waterbenders. This is huge.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The Knowledge Seeker gets on its hind legs and begs.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>To the Knowledge Seeker.</i>] Fine, you earned it. [<i>Tosses the fox a snack from his bag. To Aang and Katara.</i>] We've gotta get this information to the Earth King at Ba Sing Se. We'll wait for the next eclipse, then we'll invade the Fire Nation when they're totally helpless. The Fire Lord is going down!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>[<i>Enters the shot from behind Sokka.</i>] Mortals are so predictable, and such terrible liars. [<i>Sokka gulps. Shot changes to show Wan Shi Tong talking to them from the entrance.</i>] You betrayed my trust. From the beginning, you intended to misuse this knowledge for evil purposes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>You don't understand. If anyone's evil, it's the Fire Nation. You saw what they did to your library. They're destructive and dangerous. We need this information.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>You think you're the first person to believe their war was justified? Countless others before you have come here seeking weapons or weaknesses or battle strategies.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>We had no choice. Please, we're just desperate to protect the people we love.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>And now I'm going to protect what <i>I</i> love. [<i>Flaps his wings and the library starts shaking.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>What are you doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>I'm taking my knowledge back. No one will ever abuse it again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Sand pours from the ceiling.</i>] He's sinking the building. We've gotta get out of here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>I'm afraid I can't allow that. You already know too much. [<i>Pecks at them, but misses.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Wan Shi Tong pursues them as they run out the planetarium. The camera pans up to the surface. Appa snarls as the library starts sinking and the ground starts shaking.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>I already <i>told</i> you, I don't wanna snuggle. [<i>Appa stands up and hurries away from the library. Toph looks at the sinking library.</i>] Library sinking. [<i>Running up to the library.</i>] Library sinking! [<i>Punches both fists into the library to stop it from sinking. Her feet slip in the sand, so she pauses to solidify it.</i>] Hi-yah! [<i>Struggles to stop it from sinking again.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera pans down to an aerial view of Team Avatar and Zei running through the library. They round a corner, and Wan Shi Tong continues pursuing them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Stops running and turns back toward Wan Shi Tong.</i>] Great Knowledge Spirit, I beg you, do not destroy your vast collection of priceless tomes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang uses air suction to move Zei out of Wan Shi Tong's attack. Aang fires an air blast at Wan Shi Tong, sending the spirit falling off the side of the bridge.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Runs back to Katara, Zei, and Sokka.</i>] We've gotta get back to the surface!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Sokka, let's go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>But we still don't know when the next eclipse is gonna to happen.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Don't be stupid! We'll find out later!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No, we won't. If we leave this place, we'll never get the information. Aang, come with me to the planetarium, [<i>Aang runs up to him.</i>] I need cover. Katara, take Momo and get out of here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>But ...!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Wan Shi Tong breaks in between the two groups and pursues Katara and Zei.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Go!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Hurry, Sokka!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka and Aang run away. Zei evades Wan Shi Tong by diving into a smaller aisle of books. He grabs a book, looking at the cover excitedly. Katara runs and Wan Shi Tong swoops down. Cut to the surface with Toph holding up the library. Appa grunts nervously.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>What is it now?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to three sand-sailers. The camera pans across a sandbender's face and cuts to a side shot of the sailer. The sandbenders direct a sand blast at Appa.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>[<i>Struggling.</i>] Who's there?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The sand-sailers circle Appa and a sandbender jumps out. Cut to inside the library, where Sokka and Aang run across a bridge and reach the entrance to the planetarium.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Why are we doing this?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Because if this calendar can tell us about eclipses in the past, then maybe it can project when the next one will be.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>You can't possibly check every single date.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Adjusting the calendar wheel.</i>] I don't have to. We just need to check every date before Sozin's Comet arrives. Because after that- well, try not to think about that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka finishes adjusting the wheels and Aang pushes the lever. The camera fades from the moon traveling across the ceiling to Sokka adjusting the wheel calendar, before switching to the ceiling changing from night to day. The camera fades to Aang looking at the night sky to the moon traveling across the ceiling, to the calendar wheel, to Sokka adjusting the wheel, to the sun and moon traveling close to each other, to Sokka trying again.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Pushing the lever.</i>] Come on, eclipse.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the moon and sun traveling across the ceiling until the moon overlaps with the sun.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>That's it! The solar eclipse! It's just a few months away. [<i>Takes out a piece of paper and writes down the date.</i>] Got it. Now, let's get to Ba Sing Se.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>They run out of the planetarium. Cut to Appa surrounded by sandbenders yielding weighted ropes. They throw the ropes over Appa and solidify the sand near their feet to bring Appa down.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Don't make me put this down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Toph lets go of the library and earthbends a slice of sand at the sandbenders, but misses. She grabs the library again. Cut to a tied up Appa as the sand-sailers drag him away.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>No! Stop sinking! [<i>Fires three more slices of sand.</i>] No! [<i>Grabs the library.</i>] I'm sorry, Appa. [<i>Closes her eyes as the camera pans to show the sand-sailers dragging Appa away.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Katara running away from Wan Shi Tong. She stops beside a bookshelf, holding Momo. Wan Shi Tong walks on the other side of the bookshelf and spots Momo's tail.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>At least I'll have one specimen to add to my collection.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Wan Shi Tong tries to grab Momo with his beak, but Katara runs away with Momo. She reaches the bridge with the rope and turns back to face Wan Shi Tong.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Wan Shi Tong
</th>
<td>Your waterbending won't do you much good here. [<i>Raises his head and unfolds his wings to attack.</i>] I've studied Northern water style, Southern water style, even Foggy Swamp style.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of the ceiling. Aang flies his glider holding Sokka, who jumps off holding a book, yelling. Sokka slams the book onto Wan Shi Tong's head, knocking him out.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>That's called Sokka style. [<i>Swings his fist to the side as he says this.</i>] Learn it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Pan up to a shot of the hole in the ceiling where the rope is dangling. Light from the outside is pouring down. Cut to a shot from the side of Sokka, Katara, and Momo, and the defeated spirit lying unconscious on the bridge. More streams of sand pour in from above. Sokka and Katara climb over Wan Shi Tong and up the rope. Aang glides past them. Cut to a close shot of Sokka climbing the rope. He stops and looks back down.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Wait! Professor, let's go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zei
</th>
<td>[<i>Sitting among a pile of books holding a scroll that surrounds him. The sand is building up and beginning to cover some of the stacks. Zei is reading a scroll. The camera slowly zooms in.</i>] I'm not leaving. I can't. [<i>Drops the parchment to his lap and raises his right fist.</i>] I've spent too long trying to find this place. [<i>Places his hand on his chest and looks up.</i>] There's not another collection of knowledge like this on earth. [<i>Cut to a close-up of Zei with his eyes closed. He opens his eyes while smiling and speaks wistfully.</i>] I could spend an eternity in here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to a shot of Sokka and Katara looking at the professor. Katara looks up at Sokka.</i>] Just go!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Wan Shi Tong screeches and shakes the rope, making Sokka and Katara fall off. Aang catches them and they fly up while Wan Shi Tong pursues them. Cut to outside the library, where Aang, Sokka, and Katara land. Toph lets go of the library, falling back. Aerial shot showing the ground where the library used to be.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We got it. There's a solar eclipse coming. [<i>Jumps and hugs his sister.</i>] The Fire Nation's in trouble now!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Stands up and walks toward Toph.</i>] Where's Appa?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Toph shakes her head. Aang gasps and a tear falls down his cheek. The camera pans up from the crater to the sun. Fade to white, followed by the credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>