[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Michael Dante DiMartino
</th>
<td>Hi, this is Mike DiMartino, co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan Konietzko
</th>
<td>And Bryan Konietzko, the other co-creator of <i>Avatar</i>.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron Ehasz
</th>
<td>This is Aaron Ehasz, head writer.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the </i>Avatar<i> world map in the intro.</i>] Here-there's the map of the world. Zoom in, very ex... dramatically.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the firebender in the initial portion of the intro.</i>] We just breezed by Azula. [<i>Laughs.</i>] Weren't we going to say something...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Oh yeah. We were.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... about Azula back there?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>The, the firebender in the main title is Azula, if you don't know. [<i>Refers to the long shot of Roku bending the four elements.</i>] And this guy right here is Roku.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Azula is Zuko's sister. Who is only kinda teased in this...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That's true...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>We only see her in, uh, episode 12, and at the very end of the season in episode 20. But uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] But we...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... quickly became a fan favorite I believe.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>We had plans for her since the beginning, yeah, hmm.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>The internet fandom, internet forums really responded to Azula immediately t-well, and were like "Oh my god, like who, who is this?", and kind of asked a lot of questions, and it's really interesting.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, and she only appeared in...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... one shot, and didn't even have a line or anything.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara's male waterbending opponent, Sangok.</i>] That character is uh, Angela Mueller's brother. She designed it based on him because he got beat up by a girl.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah, there's a lot of characters that we'll, we'll base on, on people we know, or people that people on the crew know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I'd only met her brother one time, and I saw that drawing, and I said "Oh that's your brother". [<i>Laughs.</i>] It's-it's a really good caricature.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So now this is kind of like, you know, a couple weeks after episode eighteen, and-and uh, Katara's learned a lot since last time we saw her, and she and Pakku are old buddies now, and Aang's kind of a slacker.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Pakku remark that Sangok might be able to fight a sea sponge.</i>] Some kind of a sea sponge reference a second ago?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>There was, there was.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Which-for Nickelodeon fans, you might recognize as... [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] a poke, a friendly poke at our fellow Nickelodeon show.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Was it meant to be?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Really?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I think it was meant to be.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's news to me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang waterbending the snow, encasing himself in a snowman.</i>] I like the uh, the snowman trick. That's the idea that Aang doesn't really have a fighting spirit, um, he's a prodigy as a bender, but he likes to use his bending abilities to, like make up the air scooter, and, and now make himself a snowman, so he's just... you jus-just see that he's got a good heart in the way that his bending skills manifest. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the scene of Appa eating kelp in the stables.</i>] So Appa's eating some kelp. [<i>Aaron laughs.</i>] We figured that was the only kind of greenery they had around in the North Pole, was stuff that they got from the ocean.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Man, Sokka and Appa have come a long way, they were, they were... he pretty much hated Appa in the beginning.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's true.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>That's a good point.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Now he's using him to get chicks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka's yip-yip to Appa.</i>] I love that suave second yip. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] That's so perfectly done.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Imitating Sokka.</i>] Yip-yip.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That was pretty funny.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to when Yue moves closer to Sokka on Appa's saddle.</i>] Nice. [<i>Aaron, Bryan and Mike laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Four Seasons theme playing in the background.</i>] So here you'll, you'll hear the theme coming back, the love theme...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... I think. Perfect acting by Jack DeSena. [<i>Aaron laughs; Bryan imitates Sokka.</i>] Good times.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shot of black snow falling on the North Pole.</i>] This is a nice transition.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, the music really worked out well here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I remember, I think you pitched the idea of black snow, Aaron Ehasz. Was a very cool visual, was a idea to show the coming of the Fire Nation.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Momo's negative reaction to tasting the fallen black snow.</i>] I like... it's a nice uh, way to show it, how it's polluted, Momo gagging on it. [<i>Refers to the ice fountain's water getting darker.</i>] Lauren MacMullan, the director of this episode, did this cool shot where the water turns black... thought it was nice. We like to show that the Fire Nation's assault on the world is, there's a lot of different levels to it. They sort of represent an industrial revolution, so there's these cultures that are very tied in with nature, and some more than others. And, and the Fire Nation, ‘cause of their smelting skills and what-not, have gotten into this industrial revolution before everybody else, so, it's one thing that's sort of fueled their ambition and their um, conquering spirit. They needed more resources, and uh, wanted to build up their defenses and eventually just take over the world, and. So having the snow be polluted by their ships is kind of a neat way to show that their conquest effects even nature, not just um, not just these societies. And, so throughout the season, we've had like, you know, burned down forests, and uh, other various uh, imprints on nature from their conquest.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Plus, black snow is just weird.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] It is weird.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's weird and scary. [<i>Refers to Sokka and Yue talking on the stairs.</i>] I like this staging on the stairs, I thought it was interesting, the characters at different heights.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to when Yue tells Sokka they can't see each other anymore.</i>] A fine time to end it Yue. [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] Good choice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Imitating Sokka, as Yue runs past him.</i>] But we're on the way to the town meeting!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; brief pause.</i>] So, Yue has a very strong sense of duty, which is-is, you know, a good character quality. Though she's very di... divisive character, some people really like her, some people don't really like her so much...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] We, we have a lot of those characters.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] That's okay. The world's like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah. [<i>Brief pause; refers to the echo sound effects on Arnook's voice.</i>] I like the uh, treatment that Tom did on the voices in the mix here, for this kind of hall reverb. [<i>Refers to the multiple flash cuts between Yue, Pakku and Hahn.</i>] So these are these premonitions on who will...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Who will leave the, uh, tribe by the end, either by [<i>Adopts a dramatic tone.</i>] leaving the world, or just leaving the North Pole.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, there's a shot of Hahn, Yue's fiancé, who he will meet later in this episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Who's based on Dean Kelly, who's one...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Oh right? That's right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... one of our storyboard artists, and I'm sure he's not happy that we said that, because...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>He immediately cut his hair after...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] It's true!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... this episode came.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I-I made him come down to the video acting reference, and flip his hair around for [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] the Hahn scenes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Who the writer of this episode John O'Bryan, a very handsome man himself, [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] uh, is very threatened by Dean in terms of, uh...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] His level of handsomeness.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>No commentary for a short period until the Four Seasons theme starts playing.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So here's the theme, here's the, uh, theme that you hear Uncle first singing in the eighteenth chapter, then it comes back as the love theme.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>We really should put out Uncle Iroh's greatest hits...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Totally.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>He should put that out...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Finishing Aaron's sentence.</i>]... in an album.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I think he should, he should... yeah, that's good.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; refers to Aang posing like he does in the intro.</i>] See that shot right there, is a bit of an homage to the main title, where Aang's back is to the camera, and you pan up to the sun.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>D'you the sun in the opening title is a photograph that I took...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjecting.</i>] Oh that's right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... while snow-snowboarding in Whistler, in Canada?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>You're giving away all your secrets.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I'm not afraid to use [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] a photograph.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the Water Tribe symbol on the wall being destroyed by the Fire Nation.</i>] So, this is a cool symbolic strike against the Water Tribe, right there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the closeup shot of a fiery coal-ball sailing through the air.</i>] This is a cool shot, it's kinda reminiscent of the comet that's coming that you see in episode seven and eight.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I love the mechanics of that, um...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Finding the word.</i>] Trebuchet.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Trebuchet!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Trebuchet, that's right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yes, well it's a lot, you know there are two different things, there's catapults, and then there's trebuchets, which we've learned are more, uh... I don't know what the difference is, but... [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>We had a long, explanatory thing...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>In the background.</i>] I forget.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... about the trebuchets...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Well, Zuko...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... didn't we?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... Zuko's ship in 107 or 108, has a catapult, because he kinda has the old...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... rickety, hand-me-down, and then the bigger Fire Nation ships have the trebuchets.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>So it's more of a counterbalance system.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>That's right, counterbalance, that's the word I was looking for.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the coal-ball impacting against the glacier.</i>] That was cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think this sequence was storyboarded by Ethan Spaulding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yes, very well.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Very cool action sequence.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Aang jumping and evading over the Fire Nation soldiers.</i>] I like this shot right here, [<i>Makes whoosh noise.</i>] I love that, it's great. We love just accentuating Aang's acrobatic abilities, since he's an airbender, and he can, sort of uh, lighten his, his connection to the Earth, and flow. [<i>Refers to Aang forcing down the hammer, jamming it in the chain links.</i>] That was great animation, really showed the weight of that hammer, I like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>I think too, what we try to do in this show, is like, even in the big action sequences, um, have a kind of story point to them, where, for this instance, um, you know, Aang is taking out this, we needed a big moment for Aang to kind of like, be heroic and go out there and try to save the day, and he takes out this Fire Nation ship, and we see how hard it is to do that, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah, even for Aang, who's...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>And uh, he does it, and he succeeds, but then you see that...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] That's one ship.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>]... that's one out of hundreds of ships. And it's like, even he cannot...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... clearly do all of this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That's a good point. On <i>Avatar</i>, because we, we wanted the bending to be really physical, which, you know, we've said in a lot of interviews, and I think this a good example that, you know, there's a limit to how much energy they can output.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the long shot of the Fire Nation ship being suspended in ice.</i>] We-we gotta just comment this shot right here, very reminiscent of uh, episode 101, where you see the uh, ship in the Southern Water Tribe that was frozen up, so you get the idea that back-back in the first battle in the Southern Water Tribe, waterbenders had done a similar thing to stop the ships.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>And they went down fighting. [<i>Refers to the old Fire Nation armor worn by Hahn.</i>] So this is sort of a, uh, kind of ripping on our old costume design I believe. [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] Of the, from the pilot, where the, there were a lot-I just kept putting spikes, every draft [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] of the firebenders' outfits, and there were just spikes everywhere. It became kind of impractical for a kung fu moves.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>No commentary for a short period of time until Arnook starts defending Sokka from Hahn's insults.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So this guy is like an <i>Avatar</i> version of a jock. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] Just a, just a boneheaded dude.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>I like this armory, thought that came out really cool. Think Elsa Garagarza did this, it was them. [<i>Refers to the wolf carving above the armory door frame.</i>] It's cool, you see the wolf, spirit animal above the door, sort of reminiscent of the uh, wolf makeup that the Southern Water Tribe adorns when they go into battle. You see Sokka in it in 1-in episode 102.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>One other minor point about that last scene is that we were seeing Sokka, kind of use the experience he's gained, and you-we kind of see that he's grown, and that he's, kind of how valuable he is to this effort, and that, you know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, cause he, he progresses in different ways than like Aang and Katara. He doesn't have, he doesn't have the bending skills, but he's got other, leadership and other cool qualities.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, I think that's important too, because, again we, even though some of our characters have supernatural abilities, we always try to show that they're earned, and that they have to develop the skills, and, lot of trial error and hard work and practice. So Sokka's a good way to show the um, the mental capacities and... so yeah, anyways, back to what we were saying earlier. It's great to see that Aang the Avatar, you know, supposed master of all the elements, is exhausted, you know. He's, there's a limit to what a human being can do.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shots with Aang, Katara and Yue, where the lighting has changed from daytime to warmer dusk colors.</i>] The dusk-this is dusk right, that we're seeing here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yep.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>The dusk colors are really great, so many of the colors are great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Exactly. Great uh, great color correction by Kevin Kerwin. Um, a lot of those shots, the colors were really, really disparate, and he pulled them all together, really well. [<i>Refers to the nighttime shots of Zuko and Iroh.</i>] This was another really hard scene to color correct. We tried to do uh, Hye-Jung Kim the color superv-supervisor and I, tried to do this difficult lightings, lighting situation where there was a cooler color coming from outside from the nighttime, and then this warmer color coming from the gas lamps inside of this bay, it was pretty complex, and Kevin kind of wrapped it all together nicely. Color correction's one of my favorite processes in, in this show, that and mixing, just because we get to put the finishing polish on everyone's hard work.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Tsungi Horn theme playing in the background.</i>] This is a great uh, musical theme too, that first appeared in uh, episode thirteen...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Says simultaneously with Mike.</i>] Thirteen.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... Blue Spirit episode, that we've used a bunch of times for Zuko, Zuko's more emotional moments I guess.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>I love that scene with Iroh and Zuko...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... I love him telling him to wear, keep his hood up, and stuff like that, so moving...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, yeah. That was a great father and son type of relationship.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Jeremy Zuckerman, the composer for <i>Avatar</i> um, performed that duduk. It's a, I believe an Armenian instrument, and supposed to be very difficult to play, and he just went out bought one, and [<i>Laughs.</i>] played that theme.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>He's an incredible multi-instrumentalist. And he uh, believe he convolved it with a brass instrument, so it took on kind of a hybrid quality.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, it's just a great, great theme.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, I love it. [<i>Refers to Sokka fighting Hahn over his disrespectful comments about Yue.</i>] More egos clashing. Just the oldest story in, in the world, [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] over a girl.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Sokka's disheveled hair.</i>] Yeah, I like Sokka's messed up surfer hair. [<i>Bryan and Aaron snicker.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Oh, a good little...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Hahn mispronouncing Zhao's name.</i>] Notice, Hahn keeps... we decided Hahn's character trait is that he can never remembers, remember anyone's name, so he calls Sokka [<i>Elongates the "O" in Sokka.</i>] Sokka and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Which a lot of people who work on this show...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... call him [<i>Elongates the "O" in Sokka.</i>] Sokka. [<i>Refers to the sequence of Zuko sneaking into the Northern Water Tribe.</i>] This is a great sequence, also boarded by Ethan Spaulding, where they... we knew early on that the, you know, this B plot for this episode would have very little dialogue, but would be really important. I just really wanted to see Zuko's, his drive and what he's willing to um, the crazy situations he'll just dive headfirst into, and um, for his ambition.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the turtle seals that Zuko sees diving into an opening in the ice.</i>] Those were uh, turtle seals I believe...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... that we saw. [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] As you probably have noticed, all of the animals on <i>Avatar</i> are...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Most of them are... hybrids.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Simultaneously with Bryan.</i>]... hybrids. Occasionally the jokes usually come in the animals that are just normal animals, that [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] are just not hybrids at all. People think those are the weird animals.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Yue telling Aang and Katara about the Moon and Ocean Spirits.</i>] This cool little backstory on the myth of waterbending. This, this season is the water season, so it's kind of nice to-we had a lot of uh, lot of discussion in the writing process about, how we could make this little trilogy in the end focus around water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>No commentary for a short period of time until Aang agrees with Yue that getting wisdom from the spirits is better than a crazy spirit attack. </i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>It's funny that that's like, uh, taken as like uh, ridiculous, you know ridiculous pitch by Aang, and that's exactly [<i>Mike and Bryan laugh.</i>] what happens in, in the next episode.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>But it's cool, because there's, you know, stuff in here that we set up early on in like episode seven, when he first goes to the Spirit World, that, that kind of pays off here, and...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the background shots of the Water Tribe Palace.</i>] I think that painting of the palace was uh, by Bryan Evans. Beautiful painting... [<i>Refers to the long shots of the Spirit Oasis.</i>] and this is the Spirit Oasis. This is another painting by Bryan Evans, it's one of the background keys that just ended up being used in the show production. [<i>Refers to the medium shot of Tui and La.</i>] I love the fish designs by Angela Mueller, really cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>So, that's the first time we see the koi fish, who play a very important role, later on of course.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Part of the idea here, was that this oasis, was this spirit oasis was actually part of the Spirit World spilling into the real world, at this...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Right.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>... at this, at this juncture, this place.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Referring to Zuko emerging out of the frigid waters.</i>] I love this scene, you'll see Zuko's, if you pay attention, his skin color shifts as he warms himself up. [<i>Refers to Zuko warming himself up with his firebending breathing.</i>] And that's the breath of fire that Uncle advises him to use.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Which is cool, ‘cause it's, it's like a real yoga thing, the breath of fire, and it's cool just to... visualize it in <i>Avatar</i>, and actually make it a breath of fire, where you see actual flames coming out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to the shots of Zuko swimming through the caves underwater.</i>] I like these shots a lot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah, this is great underwater stuff.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Again, kinda like we were talking about Sokka, seeing how he develops without bending, I think it's great to show Zuko, you know he's not the best firebender, and, and he doesn't have all the resources in the world since he's banished. But, just shows like how his drive can take him so far, and, and uh, he can make it into this city, even though the Fire Nation takes a day or two to bust through.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Brief pause until the scene transitions back to Zuko swimming through the underwater current.</i>] Yeah, I just love the kind of tension, the kind of underwater thi- [<i>Refers to Zuko panting as he comes up for air in a small air pocket.</i>] this is my biggest nightmare.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Mine too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Being trapped underwater with frozen things above you, and you can't get out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>This reminded me of when, as a kid, and you'd put a-a uh, canoe over you, so you'd [<i>Mike laughs.</i>] you'd have like air to breathe, but you were, kind of trapped in this really claustrophobic space.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the long shot of light coming in through the ice.</i>] I love that, how you see the light come in in that one shot.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>That was more great color correction by Kevin Kerwin. [<i>Refers to Zuko starting to drown as he's unable to break through the ice.</i>] This is, yeah, my nightmare right here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] 'Cause you would not have firebending [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>] to help you get out. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we wanted to be pretty realistic that he's just absolutely exhausted, after this feat he just pulled off.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>
</th>
<td><i>No commentary for a short period of time until the shot starts to zoom in on Tui and La.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>It's a cool sequence.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>The sound design's really great by Benjamin here. [<i>Brief pause.</i>] It's great being close friends with Ben and, we used to, we were roommates for four and a half years, and we were always working on electronic music and stuff, so, it's great because I know what he's capable of in terms of really expressive abstract sounds, so when we get to something that's unusual like that, it's actually really easy to spot, and like, "Ben you know, just do some crazy sound designs and..."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Katara and Zuko fighting each other in the Spirit Oasis.</i>] So this is great, because this is like the first time Zuko and Katara have really fought, and it's after Katara has now learned some skills, so, Zuko's a little surprised by this. [<i>Laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah. We look-we just absolutely love showing character's development, and um, personality, and uh, what they learned, their abilities, and it was great, uh. We've heard that you know, a lot of kids have picked up on that, they like, they appreciate the fact that Aang has to earn these talents, he doesn-he isn't just granted them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>[<i>Jokingly.</i>] Kids love magic karate Bryan" [<i>Bryan laughs.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs; in a joking tone.</i>] No they don't.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aaron
</th>
<td>Just...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] I also like Katara's story here, where she's just like, she'll protect Aang at, at all costs...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, definitely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>... which is a great story point.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Yeah, we definitely... play up that motherly quality in her, and... [<i>Refers to Katara trapping Zuko in a ball of ice.</i>] this uh, sequence was storyboarded by Dean Kelly, who I went to school with, actually Mike, Mike and I both went to school with. [<i>Refers to the cut to Pakku as the sun rises on his face, and the lighting changes from night to day.</i>] This is another great color transition. So, this is another idea that we'd had pretty early on, where um, natural phenomena will enhance, they'll either augment or diminish um, the bend-the practitioner's bending abilities, so. The Fire Nation is located on the equator, and is closest to the sun, and so, their powers are strongest uh, during the daytime when, obviously when the sun's out. So again, just trying to, you know, it's magic, it's-it's supernatural, but we try to make it as natural as possible and, as uh, kind of organic. [<i>Refers to the cut to of an extreme close-up on Zhao's face.</i>] I like that cut, it really shows the, I don't know, maniacal, warmonger that Zhao is.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Yeah. [<i>Refers to the close-up shot on Katara's face, and the water sound effect in the background.</i>] Great sound design there when Katara opens up her eyes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>Anytime we get to do backwards sounds, I'm always excited.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>Always cool.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Laughs.</i>] Yeah. [<i>Refers to theme playing in the background.</i>] This is a great theme, uh, Jeremy Zuckerman uses this prepared piano for that kind of metallic rattle.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Refers to Zuko carrying Aang on his back through a blizzard.</i>] And I love this last image of just like, Zuko and Aang disappearing into the blizzard...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>] Yeah, again...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Mike
</th>
<td>[<i>Interjects.</i>]... it's great.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bryan
</th>
<td>... just Zuko's desperation, he has no plan, but he's just... fighting for his ambition.
</td></tr></tbody></table>]