<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The scene opens to the Western Air Temple at nightfall. Zuko is pouring tea to give to the members of Team Avatar.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to a tray full of tea cups with Zuko's hand holding a kettle and filling up the empty cups.</i>] No one can make tea like Uncle [<i>Camera pans up to Zuko's face.</i>], but hopefully I learned a thing or two. Would you like to hear Uncle's favorite tea joke?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Sure. [<i>Cut to an overhead of the group sitting around a fire.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I like jokes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>Bring it!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Okay. [<i>Serves tea to The Duke and Haru and stands up with his tray.</i>] Well, I can't remember how it starts, but the punch line [<i>The boys help themselves to the tea.</i>] is "Leaf me alone, I'm bushed!" [<i>No response.</i>] Well, it's funnier when Uncle tells it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>Right ... maybe that's because he remembers the whole thing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Everyone else laughs. Zuko smiles a little.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>It's nice to get a chance to relax a little. It hardly ever happens.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko hands tea to Teo and Toph. He subsequently approaches Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Hey, can I talk to you for a second? [<i>Stands up and walks out.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko sets down the tray of tea. The camera switches to a shot of him and Sokka walking away from where the rest of the group is gathered.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>So, what's up? [<i>Appa wakes up and looks as they walk past him.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>If someone was captured by the Fire Nation, where would they be taken?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>What do you mean? Who was captured?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>When the invasion plan failed, some of our troops were taken. I just want to know where they might be.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I can't tell you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What? Why not?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Trust me. Knowing would just make you feel worse. [<i>Turns to leave, but is stopped by Sokka.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>It's my dad. He was captured too. I need to know what I put him through.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>It's not good, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Please.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>My guess is, they were taken to the Boiling Rock.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What's that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>The highest security prison in the Fire Nation. [<i>Sokka looks at him, horrified.</i>] It's on an island in the middle of a boiling lake. It's inescapable.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So, where is this place?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Why do you need to know? What are you planning?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Nothing. [<i>Pauses for a moment.</i>] Boy, you're so paranoid.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>It's in the middle of a volcano between here and the Fire Nation. You guys actually flew right past it on your way here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Thanks, Zuko. [<i>Yawns.</i>] Just knowing makes me feel better.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Sarcastically.</i>] Yeah, I'm sure it does.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to later that night. With everyone asleep, Sokka sneaks away from everyone. He sighs and almost steps on Momo, narrowly avoiding tripping over him and waking him up. He climbs onto Appa, who awakes.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>To Appa.</i>] Shhh.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Appa goes back to sleep, as Sokka climbs on top of him. However, as he climbs up, he notices Zuko is already in the saddle with his arms crossed.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Not up to anything, huh?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Falls off Appa, his bag's contents fall out.</i>] Fine, you caught me. I'm gonna rescue my dad. You happy now?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I'm never happy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Picking up the fallen items.</i>] Look, I <i>have</i> to do this. The invasion plan was <i>my</i> idea, it was <i>my</i> decision to stay when things were going wrong. [<i>Zuko jumps off of Appa.</i>] It's <i>my</i> mistake, and it's <i>my</i> job to fix it. I have to regain my honor. You can't stop me, Zuko. [<i>Pushes Zuko aside and begins to climb up Appa on Appa's saddle.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You need to regain your honor? Believe me, I get it. I'm going with you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No. I have to do this alone.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>How are you going to get there? On Appa? Last time I checked, prisons don't have bison daycares. [<i>Sokka stops climbing, sighs, and looks back at Zuko.</i>] We'll take my war balloon. [<i>They walk off to the war balloon.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to Appa and Momo, still sleeping at sunrise. The Duke gives Appa some hay. Katara notices that Momo is holding a note.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Toph
</th>
<td>What does it say?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Katara
</th>
<td>"Need meat. Gone fishing. Back in a few days. Sokka and Zuko." [<i>As she says this, Aang yawns and turns around to lie back down.</i>] One more thing. "Aang, practice your firebending while I'm gone. Do twenty sets of fire fists and ten hot squats every time you hear a badgerfrog croak. Zuko."
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A badgerfrog croaks, waking Aang from his rest.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Sighs.</i>] Nobody else has homework. [<i>Stands up and walks to a spot and starts hot squatting while Katara and Toph walk away.</i>] One hot squat, two hot squat, three hot squat, four hot squat ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Scene cuts to Zuko and Sokka in the air in the war balloon. Zuko blasts fire into the tank to keep it moving. A moment of awkward silence between the two follows.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Pretty clouds.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Yeah ... fluffy. [<i>Sokka whistles.</i>] What?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What? Oh, I didn't say anything. You know, a friend of mine actually designed these war balloons.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>No kidding.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yep, a balloon ... but for war.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>If there's one thing my dad's good at, it's war. [<i>Blasts more fire into the tank.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah, it seems to run in the family.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Looks at Sokka, defensively.</i>] Hey, hold on. Not everyone in my family is like that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I know, I know, you've changed.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Downcast.</i>] I meant my uncle. He was more of a father to me. And I really let him down.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I think your uncle would be proud of you. Leaving your home to come help us? That's hard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>It wasn't that hard.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Really? You didn't leave behind anyone you cared about?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Well, I did have a girlfriend. Mai.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiles and looks at Zuko with interest.</i>] That gloomy girl who sighs a lot?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Smiles.</i>] Yeah. Everyone in the Fire Nation thinks I'm a traitor. I couldn't drag her into it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>My first girlfriend turned into the moon.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Shocked for a moment. Looks up at the sky briefly, before glancing back at Sokka.</i>] That's rough, buddy.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Nightfall. Sokka is asleep, snoring loudly. Zuko continues to keep the tank full. He stops to look out in the distance.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>There it is! [<i>Sokka awakens to see it.</i>] There's plenty of steam to keep us covered. As long as we're quiet, we should be able to navigate through it without being caught.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>As they enter the volcano's steam, the balloon begins losing altitude quickly.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Frantically blasting fire into the tank.</i>] We're going down! The balloon's not working anymore! [<i>Blasts fire up into the balloon.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>The air outside is just as hot as the air inside so we can't fly!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Falls to the side as the balloon tips.</i>] So what are we supposed to do?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I don't know! Crash-landing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The balloon skids along the boiling water, splashing Sokka's hand, which he shakes while blocking his mouth to prevent himself from screaming. The balloon hits the base of the rock, ejecting the two from it.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Looking at the destroyed war balloon.</i>] How are we gonna get off the island if the balloon won't work?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We'll figure something out! I suspected it might be a one-way ticket.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>You knew this would happen and you wanted to come anyway?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks to the destroyed balloon.</i>] My dad might be here! I had to come and see!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Uncle always said I never thought things through. But this ... this is just crazy!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Gathers parts from the balloon together.</i>] Hey, I never wanted you to come along in the first place! And for the record, I <i>always</i> think things through! But my plans haven't exactly worked, so this time, I'm playing it by ear. So there. [<i>After the hot water on the balloon burns his hand, Sokka kicks it into the water.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>What are you doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>It doesn't work anyway, and we don't want anyone to find it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I hope you know what you're doing. [<i>They both turn to look at the prison.</i>] There's no turning back now.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Morning. Zuko and Sokka have entered the prison, and come out of a supply room filled with reserve guard uniforms. Both of them wear prison guard uniforms.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I hope these disguises work.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We just need to lay low and find my dad as soon as possible.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A series of guards run by. One of them runs back and looks at them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Guards! There's a scuffle in the yard. Come on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two go to the yard. Prisoners are gathered in a circle as the guards move through to the inside.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>I didn't do anything! I'm going back to my cell.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Whips fire at him.</i>] Stop right there, Chit Sang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko tries to approach, but Sokka grabs his arm to stop him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We can't blow our cover.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>I've had it with your unruly behavior!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>What did I do?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>He wants to know what he did. [<i>To Zuko and Sokka.</i>] Isn't that cute? [<i>Gives them a look when they say nothing.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Uh, very cute, sir.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Super cute.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Walks up to Chit Sang.</i>] You didn't bow down when I walked by, Chit Sang!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>What? That's not a prison rule.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>Do it!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Make me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The bully guard walks away, but as he is leaving, he whips fire at Chit Sang. Chit Sang blocks it, and redirects it at him. The bully guard breaks the blast with a kick.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>Tsk, tsk. Firebending is prohibited. You're going in the cooler. [<i>Pointing at Sokka.</i>] You! Help me take him in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Whispers to Zuko.</i>] Meet back here in an hour. [<i>Runs up to Chit Sang and the guard.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Back inside, Chit Sang is led to a cooler.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>The warden will deal with you soon. [<i>Sokka closes the doors.</i>] Can you believe this guy?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Playing along.</i>] Prisoners! Am I right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>Ugh. Tell me about it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Meal time for the guards. Zuko is getting food, noticeably the only guard wearing a helmet.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Hey, new guy! I know it's the rule to have your helmet on at all times, but this is the lounge. Relax.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>But what if there's an incident? If I'm not prepared, someone could strike me on the head.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The guards laugh.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>Give it a week, he'll loosen up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Can the new guy ask you veterans a few questions about the prison?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Bluntly.</i>] No, you can't date the female guards.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Trust me, you don't want to. [<i>The female guard throws a cup at him, which causes the guard sitting behind him to laugh.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>No, that's not it. The Boiling Rock, it holds the Fire Nation's most dangerous criminals, right? [<i>The other guards nod.</i>] So what about war prisoners?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>In the yard, the warden arrives on the gondolas. Meanwhile, Sokka and the bully guard continue to stand guard by the cooler. Sokka is looking inside at Chit Sang who is shivering.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>It sure looks cold in there.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>That's why we call it the cooler. He won't be firebending there. [<i>Notices someone coming; lowers his mask.</i>] It's the warden! [<i>He and Sokka stand to attention.</i>] Look alive!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>[<i>Opens the cooler.</i>] So Chit Sang, I hear you used firebending to try to escape. You should know better.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>I wasn't trying to escape.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Bully guard
</th>
<td>He's lying! I saw it with my own eyes. [<i>He is pushed aside by one of the warden's bodyguards.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>No one has ever, ever escaped from here. I'd sooner jump in the Boiling Lake myself than let that record fall. Don't forget it. Now go back to your shivering.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Back in the yard. Zuko approaches Sokka, but does not know it is him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Hey there, fellow guard, how goes it?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Lifts up his helmet's visor.</i>] Zuko?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Shhh! Listen, I asked around the lounge. There are no Water Tribe prisoners. [<i>Lifts up his visor.</i>] I'm afraid your father's not here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What? Are you sure, did you double-check?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Yeah, I'm sure.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No. No! [<i>Bangs his fists against the wall in frustration.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I'm really sorry, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So we came all this way for nothing? I failed ... again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Ah, [<i>Holds his chin in thought.</i>] what would Uncle say? [<i>Cut to a frog-view as he looks up at the sky.</i>] Sometimes, clouds have two sides, [<i>Walks over to the railing.</i>] a dark and light, and a silver lining in between. It's like a silver sandwich! [<i>Close-up of a disinterested Sokka; voice-over.</i>] So ... when life seems hard ... [<i>Sokka glances to the side.</i>] take a bite out of the silver sandwich!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka's eyes widen when he notices something; close-up of his cheerful expression as he gets up. Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko while Sokka runs up to grab the railing next to him, excitedly looking down to the yard below.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Maybe we haven't failed after all!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>That's the spirit! [<i>Folds his arms.</i>] I can't believe that worked. [<i>Looks down.</i>] I didn't even know what I was saying.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No, what you said made no sense at all. But look ... [<i>As he points, the camera shifts to an overhead view of the yard, before rapidly zooming in on a dejected-looking Suki.</i>] It's Suki!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Suki, sitting in the prison yard in prison garb, looks up at hearing the continuous ringing of a bell.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] Prisoners, [<i>Suki gets up.</i>] back in your cells!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of the prison yard from ground level as the prisoners start to walk back inside. Cut to a frontal shot of Zuko and Sokka. The latter's eyes are now rapidly blinking pink hearts, while Zuko gives him a conspicuous look. Sokka does not pay attention and lowers the visor of his helmet with a smile before dashing out of the scene with a surprised Zuko quicking turning his head and looking after him. Cut to the prisoners' housing area. Camera slowly pans to show a guard mopping the floor and another one doing his rounds. Cut to Suki lying on her bed and staring at the ceiling in sadness. The door to her cell opens and closes, illuminating her face as her eyes turn to the door. Cut to a further off side-shot of Sokka entering Suki's cell.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Sits up; aggressively.</i>] What is it? Did I do something wrong?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Crosses arms.</i>] You mean you don't recognize me?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up. She averts her eyes; bitterly.</i>] You people all look the same to me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal shot; smugly.</i>] Oh? Then maybe you'll recognize this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka purses his lips and attempts smooching sounds as he leans in to kiss Suki. His lips are suddenly grasped by a hand. The camera switches to the side-shot as Suki violently shoves him against the door. Frontal shot of Sokka as he makes contact with the door, his helm flinging off in the process. He looks bewildered to Suki. Cut to a close-up of Suki, her left arm still stretched out in the move she used to push him away. Her angry expression instantly brightens.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Sokka! [<i>Runs up to him; cut to a side-view.</i>] It's you!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Suki rushes to pull Sokka into an embrace. Still bewildered, he does not immediately return the gesture. Cut to a frontal shot of Sokka, Suki resting her head on his shoulder, and he mellows into the embrace, returning it in all honestly while closing his eyes. Cut to a close-up side-shot of Suki, who is tearing up out of joy.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>They both stand up, not releasing each other.</i>] The other Kyoshi Warriors, are they here?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>No. I don't know where they are. They locked me in here because I'm the leader.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Places his right hand on her left cheek.</i>] Well, you won't be here for long. I'm busting you out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal shot.</i>] I'm so glad [<i>Places her hand over Sokka's on her face and closes her eyes.</i>] to see you Sokka. [<i>Opens them again.</i>] I knew you'd come.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a side-shot of the now-reunited couple as they gaze lovingly at each other. They release hands, placing them on the other's arms, and lean in to kiss; Suki throws her arms around Sokka's neck. Cut to a close-up frontal shot of Zuko standing guard outside the cell. He suddenly looks to his right. Cut to a further off shot, showing the entire hallway, revealing that the sound that drew Zuko's attention was a guard ascending nearby stairs. He taps on the cell door to get Sokka and Suki's attention. Cut to inside the cell where the couple stops kissing, Sokka casting a suspicious look to the door. Cut back to outside the cell, where the female guard approaches Zuko, who is standing in front of the cell door, his arms crossed behind his back. He turns to her as she pulls up next to him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>Excuse me. [<i>Cut to a shot from behind Zuko.</i>] I need to get into that cell.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Shot from over the guard's shoulder.</i>] No, you can't go in there! [<i>Looks at the prison cell; unsure.</i>] The lights are out. [<i>Points at the door.</i>] The prisoner could sneak up on you.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up. Cut to a side-shot; annoyed.</i>] Step aside, fool. [<i>She raises her left arm to push Zuko out of the way, though before she can touch him, he grabs hold of the arm and turns her around, slamming her face first against the door.</i>] Hey, hey, what are you doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She turns to retaliate against Zuko's action. Cut to inside the cell, where Zuko's head can be seen through the looking hole as he is slammed against the door. The camera pans down to show Sokka and Suki pushed against the door, looking up in worry. Sokka's expression turns serious as he lowers his gaze and puts on his helmet. Cut to a close-up shot of the guard's right calf as Zuko plants his own leg behind it. Switch to a further off shot. Zuko grabs a hold of the woman's right arm and forces her to bend backward, thus averting her sight from the door that slides open. Sokka quickly exits the cell and shuffles away, his back pressed against the wall. The female guard manages to push Zuko's face up with her left arm, regaining a more leveled pose herself. Cut to a close-up side-shot of her from underneath Zuko's arms as she looks to her right.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>[<i>Instantly cut to a frontal shot of Sokka, who freezes over.</i>] Guard, help! [<i>He turns to look at the struggle.</i>] I think he's an impostor! [<i>Frontal shot of Sokka, looking unsure.</i>] Arrest him!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of the gondola making its way to the prison. Cut back to inside the prison as the struggle continues.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>Get him off me and arrest him!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Grabs Zuko and throws him down on the floor.</i>] You're under arrest! [<i>Whispering.</i>] Don't worry, I'll figure it out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka leads Zuko away, followed by the female guard. Later, Zuko, now in prison garb, is in an isolated room. The door opens, revealing the warden.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>Well, well, well. I never thought I'd find you in here, [<i>Smiles evilly and walks into the cell.</i>] Prince Zuko.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Shocked.</i>] How did you know who I am?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>How could I not? You broke my niece's heart.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Even more shocked.</i>] You're Mai's uncle? I never meant to hurt her.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>Quiet! You're my special prisoner now. And you'd best behave. If these criminals found out who you are, the traitor prince who let his nation down, why they'd tear you to shreds.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Folds his arms.</i>] So what's in it for you? Why don't you just tell my father to come collect a reward?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>Oh, in due time, believe me, I intend to collect. [<i>Walks away and shuts the door.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Outside the cells, Sokka comes down and sees Zuko and Suki mopping floors.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Oh, good, you guys have met.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Actually, we met a long time ago.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>We did?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Somewhat angrily.</i>] Yeah, you kind of burned down my village.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Stops mopping for a second.</i>] Oh, sorry about that. Nice to see you again.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko and Suki stop mopping and hide from the other guards beside a staircase.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So, listen, I think I have an escape plan. I checked out the coolers again, and the point of them is to keep firebenders contained, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Yeah ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>So, they're completely insulated and sealed to keep the cold in. Well, to keep the cold in, it also has to keep the heat out, right?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>Just get to the point, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>It's a perfect boat for getting through the boiling water.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Exchanges a worried glance with Suki.</i>] The cooler as a boat? Are you sure?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I'm telling you, it'll work. [<i>Flashes back to Sokka walking around the island; voice-over.</i>] I walked around the perimeter. There's a blind spot between two guard towers. It's the perfect launching point. [<i>Sokka puts a miniature boat in the water and watching it float away.</i>] I already tested it out. We'll roll the cooler into the water and just float with the current. It'll take us straight across. As long as we don't make a sound, no one will notice. [<i>Fade back to Sokka talking to Zuko and Suki.</i>] And bing-bang-boom, we're home free.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>But how are you going to get the cooler out?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>[<i>From the staircase.</i>] Yeah, how are you going to get the cooler out? [<i>Jumps down.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Covering up.</i>] What? We didn't ... w-we didn't say that.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Yeah, you heard wrong.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>I heard you hatching an escape plan, and I want in.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>There's nothing to get in on.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Yeah, the only thing we're hatching is ... an egg?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko lowers his head and Suki covers her eyes while they both sigh in annoyance. Cut back to Chit Sang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>[<i>Unconvinced.</i>] Okay, well, I come with you or the warden [<i>Camera pans from a serious-looking Zuko to Suki.</i>] hears about this egg, too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>To Sokka.</i>] I guess we have no choice.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Okay, you're in. [<i>Handing Zuko a wrench.</i>] Now first we need someone to unbolt the cooler, from the inside.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Oh, I can get you inside.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of the stairs as two guards look down at the prison area. Chit Sang walks out from behind the stairs and stands in a spot. Zuko pretends to be mopping and bumps into Chit Sang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Hey! What are you, stupid? Watch where you're going! [<i>Shoves Zuko.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Hey, you watch who you're shoving! [<i>He pushes Chit Sang.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>I think you mean <i>whom</i> I'm shoving!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The two scuffle as the prisoners cheer them on. They break apart and Zuko goes for a punch. Chit Sang throws Zuko onto the floor. </i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Approaching. Yelling.</i>] I need backup over here!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko dodges Chit Sang as he tries to elbow him. Zuko blasts fire at Chit Sang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>No firebending! [<i>Pointing.</i>] Into the cooler!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko is taken down and escorted away by two guards. Sokka looks at Suki, who is mopping and looks back, as he walks off. Later, Sokka opens the cooler.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I can take you back to your cell if you've learned your lesson.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Raises his head slightly and releases a small breath of fire to warm himself up.</i>] Yes, I have ... completely. [<i>Reveals all the removed bolts and screws, which makes Sokka smile.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Lifts his visor; whispering.</i>] I got Suki and Chit Sang out of their cells a few minutes ago. They'll be waiting for us at the shore.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Someone's coming! [<i>Takes Sokka into the cooler and closes the door.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Yeah, new arrivals coming in at dawn.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>Anybody interesting?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Nah, just the usual. Some robbers, a couple traitors, some war prisoners, [<i>Sokka looks at Zuko with shock and worry.</i>] though I did hear there might be a pirate.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Female guard
</th>
<td>No fooling!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>War prisoners. It could be your father.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I know.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Well, what should we do? Are we going ahead with the plan or are we waiting another night?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>I don't know! Is it right for me to risk Suki's freedom, all of our freedom on the slim chance that my dad is gonna show up?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>It's your call, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to outside the prison, night time. Suki and Chit Sang are waiting for Sokka and Zuko until they hear them above, rolling the, now detached, cooler down the hill. Suki and Chit Sang move to help.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Took you guys long enough. [<i>Cut briefly to two other prisoners, a male sitting on a rock, and a female waving.</i>] This here's my girl and my best buddy, they're coming too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Fine. Everybody in the cooler. Let's go. [<i>They move the cooler into the water. Cut to Sokka lifting a rock hiding his Water Tribe outfit.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Are you sure you wanna go? You're the one who said you wanted to redeem yourself. Redeem your honor. Rescuing your dad is your chance.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Approaching.</i>] Your dad?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Turns to Zuko.</i>] If I had just cut my losses at the invasion, maybe we wouldn't be in this mess. Maybe sometimes it's just better to call it quits before you fail.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>No, it's not. Look Sokka, you're going to fail a lot before things work out.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Standing.</i>] That supposed to make me feel better?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Sokka moves away.</i>] Even though you'll probably fail over and over and over again ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Seriously, not helping.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Grabs Sokka's shoulder.</i>] You have to try every time. You can't quit because you're afraid you <i>might</i> fail.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>[<i>Standing by the cooler boat.</i>] Hey, if you two are done cuddling, can we get a move on?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>No. I'm staying. You guys go. [<i>To Suki.</i>] You've been here long enough.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>I'm not leaving without you, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I'm staying, too.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Not me, I'm out. Let's roll, baby. [<i>Pushes the cooler into the lake and jumps in.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>We gave up our only chance of escaping. I hope we haven't just made a huge mistake.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>As morning arrives, the cooler holding Chit Sang, his buddy, and his girlfriend is still within the perimeter of the prison. The current escapees are sweating as the cooler slowly floats with the current.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Chit Sang
</th>
<td>Aah, this current is so slow. I can use this to paddle. [<i>Rips off a piece of the cooler. When he puts the piece of metal in the water, the steaming water splashes on to his hand, causing him to scream loudly.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>A watchman catches notice. Two watchmen hit an alarm bell as the warden approaches.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>Guards! Secure the perimeter and lock down the prisoners! Now!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Many guards appear to lock down the prisoners as we see one guard use a fire whip to control the prisoners. Cut to the outside of the prison walls as the camera pans down to Sokka, Suki, and Zuko.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>The plan failed! They're caught!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut back to the warden near a launcher.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>Get the fugitives and throw them in the cooler!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard #2
</th>
<td>[<i>The guard in charge of the steering wheel turns toward the warden.</i>] Uh ... they are in a cooler, sir.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Warden
</th>
<td>One that's bolted down and not floating in the water! This is a lockdown! We have new prisoners arriving! Everything must be completely secure!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The male guard fires a large ballista bolt, catching hold of the cooler, and drags it back toward the prison.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>The gondola's moving. [<i>Cut to a side-view of the gondola approaching the prison. Cut to a view of the prison yard as the gondola nears its stop. Cut to Sokka and Suki now in the yard.</i>] This is it. [<i>Cut to the gondola arriving. Cut to Sokka, Zuko and Suki in the yard.</i>] If my dad's not there, we've risked everything for nothing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>We had to. [<i>Holds Sokka's hand.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Come on, come on ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a large man with a tattoo and nose ring comes off the gondola first.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Is that him? [<i>Cut to Sokka.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>My dad doesn't have a nose ring. [<i>Cut briefly to the gondola as several men step off.</i>] Where is he? [<i>Cut to the gondola briefly as we see one more prisoner exit. Hakoda does not appear.</i>] That's it? That can't be it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Suki
</th>
<td>[<i>Comforting.</i>] I'm sorry, Sokka.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Oh, no.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Male guard
</th>
<td>Hey, you! Get off the gondola!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to the gondola as Hakoda steps out.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to Sokka, Shocked.</i>] Dad ...
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Fade to the words "TO BE CONTINUED ..." followed by the credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>