[<table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Narrating.</i>] Water, earth, fire, air. My grandmother used to tell me stories about the old days. How the four nations once lived in harmony. How everything changed once the Fire Nation attacked. Only the Avatar mastered all four elements. Only he could stop the ruthless firebenders. But when the world needed him most, he disappeared. Nobody had seen him for a hundred years until my brother and I found him: an airbender named Aang. The problem is this Avatar is still a kid and even though his airbending skills are great, he has a lot to learn before he's ready to save anyone. The Fire Nation will do anything to capture Aang before he masters all four elements. So, I must keep him safe until he is ready to fulfill his destiny. My brother thinks I'm crazy, but I believe Aang can save the world.
</td></tr></tbody></table>, <table class="wikitable" width="100%">
<tbody><tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The episode starts with a shot of the sun. The camera pans down to Aang, Kya, and Sokka on a flying bison being followed by a boat.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Wahoo! Hang on, Momo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] You idiot! We're about to die!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Firebolt! [<i>Close-up.</i>] Aang, focus!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a close-up of Aang, who quickly maneuvers Appa out the way of an oncoming fireball as the camera zooms out to show Appa. Cut to below Appa as a bolt of fire flies past them. Appa flies past the camera as Sokka holds the saddle to avoid falling off. Cut to another shot below Appa, from the water, as the boat enters view. Cut to the Fire Nation ship, a frontal view of Prince Zuko with four other soldiers.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>View from behind as he turns to his soldiers.</i>] I want the Avatar. Improve your firebending [<i>Frontal view of soldiers.</i>] or you're swimming home in your armor. [<i>Close-up.</i>] Again!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Side-view of them all as the four send a huge fireball in Aang's direction, the camera pans up to follow the fireball before cutting to a frontal view of Appa as the fireball narrowly misses. Cut to a wide-view of the fireball and Appa below as the fireball explodes above Appa, much like a firework, into many smaller fireballs. Cut to a close-up of Aang looking on in awe.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Whoa!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Aang, do something!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>View from behind, from the saddle.</i>] Doing it. [<i>Side-view of Appa.</i>] Appa, yip yip! [<i>Appa flies down. Cut to a frontal view of Sokka and Kya screaming. Side-view of Appa as he manages to dodge the fireballs. Cut behind Appa he flies down to the water. Frontal view of Appa as he skims the water. The camera pans right to follow him glide over the top of the water. Cut to an underwater view of Appa. As a shadowed creature passes in front of the camera. Cut to a view from behind Aang, who turns to Kya and Sokka.</i>] You guys having fun yet? [<i>A huge sea serpent emerges from the water in front of the gang and the camera zooms out. Cut to a close-up of Aang, Sokka, Kya, and Momo, all screaming. Frontal view of Appa, who dodges the serpent and escapes its bite. Frontal view of Aang.</i>] Not bad, huh? Let's do it again!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Side-view of the boat as it nears the serpent, which turns its intention to the boat. Frontal view of Zuko and the soldiers. Two soldiers run away and one faints, Zuko stands his ground. Cut to a close-up of his foot. Cut to another close-up of him as the camera zooms out to show the serpent staying him down. Cut to a close-up as he prepares a fireball. Cut to a close-up of the serpent. As the serpent goes to attack Zuko, the screen goes black, as Zuko grunts.</i>
<p><i>Fade to a wide shot of an island as the camera pans left. Cut to a side-view of Sokka, sharpening his boomerang. Cut to a side-view of Kya, waterbending, and Aang, looking on, on a beach.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Looking good, Kya.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Side-view. To Kya.</i>] It won't be long until the Fire Nation sends their whole fleet after your little boyfriend. [<i>Frontal view of Kya.</i>] Kya, we don't have time for this.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Kya ignores Sokka and continues to waterbend. She attempts to land the water in a bag Aang is holding up and the camera pans left to follow the water to Aang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Keep it up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view of Kya.</i>] Hey! Quit playing around!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Kya turns to Sokka. Cut to a frontal view of Aang and Momo as the water drops on them.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>I said keep it up.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Frontal view of Kya. Sokka laughs. Frontal view of Aang, who uses airbending to dry himself off.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>View from behind Kya, who turns to Sokka.</i>] Okay, for the last time, waterbending is not playing. Braiding my doll's hair, now that's playing.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up. Blushing.</i>] I was six.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view of Aang laughing.</i>] And he's not my boyfriend.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang is visibly disappointed at this and Momo flies off, seemingly angry. Cut to a side-view as Kya attempts to waterbend again, but fails and becomes frustrated. Aang jumps to kneel next to her.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Listen Kya. Here's the secret to bending. [<i>Frontal view; standing.</i>] Energy comes from the Earth, through your roots, and into your branches.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view. Aang begins to enter a bending stance.</i>] My roots?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Use your legs. [<i>Side-view of Aang from behind Kya. Aang turns his head slightly and the camera cuts to Sokka, readying his boomerang. Cut back to side-view of Aang from behind Kya as Aang turns his head to see what Sokka is looking at. Cut close-up a tree with bananas on it. The camera zooms out to show Sokka aiming for it. Side-view of Aang from behind Kya.</i>] Watch closely.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang prepares a bubble of air between his hands. Frontal view of Aang as he sends out a blade of air as Sokka throws his boomerang. Cut to the tree as Aang's blade reaches it before the boomerang, but it destroys all of the fruit. Frontal view of Aang, who begins to innocently whistle as the camera zooms out to show Sokka. Sokka catches his boomerang and approaches Aang.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>What's your problem, air boy?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Me?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>That was going to be our lunch.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up.</i>] Oh uh, well, the Earth's bounty is rich, Sokka. There's got to be more food somewhere on this island. [<i>Side-view of the two.</i>]
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Poking Aang with the tip of his boomerang.</i>] So find it. I'm hungry.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Approaching, moving the boomerang away from Aang.</i>] No, Sokka. We can't let him wander around alone. What if he got hurt? [<i>Close-up of Sokka.</i>] The whole world is counting on Aang.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Staring at Aang in disbelief. Frontal view of Aang's feet as the camera pans up to his face. Aang shrugs slightly and laughs.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view. He leaves, pushing Aang out of his way.</i>] Right, so once again, I have to do everything. [<i>Camera pans left as he leaves and Momo lands on Aang's shoulder. Wide-view of the beach with Sokka in the foreground as he exits to the left.</i>] You better hope I find some food or you'll find me eating Momo.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view. Aang grabs Momo protectively in shock. Calling to Sokka.</i>] Sokka, be careful.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of a mountainside as the camera pans down to Sokka wandering around in the woods looking for food. Side-view through a bush with berries on it. He spots the bush and immediately runs to it. He eats a berry but finds that it is sour. He turns around as the camera cuts to a side-view and he sees two komodo rhinos staring at him. The camera zooms out to reveal them in their entirety and a Fire Nation soldier sat on each. Frontal view of one soldier.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Fire Nation soldier
</th>
<td>Hold it right there!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera pans down to Sokka, who turns to run. Cut to a view from behind Sokka as he flees, but the Fire Nation soldiers throw a rope around his legs, causing him to trip. Cut to a frontal view of Kya, tying a rope to Appa's horn, and the camera pans right to reveal Aang relaxing on Appa's head.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Quick Kya, [<i>Frontal view of Appa.</i>] let's go swimming before Sokka gets back.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>View from behind Kya, who turns to Aang as she talks.</i>] I'm impressed, Aang. You finished tying your end alrea- [<i>She notices Aang hasn't tied the rope to the bison. Frontal view of Aang.</i>] Aang, what have you been doing all this time?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Me? I, uh, I was just watching you. You know, trying to learn your technique.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up.</i>] This is <i>your</i> bison. <i>You</i> taught me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view of the two.</i>] Yep, it appears I taught you well. And thus the master passes the reins to the pupil. [<i>Presents her with a flower and bows.</i>] Ancient tradition. [<i>Kya grabs the flower and giggles, before throwing the flower away. Momo perks his ears up as if he hears something.</i>] What do you hear, Momo?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Both Kya and Aang look in the direction Momo looks. Momo jumps on to the horn that Kya was tying the rope to and the camera pans left to follow his movements. Kya turns to Aang as she speaks.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Aang, my brother's been gone for a long time.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Frontal view of Aang, who grabs his staff and airbends it open. Cut to a view of a shadow over water. The camera zooms out and reveals Momo flying ahead of Aang and Kya, who are on his glider. Cut to a close-up of Aang and Kya. Cut to a view of Momo flying ahead as he flies around a cliffside. The camera follows his path until a Fire Nation base is seen in the distance. Close-up of Aang and Kya as he flies up. Cut to a wide-view of the two in the distance as Aang maneuvers the glider to land on a nearby cliff. Cut to a cliff overseeing the Fire Nation base as Aang and Kya stand behind a rock formation to look down at the base below. The camera zooms slightly to show the komodo rhinos approaching the base. Cut to a view from behind the komodo rhinos. Sokka is tied up on the back of one of the komodo rhinos. Cut to a side-view of the Fire Nation base's entrance as the komodo rhinos enter. The draw bridge begins to close as the camera cuts to a frontal view of Kya.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Sokka, no! If I'm not back by- [<i>The camera follows Kya as she slides down the rocks, but stops when she sees Aang coming too. Side-view of Aang.</i>] Uh uh. Too dangerous. [<i>She approaches and forces him to sit down.</i>] You're way too important.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] You're important, too ... to me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Look, Aang, there's a bigger picture you're not seeing. [<i>Close-up of Aang.</i>] Bigger than me, Sokka, and Momo. [<i>Frontal view.</i>] You're the Avatar, start acting like it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>She leaves. Close-up of Aang, who looks sad, but suddenly perks up as if he has an idea. Cut to a view from behind Kya.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>Kya, [<i>Frontal view.</i>] remember it's all in the legs.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Side-view.</i>] Thanks.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Kya continues toward the camp and the camera pans right to show the base. Cut to a frontal view of Aang who looks on, before ducking down, and reappearing closer. Fade to a wide-view of the base's entrance as the serpent's head is brought in through the gates of the compound. Cut to a side-view of the head as it enters. Zuko is not far behind as he walks in. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko, who stops next to a soldier.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>I got your message. [<i>Cut close-up on the messenger hawk as Zuko passes it to the soldier. The camera pans up to the hawk as it squawks. Side-view of Zuko.</i>] Bring the Avatar's playmate to me.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a frontal view of Aang, using his airbending to create a ball of air around a rock, and Momo, who attempts to grab the rock.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Imitating Kya.</i>] "You're the Avatar, start acting like it." [<i>Frontal view of Aang.</i>] If that's the case, shouldn't I be using my skills to help. [<i>To Momo.</i>] Exactly, I can't let anything happen to Kya and Sokka. They're the only family I have, besides you. [<i>He moves the ball to right and the camera pans right slightly.</i>] If I were about to be eaten by a pack of angry hog monkeys, you'd save me, right? Yeah, I thought so.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang stops airbending and rolls backward, grabbing his staff in the process. Cut to a frontal view of Momo as the rock drops on his head. Momo attempts to attack the rock before stopping and flying off to follow Aang. Cut to a wide-view of the Fire Nation base. The camera pans down to reveal Zuko staring out into the horizon. Cut to a panning shot of him from behind.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>To Zuko.</i>] Hey! [<i>Close-up aerial view of Zuko, with Sokka, tied up behind next to two soldiers.</i>] Untie me and fight like a real warrior! [<i>Frontal view.</i>] I'm talking to you, scar boy! [<i>Close-up of Zuko's scar as becomes visibly annoyed. Frontal view of Sokka as the two soldiers slide away. Muttering.</i>] Yeah, tie me up with ropes.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a side-view of Zuko as he turns. Cut to a close-up aerial view of Zuko as he jumps on a ledge and jumps toward Sokka. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he lands, breathing fire from his noses, scaring Sokka. Sokka falls back and Zuko stands.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>Leave him alone!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Turning to Kya.</i>] Kya!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Fire Nation Soldier
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view of Kya approaching, tied up and flanked by two soldiers.</i>] Prince Zuko, we caught her trying to climb over the wall.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Is the Avatar with her?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Fire Nation Soldier
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] No sign of him, sir.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view from behind Kya.</i>] Search the island! He's probably hiding under a rock! [<i>Aang suddenly flies in between everyone and the shot pauses to show him smiling.</i>] Ah! [<i>Side-view of Zuko as Aang flies up and around the compound. Zuko points to him.</i>] Get him!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Aerial view.</i>] Go back, Aang!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up.</i>] And miss all the fun? Forget it.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang flies around the area. Cut to a wide-view of the compound as he lands in the middle of a circle of guards. Cut to a frontal view of him landing. The camera pans up as he stands and puts his glider away, before being surrounded by spears. Cut to zoom out for an aerial view of Aang surrounded by Fire Nation soldiers. The camera pans up to show Zuko and another soldier watching on from afar.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Yep, we're dead.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] What's the matter, Zuko? Can't handle me alone?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] You want your friends? Come and get them.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] If you insist.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Frontal view of Zuko, who points behind him and the camera pans right to show Kya and Sokka being thrown into a pit. Cut to a frontal view of Sokka and Kya as they are shoved into the pit. Cut to a frontal view of Aang, who gasps and moves to save them, only to be blocked by the guards. Cut to an aerial view as he spins his glider and takes off, leaving the guards coughing in the dust. Cut to a frontal view of two soldiers coughing in the dust, before it dissipates and a guard points to the scaffolding. The camera pans right slightly reveal Aang sitting on the scaffolding.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Soldier
</th>
<td>Up there! [<i>Frontal view of Aang, as Momo appears out of his clothing. Cut to a view from behind Aang looking down at the soldiers.</i>] After him!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>The camera pans down as three soldiers start to climb ladders. Cut to a frontal view of Aang as Momo jumps out from his clothing. Cut to a frontal view of a soldier climbing a ladder as Momo lands on his head and rotates his helmet. He jumps to the next soldier and does the same as the camera pans left. He jumps to the third soldier as the camera pans left once more before cutting to a side-view of the ground as all three soldiers fall to the ground. Cut to a frontal view of Momo flying to attack two more soldiers, but is intercepted by Zuko's messenger hawk.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view.</i>] Oooh. Get him, Momo!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang looks down and quickly jumps out of the way before a fire blast can hit him. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko, who starts shooting fire blasts at Aang. Cut to a frontal view of the scaffolding, which catches fire from the blasts that Aang dodges. The camera pans up as Aang climbs higher.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Soldier
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view of Zuko as the soldier approaches.</i>] Sir, the scaffolding!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Out of my way!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Zuko throws the guard down. Cut to behind Zuko as he makes his way toward the scaffolding and jumps on a rope. Cut to a close-up of his feet as he cuts the rope. Cut to a frontal view as he lifted up. Cut to an aerial view as he ascends through the scaffolding. Cut to a frontal view of the scaffolding as Aang continues to climb higher and reaches the top. Cut to a side-view as he looks down. The scaffolding begins to shake and Zuko breaks through and moves to attack. Cut to a frontal view as Aang dodges Zuko's attack by jumping over him. Cut to a side-view of the two as Zuko sends a fire blast at him, narrowly missing. Cut to a close-up of Aang as he lands, before jumping away to dodge another fire blast. He lands on a pole of the scaffolding and attempts to balance himself as Zuko approaches. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he sends another fire blast at Aang, who dodges. The flames cover the camera and cut to a view looking up out of the pit Kya and Sokka are in. The camera pans down and Kya is free from her ropes and untying Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>What does that kid think he's doing?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Cut to Sokka's perspective as he looks up at the hole above. Frontal view.</i>] As long as he distracts those soldiers, I can get us out of here.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Sokka, now free, produces his boomerang with a rope attached to it. Cut to Momo being chased by the Messenger Hawk. Cut to behind Momo and the hawk as the latter chases the former through the scaffolding. Momo eventually exits the scaffolding and flies toward the wall of the compound. Cut to a side-view as Momo uses his tale to swing around a piece of wood and the hawk to continue straight ahead. Cut to a side-view of the hawk as it goes crashing into the wall. Cut to a frontal view as it lands on the ground. Cut to a frontal view of Momo, who stops swinging and sniffs. The camera pans down to reveal a food basket, which he begins to eat from. Cut to an aerial view of the compound as the soldier attempt to put out the fires on the scaffolding. Cut to a side-view of a soldier, who stops and drops his hose to run away just before some scaffolding falls on him.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Guard
</th>
<td>Run! Run!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to above the scaffolding and the camera pans up to reveal Zuko and Aang. Both appear to struggle to balance as the scaffolding shakes. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko, who begins his attacks on Aang. Cut to a frontal view of Aang, who stops them with his staff.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>[<i>Close-up.</i>] Come on! Fight back!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a close-up of Aang, who laughs. Cut to a frontal view of Aang from behind Zuko as the former sends an air blast at the latter. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he is sent crashing into the face of the statue. Cut to a frontal view of Aang as the scaffolding he is standing on gives way. He falls, but he keeps himself up in the air by spinning his staff. Cut to a side-view of the scaffolding and statue as Aang moves toward the head of the statue, while Zuko climbs to the top of it. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he reaches the top and stands. Cut to a side-view as Aang approaches, landing on the statue head. Zuko disarms Aang of his staff. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he forms fire daggers. Cut to a close-up shot of the fire daggers and the camera pans right to show Aang looking on before creating an air bubble.</i>
<p><i>Cut to a frontal view of Sokka and Kya. Sokka spins his boomerang around and the camera pans up to follow its movements. Cut to a side-view of the hole above ground as the boomerang lands on the ground to the side. Cut to a frontal view of Sokka, who tugs the rope. The camera pans and zooms in on Kya, who turns to notice something, while the boomerang falls back down the hole. Cut to a frontal view of a container as water drips from it. Cut to a close-up of Kya as a water droplet lands on her head and she smiles.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Frontal view. Muttering to himself.</i>] Stupid short firebender ropes and stupid short Aang. [<i>Kya begins to enter waterbending stance. Cut to an aerial view of the container above as the water begins to shift. Cut to a frontal view of Kya.</i>] What are you doing? This isn't time to practice. I can't believe this, you never listen to me. [<i>Kya concentrates and ignores her brother.</i>] You're just off in your own little waterbending world, bending water in its world like ways. You never listen!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>The camera zooms in on Kya. To herself, as Sokka continues talking.</i>] It's all in the legs.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a close-up of her legs as she shifts positions. Cut to a frontal view as she exhales. Cut to an aerial view of the container as the water begins to rise. Cut back to a frontal view of Kya. Cut back to the container. Cut back to Kya as she makes a swift downward motion. Cut back to the container as the waterfalls out of the container through holes. Cut to a close-up of Kya as she looks up at what she has done. Cut to a side-view of the container as it breaks and goes everywhere. Cut to a frontal view of Kya, who grabs Sokka as the water crashes down on them and they swim out. Cut to an aerial view of two containers as they both break. Cut to a close-up of a shocked guard. Cut to a frontal view of the guard and two others as they are washed away by the water. The drops and reveals Sokka and Kya.</i>
<p><i>Cut to an aerial view of Zuko and Aang fighting atop the statue's head. Zuko attacks continuously but Aang does nothing but dodge and evade. Cut close-up to Aang, who is sweating and panting, as he dodges another strike from Zuko. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as he attacks again. Aang attempts to use airbending to stop him but fails. Cut behind Zuko as Aang dodges a kick from Zuko. Aang lands on his hands and knees and crawls through Zuko's legs to avoid another attack. Cut to a side-view as Zuko attacks again, forcing Aang to use airbending to propel himself back to the edge of the head, almost falling off. Cut behind Zuko as he approaches Aang. Cut to a close-up of Aang. Cut to a close-up of Zuko. Cut to a side-view of the fight as Aang circles around before Zuko attacks again. Aang dodges his attacks with the aid of airbending before jumping up into the air. In slow motion, Zuko kicks up and releases fire from his foot. Cut to a slow-motion, close-up, aerial view of Zuko with his tongue out. Cut to Aang as he narrowly avoids the attack, in slow motion, his tongue also rolling out. Cut to a side-view of the statue's head as Aang lands near the front. Cut to a view from behind Aang as he turns and the camera follows his view showing the long drop behind him. Cut to a close-up of Zuko as he speaks.</i>
</p>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Zuko
</th>
<td>Give up now and I'll make sure my father goes easy on you. [<i>Frontal view of Aang.</i>] You have nowhere left to go.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>You sure about that?
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Aang falls back over the edge. Cut to a frontal view of a shocked Zuko. Cut to a frontal view of Aang who enters the Avatar State and stops his fall with an air scooter. Cut to a close-up as he opens his eyes. Cut to a side-view from behind him as he begins running along the statue using airbending before jumping up to the head of the statue. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko as Aang lands on the head, sending out an air blast to knock Zuko off the head. Cut to a side-view of the head and scaffolding as Zuko is seen falling. Cut to a frontal view of Aang, who exits the Avatar State and noticing Zuko falling, grabs his glider and runs to help. Cut to a view under the head as Aang throws his glider ahead and jumps to grab it. The camera zooms in and follows him as he makes his way to Zuko. Cut to a frontal view of Zuko falling as Aang catches him between his legs. Cut to a frontal view as Aang and Zuko. Cut to a close-up Zuko as he opens his eyes and looks up to Aang, who smiles down at an irritated Zuko. Aang's expression shifts and he turns as he hears Sokka.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>[<i>Voice-over.</i>] Stay back!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to an aerial view of Sokka and Kya surrounded by Fire Nation soldiers. Cut to a close-up of Sokka as he sees Aang. Cut to a frontal view of Aang, who drops Zuko, and moves off to help Sokka and Kya. Cut to a side-view of Zuko, who crashes into the wall of the compound. Cut to a frontal view of the messenger hawk as Zuko lands on top of it. Cut to a side-view of Sokka as Aang circles around. Cut to a close-up of Aang, who nods to Sokka. Cut to a close-up of Sokka, who nods back.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Sokka
</th>
<td>Kya, get ready.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a view of Aang approaching on his glider, with Sokka and Kya below. Sokka swings the boomerang around and throws it toward Aang. The boomerang latches onto the glider and Aang flies off. Kya holds onto Sokka as he holds onto the rope, which is attached to the boomerang. Cut to a close-up of Aang and the camera zooms out as he struggles with the weight. Cut to a side-view of Sokka. Cut to a frontal view as he flies toward Momo. Cut to a close-up of a frightened Momo. The camera cuts to show them escaping over the wall, food basket in Sokka's hand and Momo wrapped around his head.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Side-view of Sokka and Momo, the latter still eating.</i>] Good work, Sokka! You found the food. [<i>Frontal view of Kya and Aang. Kya moans in fear.</i>] Come on, Kya, you're flying with the Avatar, start acting like it. [<i>Kya moans in fear again. Cut to an aerial view of the base as the group flies past.</i>] Woohoo!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Cut to a frontal view of Zuko, as the guards help him up. Zuko gets up and pushes the guards away, expelling fire from his mouth in the process. The messenger hawk wearily flies by as we see a close-up of Zuko's face. Fade to a side-view of Appa. As Kya speaks, cut to an aerial view of Sokka and Kya asleep in Appa's saddle.</i>
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Kya
</th>
<td>[<i>Narrating.</i>] My brother and I are quickly learning that life with Aang is one adventure after another. [<i>Side-view of Appa's head. Aang and Momo sleep on his head.</i>] But who knows, one of those adventures might even save the world.
</td></tr>
<tr>
<th>Aang
</th>
<td>[<i>Aang falls off Appa. Side-view of Appa as he falls.</i>] Aaah! [<i>Screen fades to black.</i>] I meant to do that!
</td></tr>
<tr>
<td>
</td>
<td><i>Credits.</i>
</td></tr></tbody></table>]