<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="25">Avatar Day</title>
      <director>Lauren MacMullan</director>
      <writer>John O' Bryan</writer>
      <date>2006-04-28</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins by showing a coast before panning down to in the middle
                of a forest where the gang is asleep, except for Momo. Switch to a view from inside
                Sokka's open mouth, looking out. A spider has set up its web over his mouth. Momo
                discovers the spider and inspects it with great interest. When a flies lands on the
                web, Momo tries to grab it. As he plunges his hand completely in Sokka's mouth,
                Sokka opens his eyes immediately in surprise. He shoots up and starts to spit out
                the remains of the spider and its web.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What are you doing in my mouth? <charAction>Momo
                chitters happily while lying upside down on Sokka's belly, chewing on the fly he
                "rescued" from the spider's web.</charAction> Momo, you need to be a little more
            sensitive to my boundaries.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The lemur seems to notice something else on his left. He completely ignores
                Sokka's comment and climbs on his face, where he erects himself and pricks up his
                ears to determine what it is he heard. He chitters loudly, waking up Katara, who was
                sleeping on a nearby sawed off tree trunk.</description>
      <description>Switch to Aang, who is still sleeping soundly on Appa's forearm. He wakes
                up as the ground begins to shake. Kahchi, sitting atop a rhino, jumps out of the
                thicket. Katara gasps as two more emerge from the bushes on the other side of the
                camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">
         <charAction>Shouting from up above as he looks over the campsite.</charAction> Give
            up! You're completely surrounded!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An overview shot of the campsite shows that four rhinos are circling around
                the gang.</description>
      <description>Close-up of Vachir, as he fires two flaming arrows toward Sokka, who was
                trying to crawl away like a caterpillar in his sleeping bag. The arrows pin the back
                of the sleeping bag to the ground while Sokka crawls out. He moves out of the path
                of a third arrow just in time.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Crawling toward Appa.</charAction> Come on! Come on! Come on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka climbs aboard Appa, where Aang's already waiting for him. Switch to a
                closer shot of Katara, as she also makes her way toward Appa. Just before she
                reaches him, she stops in her tracks and turns around.</description>
      <description>Kahchi spins his Guan Dao around and plants it in the sawed of tree trunk
                Katara was sleeping on a bit earlier. Next to the tree trunk lie some of Team
                Avatar's supplies.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">My scrolls!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> My staff!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He jumps off Appa's head, while Sokka just manages to get on.</description>
      <description>Switch to the Guan Dao blade into the stump, right next to a wooden box.
                The camera pans to the right to reveal Katara charging Kahchi with a water whip. She
                freezes the blade solid to the trunk, giving her the opportunity to grab the box of
                scrolls. She heads back toward Appa just as Kahchi manages to break his weapon free
                of the ice.</description>
      <description>Cut to Ogodei, who is swinging his chains around. He throws them around a
                tree and pulls it down to impede Aang's progress toward his staff. It has no effect,
                as Aang just somersaults over the fallen tree.</description>
      <description>Close-up of Yeh-Lu, as he ignites one of the hand grenades hanging on his
                belt. He throws it at Aang, who has reached his staff by now. The explosive lands
                right beside him, but the fuse is still burning. Aang swirls his staff around and
                knocks the explosive out of the way and into the woods. Aang propels himself into
                the air with airbending while the bomb explodes. He lands on Appa's
                head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa rises from the ground, leaving the Rough Rhinos behind. Mongke shoots
                a fire ball at them as they fly over. Katara and Sokka quickly duck and cover their
                heads, as the fire ball just misses them. As Sokka erects again, he notices
                something on the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stretching out his arm over the saddle as if he wants to grab
                it.</charAction> Wait, my boomerang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out on Sokka's boomerang, which still lies in the middle
                of their besieged camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Grabbing Sokka's arm.</charAction> There's no time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Oh, I see, <charAction>Turning to
                Katara.</charAction> so there's time to get your scrolls <charAction>Turning toward
                Aang.</charAction> and time to get your staff, <charAction>Looking back at Katara
                with his hand on his chest.</charAction> but no time for my boomerang?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> That's correct!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Bowing his head in defeat by this totally honest answer.</charAction>
            Oh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Mongke, who angrily turns his head as Appa disappears at
                the horizon.</description>
      <description>Screen changes to a small village at the edge of a cliff, surrounded by
                open, green fields. Appa landed nearby a small, wooden house.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To a sulking Sokka.</charAction> Sorry about your boomerang,
            Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera moves back to show how Sokka sits on the ground in a gloomy mood.
                Katara is buying supplies is the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> I feel like I've lost part of my identity.
                <charAction>He jumps up and moves Aang's hat slightly so that he can point at Aang's
                arrow.</charAction> Imagine if you lost your arrow, or Katara lost her ...
                <charAction>Makes a hair loopies gesture with a somewhat bored look.</charAction>
            hair loopies.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He slowly saunters over to the stall, where Katara gives him a loving hug
                in order to comfort him before she holding her hands in front of herself while
                smiling lovely at Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Merchant">Here's your produce, ponytail guy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He picks up the basket full of supplies, looking dejected at the
                nickname.</charAction> I used to be boomerang guy ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Katara follow Sokka with looks of sympathy as he walks away. The
                merchant heads toward Katara, who gives him some money.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Merchant">
         <charAction>Surprised, after inspecting the money.</charAction> Hey, Water Tribe
            money!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I hope that's okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Merchant">
         <charAction>Clutching the coin.</charAction> So long as it's money. <charAction>The
                merchant closes his shop, while Katara walks over to Aang, who is trying to console
                a crying Sokka as the camera pans up to show just the merchant's head.</charAction>
            Have a nice Avatar Day!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Interested.</charAction> Avatar Day?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Merchant">
         <charAction>Turning around while waving.</charAction> You guys are going to the
            festival, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all look at each other for a moment, trying to figure out what to do.
                Aang and Katara smile at each other, while tears still run over Sokka's
                face.</description>
      <description>The camera pans down to reveal an overview shot of Chin Village. Switch to
                a shot of several festive, green lanterns hanging over the street. The shot tilts
                down. Aang, Katara, and Sokka are standing in the middle of the busy street, looking
                around in interest.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's a holiday for the Avatar. Who knew?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They turn around as a large effigy of Avatar Kyoshi rolls by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing at the float.</charAction> Look! They made a giant Kyoshi
            float!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They run to the side. Switch to a close-up of Kyoshi's head. Aang, Sokka
                and Katara emerge from a side street.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">And here comes Avatar Roku! <charAction>Roku effigy rolls by.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Overview shot of the main square that is packed with people. The giant
                float of Kyoshi and Roku are being pulled to the middle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Having a huge festival in your honor is great, but frankly, it's just nice to be
            appreciated.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">And it's nice to appreciate their deep-fried festival food! <charAction>He takes a
                huge bite out of the food-item he is holding.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing at a giant float of Aang coming down the street.</charAction>
            Aang, look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's the biggest me I've ever seen!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up as Aang's float pulls up besides that of the other two Avatars on
                the main square. The camera pans to the right of the floats as a villager carrying a
                torch comes running down the street.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Now a torch, that's a nice prop. It's bright, dangerous ...
                <charAction>Sniffs.</charAction> smells manly. But I'm not sure I could carry it
            off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka takes another bite of his food as Katara points at the
                runner.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Hey, what's that guy doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With a loud scream, the runner jumps through the effigy of Kyoshi, causing
                it to catch fire. The fire spreads rapidly over the whole effigy.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villagers">
         <charAction>Chanting as Kyoshi's effigy is consumed by the flames.</charAction> Down
            with the Avatar! </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers continue chanting while the runner sets fire to the Roku
                effigy next. The camera zooms in on Aang, Katara, and Sokka, who are utterly shocked
                by the turn of events. Sokka's mouth falls open and food drips out.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of another town atop a hill. As two people are walking down
                the quiet street, a shadowy figure quickly passes them by on the roof. The Blue
                Spirit lands in front of the two people and unsheathes his dual dao swords as he
                jumps at the man carrying two baskets, suspended on a long pole. He swiftly cuts the
                baskets off in one fluid motion. The terrified man cowers back, as the Blue Spirit
                moves in to collect his prize. He hangs the baskets over his shoulders and heads for
                the woman, who is carrying a large piece of fruit on her head. The Blue Spirit
                snatches the fruit off her head and disappears as swiftly as he had come. The man
                and woman are left in confusion as to what just happened.</description>
      <description>Switch to a scene in the forest. The camera follows the descent of a fly
                that is snatched out of the air by a chameleon resting on a branch. The Blue Spirit
                is making his way through the thicket. The mask of the Blue Spirit is placed in a
                hollow part at the base of a tree. Zuko peeks around the trunk. The camera zooms
                toward a cavern where Iroh is sitting. He looks up when Zuko drops the barrels of
                food at his feet.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Wondering.</charAction> Where did you get these?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily, while walking away.</charAction> What does it matter where they
            came from?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Seriously.</charAction> Mmmm ... <charAction>Takes a bite out of one of
                the cupcakes Zuko brought. The jam drips of his chin. In delight.</charAction> ...
            mmmm!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to the burning effigies of the Avatars in Chin Village as the
                chants continue. The mayor signals to the torch-bearer, who is now on the roof, to
                throw his torch. The torch-bearer grins as he takes aim and throws his torch with a
                grunt right into the right eye of Aang's float. The crowd cheers in approval, while
                Aang looks at his own effigy burn with a look of pain on his face, closing his own
                right eye. Katara runs to the front and uses her waterbending to extinguish the
                flames with water from two large pots nearby.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager">
         <charAction>Angrily pointing an accusing finger at Katara.</charAction> That party
            pooper's ruining Avatar Day!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks angrily at the villager. He airbends himself to the top of his
                own float and lands on the left shoulder of his still smoking effigy.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angered.</charAction> That party pooper's my friend! <charAction>He
                takes off his hat and throws it away to reveal his arrow.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Pointing in shock at Aang.</charAction> It's the Avatar
            himself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager">
         <charAction>Scared.</charAction> It's going to kill us with its awesome Avatar
            powers!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I'm not, I ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang raises his hand. Several villagers run for cover in fear. The villager
                that spoke earlier throws himself into the audience. Aang looks at his hand and
                quickly hides it behind his back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Crawling back on his feet.</charAction> I suggest you leave!
                <charAction>He waves them away with a gesture of his hand.</charAction> You're not
            welcome here, Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara turns to face the mayor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Why not? Aang helps people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Landing beside Katara.</charAction> It's true! I'm on your
            side.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera zooms in slowly on the mayor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> I find that hard to swallow, <charAction>Raising
                his voice.</charAction> considering what you did to us in your past life! It was
            Avatar Kyoshi; she murdered our glorious leader, Chin the Great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Utterly shocked.</charAction> You think that I ... murdered
            someone?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager #2">
         <charAction>Lisping and slurring.</charAction> We used to be a great society before
            you killed our leader. <charAction>Pointing at himself as the camera zooms in on
                him.</charAction> Now look at us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers next to him look at him in disgust.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frightened by the appearances of the old man.</charAction> Huh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Katara places her arms on Aang's shoulders and starts to defend
                him.</charAction> Aang would never do something like that. No Avatar would.
                <charAction>Shaking her head in disapproval before pointing an accusing finger at
                the villagers.</charAction> And it's not fair for you all to question his
            honor!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager #3">
         <charAction>Raising his arm to emphasize his remark.</charAction> Let's tell her
            what we all think of the Avatar's "honor"!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He turns around to shake his rear at Aang and blows a raspberry; the
                villagers cheer in approval.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Give me a chance to clear my name!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">The only way to prove your innocence is to stand trial.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confidently.</charAction> I'll gladly stand trial!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">You'll have to follow all our rules. That includes paying bail.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Aang's face. His confident look quickly disappears as the
                camera cuts to the next shot, where he is cuffed with his hands and head stuck in a
                wooden panel and thrown behind bars. Katara holds her hand before her eyes in shame
                while Sokka leans against the prison bars. His arms are crossed and he looks annoyed
                at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Apologetically.</charAction> How was I supposed to know they wouldn't
            take Water Tribe money?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a panning down shot of the panoramic view of the village. The frame
                freezes for a moment on the open prison courtyard, where Aang's tunic is clearly
                visible. Switch to a shot from inside the prison, where Sokka, Katara, and Momo are
                still standing before the chained up Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So some people don't like you, big deal! There's a whole nation of firebenders who
            hate you. Now let's bust you out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Upbeat.</charAction> Sure you can! A little <charAction>Theatrically
                jumps back and pretends to airbend by blowing air. Katara looks ashamed for her
                brother. He moves to the back of the room to "cut" the air.</charAction>
            swish-swish-swish! <charAction>He makes a grotesque movement with his arm before
                thrusting his face in the camera.</charAction> Airbending slice! <charAction>He
                resumes his place beside Katara, who is still looking annoyed by her brother. He
                makes a circular motion with his hands and points toward the door.</charAction> And
            we're on our way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks at Sokka with big eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slightly mocking.</charAction> I think what "Master Swish" is trying to
            say <charAction>Serious tone as she looks at Aang.</charAction> is that you're supposed
            to be out saving the world. You can't do that locked up in here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Unhappy.</charAction> I can't do that with people thinking I'm a
            murderer either. I need you guys to help prove my innocence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How're we gonna to do that? The crime happened over three hundred years
            ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cunningly.</charAction> That's okay, Sokka. For some reason, I thought
            you were an expert detective.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Content.</charAction> Well, I guess I could be classified as
            such.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Aiding Aang by playing Sokka's ego.</charAction> Yeah! Back home, he was
            famous for solving the mystery of the missing seal jerky.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Bragging.</charAction> Everyone wanted to blame it on the polar leopard,
            but I figured out it was Old Man Jarko wearing polar leopard boots! <charAction>Katara
                holds her hand to her brow, annoyed by Sokka's monologue.</charAction> See, a real
            eight hundred-pound polar leopard would have left much deeper tracks. <charAction>Aang
                is making fun of Sokka, Katara holds her hand to her mouth to refrain herself from
                bursting out in laughs.</charAction> Okay, I guess I am pretty good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, you'll help me with my case?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pretends to ponder about the question. Katara stares at him, trying to
                figure out what he is doing.</charAction> Fine! But I'm going to need some new
            props. <charAction>The camera spins around. When it stops again, Sokka is wearing a hat
                with a monocle.</charAction> I'm ready. <charAction>Katara looks surprised at his
                new outfit and giggles. Sokka extends his monocle to investigate her.</charAction>
            What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wagon being pulled by an ostrich horse through the forest. An
                Earth Kingdom soldier sits in the front, holding the reins. Switch to the inside of
                the wagon, where a wealthy man in playing with his chest full of gold pieces. He is
                thrown to the front when the cart suddenly stops. The man looks around in fear,
                quickly closing and locking the chest with the precious metal. His scared eyes shift
                from side to side to as he hears rumbling noises outside. He clutches the chest
                protectively. The cold sweat is dripping down his face. He sighs in relieve as the
                noise died down, but he swiftly cowers back in fear as two swords pierce the top of
                the cart. A fist comes crashing down through the ceiling. When the aghast man looks
                up, he sees that it were the blades of the Blue Spirit that wrecked his cart. He
                anxiously holds up his treasury toward the Blue Spirit, while trying to stay away
                from him as far as possible. The Blue Spirit snatches it out of his hands and
                disappears, leaving the surprised man. The camera moves back to reveal the shocked
                man in his chart and the unconscious soldier on the ground.</description>
      <description>Cut back to a panoramic view of Chin Village, lying at the edge of the tall
                cliff and surrounded by pastures of green. Switch to on overview shot of a patch of
                sand, right outside the village wall. Three people are standing nearby a small
                shrine.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">This is the crime scene. <charAction>Cut to Sokka, who inquisitively looks around.
                He gazes directly into the camera lens through his magnifying glass, making his left
                eye appear huge. He moves on to investigate the walls of the shrine, while the mayor
                is standing at the edge of the cliff, pointing down at something.</charAction> This
            is the footprint of the killer, Kyoshi. <charAction>Sokka quickly squats beside the
                footprint to take a closer look at it.</charAction> It was at sunset, 370 years ago
            today, that she emerged from the temple, and struck down Chin the Great. After that
            tragic day, we built this statue to immortalize our great leader. <charAction>They all
                look up at a statue of Chin the Great, who has a raised left hand in
                triumph.</charAction> Feel free to appreciate it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The mayor leaves Katara and Sokka alone to investigate things further.
                Sokka moves in to examine the statue from every possible angle, while Katara looks
                curiously at him. Sokka is investigating the base of the statue, when something
                catches his attention. He looks through his magnifying monocle in order to take a
                better look at the right foot of the statue. His eyes widen as he makes a discovery.
                He swiftly runs over to the shrine that is facing the statue and examines the stone
                it is made of.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This temple and this statue were cut from the same stone. <charAction>Runs back over
                to the statue.</charAction> And we know that the statue was built after Chin
            died.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly drawing her conclusions.</charAction> So if they were built at
            the same time, that means–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka interrupts her before she can reach a conclusion.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> Shhh! I wanna solve it! <charAction>Pointing at
                the temple.</charAction> That means Kyoshi never set foot in this temple!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's a big hole in the mayor's story, <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> but
            it's not enough to prove Aang's innocence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You're right. <charAction>Blows soap bubbles with his dragon shaped pipe, while
                thinking about their next course of action.</charAction> We need to go to Kyoshi
            Island.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara walks in the frame, looking at his pipe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Where did you get that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the prison in which Aang is being held. An elephant rat sniffles his
                way over to an acorn. He picks it up and jumps away. Aang, still cuffed, leans
                dispirited against the wall of the prison. A low voice emerges from the shadows at
                the other side of the prison.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scary prisoner">You got a bald head. <charAction>Aang looks up in wonder to see who is talking.
                Switch to Aang's angle of view. A man is standing in the shadows, only his outline
                is visible.</charAction> Some nice tattoos. <charAction>The man emerges from the
                shadows. He has a strong build, earrings in both ears, and his body has a large
                snake tattoo that covers the top of his chest and down his right arm. He suddenly
                charges Aang, letting out a load growl. He is stopped in his tracks by the chains
                around his neck. Aang slides down the wall in fear, while the man addresses him
                calmly.</charAction> You're going to fit in real well around here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang smiles awkwardly as the man balls his fist.</description>
      <description>Switch to an overview of Kyoshi Island. A man in the watchtower signals the
                approach of Appa by ringing a bell. Cut to a shot of Oyaji's house as Appa's shadow
                slides over it. The man looks up. Two laughing, little children pass him on their
                way to great Appa and his riders. Appa lands right in front of the large, wooden
                statue of Kyoshi which is completely rebuilt. When Appa touches the ground, everyone
                in the village has gathered around to great them. They are all clapping as The
                foaming mouth guy makes it to the front. He sees Appa and all he can do is squeal.
                He gestures toward Appa in wonder, before letting out a load squeal and starts to
                foam before fainting. Some of the villagers look at him while doing his thing,
                feeling awkwardly. Sokka waves at the people. Koko, who was standing in the front
                with her hands raised high, notices that something is off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Angrily stamping her foot on the ground.</charAction> Where's
            Aangy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Gently breaks the news to Koko.</charAction> He couldn't be here,
            Koko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers sigh in disappointment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Nagging.</charAction> I wanted to see Aangy ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The foaming mouth guy woozily stands up again, staggering a bit. He looks
                from left to right, wipes the foam of his face and pulls his tunic over his head,
                before subtly sneaking away. The rest of the villagers do the same with the
                exception of Oyaji.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oyaji! Aang is in jail. The town of Chin says he murdered their leader in a past
            life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">They say it was Kyoshi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Kyoshi? That's crazy talk! I'll take you to her
            shrine. Maybe something there will help you clear her name.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The threesome is walking up a gentle slope.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>With feigned casualness.</charAction> So, uh ... what's Suki up to? Is
            she around?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka looks around while Katara gives him a loving smile.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">Actually, she and the other warriors left to fight in the war. You kids had a big
            impact on Suki. She said you inspired her and she wanted to help change the
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He disappointedly slants his eyes.</charAction> Oh, well ... that's
            great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They walk under a large paifang gate toward a temple at the top of a
                hill.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">This temple was converted into a shrine to Kyoshi. The clerics tell us these relics
            are still connected to her spirit. That's her kimono.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Approvingly.</charAction> She had exquisite taste.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">Please don't touch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara quickly lets go of the robe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">These fans ... <charAction>He picks up one of the fans and waves it back and
                forth.</charAction> They were her weapons, no?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Sternly.</charAction> Also refrain from touching the fans.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Squatting beside a really big pair of brown boots.</charAction> These
            were her boots? Her feet must have been enormous!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo peeks out one of them. Katara looks surprised to see him
                there.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Proudly.</charAction> The biggest of any Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Realizing something.</charAction> Wait a minute ... big feet?
                <charAction>A flashback shows the much smaller footprint they saw at the edge of the
                cliff outside Chin Village.</charAction> Little footprint? <charAction>She happily
                exclaims her findings.</charAction> There's no way–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka clears his throat to cut her off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Special outfit? Hat and pipe? These things mean
            anything to you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> You're right. I'm sorry. <charAction>She
                bows slightly in a mocking gesture.</charAction> Please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Dramatically raises his hand in the air.</charAction> Aha!
                <charAction>Showing his own boots to Oyaji.</charAction> There's no way Kyoshi could
            have made that footprint. <charAction>Moves toward Katara to explain everything to
                her.</charAction> And therefore there is nothing linking her to the crime
            scene.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Unimpressed.</charAction> Brilliant, Sokka. <charAction>Rolls her
                eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to an overview shot of Chin Village at sundown. Aang is sitting in
                a circle with three other inmates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scary prisoner">
         <charAction>In a very friendly voice that does not stroke with his scary
                appearances.</charAction> This girl you're talking about? She'll come around. You
            just gotta hang in there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang removes his head and hands out of the wooden panel.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Hopeful.</charAction> You think so?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scary prisoner">Sure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Prisoner #2">Yeah.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sensitive ruffian">You're a catch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Doubtful.</charAction> I don't know ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He rests his head on the board.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scary prisoner">Hey! You're smart, handsome, funny. Not to mention you're the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling sincerely.</charAction> You guys are great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sensitive ruffian">
         <charAction>Tears stream down his face while he talk in a very soft
                voice.</charAction> Don't be afraid to tell her how you feel. <charAction>He dries
                his tears and sniffs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to Kyoshi's shrine at Kyoshi Island. Oyaji brings Sokka's and
                Katara's attention to a painting that depicts Kyoshi and some of the
                villagers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">This piece is called "The Birth of Kyoshi". <charAction>Sokka investigates the
                painting thoroughly.</charAction> It was painted at sunrise on this day this island
            was founded. Why, it was today in fact, three hundred and seventy years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sokka spins around in shock, spitting out some of the bubbles he
                swallowed. Very surprised.</charAction> Three hundred and seventy years? Wait,
                <charAction>He grabs Oyaji by his collar.</charAction> are you sure it was
            today?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">Oh, seeing how it's Kyoshi Day, yes, <charAction>He pulls himself free from Sokka's
                grasp and throws him back a little.</charAction> I'm sure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Staring at the painting again.</charAction> This ceremony didn't take
            place at sunrise. It took place at sunset.
                <charAction>Addresses Katara.</charAction> Look at the shadows.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">They point east. So the sun must have been in the west.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">So what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shoves Katara out of the way as she yelps.</charAction> If Kyoshi was in
            the ceremony at sunset, she couldn't have been in Chin committing the crime. She has an
            alibi! <charAction>Points his pipe dramatically toward the camera upon making his
                conclusion.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara grabs the pipe out of his hand and slams him hard on the head with
                it causing him to fall down.</description>
      <description>Cut to a far off shot of Chin Village by night. The camera moves in slowly
                and keeps zooming forward, even when the picture changes to inside the prison. Sokka
                and Katara confront the mayor with their findings, while Aang listens intently at
                the bars.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Honorable Mayor, we've prepared a solid defense for the Avatar. We did an
            investigation and found some very strong evidence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Katara talks, a broadly smiling Sokka leans in toward Aang and points
                at himself to emphasize that he was the one that discovered the evidence. Aang
                flashes his teeth in return.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">Evidence? <charAction>Dismissive.</charAction> Hmph! That's not how our court system
            works.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Then how can I prove my innocence?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">Simple. I say what happened <charAction>He points to himself, before pointing to
                Aang.</charAction>, then you say what happened, and then I decide who's right.
                <charAction>Everyone gasps at once, horrified by this news.</charAction> That's why
            we call it justice. Because it's "just us."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The mayor exits the room, laughing maniacally, leaving Sokka, Katara and
                Aang standing there with their mouths wide open in shock.</description>
      <description>Cut to an overview of the amphitheater, the statue of Chin and the temple
                on the edge of the cliff. Switch to a back shot of the mayor. The camera pans to the
                left to reveal that every villager has gathered in the amphitheater. Katara and
                Sokka are seen sitting at the front.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Emotionally.</charAction> Everyone loved Chin the Great because he was
            so great. Then the Avatar showed up and killed him, and that's how it happened.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He walks away with a giant smile on his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Very deep, monotone voice.</charAction> The accused will now present its
            argument.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Raises his hand before his mouth to say some quiet, encouraging
                words.</charAction> You can do it, Aang. Just remember the evidence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Still tied up, unsure.</charAction> Right ... evidence. <charAction>He
                shifts his eyes to the left while he is trying to remember what to say.
                Enthusiastically.</charAction> Ladies and gentlemen ... I'm about to tell you what
            really happened. And I will prove it with facts. Fact number one. <charAction>Raises his
                finger to count along but blanks out.</charAction> Uhhh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Whispers.</charAction> The footprint!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh, yeah. You see ... I have very large feet. <charAction>The camera tilts down to
                reveal his small feet. The villagers are unimpressed by his argument.</charAction>
            Furthermore ... your temple matches your statue. <charAction>The villagers look from one
                to the other, not knowing where Aang is going with this.</charAction> But ... I was
            in a painting at sunset. <charAction>He quickly ends his exposition with a big
                smile.</charAction> So, there you have it, I'm not guilty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera switches view from Aang to the unimpressed crowd, to pan further
                down toward Sokka and Katara, both with big smiles on their faces, but their eyes
                reveal that they are fake. Sokka gives Aang a "thumbs up" gesture. Momo sits on
                Katara's lap, looking very confused.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Mumbles to Katara while they continue to smile.</charAction> He's
            dead.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko's and Iroh's hideout in the forest. Zuko sits next to the
                campfire as Iroh walks into the cave to inspect a new tea set.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Looks like you did some serious shopping. <charAction>He picks up a big,
                gold-colored teapot.</charAction> But where did you get the money?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Lazily resting against a tree trunk.</charAction> Do you like your new
            teapot?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">To be honest with you <charAction>He puts the pot down.</charAction>, the best tea
            tastes delicious whether it comes in a porcelain pot or a tin cup. <charAction>Iroh
                walks over to Zuko and squats down beside him.</charAction> I know we've had some
            difficult times lately. We've had to struggle just to get by. <charAction>Places a hand
                on Zuko's shoulder who closes his eyes as if he was holding something
                back.</charAction> But it's nothing to be ashamed of. There is a simple honor in
            poverty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">There's no honor for me without the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko ... <charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Even if you did capture the Avatar, I'm not
            so sure it would solve our problems. Not now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns away from his uncle.</charAction> Then there is no hope at
            all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko wants to stand up and leave the cave, but Iroh grabs him by the
                shoulders and sits him down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No, Zuko! You must never give in to despair. Allow yourself to slip down that road
            and you surrender to your lowest instincts. <charAction>Zuko bows his head as he listens
                to his uncle's wisdom.</charAction> In the darkest times, hope is something you give
            yourself. That is the meaning of inner strength.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns to face his uncle, who looks back at him with a sad look upon
                his face. Abruptly, Zuko pulls free from Iroh's grasp and heads out into the
                forest.</description>
      <description>Switch back to an overview shot of Chin Village.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Mayor Tong, I'd like for the court to hear one last testimony.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">I've already told you, it's just me and the accused. You can't call any
            witnesses!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This isn't just any witness. I'm going to call ... <charAction>Spreads her
                arms.</charAction> Avatar Kyoshi herself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers murmur among themselves while someone exits the temple. The
                guard escorts Aang in Kyoshi costume, to the front.</description>
      <description>Close-up a skeptical looking mayor. As Katara sits back down, Sokka leans
                toward her, pointing at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hopeful.</charAction> Well, she is Aang's past life. Maybe wearing her
            stuff will trigger something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Plays with his magnifying glass.</charAction> I do believe in the power
            of stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> This is a mockery of Chin Law!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pleading.</charAction> Please! If you could just wait one more second,
            I'm sure Kyoshi will be here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to Aang who is standing in the middle of the square, hiding his face
                behind one of Kyoshi's fans. He peeks over the fan.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Higher pitch.</charAction> Hey, everybody! Avatar Kyoshi here.
                <charAction>Rapidly blinks his eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Walking over to Aang.</charAction> This is ridiculous!
                <charAction>Points at Aang while he addresses the audience.</charAction> For the
            murder of Chin the Great, this court finds the Avatar–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks down in defeat, but is suddenly engulfed in a tornado of earth.
                Tong holds on to his hat to prevent it from being blown away. The sky darkens and
                when the tornado dies down, Aang is gone and the spirit of Kyoshi has taken his
                place.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">I killed Chin the Conqueror. <charAction>A flashback shows how Chin earthbends an
                earth column beneath one of his subjects as he was offering something to Chin.
                Voice-over.</charAction> A horrible tyrant, Chin was expanding his army to all
            corners of the continent.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A close-up of Chin the Great fades to a shot of a map, where the trail of
                his campaign can be seen. He had concurred everything save to Ba Sing Se. The scene
                switches to a large army standing by the shores of the sea, ready to attack when
                given the order.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">When they came to the neck of the peninsula where we lived, he demanded our
            immediate surrender. <charAction>Kyoshi calmly walks toward him to face his
                challenge.</charAction> I warned him that I would not sit passively while he took
            our home. But he did not back down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Chin and Kyoshi stand face to face. Kyoshi is around a foot bigger than
                him. Chin takes a fighting stance, but Kyoshi is unimpressed. She grabs one of her
                fans and points it at him. A powerful gust of wind washes over the surprised Chin
                and strips him of all his clothes, except for his underwear.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">On that day, we split from the mainland.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Avatar Kyoshi as her eyes glow for a second, signaling the
                Avatar State. She jumps up and stretches one of her fans to the left as she lands. A
                powerful fissure rips through the earth and explodes at the edge of the cliff. She
                repeats that move to the right now with the same effect. Kyoshi calmly closes her
                fans and slams them into the ground, causing the whole peninsula to shake. Chin
                still stands in his earthbending stance.</description>
      <description>The camera shoots from inside the ground as it opens up to reveal how
                Kyoshi made a large crack in the earth. With a series of wide arm movements, she
                bends the lava up from underneath the landmass to sever it completely. As the wall
                of lava dies down again, chunks of rock fall to the ground. Kyoshi spins around and
                creates a powerful gale right beside Chin, blowing part of his army away and making
                the rest run away in fear. An overview shot shown how lava has seeped into the sea
                and how the island is being blown away from the mainland. Chin holds on to his hat
                as he watches the island go. He screams in anger while the rocks under him start to
                cave. An overview shot reveal how he plummets to his death in the waters
                below.</description>
      <description>The overview shot in the flashback fades for the present day overview shot
                of that same cliff where now a temple is build.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">I created Kyoshi Island so my people could be safe from invaders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She slants her eyes and is engulfed by the sand tornado once more. Tong
                kneels to the ground and covers his head. While the sandstorm keeps spinning around
                Kyoshi, the darkness is lifted. Sokka holds Katara protectively in his arms while
                she clings on to Momo. When the tornado disappears, Aang is standing there once
                again, swaying from side to side. Katara catches him right before he
                collapses.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> So, what just happened?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> Uhhh ... you kind of confessed. Sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">
         <charAction>Standing up in the background.</charAction> And I find you ...
                <charAction>He brushes himself off and points at Aang.</charAction> Guilty! Bring
            out the Wheel of Punishment!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers break out into cheers as they hear the sentence. Momo looks
                around, before covering up his eyes with his tail.</description>
      <description>Cut to Iroh who is bending over the supplies.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle ... <charAction>Switch to a close-up of Iroh with Zuko on the
                background.</charAction> I thought a lot about what you said.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Iroh's sad expression clears up as he hears Zuko talk.</charAction> You
            did? Good, good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's helped me realize something. We no longer have anything to gain by traveling
            together. <charAction>Iroh's brightened expression quickly disappears
                again.</charAction> I need to find my own way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh bows his head in sorrow. Zuko looks at his uncle for a moment before
                grabbing his backpack and walking away. The camera zooms in on Iroh's
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Calling after Zuko.</charAction> Wait!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh hands Zuko the reins of the ostrich horse. Zuko mounts it, looks at
                his uncle one last time and heads off, leaving a broken Iroh.</description>
      <description>Switch back to a panning down shot of Chin Village where Aang stands before
                the Wheel of Punishment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Deep, monotonous voice.</charAction> The accused will now spin the Wheel
            of Punishment to determine his sentence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns to looks at Sokka and Katara who are giving him glances of
                sympathy.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I said I would face justice, so I will.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He gives a good spin on the wheel. The camera pans down the
                amphitheater.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager">
         <charAction>Hoping.</charAction> Come on, torture machine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager #2">Eaten by bears!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager #3">Razor pit!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Begging.</charAction> Community service! Please stop on community
            service!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Katara look very worried as the wheel starts to slow down. It
                passes by "strangled by a platypus bear" and "eaten by sharks." Aang anxiously
                awaits his punishment. The wheel comes to a halt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Monotone.</charAction> Looks like it's "boiled in oil."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers cheer loudly, while Aang looks scared and Katara and Sokka
                who are just absolutely shocked.</description>
      <description>Suddenly a lit bomb bounces into the scene and detonates into the temple.
                The blast makes the whole amphitheater shake. Sokka and Katara raise their arms to
                protect their faces from the blast.</description>
      <description>Everyone looks up when Mongke starts to talk.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">We've come to claim this village for the Fire Lord!
                <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Now show me your leader so I may ...
                <charAction>Kahchi swings his Guan Dao back and forth, slicing through the statue of
                Chin the Great. While it crumbles down, Mongke continues with a grin.</charAction>
            dethrone him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Villager">That's him over there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A scared villager points immediately toward the mayor. The mayor squeals
                and hides behind the Wheel of Punishment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">Ahhh! <charAction>Commanding.</charAction> You, Avatar, do something!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Apathetically.</charAction> Gee, I'd love to help, but I'm supposed to
            be boiled in oil.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The mayor tips the wheel one slot further. It now rests on a picture of a
                sweeping man.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">There, community service! Now serve our community and get rid of those
            rhinos!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang smiles as he rushes forward and jumps out of his Kyoshi costume to
                face Kahchi, who readies his weapon. A he charges Aang, Aang opens his fans. He
                quickly spins out of the rhino's path and uses his airbending to lift Kahchi out of
                his saddle and blows him off the cliff with another gust.</description>
      <description>Kahchi's rhino still proceeds toward the mayor, who peeping over the wheel
                and quickly hides behind it as he sees the rhino coming toward him. He squeaks in
                fear when the rhino's horns embedded themselves into the wheel, missing the mayor's
                vital part by inches.</description>
      <description>Aang turns to face Mongke who does not look pleased with the defeat of
                Kahchi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">
         <charAction>Raising his hand while shouting his command.</charAction> Rough Rhinos,
            to the town!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Vachir shoots three burning arrows at the down setting fire to the roof of
                a nearby building. Mongke uses his firebending to burn down another house. Lit
                arrows keep raining down on the rooftops. Close-up of Yeh-Lu as he rides by a hay
                wagon and drops some lit bombs in it. The wagon explodes, destroying the house next
                to it. Ogodei rides past another house and pulls down its support beams with his
                chains.</description>
      <description>Close-up as he lets out a loud scream and spins his chains above his head.
                He throws them at Katara who easily deflects them with a water whip. The chains wind
                themselves around Ogodei. She hits the rhino on the rear with another whip of her
                water and the animal dashes away with Ogodei on it.</description>
      <description>Sokka comes down a stair between two members of the Rough Rhinos. He
                adjusts his monocle so it would reflect the sunlight right into the eyes of Vachir.
                The archer turns and blindly shoots a burning arrow at Sokka. The arrow pierces his
                hat and embeds itself in the saddlebag of Yeh-Lu that is filled with bombs. Sokka
                smiles and ducks for cover. Yeh-Lu notices what is going on and tosses the saddlebag
                away, but it is too late. The force of the blast smacks him and his rhino into a
                nearby wall. As Sokka covers his head to protect himself against the flying debris,
                Yeh-Lu's helmet rolls by. Another bag lands right beside Sokka, his boomerang is
                sticking out of it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Raises his arms in the air and exclaims ecstatically.</charAction>
            Boomerang! You do always come back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka notices that Vachir is aiming at him. He quickly weighs his options
                and throws his dragon-shaped pipe at the archer. The pipe slides over the burning
                arrow and extinguishes the fire. While Vachir looks surprised at his extinguished
                arrow, Katara sneaks up behind him and cuts his saddle cord with her waterbending.
                Vachir slides down, but his foot is still stuck in his saddle, so he is dragged away
                by his rhino when Katara whips it on its rear.</description>
      <description>Switch to Aang who is having a standoff with Mongke in an alley. Mongke
                uses his firebending to increase his speed as he charges Aang. Aang jumps over him
                and is forced to raise an air shield to protect himself from Mongke's fire blast. He
                loses his fans and headdress as he slides down. Aang creates an air scooter and they
                charge each other again. He avoids Mongke's fire blast by quickly riding under the
                rhino's belly and emerges behind Mongke. He directs a powerful gale at the colonel,
                but he slides to the side to evade it. They charge at each other a third time, this
                time with Aang on foot again. When Mongke fires a powerful blast that consumes the
                whole alley, Aang jumps up and propels himself right through the blast using
                airbending, feet first. He crashes right into Mongke, sending him flying through a
                wooden fence.</description>
      <description>Cut to a scene of fireworks. Later that night, fireworks go off in the
                village.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">From now on, we'll celebrate a new Avatar Day in honor of the day Avatar Aang
                <charAction>Camera pans down to show Katara, Aang, and Sokka, each holding a bowl
                and grinning happily.</charAction> saved us from the Rough Rhino Invasion.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Looks questioningly into his bowl.</charAction> What is this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A close-up of the bowl reveals several Aang-shaped pieces of
                dough.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tong">That's our new festival food! Un-fried dough. May we eat it and be reminded of how
            on this day the Avatar was not boiled in oil.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The villagers cheer, but the gang gives each other some uncertain looks.
                They each pick up a dough cookie. Cut to a closer shot of Katara as her cookie
                droops in her fingers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Happy Avatar Day, everyone!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Uncertainly, she chews it down. She looks down at her bowl, confused of
                what to make of it. The camera pans to the right to show how Aang also sticks a
                cookie in his mouth, although half of it is still dangling out of his
                mouth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stares skeptically at his dough-cookie.</charAction> This is by far the
            worst town we've ever been to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Aang slurps the rest of his cookie inside his mouth, Sokka finally
                eats his and stares skeptically again at the next cookie.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
