<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="15">Bato of the Water Tribe</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Ian Wilcox</writer>
      <date>2005-10-07</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens up to a body of water, waves crashing against the rocks.
                The camera cuts to grass and sticks, before slowly panning up to reveal a whale
                tooth scimitar standing upright in the ground. Aang's hand comes into view as he
                grasps the weapon's hilt and yanks it out of the ground. Cut to a shot of him
                holding it up while Sokka slides down a dirt slope.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey, look! <charAction>Examines the sword.</charAction> A sword made out of a
            whale's tooth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Aang draws the weapon free from the ground, Sokka slides down the
                slope and pulls up behind the Avatar, snatching the weapon from his hands as Aang
                turned to show it to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Let me see that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka walks on for a little while, before he stops, not too far from Aang,
                to study the weapon closely. Cut to a shot of the scimitar in his hand. The scene
                switches into a flashback; Southern Water Tribe warriors are preparing their ships,
                loading them with supplies. The camera pans to the left as a warrior walks past,
                carrying a bundle, revealing that a younger Sokka is observing them, his back to the
                camera. Cuts to frontal shot of him as he looks at the scene wistfully, cradling his
                battle club. Flashback fades to present-day, where Sokka bears the same wistful
                expression while holding the whale's tooth scimitar in the same way as his
                club.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This is a Water Tribe weapon. <charAction>Turns to Aang, his expression
                serious.</charAction> See if you can find anything else.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Aang and Sokka searching the wooded area for more weapons.
                Katara walks toward them, curious.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Curiously.</charAction> Did someone lose something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rummaging through the bushes; somewhat cheerfully.</charAction> No, we
            found something!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of a spearhead lying on the ground beneath a few fallen leaves.
                Sokka kneels before it, brushes aside the debris and picks up the spearhead,
                examining it and running his fingers along its point, noticing ash on
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's burned. <charAction>Cut to shot of a tree trunk, scorch marks and sharp cuts
                running across its bark. Cut to shot of Sokka and the others.</charAction> There was
            a battle! Water Tribe warriors ambushed a group of firebenders. <charAction>He turns
                away from the tree and looking down the slope of the hill seeing a black spot on the
                ground.</charAction> The firebenders fought back, but the warriors drove them down
            this hill.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of Sokka racing down the hill along a dirt path, the camera
                panning downward. He leaps over a few large rocks in his way and continues forward.
                Cuts to shot of a sandy beach. Sokka appears on screen followed closely by Aang and
                Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Intrigued.</charAction> So, then what happened?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> I don't know. The trail ends here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing at something in the distance.</charAction> Wait, look!
                <charAction>Cut to shot of a Water Tribe ship, half obscured behind large rocks,
                sitting idly on the shore.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> It's one of our boats!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Is this dad's boat? <charAction>She and Sokka run toward it. Cut to shot of entire
                ship as they approach.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, but it's from his fleet. <charAction>Strokes the boat off, while Aang appears
                behind them.</charAction> Dad was here. <charAction>Turns to
            Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to a close-up of Iroh sipping a cup of tea, with a
                relaxed expression on his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Exhaling.</charAction> Aahh! <charAction>Cuts to shot of entire room
                where he and Zuko are seated at a low-lying table.</charAction> See Prince Zuko, a
            moment of quiet is good for your mental well-being. <charAction>Pours Zuko a cup of
                tea.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko raises the cup to take a sip, but the ship suddenly jerks; the
                vibrations cause the tea in the cup to go flying, soaking Zuko's face and hair. Zuko
                grunts in frustration, pushes his ponytail back, and rises to see what the commotion
                is about. Cut to the deck of the ship, several firebenders stand poised, ready to
                attack. A large beast, called a shirshu, suddenly leaps onto the deck, a young woman
                mounted on its back. The firebenders flee from the beast. Cuts to closer-up shot of
                the woman, who slows down the beast's progress.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Firebenders">Look out! Argh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Holding a rolled up whip.</charAction> Get back! We're after a stowaway!
                <charAction>Cut to overhead shot of the ship's deck.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Arrives with Iroh.</charAction> There are no stowaways on my
            ship.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Nyla, the shirshu, who tears off a chunk of the metal deck
                flooring and hurls it in Zuko's direction. Alarmed, the prince ducks for cover, the
                firebenders and Iroh move to the side, and the metal piece hits the doorway leading
                to the main compartments of the ship with a clang as they turn around to watch it
                hit the door. Zuko looks on in frustration while the firebenders and Iroh take a
                firebending stance.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of the interior of the ship, a gaping hole present where the
                metal flooring once was. Nyla sticks his head inside and begins sniffing around. Cut
                to shot from his point of view, the scenery slightly warped and in black-and-white
                to reflect how he envisions things. A stream of green is visible, drifting through
                the air. The camera pans right and left as the beast surveys the entire room. It
                focuses on a single barrel which topples over, revealing that a strange man has been
                hiding in there. Cut to a shot above the deck where Nyla raises his head out of the
                hole. The stowaway appears, dashing away from the scene. Nyla shoots forward in hot
                pursuit of him. Cut to side-view of the man trying to flee; Nyla appears on-camera
                and lashes out his elongated tongue. Close-up of the tongue striking the man who
                falls onto the deck, paralyzed, and with a terrified look on his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> He's paralyzed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Only temporarily. <charAction>Lifts the man and slings him over her
                shoulder.</charAction> The toxins will wear off in about an hour. But by then, he'll
            be in jail and I'll have my money. <charAction>Walks to Nyla.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But how did you find him on my ship?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Prepares to mount Nyla, the stowaway already slung onto his
                back.</charAction> My shirshu can smell a rat a continent away. <charAction>Mounts
                her shirshu.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Well, I'm impressed. <charAction>June cracks her whip. Cuts to shot of the shirshu
                bolting off the ship and racing down the dock.</charAction>
            Very impressed. <charAction>Leaning over the ledge of the
                ship with Zuko, stroking his beard thoughtfully; Zuko look at him,
                disgusted.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to that night, the camera panning downward to show that
                Team Avatar has settled down for the night beside the Water Tribe ship. Cut to shot
                of Appa. Aang and Momo are lying on his right paw, all three fast asleep. The camera
                pans left, showing Katara having also drifted off in her sleeping bag. Sokka remains
                awake, poking a stick into a blazing campfire, looking worried. Cut to side-shot of
                him; the scene fades to the flashback seen earlier. A younger Sokka is seen walking
                by, carrying a large bundle in his arms, wearing face-paint. Cut to a shot of Hakoda
                standing beside a ship, having handed a bundle to a man in the ship. He turns and
                walks forward. Cut to a shot of Sokka who has halted in his tracks, his father
                approaching him and standing before his son.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm coming with you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">You're not old enough to go to war, Sokka, you know that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Desperately.</charAction> I'm strong, I'm brave, I can fight! Please,
            Dad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">
         <charAction>Lays a hand on his son's shoulder; grimly and sadly.</charAction> Being
            a man is knowing where you're needed the most. And for you right now, that's here,
            protecting your sister.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I don't understand. <charAction>His eyes glisten.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Someday you will. <charAction>Sokka throws aside his bag and throws himself into his
                father's arms. Cut to close-up of him as he sobs and buries his face in his father's
                parka.</charAction> I'm gonna miss you so much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades back to present day, Sokka still looking sullenly into the
                fire. Suddenly a strange noise can be heard, its source originating from somewhere
                off-camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Alert.</charAction> Who's there? <charAction>Stands up, boomerang in
                hand.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the campsite from several feet away. A pair of boots
                appears in front of the camera. Cut to shot of a man, hailing from the Water Tribe
                with white bandages wrapped around the upper left portion of his torso, stepping out
                of the shadows. He is clearly surprised to see them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Sokka?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Quizzically, raising an eyebrow.</charAction> Bato?
                <charAction>Spirited.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Having awoken, along with Katara.</charAction> Who the what
            now?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> Bato!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Cuts to side-shot of Bato, Sokka running over to him, followed closely
                by Katara.</charAction> Sokka! Katara! It is so good to see you two.
                <charAction>Hugs Katara and Sokka.</charAction> You've grown so much!
                <charAction>Aang follows them, but remains standing a few feet
            away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Bows in greeting.</charAction> Hi, I'm Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Where's Dad?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Is he here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">No, he and the other warriors should be in the Eastern Earth Kingdom by now.
                <charAction>Both siblings look crestfallen at this news. A gust of wind blows,
                causing them to shiver. Cut to a shot of Bato who shivers as well.</charAction> This
            is no place for a reunion. Let's get inside.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He turns and slings his arms around Sokka and Katara, leading them away.
                After a moment, he looks back at Aang and gestures for him to follow. Cut to an
                overhead shot of the shore, the campsite in the distance, as the group begins
                walking away. The scene cuts to a different location altogether, the moon hanging in
                a purplish-blue night sky. The camera pans downward to show the roof over of the
                entrance to an open courtyard. Cut to a shot inside the courtyard, a few nuns
                milling about, Appa and the group approaching.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">After I was wounded, your father carried me to this abbey. The sisters have cared
            for me ever since. Superior, <charAction>A woman turns around.</charAction> these are
            Hakoda's children. They've been traveling with the Avatar. I found them by my
            boat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">Young Avatar, it gives me great joy to be in your presence. Welcome to our
            abbey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thank you, it's truly an honor to be here. If there's anything- <charAction>Sokka
                abruptly cuts him off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What smells so good, Bato?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Sniffs.</charAction> The sisters craft ointments and perfumes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Perfume? <charAction>Pointing his thumbs at Appa.</charAction> Maybe we can dump
            some on Appa, because he stinks so much. <charAction>Waves his hand in front of his
                face.</charAction> Am I right? <charAction>Everyone is silent, a single person
                coughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">You have your father's wit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to the hut in which Bato is staying, with a tent on the
                opposite side of the door being the bed chamber, a fire with cousins in the middle,
                and various pelts placed and hung everywhere.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Bato, it looks like home! <charAction>Bato, Katara, Sokka, and Aang file
                inside.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Everything's here, even the pelts!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, nothing's cozier than dead animal
            skins.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo leaps from Aang's arms and starts hitting the head of a bear pelt. The
                bear's mouth closes, Momo is alarmed a retreats back to Aang. Katara and Sokka are
                by the fire. Katara opens the lid of a pot cooking over the fire as Bato joins
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised and delighted.</charAction> No way! Stewed sea
            prunes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Help yourself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Dad could eat a whole barrel of these things!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang takes a bowl of stewed sea prunes and sniffs it, but looks away in
                disgust and sets it to the side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Bato, is it true that you and dad lassoed an arctic hippo?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">It was your father's idea, he just dragged me along. Well, the hippo did the
            dragging! <charAction>Momo, sitting by Aang, starts to eat the stewed sea prunes that
                Aang set aside, but ends up spitting it out.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sokka and Katara are slurping their stewed sea prunes as Aang
                speaks.</charAction> Hey, I ride animals, too! There was this one time when I rode a
            giant eel and I-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cutting Aang off.</charAction> So, who was it that came up with the
            Great Blubber Fiasco?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Chuckles to himself.</charAction> You knew about that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Everyone does!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Curiously.</charAction> What's that story?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Waving Aang off.</charAction> It's a long one Aang, some other
            time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>To Bato.</charAction> You and Dad had so many hilarious
            adventures.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Not all of which were hilarious at the time, but everything's funny in hindsight.
                <charAction>Chuckling.</charAction> Hey, Aang! Please put that down,
                <charAction>Aang is shown wearing a fur pelt on his head.</charAction> it's
            ceremonial and very fragile. <charAction>Aang puts the pelt back on the wall, and sits
                in the back of the room.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Was it you or Dad that put an octopus on your head and convinced Gran-Gran you were
            a water spirit?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Your dad wore the octopus, <charAction>Lowers his voice.</charAction> but I did the
            spooky voice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a seedy tavern in the Earth Kingdom. A man is thrown
                through the roof and land of the ground. Cut to a snake tattoo on a woman's arm. The
                camera zooms out, showing that it is June's tattoo. She calmly arm-wrestles a man,
                who gnashes his teeth and sweats. The shot changes to the back of the crowd where
                Zuko arrives.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Out of my way! <charAction>Pushing a man out of
                the way.</charAction> Step aside, filth!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Apologetically.</charAction> He means no offense! I'm certain you bathe
            regularly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko approaches June, who is still arm wrestling. Iroh reaches her as
                well.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I need to talk to you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Well, if it isn't my new friends: Angry Boy and Uncle Lazy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Her opponent strains to get the upper hand. Iroh laughs at her remark and
                June wins her match without breaking a sweat. The crowd cheers and throws money at
                the winner.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Your beast trashed my ship. You have to pay me
            back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>As she collects her winnings.</charAction> Well, I'd love to help you
            out, but I'm a little short on money. <charAction>To the crowd.</charAction> Drinks on
            me! <charAction>The crowd cheers.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>June moves to take sip of her drink, but Zuko grabs her wrist in
                anger.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Money isn't what I had in mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to moths flying around a lantern.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I need you to find someone. <charAction>Cut to Katara's
            necklace.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot changes to show June leaning on Nyla while Iroh and Zuko stand in
                front of June.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> What happened, your girlfriend run off on
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's not the girl I'm after, it's the bald monk she's traveling with.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Unamused.</charAction> Whatever you say.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">If you find them, I'll consider the damage to my ship <description>paid
                for</description>.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Scoffs.</charAction> Heh, forget it. <charAction>She starts to climb her
                saddle.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Plus, we'll pay your weight in gold.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Stops and widens her eyes in surprise. She smiles. Cut to a side-shot of
                June walking over to Iroh.</charAction> Make it your
            <charAction>Pokes his stomach.</charAction> weight, and we gotta deal.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Laughs with his hand on his stomach.</charAction> You got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>As she turns back to Nyla.</charAction> Get on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>June takes Katara's necklace from Zuko, and shows it to Nyla. The camera
                shows the surroundings through Nyla's sight. As the shirshu looks around, the
                colored scents of humans are shown. Nyla soon finds Katara's purple scent on the
                necklace, and the threesome head off. The scene changes to an aerial shot of the
                abbey, and cuts to inside Bato's room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">There's something I should tell you kids. I'm expecting a message from your father.
                <charAction>Aang is shown with his eyes closed, excluded from the
                group.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Slightly demanding.</charAction> When?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Any day now. Your father said he'd send a message when they found the rendezvous
            point. If you wait until the message arrives, you can come with me, and see your father
            again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks toward his friends with a sad and worried look.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's been over two years since we've seen Dad. That would be so incredible!
            Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I do really miss him, it would be great to see Dad.
                <charAction>Aang gets up to leave, but no one notices him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">It's been far too long, hasn't it? <charAction>As Aang leaves.</charAction> I'm not
            sure when word will arrive, but when it does-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang closes the door and heads toward the abbey gate. Cut back to inside
                Bato's room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It would be great, but we can't. We have to take Aang to the North Pole
            first.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Even if we do have time to wait for the message, who knows how far we'd have to
            travel. We don't have time for a long detour.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">I'm sure your father would understand, and be proud that his children are helping
            the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to footprints on the beach at night. The camera pans upward
                to reveal Aang sitting on the bow of Bato's boat.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't believe they would leave me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An ostrich horse can be heard coming. A messenger arrives.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Messenger">I'm looking for Bato of the Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uhhh, I know Bato!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Messenger">Make sure he gets this! <charAction>Hands Aang the scroll and rides
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang curiously unravels at the message, finding that it is actually a
                map.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's the map to Sokka and Katara's dad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang's curious look changes to frustration as he crumples the map and
                stuffs it inside his clothes. Shot changes to a further distance of Aang sitting on
                the boat. Cut to an aerial shot of the abbey. Cut to a door which Aang
                opens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey everyone! Sorry I was gone so long.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns to face him.</charAction> Hey, Aang, I didn't notice you
            left.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yup, but now I'm back. <charAction>Sitting down.</charAction> Sure could go for some
            delicious sea prunes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang quickly takes some bites of sea prunes, but chokes them back up, yet
                he pretends to enjoy them. Katara, Bato, and Sokka look at him strangely. The scene
                changes to the herbalist's home that Aang visited to find a cure to Katara and
                Sokka's sickness in the past. Nyla growl can be heard, to which Miyuki hisses. The
                herbalist turns around to find Nyla, June, Zuko, and Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Out for a bit of fresh air, are we?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We're looking for someone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">I hope it's not Miyuki <charAction>To Miyuki.</charAction> Miyuki, did you get in
            trouble with the Fire Nation, again? <charAction>Miyuki meows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">The Avatar's been through here. Let's keep moving.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial shot of the abbey. The shot changes to show Aang
                airbending a pile of hay to Appa. As he finishes his form, the map falls out of his
                sleeve.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">Aha! I caught you. <charAction>Picks up the crumpled paper as Aang looks at her
                nervously.</charAction> You should be ashamed of yourself ... Littering in the
            courtyard.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Takes back the crumpled paper.</charAction> I'm sorry, I'll take care of
            this. <charAction>Bows. As Mother Superior walks away, Aang stuffs the map back up his
                sleeve.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to Bato's ship the next day. Bato, Sokka, Katara, and Aang
                are seen walking toward it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">This ship is sentimental to me. It was built by my father.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks down at the ground, noticing the tracks from the messenger's
                ostrich horse are still visible. He airbends the sand to cover the tracks and
                whistles nonchalantly. Aang walks up to Bato.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Bato.</charAction> Is this the boat he took you ice dodging
            in?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Yep! It's got the scar to prove it. Ha. How 'bout you Sokka? You must have some good
            stories from your first time ice dodging. <charAction>Sokka begins to look
                saddened.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">He never got to go. Dad left before he was old enough.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Oh, I forgot you were too young.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What's ice dodging?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">It's a rite of passage for young Water Tribe members. When you turn fourteen, your
            dad takes you- <charAction>Bato smile and puts his hand on Sokka's shoulder with a new
                thought.</charAction> You know what, you're about to find out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>June, Zuko, and Iroh followed Katara's trail to the Makapu Village. As
                citizens flee from Nyla in terror, he stops in front of Aunt Wu's shop. Wu remains
                outside her shop, completely calm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Why are we stopping?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Because the girl must have spent a lot of time here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We have no time for this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko gets off Nyla and hangs the necklace in front of his face. Nyla
                appears agitated and he snaps at Zuko, who swiftly ducks down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Hey! Watch it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>As Iroh laughs from behind her.</charAction> Oh look, he likes
            you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aunt Wu approaches Iroh, still calm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aunt Wu">Care to hear your fortune, handsome?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">At my age, there's really only one big surprise left, and I'd just as soon leave it
            a mystery.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The threesome leave on Nyla, and the scene cuts back to Bato's ship, which
                is now sailing close to shore.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Ice dodging is a ceremonial test of wisdom, bravery, and trust. <charAction>Shot
                changes to on the boat.</charAction> In our village, ice dodging was done by weaving
            a boat through a field of icebergs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How are we supposed to ice dodge without ice?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">You'll be dodging those. <charAction>Points to a group of tall, sharp, jagged rocks
                near the shore. Katara and Sokka appear nervous.</charAction> Sokka, you steer and
            call the shots, lead wisely. Katara, you secure the main sail. <charAction>Katara grabs
                a rope.</charAction> The winds can be brutal, so be brave. Aang, you control the
            jib. Without your steady hand, we all go down. Your position is about trust.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blinks. Defensively.</charAction> I know that. Why wouldn't I know that?
                <charAction>Folds his arms.</charAction> I'm the Avatar; I know about trust.
                <charAction>He crosses his arms and looks away, but gives Bato a second
                glance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">For this is to be done right, I cannot help. <charAction>Sits cross-legged at the
                front of the boat.</charAction> You pass or fail on your own.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Studies the rocky shores.</charAction> Aang, ease up on the jib. Katara,
            steady. <charAction>Katara looks at the shore with concern.</charAction> Aang, less
            sail. Katara, give him room. <charAction>The ship moves to the side and sails between
                some rocks.</charAction> Aang, helm to lee. Helm to lee!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What does that even mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The waves knock Bato around. Sokka struggles while Katara and Aang close
                their eyes. The shot changes to show the boat pass between more rocks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Great job!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Aang smile. Aerial shot of the boat heading toward a large
                bundle of rocks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">There's no way through!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We can make it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Stands up and grabs the side of the boat.</charAction> Sokka, you've
            already proven yourself. Maybe we should-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, I'm gonna need air in that sail. <charAction>Aang nods.</charAction> Katara, I
            want you to bend as much water as you can between us and those rocks. Now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara bends the water below the boat while Aang fires airbending blasts at
                the sail. Sokka groans nervously as the boat clears the rocks. When they reach clear
                water, Sokka sighs and relaxes. The rest of the group smiles at him. Fade to an
                aerial shot of Bato's boat beached on the shore. Shot changes to Bato carrying a
                small cup of purple paint.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Dips his fingers in the paint.</charAction> The spirits of water bear
            witness to these marks. For Sokka, the Mark of the Wise. <charAction>Uses his thumb to
                put an arc and small dot on Sokka's forehead.</charAction> The same mark your father
            earned. For Katara, <charAction>Uses his thumb to put a crescent moon mark on Katara's
                forehead.</charAction> the Mark of the Brave. Your courage inspires us.
                <charAction>Using his thumb to put an arc on Aang's forehead.</charAction> And for
            Aang, the Mark of the Trusted. You are now an honorary member of the Water
            Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't. <charAction>Looks down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Of course you can!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubbing off his mark and backing away.</charAction> No, you can't trust
            me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Aang, what are you talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Takes the crumpled map out of his sleeve.</charAction> A messenger gave
            this to me for Bato. <charAction>Katara takes it from him.</charAction> You
                have to understand. I was afraid you would-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> This is the map to our father! You had it the
            whole time? How could you? <charAction>Aang shrugs his shoulders.</charAction> Well, you
            can go to the North Pole on your own. I'm going to find Dad. <charAction>Walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">Well, Sokka. I think you should-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Turns back.</charAction> Katara, are you with me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns to look at Aang and closes her eyes.</charAction> I'm with you
            Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sadly looks at Sokka, Katara, and Bato as they walk away. Cut to an
                aerial shot of the abbey. The shot changes to show Bato helping Katara secure her
                pack as Sokka puts on his own pack. Sokka and Bato off camera. Cut to Aang sitting
                on Appa with Momo next to him. Shot changes to show Katara walking in front of the
                camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Good luck.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay. You too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara joins Sokka and Bato at the abbey gate. Mother Superior, in front of
                Appa, stares at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Guess I should be moving on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">That would be best.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa growls. The shot changes to outside the abbey. Appa walks out and Aang
                notices three figures walk away in the distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm an idiot, Momo. <charAction>Momo chitters.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial view of the abbey. The shot cuts to three nuns stirring
                perfume. The sound of rumbling alerts the nuns as they stare in fright as Nyla
                enters the abbey holding June, Iroh, and Zuko. The shot cuts to Nyla's point of
                view, who sees the purple scent and turns his head to follow it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">We're getting close. <charAction>Whips Nyla, who runs out of the abbey and into the
                woods.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a view of the sky amidst some trees and the camera pans down to show
                Bato, Katara, and Sokka walking through the woods. A wolf's howl can be heard in the
                distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> That wolf sounds so sad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's probably wounded.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Turns back to them.</charAction> No, it's been separated from the pack.
            I understand that pain. It's how I felt when the Water Tribe warriors had to leave me
            behind. They were my family, <charAction>Shot of Sokka, who looks sadly at the
                camera.</charAction> and being apart from them was more painful than my
            wounds.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to another one of Sokka's flashbacks. The young Sokka stands at the
                end of an ice pier as eight ships travel away, fading into the fog. Frontal shot of
                the young Sokka fades to Sokka wearing a similar expression from the flashback as he
                stares at the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We need to go back. I wanna see Dad, but, helping Aang is where we're needed the
            most.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> You're right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Walks up to Katara and Sokka and puts his arms on their
                shoulders.</charAction> Your father will understand, and I know he's proud of
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Thanks, Bato.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">I know where to go from here. <charAction>Takes the map from out of his Water Tribe
                outfit.</charAction> Take this in case you want to find us. I'll leave a message at
            the rendezvous point.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans up and cuts to Aang and Momo sitting on Appa with the
                abandoned Water Tribe ship behind them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Looks like we're going alone, guys.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">
         <charAction>Runs on camera. Desperately.</charAction> Avatar, you must
            leave!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Okay, I get it. Everybody wants me gone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">A group of people came to the abbey looking for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Who?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">A fierce looking woman with a horrible monster, and a young man with a
            scar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">The beast was using the scent of a necklace to follow you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">A necklace? <charAction>Gasps.</charAction> Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a long path heading toward the abbey and the camera pans down to two
                figures walking toward the abbey. The shot changes to show Sokka and Katara walking
                down the path. Sokka hears a rumbling noise and puts his hand up to stop his sister
                from walking. Nyla jumps behind them and they both turn around in fear. Nyla looks
                at Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> So this is your girlfriend. <charAction>Zuko jumps
                down.</charAction> No wonder she left, she's way too pretty for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>To Sokka and Katara.</charAction> Where is he? Where is the
            Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We split up. He's long gone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">How stupid do you think I am?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Pretty stupid. <charAction>Grabs his sister.</charAction> Run!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They start running, but Nyla uses his tongue to paralyze
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What are we supposed to do now?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Nyla walks closer to Sokka and Katara.</charAction> It's seeking a
            different scent. Perhaps something that the Avatar held.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Nyla knocks the map off Sokka's pack and smells its blue scent and follows
                the trail. Cut to the gates of the abbey as Nyla breaks them down. Nuns scatter and
                the shot shows Nyla holding June, Iroh, Zuko, Katara, and Sokka. Nyla walks around
                in a circle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What's it doing? It's just going in a circle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shows Nyla's point of view as he follows the blue scent trail up
                into the air and sees Aang flying down. The shot changes to Aang flying over Nyla,
                who stands on his hind legs and attempts to paralyze the Avatar with his tongue,
                throwing off his riders. Nyla falls down, too.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks up.</charAction> Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Up! <charAction>June cracks her whip. Nyla stands up and June mounts
                him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>June and Nyla charge at Aang, but Appa knocks down Nyla by leaping on the
                shirshu's side. Appa growls and snorts at June and Nyla. Cut to Zuko and Aang facing
                each other. In the background, two nuns drag Sokka and Katara to the side of the
                abbey. Shot changes from Zuko to Aang to Zuko. Zuko firebends a blast at Aang, who
                stops it by waving his glider. Aang sends a blast of air at Zuko, who sidesteps it
                and sends a fire blast at Aang, who spins his staff to stop the blast. Aang sends an
                airbending blast at Zuko, who sidesteps it and sends another fire blast at Aang.
                Aang jumps to avoid the blast. Zuko moves in closer to Aang and sends two fire
                blasts at Aang's head and feet. Aang throws his staff and both jump and duck at the
                blasts. Zuko punches and kicks at Aang, sending fire blasts at him. Aang avoids
                these blasts and sends an air blast at Zuko's head. Zuko ducks and sends more fire
                blasts at Aang. Zuko and Aang both firebend and airbend, respectively, at each other
                at the same time, creating large explosion that forms a mushroom cloud. The shot
                changes to show Zuko and Aang fall on different roofs. Cut to Nyla and June lying on
                the ground. Iroh runs up to June and puts his hand on her cheek. June wakes up and
                stands up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Whips Nyla.</charAction> Come on! Get up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Nyla gets up. Shot of Iroh smiling. Cut to Nyla running across the abbey
                with June riding him. Cut to Appa's paw as Nyla lashes his tongue at it. Appa lands
                and falls down, paralyzed. Cut to a shot of June looking at Appa, who opens his eyes
                and slowly gets back up to his feet and growls. Nyla growls back and they charge at
                each other when June cracks her whip. The collision between the two beasts sends
                June flying over Appa, and she takes the opportunity to whip the sky bison. She
                lands on the ground and quickly rolls to the side before Appa stomps on the ground
                behind him where June had landed, cracking the floor.</description>
      <description>Cut to Aang on the roof as he lifts his head and groans and gasps. Cut to
                Zuko running across the roof and sending a fire blast at the camera. Aang jumps into
                the air. Zuko sends a fire blast at Aang's feet. Aang jumps up and sends an
                airbending blast at Zuko. When Aang lands, Zuko sends a fire blast at him. Aang uses
                an air shield to stop it. Aang gets up and sends a stream of air at Zuko, sending
                him to an abbey corner tower. Aang runs toward Zuko and attacks him with an air
                blast. Zuko jumps off the roof and Nyla jumps on. As Aang runs away from the
                shirshu, Appa uses his tail to send an airbending blast at the roof. Cut to Sokka
                and Katara sitting by a wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm ... starting to get some feeling back! <charAction>Rubble from the roof falls on
                him.</charAction> Ow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang jumping in the abbey courtyard stream and Nyla follows him. Cut
                to June and Nyla on the roof. They run to the side as a part of the abbey roof
                explodes. The dust clears to show Appa. Cut to Iroh examining some perfume bottles.
                He sniffs one and sneaks it into his sleeves. Cut to Aang standing by a well. Zuko
                sends him three firebending blasts. Aang jumps to the other side of the well to
                dodge them. Zuko sends another fire blast at him. Aang ducks and notices Zuko is
                carrying Katara's necklace.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You've got something I want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang jumps between the four beams of the well. He dodges Zuko's fire blasts
                by moving on all sides of the well. Zuko breaks two of the well's beams and sends
                the wooden structure away. Zuko jumps on the well's circular stone structure to join
                Aang. Zuko sends two fire blasts at Aang, who dodges them by stepping around the
                well. Aang sends two air blasts at Zuko. The shot focuses on well as the two
                opponents walk on top of the well. Aang snatches at Katara's stole necklace, but
                misses. Zuko lunges at Aang, who jumps onto his back. Cut to a shot of Aang flying
                through the air as he grabs Katara's necklace off his foot. Aang lands in the well.
                Zuko sends a fire blast down the well. The water from the well rises out and sends
                Zuko flying. Aang jumps out with the water, which rains a little before Zuko falls
                down. Zuko stands up.</description>
      <description>Cut to Appa, who walks toward Zuko. Nyla's tongue lashes out at Appa from
                off-camera. Appa growls and the shot changes to show June riding Nyla. June cracks
                her whip and Nyla's tongue lashes out at Appa again. Appa falls down and Nyla looks
                toward Sokka and Katara. Mother Superior makes both of them smell a vial of
                perfume.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That thing sees with its nose. Let's give him something to look at.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mother Superior">The perfume?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka nods. Cut to four pots of perfume. The nuns and Sokka push the pots.
                Cut to Nyla and Zuko cornering Aang. Zuko attacks Aang with a two fire blasts. Sokka
                and the nuns pour the perfume pots onto the ground. Katara waterbends the perfume
                into the air and pours it on Nyla. The shot changes to show Nyla's point of view as
                the perfume scents cloud his vision of Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Nyla paralyzes Zuko as Iroh looks at Nyla in concern.</charAction> June!
            No! <charAction>Nyla tongue lashes out and hits June, who falls back into Iroh's
                arms.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Nyla running around in a circle and bumps into more perfume
                pots. Nyla jumps over the abbey wall. Shot cuts to Aang picking up his staff and
                wiping his brow. Katara and Sokka stand next to Aang and smile at him. Cut to Zuko
                and Iroh lying down on the ground. Iroh cradles June in one hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle? I didn't see you get hit with the tongue.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Shhh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh goes back to his position, smiling. June opens her eyes angrily upon
                learning this.</description>
      <description>Cut to Appa flying with Team Avatar on his back. Cut to a closer shot of
                Sokka and Katara as Aang steers the bison.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So ... where do we go?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're getting you to the North Pole.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, we've lost too much time as it is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turns to the group.</charAction> Don't you want to see your
            father?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Of course we do, Aang. But, you're our family, too. And right now, you need us
            more.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">And we need you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I wish I could give you a little piece of home, Katara. Something to remind you
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'll be okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Still, just a little trinket. Maybe something like ... <charAction>Holds up Katara's
                necklace.</charAction> this? <charAction>Closer shot of the
            necklace.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Takes the necklace.</charAction> Aang, how'd you get that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Zuko asked me to be sure I got it to you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aw, that's so sweet of Zuko. Could you give him a kiss for me when you see
            him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara kisses Aang on the cheek and Aang blushes and twiddles his thumbs.
                Further shot of Appa flying toward the horizon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
