<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="29">Bitter Work</title>
      <director>Ethan Spaulding</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2006-06-02</date>
      <location nation="earth">Quarry Campsite</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens in a mountainous terrain at sunrise as it pans down and
                to the right. All of Team Avatar is sleeping. Cut to Aang rising and jumping up with
                airbending, barefoot, and filled with excitement.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Today's the day! <charAction>Lands near a sleeping Sokka.</charAction> Can you
            believe it? After all that time searching for a teacher, I'm finally starting
            earthbending! <charAction>Momo chitters and lands on Sokka.</charAction> And this place,
                <charAction>Momo moves on to Appa's head.</charAction> it's perfect, don't you
            think? Sokka? <charAction>Sokka grumbles and glares at Aang with tired
                eyes.</charAction> Oh, you're still sleeping, huh? <charAction>Sokka again grumbles
                and puts his head back down. Aang whispers.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The ground shakes, causing Aang to turn to look toward the source of the
                rumbling. The camera quickly pans to the left to an earth tent, the slabs of which
                are tossed in every direction mere moments after. As the dust clears, Toph is
                standing in the middle with her left hand raised in the air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Goooood morning, <charAction>She puts both her hands on her hips.</charAction>
            earthbending student!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the side-shot of Appa, with Momo on his head, Sokka, still sleeping
                and curled up within his sleeping bag with Aang standing at his feet, and Katara,
                who is sitting upright in her own sleeping bag. Toph walks over to
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good morning, Sifu Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Aang bows slightly to Toph; disappointed and tiredly.</charAction> Hey,
            you never called me Sifu Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Scratches the back of his head.</charAction> Well, if you think I should
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka suddenly sits up, grumbling at Aang. Cut to a closer shot of Aang,
                who looks down in wonder, and Toph, who has a smile on her face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Sorry, Snoozles, we'll do our earthbending as <charAction>Whispers slightly, though
                with amusement in her voice.</charAction> quietly as we can.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Toph's feet as she slams her left heel into the
                ground, creating a crack. Cut to a side-shot of Sokka, who had laid himself back
                down. An earth pillar rises up right underneath him, catapulting him screaming into
                the air. Cut to an aerial shot of the team's camping spot as Sokka flies directly
                toward the camera. After he has flown so close to the camera that the shot was
                nothing more than a close-up of this uvula, the scene cuts back to ground level of
                the campsite, where Katara is standing up and joins Toph and Aang in looking toward
                the sky. Sokka crashes to the ground in their middle with a loud thud. He
                immediately jumps to his feet, still in his sleeping bag with only his head visible,
                and hops toward Aang while grumbling. He stops in front of the Avatar and grumbles
                to his face, before jumping toward Toph and doing the same to her. He subsequently
                hops toward the camera and out of the shot, still grumbling angrily. Everyone else
                turns to watch him go.</description>
      <description>Cut to Toph staring after Sokka with her hands to her sides. Aang had
                jumped up and now softly lands beside her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> So what move are you going to teach me first?
                <charAction>Stretches out his right arm, his fist clenched, and brings it down like
                a hammer.</charAction> Rock-a-lanche? <charAction>He brings his left clenched fist
                to his right elbow, while his right arm is bent upward, the fist also clenched. He
                trembles with the motion.</charAction> The Trembler? Oh, maybe I could learn to make
            a <charAction>Stretches both arms over his head and starts to spin around.</charAction>
            whirlpool out of land!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Puts a hand on Aang's chest.</charAction> Let's start with ...
                <charAction>Makes the gesture.</charAction> move a rock.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Claps excitedly.</charAction> Sounds good, sounds good!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to another part of the canyon where Toph and Aang are standing in
                front of two rocks as Katara watches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">The key to earthbending is your stance. You've got to be steady and strong. Rock is
            a stubborn element. If you're going to move it, you've got to be like a rock
            yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Like a rock. Got it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Good. Now the actual motion of this one is pretty simple. <charAction>Slams the rock
                against the canyon wall.</charAction> Okay, you ready to give it a try?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm ready. <charAction>Tries to move it, but instead he is forced backward into
                Appa.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Amused.</charAction> Rock beats airbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh has a flashback in a dream about Lu Ten. Lu Ten pretends to firebend
                at Iroh who fakes a groan and falls over.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lu Ten">I got you, Dad! <charAction>Playfully jumps on top of Iroh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Both laugh as the scene fades to Iroh in a dream sitting over Lu Ten's
                tomb.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">My beloved Lu Ten, I will see you again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades again as Iroh wakes up to Zuko calling him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle ... you were unconscious. Azula did this to you. It was a surprise
            attack.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Somehow, that's not so surprising. <charAction>Groans.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Hands Iroh some tea.</charAction> I hope I made it the way you like it.
                <charAction>Iroh takes a sip from the cup and his eyes widen. He lets out a cry of
                disgust, but manages to mask it.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Grimaces.</charAction> Good. That was very ... uhhh ... bracing.
                <charAction>He is handed another cup, which he throws out secretly behind his
                shoulder.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">So Uncle, I've been thinking. It's only a matter of time before I run into Azula
            again. I'm going to need to know more advanced firebending if I want to stand a chance
            against her. I know what you're going to say: she's my sister and I should be trying to
            get along with her.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>With the exact opposite of Zuko's thoughts.</charAction> No, she's
            crazy, and she needs to go down. <charAction>Zuko nods. Iroh grunts as he stands
                up.</charAction> It's time to resume your training.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the canyon. Katara and Toph are standing next to the boulder Aang
                tried to move. Aang walks up, a hand behind his head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't understand what went wrong. He did it exactly the way you did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Maybe there's another way ... what if I came at the boulder from another
            angle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">No. That's the problem. You've got to stop thinking like an airbender. There's no
            different angle, no clever solution, no trickety-trick that's going to move that rock.
            You've got to face it head on. And when I say head on, I mean like this ...
                <charAction>Jumps up and destroys the rock with her head.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Whoa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph begins to walk away, but Katara stops her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Trying to help Toph teach.</charAction> I've been training Aang for a
            while now. He really responds well to a positive teaching experience. Lots of
            encouragement and praise. Kind words. If he's doing something wrong, maybe a gentle
            nudge in the right direction.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Thanks, Katara. A gentle nudge. I'll try that. <charAction>Moments later; yelling at
                the top of her lungs.</charAction> Keep your knees high, Twinkle Toes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang carrying a large rock on his back, struggling to hold it up.
                The camera zooms out, showing Toph in the background stomping down and causing
                pillars of rock to rise underneath Aang's feet as he walks. Aang loses his balance
                and falls off-screen.</description>
      <description>The next move shows Toph digging through rock with her fingers. The camera
                pans over and Aang rubs his hands together and tries to do the same thing, but
                smashes his hand against the rock and grunts in pain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Rock-like!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Next, Toph gives Aang one of Sokka's weapons, much to Sokka's dismay. Cut
                to Sokka's face with Toph's hand holding him back. He grunts, trying to move
                forward. Cut to a side-view, showing Sokka struggling to get his club back from
                Toph, who is holding it to the side and preventing Sokka from grabbing it. She
                shoves him backward and he stalks offscreen. She hands the weapon to Aang. He is
                blindfolded as he tries to smash rocks Toph brings up. He finally gets one after
                about five times. Cut to Toph, who nods in approval.</description>
      <description>During their next session, Toph builds herself into a shield of rock which
                Aang has to push back over a marked boundary. He is successful. His training begins
                to move smoothly.</description>
      <description>During another training session Aang is standing on two pillars of earth
                tossing a rock into the air while switching hands to catch it each time. Toph walks
                between the two pillars of earth and uses earthbending to shake the
                pillars.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Rock-like!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans up to reveal Aang holding a solid stance without losing his
                balance. Toph appears on a pillar near him and nods. Aang smiles, knowing he is
                finally getting the hang of it.</description>
      <description>In another part of the canyon, Sokka is looking for food when he stumbles
                upon an animal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You're awfully cute, but unfortunately you're made of meat. Just a bit closer ...
                <charAction>Jumps but falls into a crack that is in the ground. He looks at the
                cub.</charAction> Gotcha! <charAction>Sinks further in.</charAction> You are one
            lucky little meat creature.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at Iroh and Zuko's setup.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Lightning is a pure form of firebending, without aggression. It is not fueled by
            rage or emotion the way other firebending is. Some call lightning the cold-blooded fire.
            It is precise and deadly, like Azula. To perform the technique requires peace of
            mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I see. That's why we're drinking tea, to calm the mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Oh yeah, good point! I mean, yes. <charAction>Outside.</charAction> There is energy
            all around us. The energy is both yin and yang. Positive energy and negative energy.
            Only a select few firebenders can separate these energies. This creates an imbalance.
            The energy wants to restore balance, and in a moment the positive and negative energy
            come crashing back together, you provide release and guidance, creating lightning.
                <charAction>Steps up, and generates lightning, and shoots it away from the
                two.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm ready to try it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Remember, once you separate the energy, you do not command it. You are simply its
            humble guide. Breathe first.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko takes a deep breath. He tries to generate lightning, but instead an
                explosion launches him back. Iroh shakes his head in disappointment. </description>
      <description>Back at the canyon, Aang's earthbending training continues.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">This time we're going to try something a little different. Instead of moving a rock,
            you're going to stop a rock. Get in your horse stance! I'm going to roll that boulder
            down at you. If you have the attitude of an earthbender, you'll stay in your stance and
            stop the rock. Like this! <charAction>Stretches out, still in
            stance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sorry Toph, but are you really sure this is the way to teach Aang
            earthbending?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I'm glad you said something. Actually there is a better way. <charAction>Blindfolds
                Aang.</charAction> This way, you'll actually have to sense the vibrations of the
            boulder to stop it. Thank you, Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, thanks, Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Heh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Toph standing at the top of the hill with Aang at the bottom. She
                shoves the rock forward and it begins to roll down the slope. Aang looks worried and
                afraid as it rolls toward him. He jumps over the boulder at the last second, causing
                it to roll past and crash into the cliff. Toph comes running toward
                Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess I just panicked. I don't know what to say.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">There's nothing to say, you blew it! You had a perfect stance, and a perfect form.
            But when it came right down to it, you didn't have the guts!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> I know. I'm sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, you are sorry! If you're not tough enough to stop
            the rock, then you can at least give it the pleasure of smashing you instead of jumping
            out of the way like a jelly-boned wimp! Now, do you have what it takes to face that rock
            like an earthbender?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I don't think I do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, it's no big deal. You'll take a break and try earthbending again when you're
            ready. Besides, you still have a lot of waterbending to work on. Okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, that sounds good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, whatever, go splash around until you feel better.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all exit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to Zuko and Iroh. Another attempt by Zuko to generate lightning
                fails.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Why can't I do it? Instead of lightning it keeps exploding in my face ... like
            everything always does.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I was afraid this might happen. You will not be able to master lightning until you
            have dealt with the turmoil inside you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What turmoil?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko, you must let go of your feelings of shame if you want your anger to go
            away.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But I don't feel any shame at all. I'm as proud as ever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Prince Zuko, pride is not the opposite of shame, but its source. True humility is
            the only antidote to shame.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Well, my life has been nothing but humbling lately.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I have another idea. I will teach you a firebending move that even Azula doesn't
            know, because I made it up myself. <charAction>Zuko smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to Sokka, who remains trapped with the small, brown
                animal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You probably think I deserve this, don't you? Look, I'm sorry I hunted you, but
            that's just the natural order of things. Big things eat smaller things, nothing
            personal. But this time it didn't work out that way. I admit it ... you're cute. Okay,
            you convinced me, if I get out of this alive, it's a karmically correct, vegetarian
            existence for me. No meat. Even though meat is so tasty. <charAction>The cub brings an
                apple.</charAction> Hey, looks like my karma is already paying off! That's okay, I
            got it. <charAction>Tosses his boomerang at it in a desperate attempt.</charAction> Now,
            come back boomerang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In a pond in another part of the canyon. Momo tries to grab a frog. Aang
                and Katara move a single blob of water back and forth among each other in a circular
                motion.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You know this block you're having is only temporary, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't want to talk about it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You do realize that's the problem, don't you? If you face this issue instead of
            avoiding it–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frustrated at himself.</charAction> I know, I know, I know, I know! I
            get it, all right? I need to face it head on like a rock, but I just can't do it. I
            don't know why I can't, but I can't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, if fire and water are opposites, then what's the opposite of air?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess it's earth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's why it's so difficult for you to get this. You're working with your natural
            opposite. But you'll figure it out. I know you will. Think fast! <charAction>Throws a
                piece of reed at him, but Aang slices it in half with waterbending.</charAction>
            Excellent. You have the reflexes of a waterbending master.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks, Katara. Sifu Katara.
                <charAction>Bows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara also bows at Aang. Back to Zuko and Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Fire is the element of power. <charAction>Draws the firebending insignia in the
                dirt.</charAction> The people of the Fire Nation have desire and will, and the
            energy to drive and achieve what they want. Earth is the element of substance.
                <charAction>Draws the earthbending insignia.</charAction> The people of the Earth
            Kingdom are diverse and strong. They are persistent and enduring. Air is the element of
            freedom. <charAction>Draws the airbending insignia.</charAction> The Air Nomads detached
            themselves from worldly concerns and found peace and freedom. Also, they apparently had
            pretty good senses of humor! <charAction>Smiles broadly but returns to a more serious
                demeanor when Zuko doesn't react at all.</charAction> Water is the element of
            change. <charAction>Draws the waterbending insignia.</charAction> The people of the
            Water Tribe are capable of adapting to many things. They have a deep sense of community
            and love that holds them together through anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Why are you telling me these things?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It is important to draw wisdom from many different places. If you take it from only
            one place, it becomes rigid and stale. <charAction>Divides the four insignias into
                separate sections.</charAction> Understanding others, the other elements, and the
            other nations will help you become whole. <charAction>Draws a circle around the
                insignias.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">All this four elements talk is sounding like Avatar stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It is the combination of the four elements in one person that makes the Avatar so
            powerful. But it can make you more powerful, too. You see the technique I'm about to
            teach you is one I learned by studying the waterbenders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the campsite. Aang is meditating when Toph enters, holding Aang's
                staff.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Aang, I found these nuts in your bag. I figured you wouldn't mind. And besides, even
            if you did, you're too much of a pushover to do anything about it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">As a matter of fact, I don't mind. I'm happy to share anything I have.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You know, I'm really glad you feel that way. Because I also have this great new
            nutcracker.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She spins Aang's staff above her head. Cut to Aang, who looks over his
                shoulder with a pained expression on his face. Cut to Toph as she smiles widely,
                lifts the staff, and starts using it to break nutshells.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Actually, I prefer if you didn't ... <charAction>Crack.</charAction> That's an
            antique, handcrafted by the monks ... <charAction>Crack.</charAction> It's a delicate
            instrument!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">It's not the only delicate instrument around here. <charAction>Walks away, hitting
                the staff off rocks.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Resumes meditating.</charAction> Ohm.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hey Aang, have you seen–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frustrated.</charAction> Meditating here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's important. It's almost sundown and Sokka isn't back yet. I think we should
            search for him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We'll find him faster if we split up. <charAction>The two begin to
                search.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay, karma person or thing, whoever's in charge of this stuff. If I can just get
            out of this situation alive, I will give up meat and sarcasm. Okay? <charAction>Sokka's
                warrior's wolf tail gets yanked out of his hair by the cub.</charAction> Ow! That's
            all I got. It's pretty much my whole identity. Sokka, the meat and sarcasm guy. But I'm
            willing to be Sokka, the veggies and straight talk fellow. Deal? <charAction>Aang shows
                up.</charAction> Aang! Thank goodness! Have you got any meat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka! Are you okay? <charAction>Tries to pull him out.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aggh, stop, stop! You're going to pull my fingers off and I don't think the rest of
            me is coming!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hmmm ... I bet I can airbend you out of here. <charAction>Blows up a gust of wind
                but Sokka remains trapped.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Seriously Aang, I know you're new at it, but I could use a little earthbending here.
            How about it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't ... I can't do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, if you can't earthbend me out of here, go get Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't do that either.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You can't? Why not?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It would just be really ... uncomfortable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Uncomfortable? <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Well, I wouldn't want you to
            feel uncomfortable ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks, Sokka. This whole earthbending thing really has me confused. There's so much
            pressure. Everyone expects me to get it right away. It puts me in a really awkward
            position.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Awkward position, I think I know the feeling.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">If I try, I fail. If I don't try, I'm never going to get it. I feel like I'm caught
            between a rock and a hard place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hmmm ... how about that. Aang, this is my friend, Foo Foo Cuddlypoops. Foo Foo
            Cuddlypoops, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Awww, what a cute name for a baby saber-tooth moose-lion cub.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Really? He looks nothing like a saber-tooth moose-lion.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's hard to tell before their giant teeth and horns grow in. What are you doing out
            here little guy? Did you lose your mama?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, a large moose-lion appears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts back to Zuko and Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Waterbenders deal with the flow of energy. A waterbender lets their defense become
            their offense, turning their opponents' energy against them. I learned a way to do this
            with lightning.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You can teach me to redirect lightning?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">If you let the energy in your own body flow, the lightning will follow it. You must
            create a pathway from your fingertips, up your arm to your shoulder, then down into your
            stomach. The stomach is the source of energy in your body. It is called the sea of chi.
            Only in my case it is more like a vast ocean. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> From the
            stomach, you direct it up again, and out the other arm. The stomach detour is critical.
            You must not let the lightning pass through your heart, or the damage could be deadly.
            You may wish to try a physical motion, to get a feel for the pathways' flow, like this.
                <charAction>The two begin to practice the redirection motion.</charAction> Now, are
            you focusing your energy? Can you feel your own chi flowing in, down, up, and
            out?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I think so.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Come on, you've got to feel the flow. <charAction>They practice the motion for a few
                minutes.</charAction> Excellent! You've got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Great, I'm ready to try it with real lightning!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">What, are you crazy? Lightning is very dangerous!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I thought that was the point! You teaching me to protect myself from it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yeah! But I'm not going to shoot lightning at you! If you're lucky, you will never
            have to use this technique at all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Well, if you won't help me, I'll find my own lightning. <charAction>Rides
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the canyon, Aang begins to talk to the saber-tooth moose-lion
                mother.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey there, we found your cub! See, we have no problem with you! We're
            friendly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, this is bad, you've got to get me out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The moose-lion charges at Sokka, but Aang sends it over his head with
                airbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This is really bad! Please Aang, you have to earthbend me out, there's no other
            way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang tries, but all his attempts produce nothing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh no! <charAction>Gets on top of a rock to try and distract the saber-tooth
                moose-lion.</charAction> Woo-hoo, look at me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The moose-lion charges again but is again held off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Please, don't leave me again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I won't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He stands his ground, and at the last second, throws the moose-lion back
                with a blast of air. The beast leaves. Suddenly, slight clapping can be heard. Cut
                to shot of Toph sitting on a rock nearby.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What are you doing here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Just enjoying the show.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What? You were there the whole time?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Pretty much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Why didn't you do something? Sokka was in trouble! I was in trouble! You could have
            gotten him out and helped us get away!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Guess it just didn't occur to me. <charAction>Throws a nut down and attempts to
                crack it with the staff.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Grabs hold of it.</charAction> Enough! I want my staff back!
                <charAction>Takes it away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Do it now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Earthbend, Twinkle Toes. You just stood your ground against a crazy beast. And even
            more impressive, you stood your ground against me. You've got stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Do it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang slams the ground and sends a rock into the canyon wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You did it! You're an earthbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't believe it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Awww, this is a really wonderful, touching
            moment. So could you get me out of here so I can give you both a big, snuggly
            hug?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No problem, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Actually, you should probably let me do that. You're still a little new to this. You
            might accidentally crush him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, no crushing, please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph kicks up the rock and yanks him out. Nightfall hits. Katara meets up
                with them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You found him! <charAction>Embraces Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">The whole time, I was in that hole, not knowing if I was going to live or die. It
            makes a man to think about what's really important. I realized–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Interrupting Sokka.</charAction> Hey Katara, look what I can do!
                <charAction>Bends a rock and slams it on the ground.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You did it! I knew you would! <charAction>Whispering to Toph.</charAction> You tried
            the positive reinforcement, didn't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Yep, it worked wonders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa, Appa, I can earthbend now! The key is being completely rooted. Physically and
            mentally unmovable!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa licks him and sends him flying a few feet. Sokka laughs hysterically,
                and Aang laughs as well. Meanwhile, Zuko has tracked down a storm, seeking
                lightning.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You've always thrown everything you could at me! Well, I can take it, and now I can
            give it back! <charAction>Yelling as loud as he can at the storm.</charAction> Come on,
            strike me! You've never held back before!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>No lightning strikes. Tears stream down Zuko's cheeks, and he yells at the
                top of his lungs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
