<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="23">Return to Omashu</title>
      <director>Ethan Spaulding</director>
      <writer>Elizabeth Welch Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2006-04-07</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to a bright, blue sky, the sun shining. The camera zooms
                out quickly to reveal a red Fire Nation flag waving in the wind. Cuts to shot of the
                Earth Kingdom city of Omashu having been captured by the Fire Nation. A bold red
                flag bearing the Fire Nation insignia is proudly hung; gray plumes of smoke fill the
                air surrounding the fallen city.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Viewing the city, his back to the camera; in a somewhat shocked
                tone.</charAction> I can't believe it. I know the War has spread far,
                <charAction>Turning toward the camera sadly.</charAction> but Omashu always seemed
            ... untouchable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Up until now it was. <charAction>Crosses arms over chest.</charAction> Now Ba Sing
            Se is the only great Earth Kingdom stronghold left.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of entire group standing on the cliffside overlooking the
                city.</charAction> This is horrible, <charAction>Approaches Aang; cuts to side-view
                of the two standing next to each other.</charAction> but we have to move
            on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I'm going in to find Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, stop. We don't even know if Bumi's still ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What? If he's still what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Unsurely.</charAction> A-around.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know you had your heart set on Bumi, but there are other people who can teach you
            earthbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This isn't about finding a teacher. This is about finding my friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to below Omashu's gate where Aang is attempting to open the
                entrance to a secret tunnel.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">A secret passage? Why didn't we just use this last time?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang opens the tunnel, revealing it to be filled with sewage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That answer your question?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Eww!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The group proceeds through the tunnel to the inside of Omashu. Aang
                conjures an air ball with his staff to clear the path while Katara uses waterbending
                to maneuver the sewage carefully around her. Sokka, on the other hand, is
                continually soaked in the foul substance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That wasn't as bad as I thought.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka emerges covered in slime. Katara spots water nearby and splashes
                Sokka with it using waterbending to wash off the sewage followed by Aang who uses
                airbending to dry him off while he screams which reveals that three pentapi have
                attached themselves to his skin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In a panicking tone while trying to yank the pentapox off.</charAction>
            Ahh! They won't let go! Help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Quickly tackles Sokka into a wall in order to slience him; in a somewhat
                cheerful tone.</charAction> Shh! Stop making so much noise. It's just a purple
            pentapus.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka looks at the pentapuses in fear. Aang removes the first pentapus by
                lightly rubbing its head as Sokka watches. Sokka rubs the spot where the creature
                was attached, and does the same procedure to get the second one off. Several guards
                suddenly approach them as Aang takes the third one off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard one">Hey! What are you kids doing out past curfew?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sorry. We were just on our way home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The kids turn and walk away, Sokka bringing up the rear. The guard notices
                the red welts on the back of Sokka's neck.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard one">
         <charAction>Notices the spots where the pentapus was attached to Sokka.</charAction>
            Wait, what's the matter with him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Uh, he has pentapox, sir. <charAction>As he approaches.</charAction> Umm, it's
            highly contagious.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Exaggerating.</charAction> Oh, it's so awful. I'm dying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">And deadly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard two">Hey, I think I heard of pentapox! Didn't your cousin Chang die of it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard one">We'd better go wash our hands, and burn our clothes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guards run away in fear.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thank you, sewer friends.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switches to on board Azula's ship. She is consulting her assistants,
                Li and Lo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Li">When tracking your brother and uncle, traveling with the royal procession may no
            longer be an option.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lo">May no longer be wise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lo and Li">If you hope to keep the element of surprise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You're right. The Royal Procession is dead weight. If I want to catch my prey, I
            must be agile, nimble. I need a small, elite team. It's time to visit some old
            friends.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switches to Omashu by twilight, where Aang, Katara and Sokka with
                Momo on his shoulder are sneaking around. They hide behind some metal bars used for
                construction as a patrol passes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Let's find Bumi and get out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Where would they be keeping him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Somewhere he can't earthbend. Somewhere made of metal.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The foursome goes on. The picture switches to a close-up of a young woman
                with black hair and an emotionless expression named Mai. Behind her walk two Fire
                Nation guards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">There really is no fathoming the depths of my hatred for this place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider shot to show Mai walking next to an older woman carrying a
                baby. They are being escorted by Fire Nation guards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Michi">Mai, your father was appointed governor. We're like royalty here. Be happy and enjoy
            it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The picture widens as the camera zooms up to show some rocks, ready to be
                pushed down one of Omashu's mail delivery chutes which ends near where Mai's party
                is walking. You can clearly see the light of the torches from up
                above.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Resistance fighter">The targets are approaching.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of a bearded man wearing an Earth Kingdom military
                uniform.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">Take them out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Mai's party walking down below.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>In a dull tone.</charAction> I thought my life was boring in the Fire
            Nation, but this place is unbearably bleak. Nothing ever happens.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the resistance fighter at the beginning of the chute, who pushes the
                rocks down the chute with earthbending. Aang and his friends walk by and they see
                the rocks crumbling down at high speed. Aang looks in distress at Mai's party. He
                raises his staff and pulverizes the rock with a blast of air as it passes. Mai's
                party is alerted by the sound and looks up to see what caused it. Close-up of Mai
                who squints her eyes to make out who is standing above her before the picture shows
                Aang again. Cut back to the party.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Michi">
         <charAction>Pointing at Aang.</charAction> The resistance!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Mai, who is seen for the first time with a faint smile on her
                face. She spreads her arms at Aang, causing tiny arrows to fly toward him. Aang
                quickly jumps up, avoiding the arrows which bury themselves in the stack of
                construction material Aang lands on. Aang, Katara, Sokka and Momo run away as two of
                the Fire Nation guards are climbing up ladders to get to them.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Katara quickly turns around and uses the water from her pouch to form a
                    water whip and send the two guards flying off into the deep. As you see them
                    falling, we see Mai reaching the top. While she is running toward Katara, she
                    stretches out her right hand, shooting off some more arrows. Katara raises a
                    shield of ice to protect herself as the arrows embed themselves in it. Mai keeps
                    charging Katara, who runs away. Mai jumps over the icy wall in hot pursuit of
                    Katara. Aang awaits Katara and lets her pass as he awaits the arrival of Mai.
                    With a spinning sweep of wind, he causes some of the construction scaffolding to
                    collapse. Mai sees the scaffolding collapse and directs a throwing star right at
                    Aang. He twirls his staff in front of him and catches the flying star with it.
                    Mai stands on one side of the collapsed scaffolding and has a clear shot on
                    Aang, Katara, Sokka and Momo. As she throws more arrows at them, the ground
                    beneath the team opens up, making them disappear and rapidly closes again. Mai
                    looks at the place where her targets disappeared, letting out a deep sigh. She
                    turns around and walks away.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to a tunnel scene. The image shows the rectangle where the kids
                    fell through. Green sewage waste drips from the ceiling. The camera moves down,
                    revealing a group of people who are looking at the three kids. Aang and Sokka
                    are rubbing their heads, while Katara just sits there a bit disorientated. Cut
                    to a shot of Yung, flanked by two other men.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>The picture switches to an upside down shot of some grass. When the
                    view pans up, we see mountains, circus tents and some people working in the
                    background. Azula, also upside down, walks in.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Ty Lee, could that possibly be you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves to show a close-up of a girl, Ty Lee, standing on her
                index fingers. She smiles when she sees Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Azula!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ty Lee flips from her stance and spins around in a graceful twirl to bow
                down before Azula. She runs forward to embrace Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">It is so good to see you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Please, don't let me interrupt your ... <charAction>Raises an eyebrow in
                wonder.</charAction> whatever it is you were doing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ty Lee, still smiling, does a back flip and ends up lying on her chest with
                one leg stretched out over her head and the other straight up to the
                sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Glances around.</charAction> Tell me, what is the daughter of a nobleman
            doing here? <charAction>Looks back at Ty Lee.</charAction> Certainly our parents didn't
            send us to the Royal Fire Academy for Girls to end up in ... <charAction>Looks to her
                side.</charAction> places like this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula looks as three men are trying to move a platypus bear. The Bear
                groans and moves up to reveal that it has laid an egg. Azula looks at this in
                disgust and turns her attention back to Ty Lee, grinning once more.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I have a proposition for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Ty Lee who is still lying on the ground, watching the same Platypus
                bear as Azula, but she looks happy to see what has happened. When Azula addresses
                her, she diverts her attention away from the bear and looks at Azula in a wondering
                gaze.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I'm hunting a traitor. <charAction>While looking casually at her nails.</charAction>
            You remember my old fuddy-duddy uncle, don't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Resting on her chest and elbows, but now with her both feet resting on
                her head.</charAction> Oh yeah. He was so funny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I would be honored if you would join me on my mission.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Oh ... I ... uh ... would love to. <charAction>She stands up in a fluid elegant
                movement.</charAction> But the truth is, I'm really happy here. <charAction>Smiling
                sincerely.</charAction> I mean, my aura has never been pinker!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Raising up her hand in a "stop" motion to Ty Lee.</charAction> I'll take
            your word for it. Well, I wouldn't want you to give up the life you love just to please
            me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Bows in respect.</charAction> Thank you, Azula. <charAction>Continues
                stretching.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>While walking away.</charAction> Of course, before I leave, I'm going to
            catch your show.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ty Lee's accidentally breaks her stance, as she gasps in panic. She
                continues her stretch once more and the expression of panic changes to one of
                worry.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Hesitantly.</charAction> Uh ... yeah ... sure ... uh ... of course
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Omashu, where a lot of people have gathered in some sort of
                underground cave. At the other side of the room, Aang, Sokka, and Katara enter the
                large space through a tunnel; they are talking to three other men.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, is King Bumi with you guys? Is he leading the resistance?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Yung who angrily balls his fist as he answers Aang's
                question.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">Of course not! The day of the invasion, we readied ourselves for battle. We were
            prepared to defend our city ... to fight for our lives and for our freedom. But before
            we even had a chance, King Bumi surrendered.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves slowly toward Aang, who is clearly disconcerted by the
                news. Katara gives Aang a look of concern.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">The day of the invasion, I asked King Bumi what he wanted to do. <charAction>Cut to
                his close-up.</charAction> He looked me in the eye and said ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A flashback shows the day Omashu was under attack. King Bumi and Yung stand
                atop one of the city's walls, looking down while fire balls decorate the
                sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">I'm going to do ... nothing! <charAction>He starts to laugh and snort like the mad
                lunatic he is.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The flashback fades away to make room for another close-up of
                Yung.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">It doesn't matter now. <charAction>Cut to Aang who sadly lowers his eyes as the
                resistance leader continues.</charAction> Fighting the Fire Nation is the only path
            to freedom. <charAction>Switch to a close-up of Yung again.</charAction> And freedom is
            worth dying for.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Yung ends his speech, a smile plays on his face. Aang sadly leans on his
                staff. He raises his eyes as while he addresses Yung.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Actually there's another path to freedom. You could leave Omashu. You're directing
            all your energy to fight the Fire Nation. <charAction>The camera pans to the right,
                showing several Earth Kingdom soldiers.</charAction> But you're outnumbered. You
            can't win. Now's the time to retreat, so you can live to fight another day.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">You don't understand. They've taken our home, and we have to fight them at any cost!
                <charAction>He makes some powerful hand gestures to make his point more
                clear.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Resistance fighter #1">
         <charAction>In a soft tone.</charAction> I don't know, Yung, living to fight another
            day is startin' to sound pretty good to me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Resistance fighter #2">
         <charAction>He takes a step forward and points toward himself. He addresses Yung
                with a decisive tone.</charAction> Yeah, I'm with the kid!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yung looks at all the people who have taken refuge under ground and now are
                living in the sewer tunnels while they whisper among themselves. He looks back at
                Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">Fine. But there's thousands of citizens that need to leave. How're we going to get
            them all out?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to Sokka whose hand is on his chin as he is cooking up a plan. He
                points at Yung as he exclaims his idea.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Suckers!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara raises one eyebrow and just stares at Sokka. The rest of the group
                follows her example. Momo chirps questionably. Sokka blinks, shifting his eyes right
                and left, smiling broadly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You're all about to come down with a nasty case of pentapox.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a bucket of water filled with pentapi. A hand reaches in
                and takes one out. The civilian, whose face is already covered with the marks of
                removed pentapi, places it on his exposed left arm. Its jellylike body moves up and
                down a bit. After a few seconds, someone else removes the pentapus by gently rubbing
                its head. We see several shots of people placing and removing pentapi from their
                face, shoulders and arms.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to a top view of the people as Sokka walks over to them to
                    address them. While he speaks, the camera pans out, showing a close-up of all
                    the inhabitants of Omashu covered with the suction spots of the
                    pentapi.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">The marks make ya look sick, but you gotta act sick too. Ya gotta sell it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An old man hobbles into view, leaning heavily on his cane. He clutches his
                back while moaning in pain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grabs the guy who is standing next to him and points at the old
                man.</charAction> Now that's what I'm talkin' about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man turns around, smiling. He taps his wooden leg with his
                cane.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old man">Years of practice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay everyone! Into sick formation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and the other civilians start walking toward the gates of Omashu.
                Just as Katara wants to join them, she notices that Aang is walking off in the other
                direction.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, what are you doing? Aren't you coming with us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He turns around.</charAction> No. I'm not leaving until I find
            Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo jumps on Aang's shoulders, tugging Aang's lips. He grabs Momo by his
                neck and places him back on the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sorry Momo, I'll feed you later.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang uses airbending to propel him unto the air. He whizzes away, jumping
                from one rooftop to the other.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to some Fire Nation soldiers with spears who are guarding the
                    gates of Omashu. A moaning crowd of 'sick' people walks toward them from every
                    direction. They move like zombies, swaying back and forth. One of them even
                    falls down. The guards back away as the sick crowd reaches them. Sokka
                    theatrically grabs his face and moans painfully, before stretching out his hands
                    toward the frightened guards.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">Plague! Plague!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guards on the ground start to retreat into the citadel behind them,
                away from the sick, while another guard rings the gong to alert everyone of the
                problem at hand.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to the governor of Omashu and his family, including Mai, who is
                    eating a bowl of fire flakes, watching on one of his balconies, looking out over
                    the city.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">What is going on down there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">I saw some kids yesterday who were sick with pentapox. It must have spread!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">Pentapox! <charAction>He pulls his beard.</charAction> Hmm, I'm pretty sure I've
            heard of that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Michi">Oh, this is terrible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">What should we do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">Drive them out of the city <charAction>He points toward the gates.</charAction> ...
            but don't touch them! We have to rid the city of this disease!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guard bows in respect before leaving to spread the governor's orders.
                Mai calmly offers her dad the bowl of fire flakes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">Fire flakes, Dad?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Michi">
         <charAction>Gasping.</charAction> How awful!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The governor's family is shown from behind. As his wife hugs her husband,
                the little baby beside her, Mai's brother Tom-Tom toddles away from the
                group.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to Aang running through the streets of the city. He nimbly
                    climbs a house and balances on the railing, before landing on a flat rooftop. He
                    spots a giant, white creature below, sadly pushing forth a turnstile. Aang jumps
                    down to discover that the creature is Flopsie, King Bumi's pet goat
                    gorilla.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Flopsie!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Aang calls his name, Flopsie turns around and happily tries to reach his
                friend. His chains hold him back, so he sadly ceases his attempts. Aang jumps over
                him and uses the water from his drinking bowl to freeze the lock on his chains. With
                one swing of his staff, Aang destroys the lock, freeing Flopsie. The happy animal
                hugs and licks Aang's face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come on, Flopsie. <charAction>He climbs on top of Flopsie.</charAction> You gotta
            help me find Bumi. Yip Yip! <charAction>Flopsie does not move a muscle.</charAction> Oh
            ... I guess that doesn't work with you. Let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Flopsie races off at great speed. Meanwhile Momo is soaring through the
                city. He lands on a balcony and peeks through a window. We see a cluttered room with
                dressing panels at the back. A teddy bear is thrown repeatedly in the air by someone
                behind the panels. Momo spots a full scale of berries and starts to drool. He
                quickly enters the chamber through the window and starts to stuff his face. He
                rapidly spits out the seeds. Some of them land behind the panels. Cut to Tom-Tom who
                is playing with the stuffed animal behind the panels. He notices the seeds and
                crawls away, following their path. The trail of seeds leads right back to Momo, who
                is still sitting on the table, his tail dangling over the edge. Tom-Tom sits up in
                wonder as he examines the tail before pulling it. Cut to a surprised Momo who is
                pulled down to the ground in mid bite. He pulls a giggling Tom-Tom along as he tries
                to get away from his grasp. Momo pulls free and jumps out of the window on to the
                railing. As he looks back, he sees that the baby stumbles toward him with his arms
                spread out wide. Momo backs away, leaping of the railing and flying
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The baby is too late to grab Momo, so he tumbles off the railing. While he
                is sliding down the roof, he cannot stop giggling. He lands in a box of berries
                sliding down one of Omashu's chutes. Momo lands on the same box and starts to stuff
                his face again. His eyes open wide as Tom-Tom emerges behind him. The baby grabs
                Momo's tail and bites it. The lemur jumps in the air and frantically flaps his wings
                in an attempt to get away once more. As the slope becomes steeper, Momo is able to
                lift himself as well as Tom-Tom who is still clinging on to his tail. The lemur
                cannot bear the weight and they start to descend. Tom-Tom is being dragged over the
                ground as they crash-land. Tom-Tom rolls over the ground and lands on top of Momo,
                pinning him to the ground, and causing him to screech and shake around
                desperately.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The moaning crowd passes them by, diverting Tom-Tom attention away from
                Momo. Momo escapes into the crowd. The baby pushes himself to his feet and staggers
                after the crowd, out of the gates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Fire Nation circus at night. Upon entering, performers in two
                Chinese dragon's costumes are dancing. As they move out of the frame, the circus
                master, Shuzumu, stands before the circus' main ring, addressing the
                crowd.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">We're deeply honored to have the Fire Lord's daughter at our humble circus.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a shot from the back, revealing Azula sitting in high box seat
                with two guards at her side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">Uh ... tell us if there is anything we can do to make the show more
            enjoyable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I will.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the circus ring. The camera moves up, revealing a net
                spanned under an acrobat who is balancing on a rope, high up in the air on one hand.
                The camera zooms in. The acrobat is Ty Lee, who is wearing very colorful
                clothing.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to a shot of Azula and Shuzumu, who are both looking up,
                    fascinated by Ty Lee's performance.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Incredible. Do you think she'll fall?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">Of course not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Then wouldn't it make it more interesting if you removed the net?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula looks directly at Shuzumu. Close-up of the concerned look upon his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">
         <charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Uh ... the thing is ... the performers
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You're right, you're right. That's been done. <charAction>After a short pause, she
                continues with a tone of dark pleasure.</charAction> I know. Set the net on
            fire.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> Of course, Princess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With a worried look upon his face, Shuzumu leaves the box to set the net of
                fire. Ty Lee looks down in concern at the consuming flames beneath her. She
                continues with her act.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut back to the box seat, where Shuzumu is balling his fist and
                    clenching his teeth, hoping that Ty Lee will not fall off.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Ecstatic.</charAction> Brilliant, just brilliant! <charAction>She looks
                down at Shuzumu and asks happily.</charAction> Ooh, what kind of dangerous animals
            do you have?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shuzumu looks up, hopeful that he can change the subject to the animals and
                save Ty Lee from her burning peril.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shuzumu">Well, our circus boasts the most exotic assortment-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Release them all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shuzumu looks utterly shocked by Azula's command. Close-up again of Ty
                Lee's worried face, as she is still balancing on one hand above the flames. Cut to
                an outside-view of the circus. As the camera pans up, several animal noises fill the
                night.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to an overview shot of a campsite in the surrounding mountains
                    of Omashu. People are sitting around several campfires. Cut to Aang and Flopsie
                    who are walking into the camp. Katara and Sokka move to greet a sad looking
                    Aang.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> We looked everywhere. No Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara hugs him. Flopsie moans sadly, so Sokka turns around and hugs
                Flopsie's face.</description>
      <section>
         <description>The arrival of Yung interrupts their hugs.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">We've got a problem. We just did a head count.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried, turns back to Yung.</charAction> Oh no. Did someone get left
            behind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">No, we have an extra.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yung points to something to the left. Katara gazes in that direction and
                sees Momo staggering forward with the Tom-Tom clamped around his neck. Team Avatar
                and Yung just stare for a second at the poor animal and the baby.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the governor's house in Omashu. The governor's wife is sobbing on
                the balcony. Her daughter Mai slowly reaches into her robe and pulls out a
                handkerchief and gives it to her mother with a bored expression on her face. The
                governor rests his hands on the railing of the balcony as he stares out over his
                city. His sobbing wife, apathetic daughter and two guards stand behind him. Zoom
                toward the governor as he speaks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">So, the resistance has kidnapped my son. Everything so clever, so tricky. Just like
            their King Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He balls his right hand into a fist. One of the guards behind him steps
                forward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">What do you want to do, sir?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans out, showing a panoramic view of the city. </description>
      <section>
         <description>The view fades to a bouquet of black flowers that are being placed on a
                    desk. As the camera moves back, Azula and Ty Lee are revealed in Ty Lee's
                    dressing room. Azula is standing behind Ty Lee, who is sitting at the desk and
                    looking through a mirror.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">What an exquisite performance. I can't wait to see how you'll top yourself
            tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut closer to Ty Lee. Azula and Ty Lee's face are visible in Ty Lee's
                mirror.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Smiling at Azula's reflection in the mirror.</charAction> I'm sorry
            Azula, but unfortunately there won't be a show tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Hangs up her tiara.</charAction> The universe has given me strong hints
            that it's time for a career change. <charAction>She gets up and turns around to face
                Azula.</charAction> I want to join you on your mission.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zoom to a satisfied looking Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to an overview shot of the campsite in the valley. The gang,
                the baby, Flopsie and three resistance fighters are sitting at one of the many
                campfires. The baby is still trying to catch Momo. The lemur leaps out of the way
                and the baby tumbles down, right next to Sokka's club. He picks it up and starts to
                suck on it. The camera moves back as Sokka snatches the club out of the baby's
                hands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No! Bad Fire Nation baby!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The child starts to cry. Katara looks from the baby to Sokka and whacks him
                across the face before placing her hands on her hips in a motherly
                fashion.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Oh ... all right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka gives his club back to the baby who immediately stops crying and
                starts to play with it. Katara hugs him from behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Baby voice.</charAction> Oooh, you're so cute. <charAction>She kisses
                him on the cheek, while an annoyed Sokka looks the other side, resting his head on
                his hand.</charAction> Mmmmm ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Yung sitting on the other side of the fire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">Sure he's cute now, but when he's older, he'll join the Fire Nation army.
                <charAction>Switch to Katara who is happily playing with the baby under the annoyed
                gaze of her brother.</charAction> You won't think he's so cute then. He'll be a
            killer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara picks the baby up and shows him to Yung.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Does that look like the face of a killer to you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Yung whose face remains totally indifferent at the
                sight of the cute baby.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to a picture of an arriving messenger hawk. The animal shrieks
                    and lands on a nearby rock.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yung">A messenger hawk!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of the canister on the hawk's back. It has the Fire Nation
                insignia on it. Aang unrolls the scroll, close-up of the message.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's from the Fire Nation governor. He thinks we kidnapped his son.
                <charAction>Switch to another view. Aang is shown standing at the other side of the
                campfire, reading the message.</charAction> So ... he wants to make a trade. His son
                <charAction>Zoom to Aang's surprised face while he continues dramatically, his eyes
                widening.</charAction> for King Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a panoramic view by day of the mountains surrounding Omashu. Aang
                holds the baby in his arms while he stares at Omashu. He walks down the hill he was
                standing on toward Katara and Sokka, who are waiting next to Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You realize we're probably walking right into a trap.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't think so. I'm sure the governor wants his son back as much as we want Bumi.
                <charAction>Smiling at the sleeping baby he holds against his chest.</charAction>
            It's a new day. I have a good feeling about this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to inside the city of Omashu. A royal palanquin is being carried up the
                stairs toward the house of the governor. The silhouette of Azula can be seen through
                the veils. At the base of next stairs, the lonely figure of Mai awaits the arrival
                of the palanquin. Azula gets out and she and Ty Lee walk over to Mai. They halt
                before her. Mai puts her hands together and bows slightly toward
                Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">Please tell me you're here to kill me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A close-up of Mai. She looks up at Azula and a slight smile appears on her
                otherwise emotionless features. Both girls start to laugh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Placing her hands on Mai's shoulders.</charAction> It's great to see
            you, Mai.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ty Lee rushes forward to give Mai a big hug. Mai uncomfortably pats her
                back a little with her left hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">I thought you ran off and joined the circus. You said it was your calling.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Releases Mai.</charAction> Well, Azula called a little louder.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I have a mission and I need you both. <charAction>Azula places a hand on both her
                friends' shoulders.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">Count me in. Anything to get me out of this place. <charAction>She looks annoyed at
                the palace.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a large red flag with the black Fire Nation mark on it. The camera
                pans down and shows that Azula is sitting on the throne of Omashu, flanked by two
                Fire Nation guards. The governor and his wife are in front of her, as well as Mai
                and Ty Lee.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">I apologize. <charAction>Switch to a closer shot of the governor who squatting down
                on a pillow.</charAction> You've come to Omashu at a difficult time. At noon we're
            making a trade with the resistance to get Tom-Tom back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Yes, I'm so sorry to hear about your son, but really, <charAction>She crosses her
                legs and clasps her hands.</charAction> what did you expect by just letting all the
            citizens leave? <charAction>She stands up, addressing the governor in a harsher
                tone.</charAction> My father has trusted you with this city and you're making a mess
            of things! <charAction>She emphasizes her words with a hand
            gesture.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The governor and his wife prostrate themselves before her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ukano">Forgive me, Princess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula walks between the four bowing people in front of her, looking down
                upon the governor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You stay here. <charAction>Mai and Ty Lee get up behind her.</charAction> Mai will
            handle the hostage trade so you don't have a chance to mess it up. <charAction>Cut to a
                shot of the still smoking city of Omashu, followed by some shots of Fire Nation
                construction sites.</charAction> And there is no more "Omashu". I'm renaming it in
            honor of my father, the city of New Ozai.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera stops on a large statue of Ozai, still in its scaffolds. The
                camera pans down. A long overview shot reveals Aang, Katara and Sokka standing on a
                large wooden scaffold. They look serious as a party of three girls approaches, with
                Mai leading the way.</description>
      <section>
         <description>A crane is shown, lowering a metal cage. A close-up of the cage reveals
                    that it is used to contain King Bumi. Only his head is left
                    uncovered.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Chuckling.</charAction> Hi, everybody!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang smiles as he sees his friend. The cage touches the ground behind Azula
                and the rest.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">You brought my brother?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">He's here. We're ready to trade.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>To Mai.</charAction> I'm sorry, but a thought just occurred to me. Do
            you mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi follows the conversation, shifting his eyes from one speaker to the
                other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Turning to Azula.</charAction> Of course not, Princess Azula.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">We're trading a two year old for a king. <charAction>Looks up at Bumi.</charAction>
            A powerful, earthbending king?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Nods.</charAction> Mmm hmmm!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It just doesn't seem like a fair trade, does it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Mai's gray eyes as she ponders over the idea. She looks at her
                brother who yawns and happily rests his head against Sokka's shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">You're right. <charAction>Azula smiles slyly while Mai walks forward.</charAction>
            The deal's off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Mai holds up her hand, gesturing the guards to pull Bumi back up. As the
                chains reel in from above, the King is suspended in the air once
                again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Clearly amused by all this.</charAction> Whhhoa! See you all
            later!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi chuckles and snorts as he is lifted from the scenery. Aang watches him
                go.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Bumi!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He sprints forward with his glider at the ready, increasing his speed with
                airbending. Azula tries to stop him by blocking his path with a mighty stream of
                blue flames. Aang dodges these by leaping high up into the air. Azula is completely
                shocked by this incredible jump. Aang briefly touches the scaffolding around the
                statue and pushes himself off, opening his glider in mid air. While opening his
                glider, he loses his hat, leaving his arrow tattoo exposed. He holds on to the hat
                with his teeth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> The Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang circles up toward Bumi's coffin. Cut back to Azula who smiles
                smugly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">My lucky day.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She runs over to a pulley and blast through the rope that serves as a
                break. The winch begins to spin rapidly. Azula grabs hold to the rope and is pulled
                up rapidly toward the top of the construction scaffolding.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Aang lands on the top of Bumi's metal cage.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Aang, is that you? Where did you come
            from?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hang on! We're gonna get you out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He takes a deep breath of starts to blow a cold wind on the chain that is
                lifting Bumi up. The chain slowly starts to freeze.</description>
      <section>
         <description>On the ground, Mai and Ty Lee charge Sokka and Katara. Mai readies her
                    stiletto's while Katara takes on a defensive position.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We've got to get the baby out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Blows on the bison whistle before looking at his sister with a big
                smile.</charAction> Way ahead of ya! <charAction>Tom-Tom reaches for the whistle and
                starts to play with it.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overview shot of Sokka and Katara running to the edge of the big
                platform. Before they can reach it, Ty Lee's fist emerges from one of the holes in
                the floor and punches Sokka's foot, causing him to fall over and slide toward the
                edge. He protectively clutches the baby in his arms, preparing for the worst, but
                they stop just in time.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch back to Katara, who sees Ty Lee jumping out of the hole in the
                    floor and setting course for Sokka. She bends water from her pouch to attack
                    her, but notices something behind her. Cut to a close-up of Mai, who throws four
                    knives at Katara. Katara reacts by quickly by using her water whip to raise up
                    several wooden planks. A close-up of Katara shows that the wooden board is just
                    in time to prevent the knives from piercing her face. The knives embed
                    themselves in the wood. Katara uses her water whip again to shoot the wooden
                    boards to Mai. She turns around in one fluent motion toward Ty Lee who has
                    almost reached Sokka and the baby by now. The water whip grabs Ty Lee by the
                    ankle, pulling her to the ground. This gives Sokka the time he needs to get up
                    and head for a nearby ladder. He slides down and starts his descend of the
                    scaffolding.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to Bumi and Aang, who are still being raised in the air. Aang is
                    still trying to freeze the chain with his breath.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Aang, stop your blowing for a minute.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A close-up shows that he finally succeeds in freezing the chain, when an
                explosion occurs on top of the scaffolding. Azula is propelled in the air and shoots
                a plume of blue fire toward Aang with a powerful kick. Aang startles by her sudden
                appearance and swift attack. He deflects the flame with a strong air current of his
                own.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Now hold on just a <charAction>The swing of Aang's staff breaks the frozen chain and
                they freefall down.</charAction> duahhh!!!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns over Bumi's coffin, so he would crash to the ground head first.
                As they are about to crash upon one of Omashu's chutes, Aang creates an air ball
                under them to break their fall. They rapidly slide down the chute they landed
                in.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to Azula who was following the spectacle from atop the scaffolding.
                    She frowns and sprints to a nearby chute, pursuing the Avatar and the King down
                    the chute in a box of her own.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to a laughing Aang standing on Bumi's coffin.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's just like old times, isn't it, Bumi?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Looking serious.</charAction> Aang, I need to talk to you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's good to see you too!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Aang is still smiling, he notices the fast approach of something in a
                chute on his left. He turns to see what it is, just as Azula shoots several fire
                missiles toward them. He spins his staff above his head to deflect them. Both chutes
                come together and Azula is now behind them. Aang directs a gust at her, but she
                parts it with her hands clasped together in front of her. She retaliates with
                several fire blasts. Aang ducks underneath them and starts to peddle with his staff,
                increasing their speed. They enter a portion of the chute that has wooden arches
                over it at short intervals. Aang cuts these through with an air blade, making them
                collapse upon the track. Azula is caught in the dust cloud, knocked up by the
                falling debris. When her box emerges again, it seems to be empty. Aang does not see
                Azula anymore and sighs in relief, but his sigh quickly turns into a scream as Azula
                emerges again from the box, sending another beam of fire toward him. Aang drops flat
                on his belly to avoid it. Cut back to the large wooden platform where Mai and Katara
                are still fighting. Mai dodges Katara's water whips and answers her attacks by
                shooting stiletto's out of the launcher attached to her leg. Katara easily defends
                herself by freezing the water to create an ice wall. Mai uses this time to charge
                Katara head on. The waterbender defends herself by capturing Mai's right arm in a
                stream of water and freezing it. Mai tries to break the ice, but fails. Ty Lee
                climbs on the platform behind Katara. She bounces toward Katara and hits her with
                several quick jabs on her arms. Katara is surprised by this attack and loses control
                over her water stream that splashes on the ground. She tries to raise the water
                again, but it only moves a little.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Taunting.</charAction> How are you gonna fight without your
            bending?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Mai pulls out a sai from her robe and takes aim at a shocked Katara. Just
                as she is about to throw the weapon, Sokka's boomerang knocks it out of her hand. Ty
                Lee and Mai spin around to see Sokka flying in on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Catching the boomerang.</charAction> I seem to manage!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Appa land between Katara and her attackers. As Appa lands, he
                slams his tail hard on the ground, sending Mai and Ty Lee flying off the
                scaffolding.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Sokka and Katara are flying down the chutes of Omashu atop Appa's head.
                    Katara looks and points to her left.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">There's Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Gazing in the direction Katara pointed.</charAction> We can catch
            him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With a growl, Appa changes course toward Aang.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to Azula who is still on the offensive, directing multiple beams of
                    fire at Aang. He spins his staff around in defense while they are still
                    rocketing down the chute. Appa pulls up next to him.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hang on, Bumi! Our ride's here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa swerves to avoid another blue fire blast. As he pulls closer again,
                Aang lifts up the coffin by hitting the side of the chute. Katara and Sokka try to
                grab hold of the coffin as it passes overhead, but they cannot reach it. Bumi
                screams as he and Aang fall down. Aang moves the coffin to a more horizontal
                position in midair. Their fall is broken by another chute as they land crosswise on
                it, breaking right through. They land on another chute and start to slide down once
                again with Azula on their trail.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Switch to Azula who creates a whirling disk of flames and sends it down
                    the chute. It rapidly gains on Aang and Bumi. Bumi peeks at the upcoming fire
                    disk and clenches his teeth in effort. A pillar of earth rises in the middle of
                    the chute, protecting them from the disk. Azula gasps for air as she notices
                    that her path is blocked. She jumps up in the nick of time and slides down the
                    chute on foot, while her box slams to pieces against the rock. She eventually
                    halts in the middle of the chute, looking displeased at Aang and Bumi who
                    continue their descent.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to Aang and Bumi who are nearing the end of the
                    chute.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You could earthbend? All along?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Well, they didn't cover my face.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi strains himself again in effort and raises another earth pillar to
                stop their descent down the chute. The coffin hits it and ends up standing straight
                atop the rock, while Aang lands in front of it, looking up at his
                friend.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slightly annoyed and angry.</charAction> I don't understand. Why didn't
            you free yourself? Why did you surrender when Omashu was invaded? What's the matter with
            you, Bumi?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Listen to me, Aang. There are options in fighting,
            called jing. It's a choice of how you direct your energy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a close-up of an annoyed Aang, counting along on his fingers as
                he sums up the different jings.</charAction> I know! There's positive jing when
            you're attacking, and negative jing when you're retreating.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">
         <charAction>Happily smiling.</charAction> ... and neutral jing when you do
            nothing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He looks shocked at his three raised fingers.</charAction> There
                arethree jings?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Well, technically there are eighty-five, but let's just focus on the third. Neutral
            jing is the key to earthbending. It involves listening and waiting for the right moment
            to strike.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Starting to understand.</charAction> That's why you surrendered, isn't
            it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Yes, and it's why I can't leave now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sadly turns around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> I guess I need to find someone else to teach
            me earthbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Your teacher will be someone who has mastered neutral jing. You need to find someone
            who waits and listens before striking.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo lands on Aang's shoulders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Hey, Momo!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Momo's mastered a few jings himself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo screeches loudly at Bumi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="King Bumi">Goodbye, Aang. I'll see you when the time is right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>King Bumi lets his coffin tumble backward and begins his ascend of the
                chute. He laughs and snorts like a mad man while he uses his earthbending to drive
                him back to the top of the chute, leaving Aang and Momo behind.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to the royal palanquin being carried out the city, flanked by Mai
                    and Ty Lee.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">So, we're tracking down your brother and Uncle, huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Turning to Mai.</charAction> It'll be interesting seeing Zuko again,
                <charAction>Teasing.</charAction> won't it, Mai?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Mai looks away as a smile plays upon her face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's not just Zuko and Iroh anymore. <charAction>Cut closer to Azula who continues
                on a serious tone.</charAction> We have a third target now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene fades to Aang that night, peeking down over the gutter of the
                governor's house. The governor holds his wife while they are looking over the city
                with a sad expression on their face. Aang silently lands behind them and drops off
                Tom-Tom. Aang takes off again while the child toddles toward his parents. As they
                hear the cooing of the child, they turn around, gasping with surprise and
                excitement.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Michi">Tom-Tom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The governor and his wife joyfully take the baby up into their arms under
                the watchful eye of Aang who is sitting on the roof. He smiles at the happy scene of
                the reunited family before he takes off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
