<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="58">Sozins Comet Part 1</title>
      <director>Ethan Spaulding</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2008-07-19</date>
      <location nation="earth">Tavern</location>
      <location nation="earth">Ba Sing Se</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens at night to a wide shot of the Earth Kingdom tavern, Appa
                resting outside. Cut inside to frontal view of Team Avatar, sans Aang. June kicks a
                chair in the foreground and sits down and begins drinking her tea.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> Hey, I remember her! <charAction>Cut to frontal
                view of Zuko, Sokka standing behind.</charAction> She helped you attack us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Yup. <charAction>Walks forward.</charAction> Back in the good old days.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide shot as they all walk up to June.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Oh great. It's Prince Pouty. <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Where's your creepy
            grandpa?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Katara and Zuko.</charAction> He's my uncle. And he's
            not here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> I see you worked things out with your
            girlfriend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko and Katara who become flustered and embarrassed, looking at
                each other as they speak, before cutting to June.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I'm not his girlfriend!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Speaking at the same time.</charAction> She's not my
            girlfriend!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Okay, okay. Sheesh. I was only teasing. So
            what do you want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frontal view of June with Zuko and Suki behind.</charAction> I need your
            help finding the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">Hm. Doesn't sound too fun. <charAction>Sips her tea.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily; leans closer, while clenching his fists.</charAction> Does the
            end of the world sound like more fun?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to side-view of Appa and Nyla growling at each other. Appa licks Nyla,
                and they lay down. They both stand up as the gang and June walking toward them. Cut
                to frontal view of the approaching group as June holds up a piece of
                meat.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Shaking the piece of meat.</charAction> Nyla. <charAction>She throws the
                meat to Nyla. Cut to frontal view of Nyla, who catches it in his mouth and starts
                chewing it before swallowing it; June walks up to him and starts petting
                him.</charAction> Who's my little, hmm, Snuffly-Wuffly? <charAction>Nyla sticks his
                toxins-coated tongue out and she dodges it and forces his mouth closed.</charAction>
            Whoa! Careful there. <charAction>To Team Avatar.</charAction> Okay. So who's got
            something with the Avatar's scent on it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara standing on Appa's back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pulls out Aang's glider from Appa's saddle.</charAction> I have Aang's
            staff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Nyla as June approaches and holds the staff out in front of Nyla. He
                sniffs it. Cut to wide-view of the group as Nyla begins to walk around in circles,
                trying to sniff the scent out somewhere else. Cut to overhead view. Cut to closer
                view of the group as Nyla returns to June and continues sniffing. Cut to frontal
                view as Nyla lies back down and covers his nose.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Well, what does that mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Petting Nyla.</charAction> Means your friend's
            gone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> We know he's gone. That's why we're trying to
            find him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Close-up as June stands up.</charAction> No, I mean he's
                gone gone. <charAction>Turns to face everyone
                else.</charAction> He doesn't exist.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the others as the look on with worry and confusion. The camera cuts
                to a mysterious island. Cut inside the forestry as Momo is chasing a squirrel
                creature in a tree. Camera pans across the branch as Momo chases the squirrel and
                Aang is seen walking around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Where are we, Momo? <charAction>Cut to view of the sky through the trees as
                dragonflies fly past. The camera pans down as Aang speaks.</charAction> Maybe I'm in
            the Spirit World? <charAction>Cut to frontal view of Aang stepping under a
                branch.</charAction> But wait. You can see me. <charAction>Momo approaches on the
                branch. Cut to a close-up of Momo.</charAction> We could both be in the Spirit
            World. <charAction>Cut back to Aang. He uses airbending and the camera pans across as he
                moves.</charAction> Nope. My bending works. <charAction>Momo lands on him. Points to
                the hilltop. Cut to path up a hill. Camera pans up as Aang talks.</charAction> Maybe
            if we climb to the top of the island, we can figure out where we are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To June.</charAction> What do you mean Aang doesn't exist?
                <charAction>Side-view of the group.</charAction> Do you mean he's ... you know,
            dead?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Frontal view as she pets Nyla.</charAction> Nope. We could find him if
            he were dead. Wow, it's a real head-scratcher. See ya. <charAction>Cut to a wide-view of
                the group as she starts climbing on top of Nyla.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Helpful. Real helpful.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>To June.</charAction> Wait. I have another idea. <charAction>Frontal
                view.</charAction> There's only one other person in this world who can help us face
            the Fire Lord. I'll be right back with a smell sample.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of a sandal that Zuko holds up. Camera zooms out quickly to
                show the members of Team Avatar are holding their noses in disgust, except for Zuko
                and Toph. Zuko looks embarrassed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You saved your uncle's sweaty sandal? Ugh! <charAction>Pinches nose even
                tighter.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> I think it's kind of sweet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to June as Nyla jumps forward. Cut to side-view of Zuko and Nyla as the
                latter sniffs the sandal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Determined.</charAction> Let's do this. <charAction>Cut to
                wide-view as she and Nyla run off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Hey! Wait up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all quickly get on Appa. Cut to behind Appa as his tail hits the
                ground he takes off in the same direction. Cut to side-view of Nyla running up a
                hill as Appa flies behind. Fade to a shot behind Nyla as he jumps over a cliff edge.
                Camera pans to the right slightly as Appa follows closely behind. Fade to frontal
                view of Nyla running along with Appa close behind before Nyla jumps forward toward
                the camera. Cut to wide-view of Appa and Nyla approaching the destroyed Outer Wall
                of Ba Sing Se. Cut to frontal view of the wall as Nyla jumps in front of the camera
                and the camera pans up to show Appa above. Cut to close-up aerial view. The camera
                pans out as the group stops near the rubble. Appa lands and Nyla starts digging at
                the wreckage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We're going to Ba Sing Se?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="June">
         <charAction>Cut to side-view of the group as Nyla continues scratching the
                wall.</charAction> Your uncle's somewhere beyond the wall. <charAction>Nyla stops
                digging and walks away.</charAction> Nyla's getting twitchy so he can't be too far.
                <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Good luck.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to side-view of Zuko as Nyla and June leave and he turns to watch. As
                they disappear over the hill he turns away to the others.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's been a long day. <charAction>Aerial view. Camera zooms out.</charAction> Let's
            camp and start our search again at dawn.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the island. The camera pans down from trees to Aang and Momo as
                they approach a strange, flat rock-formation. Cut to a frontal view of Aang looking
                at the rock-formation. Cut to an aerial view of the entire clearing as Aang steps on
                to it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's a hexagon. <charAction>Cut to Aang's feet as Momo jumps off his shoulder. Bends
                down to place a hand on the ground.</charAction> It doesn't seem like normal rock.
                <charAction>Stands back up. Cut to a side-view as he attempts earthbending, but
                nothing happens.</charAction> It's not made of earth. <charAction>Sits
                down.</charAction> This is so strange. <charAction>Frontal view of Aang with Momo in
                the foreground, his back to the camera.</charAction> I wish I had some help right
            now. I wish I had Roku. <charAction>Suddenly realizes something.</charAction> I
                do have Roku! <charAction>Takes a deep breath and starts
                meditating. Fade to close-up of Aang. Cut to side-view as Momo runs off and the
                spirit of Avatar Roku appears before Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Avatar Roku">You're right, Aang. <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> All the past Avatars, all
            their experience and wisdom, is available to you <charAction>Cut to close-up of
                Aang.</charAction> if you look deep inside yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking around.</charAction> So where am I, Roku? What is this
            place?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Avatar Roku">
         <charAction>Side-view.</charAction> I ... don't know, Aang. <charAction>Close-up of
                Aang.</charAction> But I see you are lost in more ways than one right now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I am. I need to figure out what to do once I face the Fire Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to Appa. The camera pans to the right to show Zuko, Katara,
                Suki, and Sokka asleep on Appa's legs and tail. Cut to Toph, who is sleeping in an
                earth tent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Huh? <charAction>She suddenly senses something
                and wakes up. Cut to outside her rock tent as it begins to
            low.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out as the group is surrounded by a wall of fire. Cut to
                an aerial view of the area showing Team Avatar is trapped. Cut behind the group as
                the camera pans across to left. The group turn and look up to see Piandao, Jeong
                Jeong, Pakku, and Bumi. The camera zooms in on Piandao before panning to left to
                focus on Jeong Jeong, before panning again to Pakku, and finally to
                Bumi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Well, look who's here! <charAction>Starts laughing and
            snorting.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Team Avatar looking confused, except for Katara and Sokka, who are
                both excited.</description>
      <section>
         <description>The scene changes back to the island, which now looks somewhat
                    invisible from the outside. Cut to side-view of Aang on the island, talking to
                    Avatar Roku's spirit.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Everyone expects me to take the Fire Lord's life,
                <charAction>Side-view.</charAction> but I just don't know if I can do that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Avatar Roku">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> In my life, I tried to be disciplined and
            show restraint, but it backfired when Fire Lord Sozin took advantage of my restraint and
            mercy. <charAction>Fade to a flashback of Sozin, close-up shot. Sozin moves forward and
                the camera cuts to a side-view of him attempting to attack Roku from behind. The
                camera pans left to show the flames engulf Roku. Cut to a shot inside the flames as
                they dissipate to reveal Roku gone. Fade to a close-up shot of Sozin from behind
                looking at his army. Fade to a panning shot of air temples on fire. Overlaid shot of
                close-up Sozin.</charAction> If I had been more decisive and acted sooner, I could
            have stopped Sozin and stopped the war before it started. <charAction>Cut back to
                side-view of Aang and Roku.</charAction> I offer you this wisdom, Aang: You must be
            decisive. <charAction>Cut behind Roku as he vanishes. Cut close-up to Aang,
                disappointed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Outer Walls of Ba Sing Se. Wide shot of the entire group now
                joined by the masters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What's going on? <charAction>Cut to closer view
                from behind the masters.</charAction> We're surrounded by old people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Not just any old people. <charAction>Walks up to Pakku. Side-view of the
                masters.</charAction> These are great masters and friends of ours.
                <charAction>Camera pans and zooms in on Katara and Pakku as she bows to
                Pakku.</charAction> Pakku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Bows back.</charAction> It is respectful to bow to an old master,
                <charAction>Frontal view. Extends his arms out.</charAction> but how about a hug for
            your new grandfather?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Surprised and overjoyed, as is Sokka behind
                her.</charAction> That's so exciting! <charAction>Frontal view of Pakku as she hugs
                Pakku.</charAction> You and Gran-Gran must be so happy to have found each other
            again!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I made her a new betrothal necklace and everything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Runs up and hugs Pakku. Camera zooms in on Pakku.</charAction> Welcome
            to the family, Gramp-Gramp!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Gently pushes Sokka away; slightly annoyed.</charAction> You can still
            just call me Pakku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> How about Grand-Pakku?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Close-up. Not amused.</charAction> No. <charAction>Side-view of Zuko and
                Pakku as Sokka walks away behind Katara sadly. Camera zooms out to show Jeong
                Jeong.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Zuko walks up to Jeong Jeong.</charAction> And this was Aang's first
            firebending teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jeong Jeong">
         <charAction>Close-up. Bows.</charAction> Jeong Jeong.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view. Bows to Piandao.</charAction> Master Piandao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Bows back.</charAction> Hello, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Cut to over-head view from behind the masters.</charAction> So wait. How
            do you all know each other?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view.</charAction> All old people know each other. Don't
            you know that? <charAction>Laughs and snorts.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">We're all part of the same ancient secret society. A group that transcends the
            divisions of the four nations.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> The Order of the White Lotus.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Piandao and Jeong Jeong. Bumi slides in front of the
                camera.</charAction> That's the one. <charAction>Slides off
            camera.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jeong Jeong">The White Lotus has always been about philosophy and beauty and truth.
                <charAction>Aerial view.</charAction> But about a month ago, a call went out that we
            were needed for something important.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Cut close-up behind Zuko with Pakku and Katara in the background. To
                Zuko.</charAction> It came from a Grand Lotus: your uncle, <charAction>Close-up of
                Zuko.</charAction> Iroh of the Fire Nation. <charAction>Zuko
            smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Camera zooms out to show Toph behind Zuko.</charAction> Well, that's who
            we're looking for.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Then we'll take you to him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Appears behind Piandao and Jeong Jeong and pushes them out of the
                way.</charAction> Wait! Someone's missing from your group. <charAction>Walks up to
                the camera.</charAction> Someone very important. <charAction>Walks right up to the
                camera.</charAction> Where's Momo?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view. Leaning backward almost all the way, as Bumi is right in his
                face.</charAction> He's gone. <charAction>Pauses.</charAction> And so is
            Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Camera zooms out.</charAction> Oh well. <charAction>Pats Sokka on the
                chest, which causes him to almost fall back.</charAction> So long as they have each
            other, I'm sure we have nothing to worry about. Let's go! <charAction>Slams in to the
                ground. Cut to underneath Bumi as he launches himself away using earthbending while
                laughing and snorting.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back on the island. Cut to Momo behind a branch before flying off. Cut
                to frontal view of Aang who is meditating as Momo arrives next to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Avatar Kyoshi. I need your wisdom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo runs off. Fade to close-up of Aang. Side-view as the spirit of Avatar
                Kyoshi appears before him and the camera pans right to where she sits.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">In my day, <charAction>Flashback to frontal view of Chin the Conqueror. Cut to
                close-up of Avatar Kyoshi.</charAction> Chin the Conqueror threatened to throw the
            world out of balance. <charAction>Kyoshi enters the Avatar State briefly and begins to
                earthbend. Cut to wide shot as a dust cloud appears as she separates the
                land.</charAction> I stopped him. <charAction>Cut to side-view of Kyoshi as she uses
                airbending to push the land apart.</charAction> And the world entered a great era of
            peace. <charAction>Cut to aerial view of the land separating.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over; Side-view of Chin as he falls to his death.</charAction> You
            didn't really kill Chin. <charAction>Camera cuts back to close-up view looking up at
                Aang.</charAction> Technically, he fell to his own doom because he was too stubborn
            to get out of the way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view.</charAction> Personally, I don't really see the
            difference, but I assure you, I would have done whatever it took to stop Chin.
                <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> I offer you this wisdom, Aang: Only justice
            will bring peace. <charAction>Vanishes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up. Disappointed. Side-view as he leans back.</charAction> I knew
            I shouldn't have asked Kyoshi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the rest of the group as the camera pans right to show the
                group walking with the White Lotus members to their campsite.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, Bumi ... <charAction>Cut closer, side-view. Camera follows them as they
                walk.</charAction> how did you end up escaping your imprisonment in Omashu?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Escape? I didn't escape. Everybody else escaped. <charAction>Close-up.</charAction>
            There I was back in Omashu, <charAction>Flashback of Omashu while under control of the
                Fire Nation during the Day of Black Sun.</charAction> waiting for just the right
            moment. <charAction>Cut to close-up of Bumi suspended in a metal box.</charAction> I
            didn't know what or when, but I knew I'd know it when I knew it. <charAction>Camera pans
                round as he looks up to see the solar eclipse. Speaking in flashback.</charAction>
            An eclipse. That'll do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut close-up as he begins twitching his face. Cut to buildings beginning to
                crumble and break. Cut back to Bumi in the cage as the camera zooms in with pieces
                of earth heading to the cage. Frontal view of the cage as Bumi uses the broken
                pieces of the buildings to break himself free. Cut to the ground below as Bumi drops
                down and firebenders quickly show up to confront him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Firebender">What do you think you're doing? <charAction>Zooms in on the
            firebender.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The firebenders attempt to blast Bumi, but are powerless due to the
                eclipse. They look at Bumi in horror. Cut to frontal view of Bumi, who smiles
                evilly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Taking back my city! You've got no firepower. And it's payback time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi launches himself forward. Cut behind Bumi as he launches himself off
                the platform. Frontal view of Bumi as he lands. He uses earthbending and lifts a
                large piece of earth up. Cut to side-view of a building being separated by the
                pillar of earth. Cut back to Bumi, and back to the building as he moves the building
                with the use of the pillar. Cut to frontal view of firebenders running away. Camera
                pans up to reveal entire buildings beginning to move. Cut to Bumi running to left
                and stops to earthbend again sending more buildings flying. Cut to wide-view of
                Omashu. Cut to side-view of the entrance to Omashu as Fire Nation soldiers flee. </description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to frontal view of Bumi who turns and looks back to see a giant
                    statue of Fire Lord Ozai. Frontal view of Bumi as he uses earthbending to stop
                    oncoming Fire Nation soldiers. He sends small pieces of earth flying forward.
                    Cut to close-up of the statues face as two small pillars become embedded in the
                    eyes. Two more smaller ones go into the nostrils and large chunks go in the
                    mouth and cheeks. Cut to side-view of the base of the statue as it begins to
                    shift and rise. Cut to close-up of Bumi who struggles to lift the statue. Cut to
                    a wide shot of Omashu looking up at the statue as it begins to fall over. The
                    statue slides down toward the camera. Cut to wide side-view of Omashu's entrance
                    as the statue falls over the side and breaks the bridge before falling in to the
                    canyon below. Cut to close-up view of Bumi looking down at his handiwork and he
                    begins to laugh. He starts eating a piece of jennamite before the camera cuts
                    back to a frontal view of present-day Bumi.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Amazed.</charAction> Wow! You took back your whole city all by
            yourself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Side-view of entire group.</charAction> So what about you guys? Did you
            do anything interesting on the day of the eclipse?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Side-view of Sokka and Zuko, who look at each other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly.</charAction> Nah.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly.</charAction> No, not really.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to close-up of Aang, who is becoming
                irritated.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I need to look deep inside myself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up frontal view as Aang starts meditating. Side-view of Aang as the
                spirit of Avatar Kuruk, a male Avatar from the Northern Water Tribe, appears before
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> I am Avatar Kuruk. <charAction>Cut to flashback
                to a close-up view of a younger Avatar Kuruk. The camera zooms out to show him
                surfing.</charAction> When I was young, I was always a go-with-the-flow kind of
            Avatar. <charAction>The camera pans round to follow his movements on the wave before
                holding steady as he surfs away.</charAction> People seemed to work out their own
            problems, and there was peace and good times in the world. <charAction>Cut to shot of
                the sun and the camera pans down to Kuruk with Ummi and they kiss.</charAction> But
            then, <charAction>Fade to a side-view of Koh in the Spirit World. Koh moves in front of
                the camera to reveal the face of Ummi.</charAction> I lost the woman I loved to Koh,
            the Face Stealer. <charAction>Fade back to close-up side-view of present-day
                Kuruk.</charAction> It was my fault. If I had been more attentive and more active,
                <charAction>Close-up of Aang.</charAction> I could've saved her. Aang,
                <charAction>Close-up of Kuruk.</charAction> you must actively shape your own destiny
            and the destiny of the world. <charAction>Vanishes. Frontal view of Aang, even more
                disappointed as he places his head in his hands.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Outer Walls of Ba Sing Se showing the moon. The camera pans down to
                show the White Lotus campsite and the group approaching. Cut inside the camp as Bumi
                lowers a rock wall to allow entrance to the camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Stepping into the camp.</charAction> Well, here we are. Welcome to Old
            People Camp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Side-view of Jeong Jeong, Piandao, and Pakku. As Zuko speaks, Jeong
                Jeong and Pakku walk off and Appa stops behind Zuko and Piandao.</charAction> Where
            ... where is he?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Points to a tent on the other side of the camp. Camera cuts and zooms in
                showing a tent.</charAction> Your uncle's in there, Prince Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Zuko, who becomes worried and ashamed before walking toward the
                tent. Cut to Zuko from behind as he approaches the tent before stopping. Close-up of
                Zuko. Side-view as he sits down. Katara walks up to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> No, I'm not okay. My uncle hates me, I know
            it. <charAction>Katara sits down next to him.</charAction> He loved and supported me in
            every way he could, and I still turned against him. How can I even face him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view of Zuko.</charAction> Zuko, you're sorry for what you
            did, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">More sorry than I've been about anything in my entire life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Then he'll forgive you. He will.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko stands up. Cut to side-view of him standing at the tents entrance and
                he exhales deeply. He walks into the tent. Cut to an aerial view inside the
                tent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Zuko as he hears snoring. Frontal view of Iroh, asleep with
                Zuko standing at the entrance. Close-up of Zuko as he smiles and sits down next to
                him. The camera cuts to the island.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> All these past Avatars. <charAction>Cut to
                frontal view of Aang.</charAction> They keep telling me I'm gonna have to do it.
            They don't get it. <charAction>Momo chitters.</charAction> You're right. Maybe an Air
            Nomad Avatar will understand where I'm coming from. <charAction>Close-up of Momo, who
                stares at him. Frontal view of Aang as Momo jumps to his other side.</charAction> I
            know you can't really talk. Pretending you can just helps me think. <charAction>Momo
                chitters again; Aang becomes annoyed.</charAction> I'm going to pretend I didn't
            pretend to hear that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to close-up of Aang meditating. Cut back to frontal view as the spirit
                of Avatar Yangchen, a female Air Nomad Avatar, appears before him. Aerial view from
                behind Aang as Yangchen's spirit sits before him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>Side-view.</charAction> I am Avatar Yangchen, young airbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Avatar Yangchen, <charAction>Close-up of Aang.</charAction> the monks always taught
            me that all life is sacred. Even the life of the tiniest spider-fly caught in its own
            web.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view.</charAction> Yes. All life is sacred.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Smiles.</charAction> I know, I'm even a vegetarian. I've
            always tried to solve my problems by being quick or clever. And I've only had to use
            violence for necessary defense. And I've certainly never used it to take a
            life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>Cut to behind Aang as the camera pans up to show Yangchen.</charAction>
            Avatar Aang, I know that you're a gentle spirit, and the monks have taught you well, but
            this isn't about you. <charAction>Close-up side-view of Aang.</charAction> This is about
            the world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But the monks taught me that I had to detach myself from the world so my spirit
            could be free.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>Side-view of Aang and Yangchen. Camera pans slowly to the
                right.</charAction> Many great and wise Air Nomads have detached themselves and
            achieved spiritual enlightenment, <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> but the Avatar can
            never do it. Because your sole duty is to the world. Here is my wisdom for you:
                <charAction>Close-up of Aang. Camera zooms out.</charAction> Selfless duty calls you
            to sacrifice your own spiritual needs, and do whatever it takes to protect the world.
                <charAction>Yangchen's spirit vanishes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Momo appears behind a tree and approaches Aang. Close-up aerial view of
                Aang. Sorrowfully.</charAction> I guess I don't have a choice, Momo.
                <charAction>Camera zooms out as Aang looks up.</charAction> I have to kill the Fire
            Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to an aerial view of the White Lotus camp. Cut to aerial
                view inside Iroh's tent. Zuko sits nearby as Iroh wakes up. Cut to frontal view of
                Iroh as he stretches. He glances back slightly and sees Zuko, but says nothing.
                Frontal view of Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to view of Iroh from behind.</charAction> Uncle, <charAction>Cut to
                view of Zuko over Iroh's shoulder.</charAction> I know you must have mixed feelings
            about seeing me. <charAction>Cut briefly to view of Iroh from behind before back to a
                frontal view of Zuko.</charAction> But I want you to know, <charAction>Starts to
                cry.</charAction> I am so, so, sorry, Uncle. I am so sorry and ashamed of what I
            did. I don't know how I can ever make it up to you. But I'll- <charAction>He is cut off.
                Cut to side-view as Iroh pulls him into a hug, while starting to cry as well.
                Close-up of Iroh who starts to smile. Close-up of Zuko who becomes shocked and
                confused.</charAction> How can you forgive me so easily? I thought you would be
            furious with me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> I was never angry with you. I was sad because I
            was afraid you had lost your way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Side-view of the two.</charAction> I did lose my way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Releases him.</charAction> But you found it again. <charAction>Frontal
                view.</charAction> And you did it by yourself. <charAction>Frontal view of Zuko over
                Iroh's shoulder.</charAction> And I am so happy you found your way here.
                <charAction>Side-view. Hugs him again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It wasn't that hard, Uncle. You have a pretty strong scent.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out before cutting to the island. A squirrel runs along a
                branch before cutting to an aerial view of the rock formation. Birds fly past the
                camera as Momo and Aang sleep on the rock formation. Cut close-up to Aang as he
                wakes up and yawns. The camera follows him as he sits up and notices
                something.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait. <charAction>Cut to view of "approaching" mountains.</charAction> Is it just
            me, or are those mountains getting bigger?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Aang as Momo chitters. Aang bends down and uses
                airbending to launch himself up. Cut to the top of a tall tree that Aang lands on.
                As he looks foward, Momo flies around and lands on his shoulder. Cut to a close-up
                of Aang and Momo. Aang turns around to show a wake behind the
                "island".</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">They're not getting larger, <charAction>Turning back. Excitedly.</charAction>
            They're getting closer! <charAction>Aang jumps off the tree. Cut to side-view as he runs
                toward the edge of the island, Momo in his wake.</charAction> The whole island is
            moving!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to side-view of the island as Aang leaps out from the brush and jumps
                in to the water. Cut underwater as Aang dives down. Cut to Momo landing on a branch
                looking down at where Aang entered the water and chitters. Cut to side-view of Aang
                underwater as he swims down. Cut to a frontal view as he inspects the island. Cut to
                a wide-view as a paw moves past him. Cut to frontal view of Aang who hovers for a
                moment before swimming up to the surface. Cut to the surface of the water as Aang
                emerges, gasping for breath, and Momo lands nearby.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's amazing Momo! The biggest animal in the world! I've gotta to swim around and
            find its face. <charAction>Momo chitters in response and he swims off toward the front
                of the "island". Momo follows him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial view of Momo flying above Aang, who is swimming in the
                water below. Cut to a distance view of the entire island from behind. Cut to aerial
                view of the White Lotus camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Uncle, you're the only person other than the
            Avatar who can <charAction>Side-view of Iroh with Zuko sat next to him. Toph sits to
                Zuko's right and Katara has her back to the camera opposite Toph.</charAction>
            possibly defeat the Father Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You mean the Fire Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> That's what I just said!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Hmmm ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We need you to come with us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> No, Zuko, it won't turn out well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Aerial view of the group.</charAction> You can beat him!
                <charAction>Turns to the others.</charAction> And we'll be there to help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Even if I did defeat Ozai, <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> and I don't know that
            I could, it would be the wrong way to end the war. <charAction>Aerial view of the
                group.</charAction> History would see it as just more senseless violence, a brother
            killing a brother to grab power. The only way for this war to end peacefully is for the
            Avatar to defeat the Fire Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up of Zuko from over Iroh's shoulder.</charAction> And then ...
            then you would come and take your rightful place on the throne?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> No. Someone new must take the throne. An idealist
            with a pure heart <charAction>Frontal view from the side of Iroh as the camera zooms in
                on Zuko.</charAction> and unquestionable honor. It has to be
                you, Prince Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko briefly looks away.</charAction> Unquestionable honor? But I've
            made so many mistakes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yes, you have. <charAction>Close-up of Iroh from over Zuko's shoulder.</charAction>
            You've struggled; you've suffered, but you have always followed your own path.
                <charAction>Close-up of Zuko.</charAction> You restored your
                own honor, and only you can restore the honor of the Fire
            Nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko looks away.</charAction> I'll try, Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Side-view of Toph.</charAction> Well, what if Aang doesn't come
            back?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Aerial view of group.</charAction> Sozin's Comet is arriving, and our
            destinies are upon us. Aang will face the Fire Lord. <charAction>Extreme
                close-up.</charAction> When I was a boy, I had a vision that I would one day take Ba
            Sing Se. <charAction>Cut to Zuko and the camera pans across to right showing Toph,
                Sokka, Suki, and Katara.</charAction> Only now do I see that my destiny is to take
            it back from the Fire Nation, <charAction>Extreme
                close-up.</charAction> so the Earth Kingdom can be free again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Side-view of Suki and Katara.</charAction> That's why you gathered the
            members of the White Lotus.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yes. <charAction>Close-up from over Zuko's shoulder.</charAction> Zuko, you must
            return to the Fire Nation, so that when the Fire Lord falls, you can assume the throne
            and restore peace and order. <charAction>Extreme close-up of Zuko.</charAction> But
            Azula will be there, waiting for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I can handle Azula.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Not alone! <charAction>Frontal view of Iroh from the side of Zuko.</charAction>
            You'll need help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Extreme close-up.</charAction> You're right. Katara, <charAction>Frontal
                view of Katara over Zuko's shoulder.</charAction> how would you like to help me put
            Azula in her place?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It would be my pleasure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What about us? <charAction>Side-view of Toph with Sokka sitting to the right and
                behind.</charAction> What's our destiny today?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> What do you think it is?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> I think that, even though we don't know where
            Aang is, we need to do everything we can to stop the airship fleet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Camera pans back and to the left to Toph.</charAction> And that means
            when Aang does face the Fire Lord, we'll be right there if he needs us.
                <charAction>Close-up of Iroh, who smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to side-view of Toph and Suki on board an eel hound. The camera zooms
                out to show the entire eel hound and Sokka and Piandao are on the ground beside
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Nothing runs faster over land or swims quicker than a giant eel hound.
                <charAction>Frontal view of Piandao with Sokka's back to the camera. Piandao hands
                Sokka a map, who examines it.</charAction> The air ship base is on a small island
            just off the Earth Kingdom shore. <charAction>Frontal view of Sokka over the shoulder of
                Piandao.</charAction> You should be able to intercept the fleet within a day's
            journey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He puts the map away.</charAction> Thank you, Master.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to frontal view as they bow to each other before Sokka hugs Piandao.
                Camera pans right to Appa, with Zuko up front and Katara in the
                saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>To Iroh.</charAction> So if I'm going to be Fire Lord after the war is
            over, <charAction>Side-view of Zuko.</charAction> what are you going to do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> After I re-conquer Ba Sing Se, I'm going to
            re-conquer my tea shop, and I'm going to play Pai Sho every day. <charAction>Flips a Pai
                Sho piece and catches it as he speaks.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Zuko with Katara, in the background, as they both look
                left. Cut to Sokka, Toph, and Suki looking back and Sokka nods. Cuts to a aerial
                shot of the entire group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Goodbye, General Iroh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Goodbye, everyone. Today, destiny is our friend.
                <charAction>Whispers.</charAction> I know it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to aerial view as the eel hound sets off followed soon after by Appa.
                The camera pans up slightly as the Order of the White Lotus members wave. Cuts back
                to the side of the island, now close to the mountains. Cut to the top of the trees
                on the island and the camera pans down to Aang swimming in the water. Aang stops and
                Momo chitters behind him as he dives in the water. Cut underwater as Aang swims to
                the front of the island to take a closer look. Cut to frontal view of Aang and the
                camera pans down to follow him as he swims. He stops and an eye opens behind him.
                Cut to frontal view of a surprised Aang and he swims back as a giant paw moves
                underneath him and lifts him up. Cut to above the water as Aang and the paw emerge.
                A wave of water covers the camera view before falling down to reveal a face. The
                camera cuts and zooms out to show the entire creature as Aang stands on it's
                paw.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Side-view.</charAction> A lion turtle! <charAction>Frontal view. Bows to
                it. Frontal view of Lion turtle.</charAction> Maybe you can help me. Everyone, even
            my own past lives, are expecting me to end someone's life. <charAction>Frontal
                view.</charAction> But I don't know if I can do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lion turtle">
         <charAction>Frontal view of the lion turtle's face from behind Aang. The lion
                turtle's mouth is not moving, yet it is speaking to Aang.</charAction> The true mind
            can weather all the lies and illusions without being lost. The true heart can tough the
            poison of hatred without being harmed. <charAction>Extreme close-up of its left
                eye.</charAction> Since beginningless time, <charAction>Side-view of the lion turtle
                as it lifts it's other paw out of the water and moves it toward Aang.</charAction>
            darkness thrives in the void but always yields to purifying light.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The lion turtle placed two claws on Aang, one on his forehead and the other
                on his chest, and a bright light issues forth from it. Fade to side-view of the lion
                turtle's paw as it moves slowly toward a small cliff in the Earth Kingdom, and Aang
                steps off onto dry land. Momo flies onto Aang's shoulder. Cut to frontal view of the
                lion turtle from behind Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lion turtle">Wait for him. He will come.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang bows to the lion turtle. The lion turtle sinks under the water.
                Frontal view of Aang as he stands up out of the bow. Cut to wide-view of the lion
                turtle swimming away. Cut to frontal view of Aang, who leaps off-camera. Cut to a
                wide-view of Ozai's base.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> It's time for this world to end in fire, and for
            a new world to be born from the ashes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera backs up as he speaks revealing his airship fleet. Cut to the comet,
                which enters Earth's atmosphere. Cut back to behind Ozai, before panning right
                fading to Aang and Momo from behind in a different location. Cut to a frontal view
                of Aang. Cuts to close-up of the comet, followed by a close-up of Aang's face with
                the comet behind him on the horizon. Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
