<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="20">The Siege of the North Part 2</title>
      <director>Dave Filoni</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2005-12-02</date>
      <location nation="water">Northern Water Tribe</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to the Northern Water Tribe as the siege continues. Four
                fireballs streak past the screen. Cuts to overhead shot of the city as the fireballs
                strike various locations. The camera pans downward past the Tribal Chief's palace to
                the Spirit Oasis where Appa can be seen presiding by the pond. Cuts to shot of the
                two koi fish, the Moon and Ocean Spirits, swimming in their usual circular pattern.
            </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Off-screen; sorrowfully.</charAction> I can't believe I lost
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to full shot of the pond, Sokka and Yue standing beside Katara, who is
                kneeling on the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You did everything you could, and now we need to do everything we can to get him
            back. <charAction>Cuts to shot of Katara who looks up at her brother, tears in her
                eyes.</charAction> Zuko can't have gotten far. We'll find him. Aang's gonna be
            fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay. <charAction>Closes eyes and gets up. Camera pans over to where Momo remains
                motionless on the ground. Cuts to shot of Appa, Katara having mounted the
                bison.</charAction> It's all right. You stay here, Momo, in case Aang comes
            back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yip, yip.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans upward as Appa takes off, heading upward to a location
                above the oasis, a vast frozen tundra where a blizzard is raging. Cuts to shot of
                the icy terrain of the tundra as the bison progresses. Cuts to shot of the ground, a
                path visible in the snow where someone has clearly been trudging along; the camera
                pans upward. Cuts to shot of Zuko plodding through the snow, his face partially
                covered to protect him from the cold, Aang slung across his back. Cuts to shot of an
                unconscious Aang, his tattooed arrows glowing.</description>
      <description>The scene changes suddenly, zooming out on Aang who is sitting in a
                meditating position on a small wooden platform in an unknown location in the Spirit
                World. Cuts to shot of his surroundings which are not that of the icy tundra, but a
                mystical swamp dotted with trees. A large white bird of some sort flies past. Cuts
                to shot of Aang as the bird flies over the screen; he stands and begins wandering
                about. Cuts to shot of a figure in the distance sitting beneath a simple wooden
                entranceway. The figure can be heard uttering the sound "Ohm". Aang appears
                on-screen, turns his head in the direction of the sound and begins making his way
                toward the figure. Cuts to side-view of the figure, a monkey-like creature, as Aang
                approaches him, before cutting to a shot of the two with the figure's back to the
                camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hello? I'm sorry to disturb you. I just really need to find the Moon and the Ocean
            Spirits.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Baboon spirit">
         <charAction>Cut to a frontal shot of the baboon spirit.</charAction> Go. Away.
                <charAction>Opens one eye. Cut back to the side-shot.</charAction> You're still
            here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yes, I need -</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Baboon spirit">
         <charAction>Cut to close-up of the baboon spirit who shuts his eyes tightly. Louder,
                trying to distract himself.</charAction> Ohm! <charAction>A firefly flies past;
                points at the insect.</charAction> Perhaps that thing will help you. Chase it.
                <charAction>Aang runs after it. The mystical monkey keeps his eyes shut for a second
                more before opening one to confirm Aang's departure. He shakes his head and breathes
                a sigh of relief.</charAction> Finally.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of Aang chasing the insect throughout the swamp and up a
                tree. He leaps up and manages to grasp hold of it and is delighted in doing so. Cuts
                to zoomed out shot of him as he lands on a tree branch which instantly shrivels up
                and disappears entirely, causing him to fall. Cuts briefly to close-up shot of an
                alarmed Aang before switching to a shot of him falling into the water. Aang is shown
                lying on his back in the water, the firefly having escaped his grip. It flies away
                as he tries to reach it again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He stands up. Cuts to shot of him looking down at the water, when Roku
                suddenly appears before Aang in a reflection in the water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Hello, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at him; surprised.</charAction> Roku!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts back to the real world, where Zuko continues his trek
                through the icy tundra. Cuts to close-up of him before a shot of the ground where he
                steps on ice that begins cracking beneath his feet; his eyes widen in surprise at
                this. Cuts to overhead shot of him, the camera zooming out, as the ice begins to
                splinter and cave in. Cuts to shot of him on high alert as he begins running, before
                switching to an overhead shot of him as he races through the snow. Cuts to shot of
                him as the impact of the ice caving in throws him off-balance.</description>
      <description>Zuko is thrown several feet away and lands roughly in the snow, losing his
                grip on Aang and kicking up a cloud of snow. The cloud dissipates, showing Zuko and
                Aang lying in the snow. Cuts to shot of Zuko, as he raises his head and looks at the
                scene. Cuts to shot of the aftermath of the cave-in, the ground severely disrupted,
                and a shot of Zuko once more. He spots a cave off in the distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Shelter. <charAction>Drags Aang into the cave and ties him up.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back in the Spirit World, Aang is speaking with Roku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Roku, the Water Tribe's under attack. I need to find the Ocean and the Moon
            Spirits.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Pops out of the reflection in front of Aang.</charAction> The Ocean and
            the Moon are ancient spirits. They crossed over the Spirit World to the mortal world
            very near the beginning. There is only one spirit I know of who is old enough to
            remember.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Who?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">The spirit's name is Koh, but he is very dangerous. They call him the Face Stealer.
                <charAction>Aang looks horrified.</charAction> When you speak with him, you must be
            very careful to show no emotion at all. Not the slightest expression, or he will steal
            your face. <charAction>Aang looks even more horrified but calmly nods, understanding the
                situation.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, in the real world, Katara, Sokka, and Yue arrive to where the
                ice broke earlier. In the cave, Zuko is keeping warm with Breath of Fire while Aang,
                now tied up, remains in the Spirit World.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I finally have you, but I can't get you home because of this blizzard.
                <charAction>Stands up and looks outside the cave.</charAction> There's always
            something. Not that you would understand. You're like my sister. Everything always came
            easy to her. She's a firebending prodigy, and everyone adores her. My father says she
            was born lucky. He says I was lucky to be born. I don't need luck, though. I don't want
            it. I've always had to struggle and fight and that's made me strong. It's made me who I
            am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, back at the invasion, the Fire Nation has breached part of the
                wall. On the lead ship, Zhao and Iroh are speaking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I don't need to remind you we have a time limit. If we don't defeat the Water Tribe
            before the full moon rises, they will be undefeatable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I assure you I have everything under control. I intend to remove the moon as a
            factor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Remove the moon? How?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Hahn appears behind them and points his spear at Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hahn">Admiral Choi! Prepare to meet your fate!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He charges at Zhao, who casually tosses him overboard as he is still
                screaming. A loud splash is heard, while Iroh shakes his head in
                disappointment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Continuing as if nothing happened.</charAction> As I was saying, years
            ago I stumble upon a great and powerful secret: the identity of the Moon Spirit's mortal
            form.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I was a young lieutenant serving under General Shu in the Earth Kingdom.
                <charAction>Fade to a flashback of a young Zhao tearing through scrolls in a
                library.</charAction> I discovered a hidden library. Underground, in fact. I tore
            through scroll after scroll. One of them contained a detailed illustration, and the
            words "moon" and "ocean". I knew then that these spirits could be found and killed.
                <charAction>The memory ends with a close up of Zhao's eyes, fade to the
                present.</charAction> And that it was my destiny to do so.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Somewhat angrily.</charAction> Zhao, the spirits are not to be trifled
            with!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Yes, yes ... I know you fear the spirits, Iroh. I've heard rumors about your journey
            into the Spirit World. But the Ocean and Moon gave up their immortality to become a part
            of our world. And now they will face the consequences.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back in the Spirit World, Aang walks up a giant tree, seeing the entrance
                to the cave Koh can be found in. Aang stares and slightly steps toward the cave
                hearing creepy noises. He glances to his left noticing that the noise wasn't coming
                from the cave. Aang sighs in relief.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You're just a curly tailed blue nose.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The monkey turns its head toward Aang, exposing that he has no
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Startled.</charAction> Aaahhh! <charAction>Aang takes a deep breath and
                speaks with his and Avatar Roku's voices combined.</charAction> Show no fear. Show
            no emotion at all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang steps into the cave with a straight face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hello? I-I'm looking for a spirit named 'Koh'.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Aang says the spirit's name, some "roots" on the ceiling begin to move.
                Aang looks around, sensing movement, but sees nothing. Cut to a close-up of Aang's
                face that pans slightly left, leaving the right hand portion of the screen over his
                shoulder momentarily empty. A moment later, a white face appears with gray patches
                around its eyes and luscious, blood-red lips. Cut to a close-up of the lips, which
                smile. Cut to a profile of Aang, his face emotionless. Suddenly, a huge
                centipede-like body arcs around Aang and appears in front of his face. The white,
                clown-like face of Koh is inches away from Aang. Around the spirit's face are eight
                additional legs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Creepily, circling Aang.</charAction> Welcome!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang keeps his face straight. Cut to a long shot; the spirit hangs from the
                ceiling in front of Aang, who bows with his hands clasped in front of him in a
                gesture of honor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Emotionlessly.</charAction> Thank you. <charAction>Koh wheels around
                Aang to look at him from behind. His voice is low and melodic, almost
                purring.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">My old friend, the Avatar. It's been a long time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You know me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Now facing the camera, away from Aang.</charAction> How could I forget
                <charAction>He switches with a "winking" effect, as if some sort of nictitating
                membrane closes briefly over the old face to reveal a new one, to a mad face of a
                middle-aged, mustached man with thick eyebrows, long mustache, and beard;
                angrily.</charAction> you? One of your previous incarnations tried to slay me!
            Nearly eight or nine hundred years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confused, yet seriously.</charAction> I didn't know that. Why did he, or
            I, try to kill you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Switches to Ummi's scared, sad face.</charAction> Oh, it was something
            about stealing the face of someone you loved. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Aang with
                the camera slowing, zooming in on his face. Cut back to Koh, whose face turns
                malicious and switches to a baboon's while laughing. Switch to a side-shot; Aang
                keeps a straight face while not taking his eyes off Koh as he circles around
                him.</charAction> Of course, that's all behind us. Why should I hold a grudge
            against you for something in a past life? After all, you're a different person now.
                <charAction>Speaks into Aang's ear from behind.</charAction> You've come to me ...
            with a new face.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang closes his eyes and takes a deep breath to the words into his ear,
                crossing the scene to the real world, Zuko seeing his breath.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Guess we'll be here awhile.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to exterior of the cave. Cut to Appa in the blizzard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Don't worry, Prince Zuko can't be getting too far in this weather.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm not worried they'll get away in the blizzard. I'm worried that they
            won't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">They're not going to die in this blizzard. If we know anything, it's that Zuko never
            gives up. They'll survive, and we'll find them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The screen flashes white back to the Spirit World to Aang's talk with the
                face stealer, Koh circling loosely around Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Continues to circle around Aang.</charAction> It's been a long time
            since I've added a child's face to my collection. <charAction>His face is now that of an
                owl.</charAction> So ... how may I help you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I need to find the moon and the ocean.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">Their spirit names are Tui and La, push and pull. And that has been the nature of
            their relationship for all time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Side-view of Aang.</charAction> Please. Help me find them. An entire
            culture could be destroyed if I don't get their help. <charAction>Top-down view of Koh
                who changes his face to that of an old man. Aang is visible below
            him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">Oh, you think you need their help. <charAction>Koh looks to the side.</charAction>
            Actually it's quite the other way round. <charAction>In an instant, Koh turns and bolts
                to Aang, stopping just short of the young Avatar; with an angry blue ogre-like face
                with red eyes and upright fangs.</charAction>
         Someone's going to kill them!&gt;
         <charAction>Aang closes his eyes briefly before opening them to look at
                Koh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What do you mean? How can I find them and protect them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Flipping back to his white face.</charAction> You've already met them,
            actually. <charAction>View of Koh from behind Aang as Koh moves to look away, turning
                his back on Aang.</charAction> Tui and La, your moon and ocean, have always circled
            each other in an eternal dance. They balance each other, push and pull, life and death,
                <charAction>Close-up of Aang's face.</charAction> good and evil, yin and
            yang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang's eyes open wide as he experiences a flashback of the white and black
                fish circling each other in the pond and the vision he had of them as they turned
                into the yin and yang symbol just before he entered the Spirit World. Back to
                Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> The koi fish! <charAction>Hearing the emotion in
                Aang's voice, Koh quickly reels around to stare at the now expressionless face of
                Aang.</charAction> I must be going now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koh">
         <charAction>Flipping to the face of a bald, young man.</charAction> We'll meet
            again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Koh recedes into the shadows as Aang walks out of his cave. Cut to Aang
                running in front of the tree that is Koh's lair. He stops and talks to the
                ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The spirits are in trouble, I need to get back to the physical world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Cut to Roku's image on the ground.</charAction> A friend is here, to
            guide you back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aang turns around; excitedly.</charAction> Hei Bai!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The spirit groans as Aang jumps onto him and sets off. Cut back to the
                physical world. Two fireballs hit the city. Cut to two Water Tribe members fleeing
                as a tank destroys a totem pole behind them. Cut to two Water Tribe members trying
                to stop a tank. Cut to a view of the ocean with many fire navy ships and the moon
                looming behind. Cut to a bridge as two fire navy soldiers move in front of the
                camera as a waterbender drops down to move the bridge back from where the fire navy
                soldiers came from, taking the soldiers with it. Cut to a waterbender facing a tank,
                submerging the tank in the snow and ice around it. Cut to waterbenders attacking
                fire navy soldiers with shards of ice, who use shields to protect themselves. Cut to
                a shot behind Pakku who freezes and takes down eight oncoming soldiers. Pakku dodges
                a fire blast, having become surrounded with tanks and soldiers. Unleashing a wave of
                water he slices tanks wheels off and freezes soldiers behind him in ice. Pakku lifts
                himself into the air with water while being fired upon by firebenders. Avoiding the
                blasts, he knocks the firebenders away using his water cyclone as a wave. Cut to
                waterbenders sending a tank flying toward Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">We'll be following this map to a very special location. And when we get there, we're
            going fishing. <charAction>He smirks.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the Spirit World. Aang arrives at his starting location and
                jumps off Hei Bai.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is where I came in, but how do I get back?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Hei Bai stands on his hind legs and sends a beam of energy at Aang, who
                disappears to the physical world.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Baboon spirit">
         <charAction>Cut to baboon spirit sitting on a rock. Opening his eyes.</charAction>
            Good riddance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Hei Bai, having assumed his monstrous form, shoots an intense beam from his
                mouth at the baboon spirit sending it flying, before reverting to his original form.
                Back in the physical world, cut to a view of the arch way and water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Momo! <charAction>Walking toward Momo. Closer view of Aang with Momo.</charAction>
            Momo. Oh no, where's my body?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang is surrounded by energy and flies into the air. Cut to a wide-view of
                the entire Water Tribe city as Aang continues to fly toward the cave. Cut to close
                shot of Katara. Noticing Aang she turns around. Cut to shot of Appa flying in the
                sky as Aang shoots past overhead to the cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Look, that's gotta be Aang! Yip-yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang entering the cave, filling it with light. Cut to Aang waking
                up, attempting to get out of his restraints and noticing Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Welcome back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to close-up of Aang as he narrows his eyes.</charAction> It's good
            to be back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends Zuko into a wall and propelling himself backward out of the
                cave. Cut to cave exterior. Close-up of Aang wriggling like a worm in an attempt to
                get away, only to be caught by Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko pulls Aang up by his collar as seen from behind Aang.</charAction>
            That won't be enough to escape.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>On seeing Appa.</charAction> Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa lands. Katara slides off. Close-up of Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Throwing the tied-up Aang aside who yelps.</charAction> Here for a
            rematch?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Confidently while countering his fire blasts.</charAction> Trust me
            Zuko, it's not going to be much of a match.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara uses waterbending to launch Zuko into the air before plummeting him
                down to the ground, knocking him out. Close-up shot of Sokka running toward Aang to
                untie him with Zuko lying unconscious.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, this is some quality rope!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We need to get to the oasis; the spirits are in trouble!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a wide-view of the area with Aang airbending himself atop Appa.
                Close-up shot of Aang landing on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait, we can't just leave him here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Sure we can. Let's go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, if we leave him he'll die.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends himself off Appa and retrieves Zuko, bringing him to
                Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, this makes a lot of sense. Let's bring
            the guy who's constantly trying to kill us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa takes off. Cut to Tui and La in the oasis lake. Zhao grabs Tui from
                the water, placing it in a sack. The moon goes red, followed by everything else. Cut
                to close-up of the now red moon. Cut to a view of the entire city turning red. Cut
                to Pakku who loses his waterbending and falls to the ground. Cut to a waterbender
                attempting to waterbend but loses his bending. Cut to three more waterbenders,
                bending water, but they too lose their bending. Cut to Fire Navy soldiers
                firebending. Cut to Appa flying with the red moon behind him. Appa groans as it cuts
                to the saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Yue grabs her head as if in pain.</charAction> Are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">I feel faint.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang. Holding his head with one hand.</charAction> I feel it,
            too. The Moon Spirit is in trouble.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Cut back to the saddle.</charAction> I owe the Moon Spirit my
            life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What do you mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Close-up of Yue.</charAction> When I was born I was very sick and very
            weak. <charAction>Flashback to Yue as a baby.</charAction> Most babies cry when they're
            born, but I was born as if I was asleep, my eyes closed. <charAction>Cut to waterbenders
                attempting to heal Yue as a baby.</charAction> Our healers did everything they
            could. <charAction>Panning shot of Yue and the waterbenders, along with Yue's
                parents.</charAction> They told my mother and father I was going to die.
                <charAction>Cut to Arnook staring at the moon.</charAction> My father pleaded with
            the spirits to save me. <charAction>Cut to shot panning down from the moon to the
                oasis.</charAction> That night, beneath the full moon, he brought me to the oasis
            and placed me in the pond. <charAction>Cut to Yue being placed into the
                pond.</charAction> My dark hair turned white. <charAction>Close-up of Yue in the
                oasis.</charAction> I opened my eyes and began to cry, and they knew I would live.
                <charAction>Cut to Yue in her parents arms with the archway and moon behind
                them.</charAction> That's why my mother named me Yue. <charAction>Cut back to Appa's
                saddle.</charAction> For the moon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Cut to Zhao at the oasis.</charAction> I am ... a legend, now!
                <charAction>Cut to panning shot from Zhao's hand, grasping the bag with Tui in it,
                down to his head.</charAction> The Fire Nation will, for generations, tell stories
            about the great Zhao, who darkened the moon. They will call me, Zhao the Conqueror, Zhao
            the Moon Slayer, Zhao the Invincible! <charAction>Momo jumps on top of Zhao's
                head.</charAction> Ugh ... Get it off! Get it off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide-view of oasis as Momo flies away toward the camera. Panning
                view of Momo landing on Aang's arm and running to his shoulder, with Katara and
                Sokka are behind him. Cut to Zhao and his soldiers, readying themselves for battle.
                Cut to Aang, Sokka and Katara readying themselves. Panning shot of the
                oasis.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Don't bother. <charAction>Close-up of Zhao as he lifts the sack up threatening to
                kill Tui.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and the others surrendering.</charAction> Zhao,
            don't!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Cut to panning side-view.</charAction> It's my destiny, to destroy the
            moon and the Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view of Aang.</charAction> Destroying the moon won't hurt
            just the Water Tribe. <charAction>Close-up panning shot of the sack with Tui inside and
                Zhao.</charAction> It will hurt everyone, including you. <charAction>Cut to panning
                shot of the oasis.</charAction> Without the moon, everything would fall out of
            balance. You have no idea what kind of chaos that would unleash on the world.
                <charAction>Cut to Zhao.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> He is right Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Cut to wide shot of oasis; calmly to Iroh.</charAction> General Iroh,
            why am I not surprised to discover your treachery?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up of Iroh while he takes off his hood.</charAction> I'm no
            traitor, Zhao, the Fire Nation needs the moon, too; we all depend on the balance.
            Whatever you do to that spirit I'll unleash on you ten-fold. Let it go, now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao releases the koi fish into the oasis. Cut to close-up of Zhao as he
                hesitates before striking the koi fish with a fire slice out of anger. Cut to
                wide-view of the oasis. Cut to Iroh recoiling from the flames. Cut to Aang looking
                on and up at the moon. Cut to a view from the oasis to the sky as the moon fades out
                and the world goes gray. Cut to Zhao looking up until Iroh begins firebending at
                him. Zhao dodges and counters his firebending while retreating toward his
                firebending soldiers. They are swiftly defeated as Zhao escapes. Cut to show La
                circling the now dead Tui. Cut to Aang and the others looking on in disbelief and
                moving toward the water. Yue is seen looking on; her forward movement reveals that
                Zuko has escaped from behind her. Iroh picks up the dead koi fish.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Close-up of Yue and Sokka.</charAction> There's no hope now, it's
            over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up of Aang entering the Avatar State.</charAction> No, it's not
            over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide shot of oasis as Aang enters the water. Cut back to the others
                looking on. Aang stands in a meditative stance as La circles him. Close-up shot of
                Aang and La as the latter's eyes light up. Side-view of Aang as he descends into the
                water. Wide shot of the whole oasis as blue lightning-like energy expands from the
                oasis island into the water. Wide shot of the Water Tribe city as the oasis begins
                to light up in the same blue color. Cut back to Katara and the others watching. The
                energy moves to the edge of the oasis, rising up to form a giant amphibious-like
                creature, facing out toward the sea, with Aang in the center, controlling it. Cut to
                the Fire Nation soldiers in the city looking on at this creature's sudden
                appearance. Cut briefly to Pakku and other Northern Water Tribe members before
                changing to a view of Aang moving past a river, Fire Nation soldiers on one side,
                Pakku and his group on the other. The Water Tribe all bow down as the Fire Nation
                soldiers prepare to attack. Aang, controlling the massive creature, begins to head
                to the ocean, laying waste to any Fire Nation soldiers on the way. </description>
      <description>Cut back to Zhao who continues to flee only to be attacked by
                Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">You're alive?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You tried to have me killed! <charAction>Zuko
                attacks Zhao.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Close-up of Zhao's face.</charAction> Yes I did. <charAction>Zuko
                approaches Zhao as we see the giant energy form make its way toward the
                ocean.</charAction> You're the Blue Spirit, an enemy of the Fire Nation! You freed
            the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I had no choice. <charAction>Zuko continues his attacks, but they are blocked by
                Zhao.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">You should have chosen to accept your failure; you're a disgrace. Then, at least,
            you could have lived! <charAction>Zuko and Zhao begin to fight.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the oasis, Iroh places the dead koi fish in the
                water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's too late, it's dead.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Iroh notices Yue.</charAction> You have been touched by the Moon Spirit.
                <charAction>Close-up of Yue.</charAction> Some of its life is in you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Yes, you're right. It gave me life, maybe I can give it back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No! You don't have to do that. <charAction>Sokka reached to stop
            her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">It's my duty, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I won't let you! <charAction>Close-up of him holding her hand.</charAction> Your
            father told me to protect you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Close-up of Yue.</charAction> I have to do this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yue's hand slips out of Sokka's as she places her hands on the koi fish.
                The koi begins to glow and Yue closes her eyes. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Yue falls as Sokka catches her.</charAction> No! She's gone, she's
            gone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang as he approaches the sea and sends the fire navy ships back out
                into the ocean. Aang continues to destroy ships and drive the rest back out. Cut
                back to Sokka holding Yue. Yue fades and disappears as the koi begins the light up
                and glow. Iroh places the koi back into the oasis water. The entire lake begins to
                light up until energy floats up into the air forming an image of Yue. Side-view of
                the oasis.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Goodbye, Sokka. <charAction>Close-up of Sokka and Yue as she comes to kiss
                him.</charAction> I'll always be with you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They kiss and Yue disappears as Sokka looks up to the moon as it reappears
                in the sky, bringing the color back. Cut to Aang, still fused with the Ocean Spirit,
                in front of the Water Tribe city. Aang looks up and notices the moon has returned.
                The Ocean Spirit fades into the water and moves back to the city, dropping Aang off
                on a wall as he leaves the Avatar State.</description>
      <description>Cut to Zuko and Zhao fighting on a bridge. Zuko gains the upper hand and
                Zhao notices the moon has returned.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Shot of the moon over Zhao's shoulder.</charAction> It can't
            be!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao is consumed by the energy in the shape of a hand and dragged toward
                the water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Take my hand!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao considers it for a moment before retracting his hand. The energy
                plummets into the water, Zhao dragged along with it, and dissipates. Cut to Pakku
                and others on a ledge overlooking the city. Cut to a close-up shot of Pakku, Katara
                stands behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I've decide to go to the South Pole. Some other benders and healers want to join me.
            It's time we helped rebuild our sister tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What about Aang? He still needs to learn waterbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Well, then he better get used to calling you Master Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Arnook and Sokka standing on the ledge looking at the
                moon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">The spirits gave me a vision when Yue was born. I saw a beautiful, brave, young
            woman become the Moon Spirit. <charAction>Sighs.</charAction> I knew this day would
            come.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You must be proud.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">So proud ... and sad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko and Iroh on a raft floating away from the city.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm surprised Prince Zuko, surprised that you are not at this moment trying to
            capture the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm tired.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Then you should rest. A man needs his rest.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang looking out on the ledge in the city. Katara stands behind him.
                He realizes she's there and turns around. They embrace. Momo chitters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You too, Momo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo leaps on to Aang's shoulders as we see Sokka place his hand on Aang's
                shoulder. All four of them look out to the ocean and the moon as Appa rises up in
                front of them.</description>
      <description>Cut to Fire Lord Ozai's chambers. Cut to panning shot of
                Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">Iroh is a traitor, and your brother Zuko is a failure. I have a task for
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Azula, looking up and smiling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
