<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="52">The Firebending Masters</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>John O' Bryan</writer>
      <date>2008-07-15</date>
      <location nation="air">Western Air Temple</location>
      <location nation="fire">Sun Warriors' Ancient City</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens with a shot of the sky from the Western Air Temple, and
                the camera pans below to Zuko and Aang standing on the balcony of an upside down
                pagoda in the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I know you're nervous, but remember, firebending in it of itself is
                not something to fear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang, as he sighs heavily.</charAction> Okay. Not something to
            fear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko from behind Aang.</charAction> But if you don't respect it,
                <charAction>He raises his voice, as the camera zooms to a close-up of his
                face.</charAction> it'll chew you up and spit you out like an angry komodo
            rhino!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang's face, as he yelps in fear, before cutting back to
                Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Now show me what you've got. Any amount of fire you can make.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang, as he inhales nervously and tries to firebend. Cut to a
                close-up of his palm, as a small cloud of smoke appears, and is dissipated. Camera
                pans left to Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Maybe I need a little more instruction. Perhaps a demonstration?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of the both.</charAction> Good idea. You might
            wanna take a couple steps back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang walks back, and shot cuts to a close-up of Zuko's face, as he inhales
                deeply. Screen zooms back to show Zuko grunting, and cuts to his fist, which lets
                out a very small flame. Aang applauds at this display.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Takes a step back.</charAction> What was that? That was the worst
            firebending I've ever seen!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang.</charAction> I thought it was ... nice. <charAction>Smiles
                slightly and shrugs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko grunts again and tries firebending again, with all three attempts
                resulting in very small flames similar to the first. He grunts and looks at his
                palms.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frustrated.</charAction> Why is this happening?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubbing his head, confused.</charAction> Maybe it's the
            altitude.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning back.</charAction> Yeah, could be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to some pagodas and pans below to Aang sitting on a broken
                pillar and Zuko standing. Zuko attempts firebending, which results in a similar
                small flame again. He grunts and delivers another similar blast, as Aang yawns and
                lies down on the pillar.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Just breathe, and ... <charAction>He delivers another blast with no
                improvement.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Gets up.</charAction> That one kind of felt hot.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Very angry.</charAction> Don't patronize me! You know what it's supposed
            to look like!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sorry, Sifu Hotman.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Raises his arms to his head, and throws them down back, and shouts in
                frustration, as Aang cringes.</charAction> And stop calling me that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Sokka walking toward the teacher and his pupil, eating an
                apple. Sokka sits down near the two, as they turn their heads toward
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, jerks! Mind if I watch you two jerks do your jerkbending?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frustrated.</charAction> Get out of here! <charAction>He lashes his arm
                and points to a side.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay, take it easy. <charAction>He drops his half-eaten apple.</charAction> I was
            just kiddin' around. <charAction>He gets up and turns around, laughing as he adjusts his
                shirt.</charAction> Jerkbending, still got it. <charAction>Zuko drops his head,
                dejected, and moans.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to an aerial shot of Appa resting near a fountain at night,
                and zooms to show him eating a small bale of hay. Screen pans to the right to show
                Zuko leaning on a column with his arms crossed, looking below and thinking deeply.
                He turns his head to the campfire where everyone is settled for dinner, and walks
                toward them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Listen everybody, I've got some pretty bad news. I've lost my stuff. <charAction>He
                looks below dejectedly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Raises both hands to her head.</charAction> Don't look at me,
                <charAction>She folds her arms.</charAction> I didn't touch your stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm talking about my firebending. It's gone. <charAction>He looks below
                again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Sokka, Haru, The Duke, and Teo looking at him, as the former Freedom
                Fighter sits up. Camera pans left, as Katara laughs, and everyone's attention is
                focused on her. Zuko looks at the waterbender with an annoyed
                expression.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm sorry. I'm just laughing at the irony. You know, how it would've been nice for
            us if you lost your firebending a long time ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Camera zooms back to show everyone sitting around the campfire and Zuko
                standing.</charAction> Well, it's not lost. It's just ... weaker for some
            reason.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Holding up her bowl and glaring at Zuko.</charAction> Maybe you're not
            as good as you think you are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Screen pans left to Toph.</charAction> Ouch. <charAction>She smiles
                sarcastically.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>With an idea.</charAction> I bet it's because I changed sides.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Still holding her bowl.</charAction> That's ridiculous. <charAction>She
                drinks from the bowl.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know. Maybe it isn't. Maybe your firebending comes from rage and you just
            don't have enough anger to fuel it the way you used to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Leans toward Zuko and points a finger above.</charAction> Sooo, all we
            need to do is make Zuko angry. Easy enough.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka pokes Zuko with his sword's hilt in the head and waist several times,
                laughing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Okay, cut it out! <charAction>Sokka stops poking, as his sword slips from his hands
                and is thrown above, before falling on his head. Zuko rubs his nose.</charAction>
            Look, even if you're right, I don't want to rely on hate and anger anymore. There has to
            be another way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Cut to Toph, as Sokka sits near her, and rubs his head.</charAction>
            You're gonna need to learn to draw your firebending from a different source. I recommend
            the original source. <charAction>Eats the food from her bowl.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> How's he supposed to do that‌? By jumping into a
            volcano‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">No. Zuko needs to go back to whatever the original source of firebending
            is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Seriously.​</charAction> So, is it jumping into a volcano?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I don't know. <charAction>Places her bowl down as the shot cuts to a close-up of her
                face.</charAction> For earthbending, the original benders were badgermoles.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a cave in a flashback as a younger Toph wearing a gown is
                kneeling down, and crying, as screen zooms out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> One day, when I was little, I ran away and hid
            in a cave.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the younger Toph's face, as she is startled by a rumbling noise, and
                part of the cave's wall breaks. Shot cuts to behind Toph to show one of a
                badgermole's legs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">That's where I met them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph cringes in fear, and the badgermole comes into the screen near Toph
                and sniffs her. Toph sniffs back and the badgermole licks her cheek, causing her to
                giggle in delight. She touches the badgermole's snout with both hands before licking
                it, and giggles again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">They were blind, just like me. <charAction>The badgermole walks away as Toph
                attempts to crawls after it.</charAction> So we understood each other. I was able to
            learn earthbending, <charAction>Cut to an overhead shot of the badgermole, which moves
                its paws in a sweeping motion.</charAction> not just as a martial art, but as an
            extension of my senses. <charAction>Screen fades to an overhead shot of Toph mimicking
                the creature's actions.</charAction> For them, the original earthbenders,
                <charAction>The badgermole comes across a pile of rocks and earthbends them to the
                side.</charAction> it wasn't just about fighting. It was their way of interacting
            with the world. <charAction>She stops crawling and stands up. She earthbends a stone and
                smiles at her success.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen fades from the younger Toph's face back to the present Toph's
                smiling face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's amazing, Toph!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of the group.</charAction> I learned from the
            monks, but the original airbenders were the sky bison. <charAction>Camera pans above to
                show a mural of three sky bison. Aang leans back to look at Appa.</charAction> Maybe
            you can give me a lesson sometime, buddy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa growls from the shed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Well, this doesn't help me. The original firebenders were the dragons, and they're
            extinct.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shot cuts to behind Zuko as he looks at the group.</charAction> What do
            you mean‌? Roku had a dragon, and there were plenty of dragons when I was a
            kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko's face, as he yells.</charAction> Well, they aren't around
            anymore, okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay, okay. <charAction>Moves his arms in an appeasing manner.</charAction> I'm
            sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But maybe there's another way. <charAction>He walks toward a fountain.</charAction>
            The first people to learn from the dragons were the ancient Sun Warriors.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Walks toward Zuko.</charAction> Sun Warriors? Well, I know they weren't
            around when I was a kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning his head toward Aang.</charAction> No, they died off thousands
            of years ago. But their civilization wasn't too far from where we are now.
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of the two from the side, as Zuko turns his head toward
                the Avatar.</charAction> Maybe we can learn something by poking around their
            ruins.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's like the monks used to tell me. Sometimes, the shadows of the past can be felt
            by the present.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, what? <charAction>Aang and Zuko look back at him and the shot cuts to Sokka
                seated.</charAction> Maybe you'll pick up some super old Sun Warrior energy just by
            standing <charAction>Moves his hand in a strange motion.</charAction> where they stood a
            thousand years ago?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot.</charAction> More or less. Either I find a new
            way to firebend, <charAction>Cut to a shot of the two from the side. Zuko turns his head
                toward Aang.</charAction> or the Avatar has to find a new teacher. <charAction>Aang
                looks concerned and worried at Zuko's statement.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Aang and Zuko flying on Appa over an ocean. Cut to a bored
                Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We've been riding for hours. I don't know why, but I thought this thing would be a
            lot faster.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Appa from below, as he growls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turning his head toward Zuko.</charAction> Appa's right, Zuko. In our
            group, typically we start our missions with a more up-beat attitude.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> I can't believe this. <charAction>He lies
                down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Appa flying from behind.</charAction> Don't worry, you'll get the
            hang of it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to an aerial shot of the ocean, as the screen pans above to
                an aerial shot of an island. Scene changes to an aerial shot of Appa descending to
                land on some ruins. The ruins make Aang and Zuko full of awe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang and Zuko">Whoa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Appa landing from the side. Shot cuts to show some mountains and
                pans below to an aerial shot of Aang and Zuko walking through the
                ruins.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Even though these buildings are ancient, there's something eerily familiar about
            them. <charAction>Cut to Aang and Zuko walking.</charAction> I can tell the Fire Sages'
            temples are somehow descended from these.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to some structures as screen pans right to show more of
                them.</charAction> Okay. We've learned something about architecture. <charAction>Cut
                back to the two walking.</charAction> Hopefully, we'll learn something about
            firebending too. The past can be a great teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a tripwire, which is pulled when Aang walks by. He trips and yelps,
                as an overhead shot shows a small portion of the path in front of him going down and
                some spikes coming up from holes. Aang nearly falls on the spikes but blows a blast
                of air from his mouth which thrusts him up, and somersaults on to the other side, as
                he managed to regain balance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Scared.</charAction> Zuko, I think the past is trying to kill
            me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Kneeling down to inspect the spikes.</charAction> I can't believe it.
                <charAction>He picks the tripwire up and examines it.</charAction> This booby trap
            must be centuries old and it still works.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's probably a lot more. Maybe this means we shouldn't be here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko takes two steps back and runs toward the wall adjoining the path. He
                runs on the wall before jumping on the other side of the spikes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Dusting some dirt on his shirt.</charAction> Where's that up-beat
            attitude you were talkin' about? <charAction>He smiles, as Aang turns back. Cut to
                Zuko's point of view of the path as screen pans above to a building.</charAction>
            Besides, people don't make traps unless they've got something worth protecting.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko and Aang coming onto the building from stairs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Look, this seems promising. <charAction>Cut to Zuko and Aang from the behind, as
                they see a carving of a person being surrounded by two dragons who are breathing
                fire at him.</charAction> Though I'm not sure what this tells us about the original
            source of firebending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko and Aang looking at the carving from the side.</charAction>
            They look pretty angry to me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a part of the carving from below as screen pans right to show
                more of it.</charAction> I thought the dragons were friends with the Sun
            Warriors.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Well, they had a funny way of showing it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the both from the side, as Zuko looks down for a moment and
                starts walking, with Aang looking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Zuko, <charAction>Zuko stops walking.</charAction> something happened to the dragons
            in the last hundred years. <charAction>Zuko closes his eyes.</charAction> Something
            you're not telling me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He opens his eyes.</charAction> My great-grandfather Sozin
            happened.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko walks away with Aang following him. Scene changes to the two walking
                on a bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">He started the tradition of hunting dragons for glory. There were the ultimate
            firebenders. <charAction>Cut to them walking from below the bridge, with the screen
                panning right as they walk.</charAction> And if you could conquer one, your
            firebending talents would become legendary and you'd earn the honorary title, Dragon.
                <charAction>They approach a path which has one dragon's statue on both sides, and
                stop walking.</charAction> The last great dragon was conquered long before I was
            born, <charAction>Cut to a close-up of one of the dragon's statue's eyes as Zuko places
                one of his palms on it.</charAction> by my uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to the both from a side.</charAction> But I thought your uncle was
            ... I don't know, good?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">He had a complicated past. <charAction>Cut to Zuko's face.</charAction> Family
            tradition, I guess. Let's just move on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko starts walking as shot cuts to an overhead shot of him walking away,
                with Aang running to catch up to him. Scene changes to a vertical column with a
                sunstone in the center, as Zuko and Aang walk past it. Screen pans above to show a
                wall with two gates, with the both walking toward them. As the both come closer,
                Zuko stops walking, and Aang runs to the gates, drops his staff, and unsuccessfully
                tries opening the gates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's locked up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko rubs his head, and looks behind, before quickly going aside to show
                the sunstone from the column in front of the gates beaming light.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Wait. <charAction>Cut to an overhead shot of Zuko, as he realizes something and
                takes a step behind, and looks at the position he stood at a moment before. Screen
                zooms in to show the light from the sunstone beaming on a circular carving on the
                ground.</charAction> It's a celestial calendar. <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of
                Zuko and Aang standing in front of the column as screen pans to right to show the
                gates.</charAction> Just like the Fire Sages have in their temples. <charAction>Cut
                to a similar sunstone above the gates.</charAction> I bet that sunstone opens the
            door, but only when sunlight hits at just the right angle. <charAction>Screen pans below
                to show Aang in front of the gates.</charAction> On the solstice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Exasperated.</charAction> Monkeyfeathers! The solstice again? We can't
            wait here that long.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> No, we can't. <charAction>He unsheathes one of
                his swords.</charAction> But we might be able to speed time up. <charAction>Cut to
                the circle carved on the ground on which light from the sunstone is being beamed. He
                places his sword on it with an angle, causing it to reflect the light. Cut to Zuko
                reflecting the light from the column.</charAction> Let's see if we can outsmart the
            sunstone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the side of the gate as the light being reflected by Zuko's sword
                moves to the other sunstone on top of the gates. Screen pans below to show Aang
                looking at it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nothing's happening.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko, who is kneeling down and reflecting the light.</charAction>
            Come on ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of the sunstone as the ground starts shaking. Cut to
                inside the room as the gates are opened and the shaking stops.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He picks his staff, and Zuko, walking up to the gates, unsheathes his
                sword.</charAction> You know, Zuko, I don't care what everyone else says about you.
                <charAction>Aang nudges Zuko with his elbow.</charAction> You're pretty
            smart.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko smiles at Aang's compliment, before realizing what Aang actually said.
                Aang walks inside the dark room and looks around it. He narrows his eyes, as the
                shot cuts to show a statue of a man with an angry expression. Cut back to Aang, who
                gasps.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Relax. They're just statues.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of two statues from behind Aang and Zuko. Cut to an aerial
                shot of the room to show many statues lined up in a circle as they both walk into
                it. Aang walks up to a statue and reads something on it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It says this is something called the Dancing Dragon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang places his staff to lean on the statue. Cut to a shot of the statue
                from behind Aang to show him taking the same posture the statue is in. Cut to his
                leg, which presses a button on the ground. Aang comes out of the posture and
                examines the button. He looks around at all the statues, runs toward Zuko, catches
                him by the hand, and pulls him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Zuko, get over here! I want you to dance with me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He pulls his hand back.</charAction> What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Just do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang pulls him to a side, as shot cuts to the both standing in front of two
                statues that are to the sides of the path that leads into the circle, as Zuko
                groans.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Let's follow the steps of the statues. <charAction>Aang and Zuko take the posture of
                the statue in front of them and move to their right and left, respectively, taking
                the postures of the statues in front of them, which pressed similar buttons lying on
                the ground in front of all the statues. Cut to an aerial shot of the
                room.</charAction> Don't you see? These aren't dance moves. These statues are giving
            us a lesson. <charAction>Cut to Zuko moving through each statue.</charAction> I think
            this is some kind of Sun Warrior firebending form.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">This better teach us some really good firebending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang, as he does the same moves as Zuko. Cut to two statues with
                their waists bent toward each other, and their arms in the direction of each other.
                Zuko and Aang perform the same move. Cut to a part of the ground detracting and a
                vertical column emerging from it, as the both look behind at it. Cut to a close-up
                of the yellow, egg-shaped sunstone on the column. Cut to an aerial shot of Zuko and
                Aang standing in front of the column as Aang raises his arms in
                triumph.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hurray! <charAction>Putting his hands down, and rubbing his head.</charAction> Wait,
            what exactly is that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He runs toward the sunstone.</charAction> It's some kind of mystical
            gemstone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to the gemstone as Zuko runs toward it. Aang raises his
                arms.</charAction> Well, don't touch it! <charAction>Zuko stops and Aang catches up
                to him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Why not?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Remember what happened out there with those spikes? <charAction>Turns to look at the
                side and raises his arms again.</charAction> I'm just very suspicious of giant
            glowing gems sitting on pedestals.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko ignores the Avatar and picks the sunstone, as Aang's eyes
                twitch.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It feels almost alive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He tries to put the sunstone back but yells in surprise as a geyser of
                viscous slime erupts out from the pedestal and pushes Zuko toward the grates in the
                ceiling, sticking him there.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a worried Aang's face, as he turns to look at the gates of the
                room, which close.</charAction> Oh no, it's another trap!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the column as more viscous slime comes from it,
                causing Aang to walk back. Cut to Zuko who is stuck to the grates and unsuccessfully
                struggles to break free.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Ugh, I can't pull free. It's like some kind of glue.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang, as he jumps across the slime and grabs his staff on the other
                side of the room. He climbs on a statue's head, jumps onto another of the statues'
                head and airbends a gust of wind toward Zuko, due to which Zuko is pushed from his
                back to his front. Cut to an aerial shot to show that the slime is rising and the
                screen zooms to show Aang is still on the statue's head. His staff gets stuck in the
                slime and he is not successful in pulling it out. He jumps up toward the grates, as
                the slime engulfs the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Trying to pull his hands from the grates.</charAction> I can't move!
            Zuko, do something!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Me? I can't move either!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the entire room being filled by the slime. Cut to the
                other side of the grates as they groan due to the slime pushing them against the
                grates. The slime stops.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It stopped.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">At least we have air. Maybe if we stay calm, we can figure a way out of
            this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial shot of the two being stuck to the grates, as screen zooms
                out slowly. Screen fades to the building at night, and cuts to the two still stuck
                to the grates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You had to pick up the glowing egg, didn't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to their heads sticking out from the grates.</charAction> At least I
            made something happen. If it were up to you, we'd never have made it past the
            courtyard.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He opens his mouth very widely and yells.</charAction> Help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Who are you yelling to? Nobody's lived here for centuries.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, what do you think we should do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Think about our place in the universe‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the grates from the side, as Aang sighs, and a foot wearing a sandal
                steps near it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko and Aang's point of view, as the Sun Warrior chief comes
                into sight. Cut to his face.</charAction> Who is down there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to both boys bearing shocked expressions. Cut to a shot of the
                building, before cutting to Zuko and Aang as the slime is removed by aardvark sloths
                on either side of them. Shot cuts to an aerial shot to show the two surrounded by
                men and women who are in circles.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Walking toward the two.</charAction> For trying to take our sunstone,
            you must be severely punished!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and Zuko from the side.</charAction> We didn't come here to
            take your sunstone. We came here to find the ancient origin of all firebending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial shot of the people, as Ham Ghao steps
                forward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ham Ghao">Yeah, right. They are obviously thieves, <charAction>Cut to the chief and Ham Ghao
                from the side to show that he is holding the sunstone.</charAction> here to steal
            Sun Warrior treasures.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Please, I don't normally play this card, but ... <charAction>Places his palm on his
                chest.</charAction> I'm the Avatar. <charAction>Cut to Ham Ghao looking toward the
                chief from the side, puzzled. Cut to Aang, who stands up and gives a weak
                smile.</charAction> Just hear us out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Standing up.</charAction> My name is Zuko, Crown Prince of the Fire
            Nation. <charAction>Looks down at the ground.</charAction> O-or at least I used to be.
                <charAction>Cut to Zuko's point of view to the Sun Warriors as screen pans right to
                show more of them.</charAction> I know my people have distorted the ways of
            firebending, to be fueled by anger and rage. But now I want to learn the true way,
                <charAction>Cut back to Aang and Zuko.</charAction> the original way. When we came
            here, I never imagined <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot that shows the Sun Warriors
                surrounding the two.</charAction> the Sun Warrior's civilization was secretly alive.
            I am truly humbled to be in your presence. <charAction>Cut back to the two, as they bow
                their heads.</charAction> Please, teach us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the chief.</charAction> If you wish to learn the ways of the Sun,
            you must learn them from the masters, Ran and Shaw.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and Zuko.</charAction> Ran and Shaw? There are two of
            them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Walks toward them and looks at Aang.</charAction> When you present
            yourself to them, they will examine you. <charAction>Turns to look at Zuko.</charAction>
            They'll read your hearts, your souls, and your ancestry. <charAction>Takes a step toward
                Zuko and towers over Zuko, who looks worried.</charAction> If they deem you worthy,
            they'll teach you. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of the chief.</charAction> If they
            don't, you'll be destroyed on the spot.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The chief walks back, and Aang and Zuko look at each other. Scene changes
                to a building on the next day. Screen zooms to the top of the
                building.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">If you're going to see the masters, <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of the Sun
                Warriors sitting in many arcs inside the room in front of the Eternal Flame. Aang,
                Zuko, and the Sun Warrior chief are standing.</charAction> you must bring them a
            piece of the Eternal Flame. <charAction>Cut to the chief standing in front of the fire
                from behind him.</charAction> This fire is the very first one. <charAction>Raises
                his hands to his head and turns back at Zuko and Aang.</charAction> It was given to
            man by the dragons. <charAction>Cut to the chief talking to Zuko and Aang from the side
                as the other Sun Warriors look.</charAction> We have kept it going for thousands of
            years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> I don't believe it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the Sun Warriors sitting and the chief explaining their job to
                the two, as screen pans to the right.</charAction> You will each take a piece of it
            to the masters, to show your commitment to the sacred art of firebending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to an unsure Aang as he places his palm on his neck.</charAction>
            Umm, Mister Sun Chief Sir‌, yeah, I'm not a firebender yet. <charAction>Pointing to
                Zuko.</charAction> Couldn't my friend here carry my fire for me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Unyielding.</charAction> No. <charAction>He turns back to face the fire.
                Cut to Aang, who looks very uneasy, before cutting to the chief, who takes a part of
                the Eternal Flame on his hand and turns back toward the two.</charAction> This
            ritual illustrates <charAction>He turns around in a circle and splits the fire on his
                palm into two parts.</charAction> the essence of Sun Warrior philosophy.
                <charAction>Cut to Aang, as he stares at the flame.</charAction> You must maintain a
            constant heat. The flame will go out if you make it too small. <charAction>Aang cringes,
                as the screen pans to Zuko, who is standing beside Aang.</charAction> Make it too
            big, and you might lose control.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko stares at the flame and brings his arms forward to take the flame. He
                looks at Aang, as shot cuts to the chief offering Aang the flame from the
                side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sorry, I'm just a little nervous. <charAction>He takes the flame in his hand and
                his expression changes to a relieved one.</charAction> It's like a little
            heartbeat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the chief.</charAction> Fire is life, <charAction>Cut to Aang.
                Screen zooms in to his face as he smiles.</charAction> not just destruction. You
            will take your flames up there. <charAction>Cut to Zuko and Aang standing in front of
                the chief as he points to a mountain from the side. Screen zooms in to the
                mountain.</charAction> The cave of the masters is beneath that rock.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen changes to Aang and Zuko walking through a steep forest, before
                changing to the steep surface. Cut to Zuko, who has reached the top of the
                steepness, turning back to look at Aang who is lagging behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Hurry up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't. <charAction>Cut to Aang approaching a rock.</charAction> If I walk too
            fast, my flame will go out. <charAction>Climbs up the rock and looks at his
                flame.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Your flame's <charAction>Aang looks at Zuko.</charAction> gonna go out
                <charAction>Cut to Zuko from below.</charAction> because it's too small. You're too
            timid, give it more juice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He climbs another rock.</charAction> But what if I can't control
            it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> You can do it. I know you can. <charAction>Cut
                to an unsure Aang.</charAction> You're a talented kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang smiles at the compliment and climbs up another rock, reaching the top.
                Zuko starts walking and Aang follows him. Screen pans above to the top of the
                mountain. Scene changes to Zuko and Aang as the reach the top of the mountain, and
                see that warriors are already there, with the Sun Warrior chief, Ham Ghao, and
                another Sun Warrior standing. Screen zooms out to show two vertical rocks with a
                bridge in the center.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>He and the other two Sun Warriors walk up to the two.</charAction>
            Facing the judgment of the firebending masters will be very dangerous for you. Your
            ancestors <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> are directly responsible for the
            dragons' disappearance. <charAction>Zuko looks toward the side.</charAction> The masters
            might not be so happy to see you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ham Ghao">
         <charAction>He places his hand on his hip.</charAction> I know
                I wouldn't be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But once they find out I'm the Avatar ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the chief.</charAction> Have you forgotten that you vanished,
            allowing the Fire Nation to wreak havoc on the world‌? <charAction>Cut to a guilty
                Aang.</charAction> The decline of the dragons is your burden, too. <charAction>Aang
                looks toward the side.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the chief rooting his staff on the ground. The
                other two Sun Warriors get into a kneeling position and the chief walks toward Zuko
                and Aang, takes a small portion of their flames and gives the flames to both of the
                Sun Warriors, who go to each of the sides. The chief turns back and walks. Cut to
                some Sun Warriors standing and sitting, alternately, as the two Warriors standing
                create a circle made of fire. Cut to Aang and Zuko watching the chief
                walk.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turning to Zuko.</charAction> We could turn back now. We've already
            learned more about fire than we'd hoped. <charAction>Aang shows Zuko his flame and gives
                a weak smile.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No, we're seeing this through to the end. We're gonna meet these masters and find
            out <charAction>Cut to an overhead shot of Aang.</charAction> what's so great about
            them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking toward the rocks.</charAction> What if they judge us, and attack
            us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> Well, we're the Fire Prince and the Avatar.
                <charAction>Unsheathes his swords slightly.</charAction> I think we could take these
            guys in a fight, whoever they are. <charAction>He smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang, who nods uneasily. Cut to the entire courtyard to show that
                all alternate Sun Warriors have made their fire circles. Zuko turns toward the Sun
                Warrior chief.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Bring 'em out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the chief to show him stretching his both hands out on both
                sides.</charAction> Chanters!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial shot of the courtyard as the chanters play the music. Cut
                to the Sun Warriors, who are sitting down, beating their drums in a synchronized
                rhythm. Cut to the other Sun Warriors holding the fire circle in their crouched
                positions. Cut to the Warriors, as Zuko and Aang walk toward the stairs. Cut to the
                other side of the circle to show the Warriors alternatively rising and bowing. Cut
                to an overhead shot of the two nearing the steps. Cut to a shot of the stairs as
                screen slowly pans below. Cut to the chief and the other two Warriors, as they step
                aside to let Zuko and Aang pass.</description>
      <description>Zuko and Aang look at each other and take a deep breath before climbing.
                Cut to the warriors, who are still beating the drums and holding the fire circle.
                Cut to Zuko and Aang climbing the steps. Aang looks back, but continues forward.
                Shot cuts to them climbing from the side, before cutting to the chief and the two
                warriors beside him looking at them, with the screen zooming out. Cut to Zuko and
                Aang, who reach the top as the setting sun shines at them. The music stops playing
                as soon as they reach the top. Both of them look at the caves on each side of the
                bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior">
         <charAction>Cut to a Sun Warrior using an sound-amplifying device.</charAction>
            Those who wish to meet the masters, Ran and Shaw, will now present their fire.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Zuko turn toward the caves and bow down with their hands stretched
                toward the caves. Screen zooms out to show them in this posture.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">Sound the call!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A warrior takes a deep breath and blows a horn. The sound from the horn
                sends a flock of birds scattering. The cave Aang is facing rumbles, causing him to
                tremble. Aang accidentally places his hand down, extinguishing his
                flame.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What's happening‌? <charAction>He looks to look at Zuko, who turns his head toward
                Aang. Aang cringes and quickly returns back to his position, and realizes that his
                flame is extinguished and gasps. He turns toward Zuko again, and
                whispers.</charAction> Zuko, my fire went out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> What do you want me to do‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Give me some of yours. <charAction>He reaches for Zuko's flame and Zuko pushes him
                behind.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> No, just make your own.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Whispering as well.</charAction> I can't. <charAction>He reaches for
                Zuko's flame again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of the bridge.</charAction> Get some from those
            warriors. <charAction>Cut to the chief and the two Warriors beside him.</charAction>
            Hurry! <charAction>Cuts to shot of the Sun Warriors below; off-screen.</charAction> Stop
            cheating off me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The chief and Ham Ghao look at each other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> Quit being stingy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Aang trying to reach for Zuko's flame; he is unable to do so
                as Zuko raises his hand high up in the air. Aang continues his attempt to get Zuko's
                flame but Zuko stretches his arms away. Aang pulls Zuko's arm down, extinguishing
                the flame. They both look at each other. Cut to the two from inside the caves as the
                ground rumbles. Cut to the two with a worried expression. They turn to look at the
                other cave as screen zooms in to the cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh oh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two eyes glow inside a cave and a red dragon comes out, roaring, circling
                around the bridge. Cut to the boys, who take a step back. Cut to Zuko, who looks at
                the dragon. Cut to a blue dragon coming out of the other cave. It joins the other
                dragon as they circle the bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko and Aang standing.</charAction> These are the
            masters.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In a low voice.</charAction> Still think we can take 'em?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Sshh. I never said that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the dragons circling the bridge from below. Screen pans down to the
                warriors as they bow down. Cut to Ham Ghao and the chief.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ham Ghao">Oh, here it comes. <charAction>Looks up at the bridge.</charAction> Any moment now.
            Dinner for the masters.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Turns toward Ham Ghao.</charAction> Quiet, Ham Ghao!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ham Ghao">What? <charAction>Turns his head away.</charAction> Everyone's thinking it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the bridge where the dragons are still flying around the bridge. Cut
                to Aang, who looks at them flying.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Whispers.</charAction> Zuko, I think we're supposed to do the Dragon
            Dance with them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning his head toward Aang.</charAction> What‌? What about this
            situation makes you think they want us to dance‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, I think they want us to do something. Let's just try it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Unwillingly.</charAction> Fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Zuko get into the first posture of the Dancing Dragon and change
                their postures to the next. Cut to Aang spreading his arms out as the blue dragon
                flies behind him following the shape of his arms. Aang turns his arms to his side as
                the dragon turns as well. Screen zooms out to show the dragons performing the same
                movements as each other. Cut to Zuko, who pushes his hand up as the red dragon
                behind him goes up as well. Zuko dips and the dragon dives down accordingly. Cut to
                the dragons flying above the bridge as screen pans below to show the two performing
                the Dancing Dragon. Cut to them performing the final move. They look to either side
                as shot cuts to show that the dragons have stopped moving and are hovering on either
                side of the bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Still bowing.</charAction> Judgment time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the blue dragon which stares at Zuko, as Aang trembles. Zuko looks
                at it, with his mouth wide open. Cut to Aang trembles, as shot cuts to the two
                dragons sitting, with their legs at the bottom of the bridge. Cut to the red dragon
                as it breathes fire at the two. Cut to the blue dragon doing the same. Cut to Zuko
                and Aang yelling and covering their faces as they are engulfed by a multi-colored
                flame vortex. Cut to the top of the vortex from inside it. It slowly pans down to
                the boys who look at it, shocked. Cut to the bridge as the dragons continue
                breathing fire. Screen pans above to the flame vortex. Cut to the inside of the
                vortex and the two stare at the scene in awe. Cut to Aang's eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko's face, as he stares at the flames.</charAction> I
            understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The vortex slowly dissipates and the dragons curl their bodies, fly up,
                circle one time and go into their caves. Cut to the boys who still remain on the
                bridge. Cut to an annoyed Ham Ghao, before cutting to one of the warriors holding
                the circle of fire as he moves his arm in a circle, and extinguishes the flame and
                ending his hands in a position. Cut to an aerial shot of Zuko and Aang descending
                from the steps.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> Their fire was beautiful. I saw so many
            colors, colors I've never imagined.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to the two descending from the side.</charAction> Like firebending
            harmony.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">Yes. They judged you, and gave you visions of the meaning of firebending.
                <charAction>The other two Sun Warriors walk away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> I can't believe there are still living
            dragons. My uncle Iroh said he faced the last dragon and killed it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at Zuko.</charAction> So your uncle lied.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Cut to the smiling chief from the side.</charAction> Actually, it wasn't
            a total lie. Iroh was the last outsider to face the masters. <charAction>Raising his
                hand above slightly.</charAction> They deemed him worthy and passed the secret onto
            him as well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Surprised. Shot cuts to an aerial shot of the courtyard.</charAction> He
            must have lied to protect them, so no one else would hunt them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang.</charAction> All this time, I thought firebending was
            destruction. Since I hurt Katara, I've been too afraid and hesitant. But now I know what
            it really is ... it's energy, and life. <charAction>He smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Yeah. It's like the Sun, <charAction>He curls his hand into a fist.</charAction> but
            inside of you. Do you guys realize this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Well, our civilization is called the Sun Warriors
            ... so yeah.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">That's why my firebending was so weak before. Because for so many years, hunting you
                <charAction>Turns toward Aang as screen zooms out to show Aang.</charAction> was my
            drive ... it was my purpose. <charAction>Aang turns toward Zuko as well.</charAction> So
            when I joined you, I lost sight of my inner fire. But now, I have a new drive.
                <charAction>Cut to Zuko's face as screen zooms in.</charAction> I have to help you
            defeat my father and restore balance to the world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko delivers two fire blasts more powerful than in the Western Air Temple.
                Aang also bends a similar blast. Cut to Aang's face, as he grins at his success. Cut
                to both of them, who walk toward each other, smiling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sun Warrior chief">
         <charAction>He walks toward the two and become serious.</charAction> Now that you
            have learned the secrets, and you know about our tribe's existence, <charAction>He stops
                walking.</charAction> we have no choice but to imprison you here forever.
                <charAction>Cut to the two, who are shocked, before cutting back to the smiling
                chief.</charAction> Just kidding. <charAction>Cut to the two as they look relieved.
                The chief's expression becomes serious again.</charAction> But seriously, don't tell
            anyone!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to the upside-down pagodas in the Western Air
                Temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and Zuko demonstrating the Dancing Dragon to the rest of
                Team Avatar and friends.</charAction> With this technique the dragons showed us,
            Zuko and I will be unstoppable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two get into their final postures and Team Avatar
                applauds.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, that's a great dance you two learned there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's not a dance. It's a firebending form.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to Sokka, as he moves his fingers in a dancing manner.</charAction>
            We'll just tap-dance our way to victory over the Fire Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Walks toward Sokka.</charAction> It's a sacred form that happens to be
            thousands of years old!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, yeah‌? What's your little form called‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Embarrassed.</charAction> The Dancing Dragon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Team Avatar laughs, and the shot cuts to Zuko who shuts his eyes and
                cringes in embarrassment. Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
