<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="24">The Swamp</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Tim Hedrik</writer>
      <date>2006-04-14</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens with an overhead shot of rice paddies. The camera pans
                down, revealing an Earth Kingdom village. The scene cuts to a shot of a bridge over
                a nearby stream. People carrying backpacks and other loads walk back and forth over
                the bridge, either entering or departing the small village.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to a street within the village. Iroh and Zuko are sitting on
                straw mats, their stolen ostrich horse lying behind them. A cart with masks for sale
                passes by in front of them; one of the masks is seen to be the Blue Spirit mask. As
                the cart passes, another pedestrian walks in front of Iroh. Iroh holds his hat out
                to the pedestrian and begins to talk to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Somewhat enthusiastically.</charAction> Spare coins for weary
            travelers?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The pedestrian tosses a couple of copper pieces into Iroh's hat as Zuko
                turns to Iroh in anger.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily, with his arms folded.</charAction> This is humiliating! We're
            royalty! These people should be giving us whatever we want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">They will if you ask nicely. <charAction>A peasant woman strolls past; somewhat
                dramatically.</charAction> Spare change for a hungry old man?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Peasant girl">
         <charAction>Withdrawing a coin from her sleeve.</charAction> Aw, here you
            go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">The coin is appreciated, but not as much as your smile!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko slaps his forehead in frustration as the young girl giggles lightly
                and walks away. As soon as she walks away, a man with dual broadswords on his back
                wanders up to Iroh and Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Broadsword man">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> How about some entertainment in exchange for ... a
            gold piece? <charAction>He pulls the piece from his pocket with a
            flourish.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> We're not performers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Standing up.</charAction> Not professional anyway. <charAction>He puts
                the hat down and stands up, swaying lightly as he begins to sing.</charAction> It's
            a long, long way to Ba Sing Se, but the girls in the city, they look so pretty!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Broadsword man">
         <charAction>Annoyed with the quality of the entertainment.</charAction> Come on,
            we're talking a gold piece here! Let's see some action! <charAction>Zuko glances up
                sharply as the man withdraws his swords.</charAction> Dance!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man begins to slice the ground near Iroh's feet; Iroh hops up and down
                to "dodge" the attacks while Zuko struggles to control his anger at the man. A
                birds-eye shot of the street shows other citizens have stopped to watch the
                spectacle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Singing.</charAction> They kiss so sweet that you really got to meet the
            girls from Ba Sing Se!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Broadsword man">
         <charAction>Stops slicing and laughs.</charAction> Ha, ha! Nothing like a fat man
            dancing for his dinner! Here ya go! <charAction>Tosses the gold coin onto the ground and
                walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Dramatically; close to tears.</charAction> Such a kind man.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko glares after the man in anger and humiliation. The camera cuts to
                Appa, flying through a gray sky over a large forested area; it is covered somewhat
                by fog, and looks rather menacing. Sokka is rubbing a whetstone against his machete,
                while Katara is studying a scroll. Aang stares at the swamp, and seems to be in a
                trance. Sokka notices they were slowly flying down, and notices Aang's trance-like
                state.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Hey, you taking us down for a reason?
                <charAction>Aang continues to stare at the swamp.</charAction> Aang,
                <charAction>Aang snaps out of the trance.</charAction> why are we going
            down?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What? I didn't even notice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out to see Appa flying down toward the swamp</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Are you noticing now?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Moving to the front of the saddle.</charAction> Is something
            wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He still seems somewhat dazed by the swamp.</charAction> I know this is
            going to sound weird, but I think the swamp is calling to me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding his stomach.</charAction> Is it telling you where we can get
            something to eat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I ... I think it wants us to land there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shrugging.</charAction> No offense to the swamp, but I don't see any
            land there to land on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know. Bumi said to learn earthbending I would have to wait and listen, and
            now I'm actually hearing the earth. Do you want me to ignore it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka, Katara and Momo look over Appa's saddle down at the
                swamp</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't know. There's something ominous about that place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo hides inside Appa's saddle as Appa groans.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">See, even Appa and Momo don't like it here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Resignedly.</charAction> Okay, since everyone feels so strongly about
            this, <charAction>Looks at swamp.</charAction> bye swamp. <charAction>Shakes Appa's
                rope.</charAction> Yip, Yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa groans and flies upward, away from the swamp. A tornado suddenly
                emerges from out of nowhere, heading right for Appa. Sokka, hearing something, turns
                around and finally sees it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Panicked.</charAction> You better throw in an extra "yip"! We gotta
            move!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa starts to fly faster, attempting to avoid the tornado, however he is
                not fast enough to get away. As the tornado begins to move closer to Appa, the wind
                pulls Sokka right off from the saddle. Katara manages to grab his hand, holding him
                back from flying into the tornado. Aang jumps up onto Appa's saddle and creates an
                air shield around Appa, stabilizing the air and allowing Sokka to fall back into the
                saddle, uninjured. The wind sucks Appa, who is still protected by the air shield,
                into the tornado. Aang struggles to maintain the air shield, however as it shrinks,
                one of Appa's legs slips from the protective air, thereby breaking it. Aang, Katara,
                and Sokka fall off Appa, with Aang landing lightly in muddied water as the latter
                two land quite roughly. Appa and Momo are thrown elsewhere in the
                swamp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking around the swamp and at his friends.</charAction> Where's Appa
            and Momo? <charAction>Aang jumps up to the top of the trees, looking for his animal
                friends as he uses the height to search for them.</charAction> Appa! Momo!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts back to Katara and Sokka. Katara glances at her elbow before
                looking up at her brother.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing blandly.</charAction> Sokka, you've got an elbow
            leech.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He spins around, panicking, trying to find it.</charAction> Where?
            Where?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A creature is shown sticking on to Sokka's elbow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Crosses her arms; sarcastically.</charAction> Where do you
            think?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Ripping off the elbow leech and throwing it behind to Katara. He cries
                out angrily.</charAction> Why do things keep attaching to me?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang swings over the muddied water on a vine, waiting for it to stop moving
                so he can land.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You couldn't find them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jumping down into the muddy water.</charAction> No, and the tornado ...
            it just disappeared.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Sokka turn to face the darkness in the swamp. The scene switches
                to Appa, who is hanging suspended over the swamp, caught in a mass of vines. Momo
                jumps up from the saddle and begins chewing through the vines. Appa falls, with
                Momo, into the muddy water. He shakes the water from his fur and takes off flying,
                before again becoming trapped. Appa groans as Momo berates him, before the lemur
                begins to cut the vines, again. The scene switches back to Aang, Katara, and
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cutting the vines with his machete.</charAction> We better speed things
            up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> Maybe we should be a little nicer to the
            swamp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Continuing to cut the vines.</charAction> Aang, these are just plants.
            Do you want me to say "please" and "thank you" as I swing my machete back and
            forth?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe you should listen to Aang. Something about this place feels ...
                <description>alive.</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm sure there are lots of things that are alive here and if we don't wanna wind up
            getting eaten by them, we need to find Appa as fast as we can.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka continues to slice through the vines. The shot changes perspective to
                show Aang, Katara and Sokka through the vines, as though someone is looking at them.
                The scene changes to Appa and Momo. Appa is walking on the wet, muddy ground,
                trailing his footprints behind, carrying Momo on his back. A tree trunk happens to
                be in Appa's way, and the bison collapses to the ground, unwilling to attempt flying
                over it or crawling beneath it. Momo takes Aang's bison whistle and blows it to make
                Appa move. The bison ignores it the first time, growling angrily, but when Momo
                blows it a second time, he uses his tail to squash the lemur. Dazed from the blow,
                Momo sways and collapses. The scene changes back to Aang, Katara, and Sokka, now
                walking through a foggier part of the swamp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Appa! Momo!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">There's no way they can hear us and no way we can see them. We'll have to make camp
            for the night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Several flies surround Sokka. Sokka swings his machete at them, trying to
                shoo them away. At that moment, a huge bubble of swamp gas rises from the muddy
                water below them. The gas grows closer to Aang, Katara, and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What was that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nothing, just swamp gas. <charAction>Indicating.</charAction> Look, there's nothing
            supernatural going on here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The three groan as the smell reaches them, with Sokka waving his hand in
                front of his nose as Katara clamps hers shut. Suddenly, the quiet is shattered by a
                terrifying scream, causing them all to scream and huddle together, looking around
                wide-eyed for the source. The camera zooms backward, showing a small, grumpy-looking
                white bird. It opens its beak extremely wide, emitting the terrifying scream, and
                flutters off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sweating, his voice cracking.</charAction> I think we should build a
            fire.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka runs off to a nearby tree and cuts pieces of wood from its roots.
                Aang and Katara walk up to Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka, the longer we're here, the more I think you shouldn't be doing do
            that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, I asked the swamp. It said this was fine. <charAction>Grabs a nearby
                root.</charAction> Right, swamp? <charAction>Shakes the root and fakes a
                reply.</charAction> "No problem, Sokka!"</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka continues to chop up the roots, while Aang looks somewhat annoyed.
                The scene changes to a later shot of the trio around a fire. Katara glancing around
                at the swamp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Does anyone else get the feeling that we're being watched?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka is shown with a fly buzzing around him. He does not seems scared
                anymore.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Please, we're all alone out here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka uses his machete to try and scare the fly off. The fly turns into a
                big, shining ball of light. It flies away from the gang, illuminating over a dozen
                pairs of eyes staring at them. They turn around and see them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Except for them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They turn back around and huddle together.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>His calm demeanor vanishing.</charAction> Right, except for
            them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to Appa and Momo, who are lying down on a giant tree
                branch. The constant nocturnal noises echoing around them has Momo scuttling
                frantically from one end of the saddle to the other whilst chittering in fear. Appa,
                unable to sleep by the noise, growls loudly, causing the noises to stop, and Momo
                settles down on Appa's saddle. As Momo begins to close his eyes, another small sound
                is heard, causing his ears to perk up and his eyes to widen. The scene changes back
                to Aang, Katara, and Sokka. The camp fire is beginning to die out, and the three
                friends are huddled together, sleeping. Another perspective shot shows someone
                looking at them through the vines. A vine snakes its way to Sokka's leg, which is
                sticking out, and begins to wind around both it and Sokka's whole
                body.</description>
      <description>The shot cuts to an overhead view of the three, each tied up by several
                vines that snake out of the frame. The scene cuts to a close-up profile shot of the
                three. For a moment, they are still asleep - Sokka holding his machete and drooling
                - but they awake screaming as the vines simultaneously yank them all out off the
                screen and away from each other.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to Sokka. He plants the blade of his machete in the ground
                as he is dragged away. Both Katara and Aang are also dragged off into the mist.
                Sokka gets up and looks around for his sister and Aang. The respite does not last
                long as vines are suddenly thrown at him. They wrap around him and attempt to drag
                him away again. Before he can travel too far, Sokka starts hacking the vines with
                his machete. He frees himself and runs back down the tree root, pursued by more
                vines.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to Katara, struggling to free herself from the vines. Using
                a water whip she cuts through her bonds and runs off into the mist.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to Aang, who frees himself by creating an air bubble around
                him and expanding it. His bonds attach to the bubble, and Aang jumps away before
                they ensnare him again. He jumps through the trees, closely pursued by more vines.
                He escapes a vine that pulls him to the ground using his airbending to propel
                himself far away and soon finds himself alone in the swamp. Cut to a wide shot of
                Aang looking around for his friends.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Guys?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades to a shot of Appa's footprint, which is now filled with
                swamp water. Two figures are looking down at the footprint. Due is tall and skinny,
                while his friend Tho is short and fat. Both wear small, animal skin loincloths and
                have a single, large leaf on their heads to serve as a hat. Tho is carrying a stick,
                and uses it to indicate the animal track.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">What'd you reckon make a track like that, Tho?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Don't know, Due. <charAction>Points his stick at the footprint.</charAction> Some'in
            with six legs. Pretty big'uns too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans up to reveal more of Appa's tracks in the
                mud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">Leaves a nice, wide trail to folla'.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">You know what's at the end of that trail?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Due shakes his head in the negative. Cut to a close-up of Tho's smiling
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">
         <charAction>Grinning.</charAction> Dinner.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to Appa swimming in the marshy water before cutting to a
                close-up of Momo. A fly is buzzing around his head, and he watches it, shifting his
                eyes from side to side. It flies off, and Momo goes after it. He lands on a nearby
                tree root, still attempting to catch the fly. He hops from tree root to tree root,
                following the fly, although unknowingly lands on the back of a catgator. He catches
                the fly on the last root, but lets go of it as he jumps to fly away from the
                creature. It pursues Momo as he flies back to Appa. The camera pans left, following
                the chase. When Momo and the crocodile reach Appa, the sky bison's mouth is open and
                the catgator swims right into it. Appa holds the creature there for a moment, before
                spitting it back out. Momo and the catfish crocodile hiss at each other for a
                moment, and the crocodile swims off. The scene cuts back to Appa, who shakes his
                head and loudly groans.</description>
      <description>Cut to Katara, who is walking through an area where the tree roots are
                covered in white flowers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Calling out.</charAction> Aang! Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ahead of Katara is another Water Tribe woman, her back facing Katara. She
                wears the same robe as Katara and has the same hair style. Katara begins walking
                toward the figure.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hello? Hello? Can you help me? <charAction>She squints.</charAction> Mom?
                <charAction>More loudly and running toward the figure.</charAction> Mom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara runs to the figure, her eyes streaming tears of joy. She reaches the
                figure and places a hand on her shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I can't believe ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The smile leaves her face as the scene begins to lighten. Katara stands in
                front of a tree stump as she realizes the figure was only an illusion. Katara gasps,
                falling to her knees as she begins to cry. It cuts to an overhead shot of the very
                devastated Katara, and fades to shot of Sokka's hand holding his machete in the air.
                The rest of Sokka appears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang! <charAction>While slashing at the vines.</charAction> Stupid swamp! Dumb, ugly
            vines! Katara! <charAction>He becomes caught, and grunts with exertion before slicing
                himself free.</charAction> You think you're so tough, huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka trips over as he cuts through the vine in which he was tangled,
                falling offscreen with his face in the mud. Upon lifting up his head, he sees an
                image of Yue in a beam of light not far in front of him. Sokka stands up, puts away
                his machete and starts walking toward Yue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hello? Yue? <charAction>He takes a hold of his head, before removing his hands and
                shrugging, turning away from the apparition.</charAction> This is just a trick of
            the light ... swamp gas ... I ... hit my head running away last night. I'm going crazy.
                <charAction>Almost fearfully, he turns around and walks
            closer.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Princess Yue">
         <charAction>Accusingly.</charAction> You didn't protect me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka rubs his eyes in disbelief, opening them to find that Yue has
                disappeared. Sokka sighs in relief, but as he turns around he falls over backward,
                startled at seeing Yue right before his eyes again. The image of Yue disappears
                immediately after that and Sokka stands up and pulls his machete back out, almost
                threateningly.</description>
      <description>The scene switches to Aang, who is wandering the swamp calling the names of
                his friends.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara! Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Upon wading through the swamp, Aang notices an unfamiliar girl in a dress
                standing on a hill, accompanied by a winged pig.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hello? Who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The pig flies off and the girl giggles, before turning around and running
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey, come back! <charAction>He holds his hand out as though to grab
                her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang jumps to the top of the hill, only to find she has completely
                disappeared from his sight. Hearing her laugh again, Aang turns around only to see
                her running across the limbs of another tree. He uses the vines, however before he
                can even reach his destination, the girl has moved and is now running across the
                ground tries to chase the girl. Aang continues his wild chase through the treetops,
                as the scene switches to show Appa with Momo on his back swimming through the river
                that flows through the swamp. A little further on the stream, covered by fog, is a
                group of six swamp tribe members divided over three canoes; Due and Tho sitting in
                the middle canoe. They look at each other in silence for a few moments, Tho wetting
                his lips using his tongue. Appa halts as Momo chitters at the strange
                people.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">Look at that Tho. Is that a little hairy fella ridin' that thing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">No, that's what they call a "lemoo". Saw one at a traveling show once. Real smart
            they say.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">Bet he tastes a lot like possum chicken.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">You think everything tastes like possum chicken.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">C'mon now, fellas. <charAction>He moves to the front of the boat.</charAction> Just
            a little closer. Nice and easy. Nothing to worry about. We just fixin' to eat
            ya.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa turns around and takes off in the opposite direction.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> What'd you say that fer?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">
         <charAction>Shrugging as he tries to appease his friend.</charAction> Well, we
            are!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">But you don't have to tell 'em that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">
         <charAction>He shrugs again.</charAction> Well how'd I know they'd understand
            me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Come on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Due stands up in front of the canoe and starts spinning his arms, bending
                the water behind his canoe in order to chase Appa. The other two canoes follow suit,
                trailing behind Appa in a 'V' formation. Appa bounds through the river, desperate to
                escape the strange people hunting him. The scene switches back to Aang, who is still
                chasing the girl.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Peering through a wall of vegetation, Aang sees the girl on a small hill.
                Running after her, it is too late to stop as he notices that it is not the girl, but
                Katara. Aang runs into the waterbender and they both fall over. Sokka hears the
                commotion and turns around to investigate with his machete cocked - in the wrong
                direction, as only a few seconds later, Aang and Katara come barreling down the root
                he is standing on and hit him in the back, knocking him over too.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He stands up and puts his machete away.</charAction> What do you guys
            think you're doing!? I've been looking all over for you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>She has not moved, although her hand is on her head as she sits on the
                root they have fallen onto.</charAction> Well, I've been wandering around looking
            for you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He looks away before airbending himself to his feet. He appears
                embarrassed that he was not actively searching for his friends like they were
                him.</charAction> I was chasing some girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What girl?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He walks over to Katara and helps her up before rubbing his
                ear.</charAction> I don't know. I heard laughing and I saw some girl in a fancy
            dress.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically, with exaggerated hand movements.</charAction> Well, there
            must be a tea party here and we just didn't get our invitations!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I thought I saw Mom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look, we were all just scared and hungry and our minds were playing tricks on us.
            That's why we all saw things out here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You saw something too?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He looks away for a moment, before turning back and taking a step closer
                to his sister.</charAction> I thought I saw Yue. But, that doesn't prove anything.
            Look, I think about her all the time, and you saw Mom, someone you miss a lot.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What about me? I didn't know the girl I saw. And all our visions led us right
            here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang begins walking around, as if looking for something.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay ... so where's here? The middle of the swamp?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks around, his gaze finally resting on a massive tree growing right
                next to him. The camera pans to reveal exactly how enormous the tree really
                is.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, the center ... it's the heart of the swamp. It's been calling us here. I knew
            it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's just a tree. <charAction>He raises his arms above his head.</charAction> It
            can't call anyone. For the last time, there's nothing after us and there's nothing
            magical happening here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Sokka finishes his tirade, a seaweed monster jumps out from the water.
                The gang huddles together and screams, separating as the monster begins to attack
                them. The seaweed monster goes after Sokka first as the trio split up, each running
                in different directions. Sokka is picked up and swung around, only being released as
                Aang uses airbending to slice part of the monster's arm off. The monster goes after
                Aang, flicking the monk away and into the surrounding trees. Sokka is shown fighting
                with the vines that had him captured only seconds ago, and so intent was he at
                destroying them, he failed to notice a column rising behind himself. The column
                attaches to the seaweed monster and Sokka is swiped from the ground. Katara comes to
                his rescue this time as she slices at the monster's arm. It did not have the desired
                effect, as more vines grew to patch up the hole her waterbending created. She
                manages to push the monster back a little, however it is not long before she is
                flung away. Aang stops to watch her, giving the monster time to attack him. Sokka is
                absorbed into the chest of the monster as the scene changes to Appa continuing his
                escape from the Foggy Swamp members. Momo throws objects at them from the back of
                his friend, attempting to slow them down. One of these such items was a shirt that
                appears to belong to Sokka at a Foggy Swamp member, resulting in the boat that
                member was on to spin out of control.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Now, what would a lemoo need a shirt fer?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Tho manages to capture Momo after the latter hits a low tree branch and is
                thrown backward. The loss of his friend encourages Appa to run faster. The scene
                changes back to the gang fighting the seaweed monster. After using a tornado-like
                airbending move, Katara freezes Sokka in place before shooting him with water,
                expelling him from the monster's body. The fight ends as Katara begins to waterbend
                repeatedly at the monster, slicing through the vines and not allowing the monster to
                regenerate. A person is seen inside the monster, bending the vines.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">There's someone in there! He's bending the vines!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With a final slice, Katara cuts through the mask on the seaweed monster,
                the whole top half falling off. However, this does not stop the monster, and vines
                spring out of the marsh, capturing Katara high on a pillar. Aang airbends over to
                the monster and, using his native bending, rips apart the vines.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Demanding offensively.</charAction> Why did you call me here if you just
            wanted to kill us!?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">Wait! <charAction>The vines drop to reveal a slightly larger man wearing nothing but
                a leaf loincloth.</charAction> I didn't call you here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He shares a look of confusion with Sokka, who is also in an offensive
                stance.</charAction> We were flying over and I heard something calling to me,
            telling me to land.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">He's the Avatar. Stuff like that happens to us a lot.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">The Avatar? Come with me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The trio drop their stances and look at each other. The scene cuts to Huu,
                leading the gang to the top of the giant tree Aang noticed earlier.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">So, who are you then?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">
         <charAction>Bending a vine out of the way.</charAction> I protect the swamp from
            folks that want to hurt it, like this fella with his big knife.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">See, completely reasonable. <charAction>He finally puts his machete
                away.</charAction> Not a monster, just a regular guy defending his home. Nothing
            mystical about it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">Oh the swamp is a mystical place all right. It's sacred. I reached enlightenment
            right here under the banyan-grove tree. <charAction>He sits on the tree, looking at the
                group as he explains.</charAction> I heard it calling me, just like you
            did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Humoring Huu.</charAction> Sure you did. It seems real chatty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">
         <charAction>The camera zooms out as he explains, slowly revealing more and more of
                the swamp. It shows how large the banyan-grove tree is compared to the others, but
                at the final magnification, it is impossible to distinguish it from the other
                trees.</charAction> See this whole swamp is actually just one tree spread out over
            miles. Branches spread and sink, take root, and spread some more. One big, living
            organism. Just like the entire world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cuts back to Aang, looking at Huu. He is still openly
                skeptical.</charAction> I get how the tree is one big thing, but the whole
            world?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">Sure. You think you're any different from me or your friends or this tree? If you
            listen hard enough, you can hear every living thing breathing together.
                <charAction>Another shot shows the swamp river. There are the sounds of several
                animals heard in the background.</charAction> You can feel everything growing. We're
            all living together, even if most folks don't act like it. We all have the same roots
            and we are all branches of the same tree.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>She and her friends are now sitting, listening to Huu.</charAction> But
            what did our visions mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">In the swamp, we see visions of people we've lost, people we loved, folks we think
            are gone. <charAction>The shot cuts to show the people that Sokka and Katara saw in the
                swamp, before cutting back to Huu.</charAction> But the swamp tells us they're not.
            We're still connected to them. Time is an illusion and so is death.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But what about my vision? It was someone I had never met.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">You're the Avatar. You tell me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He looks down as he tries to understand.</charAction> Time is an
            illusion. So, it's someone I will meet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Huu nods.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Sorry to interrupt the lesson, but we still need to find Appa and Momo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I think I know how to find them. <charAction>Aang kneels down and places his hand on
                the tree.</charAction> Everything is connected. <charAction>Energy travels from
                Aang's hand to Appa's location. Appa is seen being captured by the Foggy Swamp
                members. Back at the banyan-grove tree, Aang stands up.</charAction> Come on! We've
            got to hurry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the Foggy Swamp members, Appa is trapped inside a net while Tho
                sings.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">
         <charAction>Singing and tapping the side of his canoe. Momo is seen struggling
                inside the sack he has been placed in.</charAction> Set my lines by the river bed!
            Caught ten fish and I killed 'em dead! Cut 'em and gut 'em and I tossed the heads in the
            water to keep them catgators fed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The boats stop when a jet of water appears and destroys the boat next to
                Tho and Due's. The two people from the destroyed boat fly into the water as Aang
                appears on a tree branch.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends a stream of air, throwing Tho into the water and freeing Momo
                who was being held by Tho.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">We're under attack!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Due scoops up a puddle of water and sends it toward Aang and Katara. The
                three become engaged in a waterbending fight, with neither side gaining an
                advantage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hey, you guys are waterbenders!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">You too! That means we're kin! <charAction>Due ceases waterbending, followed by a
                slightly disgusted Katara. He watches as Sokka and Huu run up to the branch Katara
                and Aang are standing on.</charAction> Hey Huu! How you been?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">You know, scared some folks, swung some vines, the usual.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Huu?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to the gang sitting around a fire in the Foggy Swamp Tribe.
                There is a member waterbending some liquid in a pot to stirs it, and Due grabs a
                fish from the pot before moving over to the fire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">How you like that possum chicken?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Tastes just like arctic hen. So why were you guys so interested in eating Appa?
                <charAction>He indicates the catgator lying behind Tho.</charAction> You've got
            plenty of those big things wandering around.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">You want me to eat old Slim? He's like a member of the family!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Due pulls the fish off the branch and gives it to Slim.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nice Slim!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka throws a bug at the catgator; it bounces off his nose and he growls
                at Sokka, who cowers slightly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Due">
         <charAction>Laughing.</charAction> Oh, he don't eat no bugs! That's people
            food.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Where'd you say you was from?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling. Sokka is shown chewing nonchalantly next to her.</charAction>
            The South Pole.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Didn't know there was waterbenders anywhere but here. They got a nice swamp there,
            do they?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No, it's all ice and snow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tho">Hmm. No wonder you left.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Katara.</charAction> Well, I hope you realize now that nothing
            strange was going on here. <charAction>He raises his arms for emphasis.</charAction>
            Just a bunch of greasy people living in a swamp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What about the visions?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I told you, we were hungry. I'm eating a giant bug!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka holds up said giant bug, taking a bit of its abdomen. He swallows it
                with some difficulty before exhaling sharply, sticking his tongue out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Feeding Momo.</charAction> But what about when the tree showed me where
            Appa and Momo were?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That's Avatar stuff, that doesn't count. <charAction>To Huu.</charAction> The only
            thing I can't figure out is how you made that tornado that sucked us down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huu">I can't do anything like that. I just bend the water in the plants.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, no accounting for weather. Still, there's absolutely nothing mysterious about
            the swamp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a long shot of the camp from across the river. The white screaming
                bird from earlier lands on a visible tree branch and lets out its horrible cry. A
                nearby vine rises up and bats the bird into the camera, which goes
                dark.</description>
      <description>When the image returns, it is of a full moon back in the Earth Kingdom
                village where Zuko and Iroh were seen last. The camera pans down to reveal the
                broadsword man walking down a street alone. He hears something behind him, turns and
                draws his blades. The scene cuts to a frontal shot of him, where there was nothing
                behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Broadsword man">Who's there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a close-up shot of his hands, which are both grabbed by
                another person. He is disarmed and thrown against some nearby boxes, his swords
                falling uselessly to the ground. His assailant's feet are seen to approach the
                sword. He picks them up, the camera in turn reveals that the assailant is the Blue
                Spirit himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
