<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="14">The Fortuneteller</title>
      <director>Dave Filoni</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2005-09-23</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to a sunny lake scene; Aang, Katara, and Sokka are
                sitting around a bundle of sticks with a blue tent behind Katara and are surrounded
                by trees and rocks. A large se tu suddenly bursts from the surface, leaps through
                the air, and lands with a splash into the water. Katara rises and points at
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka rises to view the spectacle. The fish, a se tu, leaps into the air
                again, facing the group in mid-jump in slow-motion before landing in the water
                again. The camera cuts to Sokka and Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">He is taunting us! <charAction>Camera zooms out to the lake and the group's camp
                site.</charAction> You are so going to be dinner!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He grabs his fishing pole from his tent set up nearby and attempts to cast
                the pole into the water unsuccessfully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Observes the fishing pole.</charAction> Hey, where's the fishing
            line?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> Oh, I didn't think you would need it, Sokka.
                <charAction>He holds up an intricately woven necklace decorated with a red
                flower.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walks over and examines the necklace.</charAction> Aw, it's all
            tangled!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rises to his feet.</charAction> Not tangled. Woven! I made you a
            necklace, Katara. I thought since you lost your other one ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He pauses in mid-sentence and displays the necklace, holding it between his
                hands as he flashes a toothy grin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling and approaching him.</charAction> Thanks, Aang.
                <charAction>Takes the necklace.</charAction> I love it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Great, Aang. Maybe instead of saving the
            world, you can go into the jewelry-making business.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't see why I can't do both.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While saying this, Katara can be seen in the background, trying on her new
                necklace. Sokka turns back to the lake, where the se tu continues its acrobatic
                display. Sokka tosses the fishing line into the water in an attempt to spear the
                fish. He only grows more frustrated when he sees the se tu leap from the water,
                unharmed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Stop taunting me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He runs into the water, holding his jawbone dagger. Aang watches him run
                off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> So, how do I look?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns to look at her, a bored expression on his face. His uninterested
                expression, however, soon transforms into one of awe and amazement. The camera
                focuses on Katara, panning upward from her feet to her head. The background around
                her has become colored with shades of pink and purple, sparkles of light glistening
                every now and then. The panshot reveals her smiling sweetly, blushing slightly with
                one hand behind her back and the other touching her necklace in a pose. The scene
                cuts to Aang, who nervously pulls at his collar with his hand, smiling
                awkwardly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> You mean, all of you or just your neck?
                <charAction>Puts his right hand behind his head in embarrassment.</charAction> I
            mean, because they both look great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Emerges from the water, holding the se tu.</charAction> Smoochie,
            smoochie, someone's in love! <charAction>Makes kissing noises before the se tu breaks
                free from his grasp, slapping Sokka in the face with its tail and disappearing under
                the water.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Embarrassed.</charAction> I ... well, uh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Stop teasing him, Sokka. Aang's just a good
            friend. <charAction>Pats the side of his head.</charAction> A sweet, little guy! Just
            like Momo. <charAction>Pets Momo, who lands on Aang's shoulder.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> Thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka emerges empty-handed from the lake, soaking wet and cross. Momo
                suddenly flies off Aang's shoulder upon hearing a loud noise in the distance. He
                leaps onto a rock followed by Aang, who observes the scene. He points to the source
                of the commotion.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Urgently.</charAction> Someone's being attacked by a platypus
            bear!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera focuses on a large, ferocious creature having dark brown fur,
                the body and head of a bear, the tail and bill of a platypus and bearing a white "V"
                across its chest. The creature stands upright on its hind legs and swings at a man
                clad in blue, who smiles merrily, his hands behind his back. The man manages to
                avoid the bear's swing by calmly stepping backward. The creature continues its
                attacks as Aang leaps onto a rock directly behind it. The camera focuses on the calm
                man, who continues to smile as though nothing is occurring.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">Well, hello there! <charAction>Dodges another swift swing of the bear's
                claws.</charAction> Nice day, isn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Make noise! He'll run off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Katara approach the scene.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, play dead! He'll lose interest!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The bear swings its claws only to miss striking the man once
                again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Whoa, close one! <charAction>Laughs
                bemusedly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cups a hand to her mouth and makes gestures with her other
                hand.</charAction> Run downhill, then climb a tree!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, punch him in the bill! <charAction>Swings a fist upward.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">And then run in zig-zags!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">No need, it's going to be fine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The platypus bear attempts to land a blow, cutting a large chunk of wood
                from the trunk of a nearby tree, the calm dodging the attack. Aang leaps into the
                air and lands onto the ground, placing himself between the calm man and the platypus
                bear. He sends the creature back slightly with an air blast.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding his hands out in front of him and assuming a fighting
                stance.</charAction> Whoa there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The platypus bear only rears up on its hind legs further, letting out a
                loud cry. Appa suddenly appears from behind the bear and bellows, causing the animal
                to bristle in fear. The bear lays a large, spotted egg and escapes the scene,
                swimming down the river.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Joyfully picks up the egg.</charAction> Mmm, lunch! <charAction>He
                sniffs it.</charAction> Lucky for you, we came along.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">Thanks, but everything was already under control. Not to worry. Aunt Wu predicted
            I'd have a safe journey. <charAction>Folds hands together and bows
                slightly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Aunt who?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">No, Aunt Wu. She's the fortuneteller from my village.
            Awful nice knowing your future.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks off to the side as she ponders this.</charAction> Wow, it must be.
                <charAction>Faces the man with a bright expression on her face.</charAction> That
            explains why you were so calm!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">But the fortuneteller was wrong! You didn't have a safe journey; you were almost
            killed!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> But I wasn't! All right, have a good one!
                <charAction>He bids them a farewell and begins to walk away only to turn back
                again.</charAction> Oh, and Aunt Wu said if I met any travelers to give them
            this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He hands Aang a wrapped parcel seemingly containing a long, thin object and
                leaves mysteriously. Sokka eyes the man suspiciously.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Maybe we should go see Aunt Wu and learn our
            fortunes. It could be fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh, come on. Fortune telling is nonsense!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang quickly unwraps the mysterious parcel, which turns out to be a red
                umbrella. He opens it and holds it over his head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What do you know? An umbrella!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At that moment, the sky darkens and it begins to rain. A low rumble of
                thunder can be heard. Katara bends an arched shield of water over her head to
                shelter herself from the weather.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That proves it! <charAction>She ducks under the umbrella.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding egg above his head to shield himself from the rain.</charAction>
            No, it doesn't! You can't really tell the future!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smugly.</charAction> I guess you're not
                really getting wet then.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka suddenly loses his grip on the platypus egg as it flies through the
                air. He attempts to catch it, however, it merely flies a few feet into the air and
                lands on his head, cracking and causing the egg to run down his face. Cut to the
                group walking along the path; as the rain continues, Aang and Katara are sheltered
                under the umbrella, while Sokka stays away from them, drenched by the
                downpour.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Crossly.</charAction> Of course she predicted it was going to rain. The
            sky's been gray all day!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Just admit you might be wrong, and you can come under the umbrella.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look, I'm going to predict the future now. <charAction>Stops walking and hops from
                foot to foot in an exaggerated way.</charAction> It's going to keep drizzling.
                <charAction>The rain continues to fall.</charAction> See?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, the rain stops falling and sky lightens up slightly. Cut to a
                shot of Aang and Katara, Aang titling the umbrella back to observe the dramatic
                change in weather.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not everyone has the gift, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a side-view of the entire team walking along the path in
                a strong, yet calm, breeze which rustles the grass on the side of the path. Aang and
                Katara continue to stroll leisurely under the umbrella ahead of Sokka. Appa plods
                behind, pausing briefly to shake his wet fur out, soaking Sokka in the process and
                causing him to flinch.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disgusted.</charAction> Agh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to a view of a large mountain, its peak covered in snow.
                The camera pans down to a small village, which lies at the mountain's very base. The
                team walks through the entrance into the village, turkey ducks quacking as they
                pass. The camera cuts to a strange man dressed in a black robe standing by a round
                doorway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Strange Man">Aunt Wu is expecting you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The trio walks through the doorway, Sokka expressing his disgust. They
                enter a room, three pillows situated on the floor to the right of the room. The
                strange man closes the door. A young girl walks into the room clad in a pink robe
                and wearing her hair in braids that stick out from the sides of her
                head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">My name is Meng and I'm Aunt Wu's assistant.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Her eyes suddenly widen. The camera cuts to a shot of Aang, panning upward
                from his feet to his head. The background is similar to that of Aang's romanticized
                shot of Katara. The pan shot reveals him to be quite bored and slumped over. Cuts to
                close-up of Meng.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Pleased.</charAction> Well, hello there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs nose in disinterest.</charAction> Hello.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Aang and Katara seat themselves on the pillows.</charAction> Can I get
            you some tea or some of Aunt Wu's special bean curd puffs?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Brightening.</charAction> I'll try a curd puff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Holds up index finger in gesture.</charAction> Just a second.
                <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> So what's your name?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Flatly.</charAction> Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Delighted.</charAction> That rhymes with Meng! And you've got some
            pretty big ears, don't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a shot of Aang, somewhat exaggerating the size of his
                ears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> I guess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Waves hand in dismissal and jokes.</charAction> Don't be modest!
                <charAction>Spreads arms outward in emphasis.</charAction> They're huge!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a shot of the entire group, Aang covering his ears in
                embarrassment and glaring at Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Begins walking away.</charAction> Well, Aang, it was very nice to meet
            you. <charAction>Smiles slyly.</charAction>
            Very nice. <charAction>Turns and
            leaves.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Likewise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I can't believe we're here in the house of nonsense.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Try to keep an open mind, Sokka. There are things in this world that just can't be
            explained. Wouldn't it be nice to have some insight into your future?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly.</charAction> It would be nice to have some bean curd
            puffs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to where Meng is shown approaching the room through a nearby hallway
                with a tray of bean curd puffs. A door in the hallway opens and a woman clad in
                green exits. She approaches Meng excitedly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Woman">Oh, Meng! Aunt Wu says I'm going to meet my true love. He's going to give me a rare
            panda lily.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">That's so romantic! <charAction>Dreamily, while casting Aang a flirtatious
                look.</charAction> I wonder if my true love will give me
            a rare flower.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Breezily.</charAction> Good luck with that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Woman">
         <charAction>Trying to contain her laughter.</charAction> Is that the big-eared guy
            who Aunt Wu predicted you'd marry?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Embarrassed by this statement, Meng pushes the woman aside and continues on
                her way to the other room. She approaches the team, her eyes fixated hopefully on
                Aang, who stares off into space, unaware of her presence. She suddenly trips; Aang
                attempts to help her recover, accidentally holding her hands in his in the process.
                The two stare at each other for a moment; Meng blushes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Enjoy your snack! <charAction>Leaves in a
                hurry.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka takes the tray of curd puffs from Aang; he prepares to sample one
                only to be interrupted by an elderly woman, clad in a yellow robe, who enters the
                room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Welcome, young travelers. Now, who's next? Don't be shy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of the team. Sokka looks away uninterested and Aang casts a
                look at Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Rising in anticipation.</charAction> I guess that's me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two exit. Aang and Sokka sit idly on the floor, Sokka tasting the curd
                puffs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Delighted; with his mouth full.</charAction> Mm, not bad, not bad!
                <charAction>Holding out bowl to Aang.</charAction> Mhm?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Refusing the bowl.</charAction> I'm good on puffs. <charAction>Sokka
                shrugs and continues eating the puffs; trying to act casual.</charAction> So, what
            do you think they're talking about back there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Causally, holding up puff.</charAction> Boring stuff I'm sure. Love, who
            she's going to marry, how many babies she's going to have.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Trying to act cool.</charAction> Yeah, dumb stuff like that ...
                <charAction>Tenses a bit and bites his fingers nervously.</charAction> Well, I've
            got to find a bathroom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He rises and walks away off-screen. Sokka lies down, relaxed and samples
                another puff. While eating it, Momo comes on-screen and sneakily takes the bowl away
                for himself. Sokka places his hand down to grab another curd puff, only to open his
                eyes and realize the bowl is gone. Cuts to Aang, who tiptoes down the hallway to
                where Aunt Wu had led Katara into another room, clearly ready to eavesdrop on their
                conversation. Cuts to shot of Aang pressing his ear to the doorway. The following
                conversation between Aunt Wu and Katara occurs off-screen from behind the
                wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Your palms are so smooth. Do you use moisturizer?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Actually, I have this special seaweed lotion. I can get you some if you want.
                <charAction>Aang sticks out his tongue; slight pause.</charAction> So, do you see
            anything interesting in my love line? <charAction>Aang immediately perks up upon hearing
                this.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Somewhat dramatically.</charAction> I feel a great romance for you. The
            man you are going to marry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Tell me more!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">I can see that he's a very powerful bender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Upon hearing this statement, Aang smiles mischievously and leaps in the
                hallway, delighted upon hearing this. Cuts to the room where Sokka sits, picking his
                teeth. Aang struts into the room happily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Looks like someone had a pretty good bathroom break.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah ... when I was in there ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disgusted, looking away and holding up a hand to signal Aang to
                stop.</charAction> I don't even want to know!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Entering the room with Katara.</charAction> Who's next?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Rising.</charAction> Okay, let's get this over with.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Dryly.</charAction> Your future is full of struggle and anguish. Most of
            it, self-inflicted.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding up his hands in protest.</charAction> But you didn't read my
            palms or anything!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">I don't need to. It's written all over your face. <charAction>Sokka resumes picking
                his teeth in disgust; to Aang.</charAction> You there, come with me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang follows Aunt Wu out of the room and into her chamber. The chamber is a
                fairly spacious, dimly lit room. Four pillars support the ceiling and four cushions
                are situated in the center of the room, surrounding a small fire. Off to the side is
                a jug of bones. Aunt Wu and Aang approach the jug.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">This is the most reliable method of telling your fortune. The bones never lie.
                <charAction>Urging Aang to pick a bone.</charAction> Go on, pick one.
                <charAction>Aang takes one bone and they sit down.</charAction> Now throw it on the
            fire. <charAction>Aang tosses the bone into the fire.</charAction> The heat makes cracks
            in the bone and I read the bone cracks to tell your destiny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of the bone sitting in the fire. The camera zooms in on the
                bone as a large crack splinters down its side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow, that's a big crack.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> I've never seen this before!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the bone, camera panning to the right to show more cracks
                forming. The bone explodes and sends a burst of flames up to the
                ceiling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Her and Aang shielding their faces in surprise.</charAction> Oh my!
                <charAction>Cuts to shot of the bone lying in the fire and back to Aunt Wu who is
                fascinated.</charAction> Your destiny! This is incredible. You will be involved in a
            great battle, an awesome conflict between the forces of good and evil. A battle whose
            outcome will determine the fate of the whole world!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> Yeah, yeah, I knew that already. But did it say
            anything about a girl?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> A girl? You want to know about
                love?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Yes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">I'm sorry, but I didn't see anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks down, disappointed at this. Aunt Wu realizes this.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Trying to cheer him up.</charAction> Well, look! <charAction>Holding her
                hand against her face in mock forgetfulness.</charAction> I must've missed
            something. <charAction>Cuts to a bone piece lying on the floor; Wu picks it
                up.</charAction> Right here. <charAction>Holds bone up to examine it.</charAction>
            It says "trust your heart and you will be with the one you love."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Really? <charAction>Rises to his feet joyfully.</charAction> Thank you, Aunt
            Wu!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He runs out of the room gleefully. Aunt Wu hold her hand to her forehead
                and shakes her head in dismay. The scene changes to an overhead view of outside Wu's
                building, the three gathered together with Appa standing behind them. The three
                begin walking down a street.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, now you got to see for yourselves how fortune telling is just a big, stupid
            hoax.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're just saying that because you're going to make yourself unhappy your whole
            life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Voice rising in anger.</charAction> That woman is crazy! My life will
            calm and happy and joyful!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He roughly kicks a nearby stone, which soars into the air and comically
                ends up ricocheting off a hanging metal sign and striking the warrior, who had been
                standing breezily with his arms crossed. He covers his head in pain and falls to the
                ground, off-camera. Hunched over out of view, he raises a finger into the frame in
                protest, his tone agitated.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That doesn't prove anything!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Satisfied.</charAction> Well, I liked my predictions. <charAction>Clasps
                her hands together anxiously.</charAction> Certain things are going to turn out very
            well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slyly, crossing his arms and leaning in toward her.</charAction> They
            sure are ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Why? What did she tell you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Ambiguously.</charAction> Some stuff. You'll find out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara exits along with Aang, who folds his hands contentedly behind his
                head. Cuts to an overhead shot of the village courtyard, a pagoda-like structure
                lying centered in the middle. Cuts to shot of the villagers looking up at the sky
                before switching to a shot of the ground where the team approaches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looking at the sky.</charAction> What's with the sky?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Also viewing the sky.</charAction> We are waiting for Aunt Wu to come
            and read the clouds to predict the fate of the whole village.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Pointing upward.</charAction> That cloud kind of looks like a fluffy
            bunny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Slightly worried.</charAction> You better hope that's not a bunny! The
            fluffy bunny cloud forecasts doom and destruction.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disgusted.</charAction> Do you even hear yourself?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Village Woman">
         <charAction>Gesturing to the mountain in the background.</charAction> The cloud
            reading will tell us if Mt. Makapu will remain dormant for another year or if it will
            erupt.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">We used to have a tradition once a year of going up the mountain to check the
            volcano ourselves. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> But every since Aunt Wu moved to the
            village twenty years ago, we have a tradition of not doing
            that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I can't believe you would trust your lives to that crazy, old woman's
            superstition!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Laying a hand on Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> Shhh! She's
            coming!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot from in between Katara and Sokka's heads. The camera zooms in
                to show Aunt Wu and her guard appearing on-screen, ascending a stairwell. Cuts to an
                overhead shot of the entire courtyard, the crowd having formed an aisle to allow for
                the two figures to pass by. Cuts to shot of Aang and Katara standing next to each
                other, smiling widely as Aunt Wu and the guard walk by them. The crowd is clapping
                for the fortuneteller. Meng appears on-screen next to Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Trying to impress him.</charAction> Hey, Aang. <charAction>Pointing
                upward.</charAction> Don't you think that cloud looks like a flower?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> Huh? Sure, I guess. <charAction>He pushes Meng
                away as the camera pans to the right; to Katara.</charAction> Hey, Katara, don't you
            think that cloud look like a flower?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Shhh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang shows clear disappointment at being hushed. Cuts to the pagoda, where
                Aunt Wu approaches. She spreads her arms outward dramatically. Cuts to shot of the
                sky, an arrow-shaped cloud hovering above. Cuts to Aunt Wu who studies a cloud
                reading book in her hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Thoughtfully.</charAction> Bending arrow cloud ... good crops this year.
            Nice big harvest.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Farmer">
         <charAction>Hugs elderly woman happily.</charAction> Darn good news!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Wavy, moon-shaped cloud ... let's see. <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Gonna be a
            great year for twins!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Poi and Ping">
         <charAction>High-five each other joyfully.</charAction> Yes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Thoughtfully.</charAction> And a cumulus cloud with a twisted nob coming
            off the end of it ... <charAction>Spreads arms outward again.</charAction> The village
            will not be destroyed by the volcano this year!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to an overhead shot of the courtyard, where the crowd cheers
                ecstatically. Cuts to shot of Aang and Katara standing among the crowds, their backs
                facing the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slightly nervous.</charAction> Since I got you here, uh, there's
            something I want to tell you. I like you, but more than normal.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara, enthralled with Aunt Wu and her predictions, runs off to follow the
                fortuneteller, clearly paying no attention to Aang. Aang becomes upset at
                this.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Crushed.</charAction> Never mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the upper levels of Aunt Wu's building, the camera panning
                downward to its entrance. Cuts to the hallway leading to Aunt Wu's chamber, where
                Katara stands before the doorway and knocks. Aunt Wu slides open the
                door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hi, Aunt Wu! Sorry to bother you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Any time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">About this man I'm supposed to marry ... <charAction>Looks down awkwardly and
                blushes.</charAction> Is he going to be handsome? <charAction>Clasps her hands
                together hopefully.</charAction> Oh, I hope he's tall!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Ah ... You want another reading?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yes, please!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two enter the room with the door sliding closed behind them. Cuts to
                shot of upper portion of Sokka's head, an angered expression on his face as he
                marches past in the courtyard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I can't believe all these saps! <charAction>Cuts to side-view of Sokka walking
                forward, Aang following close behind.</charAction> Someone really needs to scream
            some sense into them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">They seem happy, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Not for long. I'm going to prove Aunt Wu's predictions are nonsense.
                <charAction>Pulls over a man standing nearby.</charAction> Hey you, I bet Aunt Wu
            told you to wear those red shoes, didn't she? <charAction>Cuts to shot of the man's red
                shoes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">Yeah. She said I'd be wearing red shoes when I met my true love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Uh huh ... And how many times have you worn those shoes since you got that
            fortune?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">
         <charAction>Smiles sheepishly.</charAction> Everyday.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Background becomes a spiral of swirling orange and yellow flames;
                angry.</charAction> Then of course it's gonna come true!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">
         <charAction>Delighted.</charAction> Really? You think so? <charAction>Begins walking
                away.</charAction> I'm so excited!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In a fit of anger, Sokka kicks a nearby stone; it flies off-screen and ends
                up comically hitting a turkey duck, which flies on-screen and begins attacking
                Sokka. The warrior crouches over and tries to ward of the bird. The scene changes to
                Aunt Wu's chamber, shot from the view of outside the doorway. Cuts to shot of
                Katara's hand outstretched as Aunt Wu traces her finger across her
                palm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">And then you will have your third great-grandchild before quietly passing away in
            your sleep. <charAction>Cuts to shot of Aunt Wu, who does not seem particularly
                happy.</charAction> Is that enough information for you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Lifts her palm in wonder.</charAction> Wow, thanks, Aunt Wu.
                <charAction>She rises and prepares to leave, but suddenly turns back.</charAction>
            Oh wait, one more thing. How warmly should I dress tomorrow?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">You want me to do a reading for that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Katara, who nods almost crazily, a huge grin spread across
                her face. Cuts to outside in the courtyard where Aang stands behind Sokka, who is
                clearly ready to lose his mind, holding his hands up to his head in
                frustration.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Crazed.</charAction> I don't care what Aunt Wu told you! You have to
            take a bath sometime!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of a middle-aged man, covered in dirt and grime from head to
                toe. The man shrugs, grunts a bit and walks off smiling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, Sokka, you know some stuff about ladies, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pleased.</charAction>
            Some stuff? <charAction>Places an arm around Aang's
                shoulders.</charAction> You've come to the right place. What can I do you
            for?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, there's this girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Aang, Meng in the background, standing behind a barrel. She
                laughs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Thinking of Meng rather than Katara.</charAction> I think I know who you
            mean.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You do? And you're okay with it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Of course I am. And to tell you the truth, I've been picking up a subtle vibe that
            she likes you, too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Growing anxious; Meng tries to catch Aang's attention in the
                background.</charAction> She does?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh yeah, she's crazy about you. All you have to do now is not mess it up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, how do I do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">The number once mistake nice guys like you make: being too nice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You can be too nice?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yep. If you want to keep her interested, you have to act aloof, like you don't
            really care one way or the other.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, okay ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shifts to show Meng approaching Aang shyly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">Hey, Aang, I was wondering ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">See you later ... <charAction>Walks away casually and waves hand
                breezily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meng sighs and her ears droop downward, like dog ears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Impressed.</charAction> Wow, that kid is good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the entranceway to Aunt Wu's building, where a
                clearly impatient Wu is shoving Katara out the door. A couple of idle Turkey ducks
                scramble away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">And you'll be fine as long as you've got a scarf. Bye-bye now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay, okay, but one more thing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Stares horrified at Katara before sighing and leaning forward slightly
                in surrender.</charAction> All right, what is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Puts a hand to her chin thoughtfully.</charAction> Should I eat a mango
            or a papaya for breakfast tomorrow?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Papaya! <charAction>Slams the door
                shut.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Kicks the ground, sending up a small cloud of dust.</charAction> Aww, I
            hate papaya.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The view widens to where Aang can be seen slumped against the wall of the
                building, trying to act aloof on Sokka's advice.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Breezily.</charAction> Oh, hey, Katara. I didn't see you there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Half-heartedly.</charAction> Hey, Aang. <charAction>Walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Trying to catch her attention.</charAction> That's okay. I'm busy with
            my own stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang stands idly before a turkey duck flies over and lands near him. After
                a brief moment of looking at each other, the duck quacks. Cuts to shot from slightly
                behind the pagoda in the courtyard, where Katara is seen in the background standing
                by a fruit stand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Less than pleased.</charAction> Ugh, papaya please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot from behind the stand, where Katara is seen on the opposite
                side of the vendor, taking a papaya from the seller's hands. Aang casually walks up
                to her, Momo perched on his shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aloof.</charAction> So ... papaya.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Uh huh. Would you like some?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Causally, picking an apple from the stand.</charAction> You know me. I
            don't really care what I eat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Begins walking away.</charAction> Okay then. See you later.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She exits the scene as Aang bites into the apple only to spit out the
                contents afterward in disgust.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slightly downcast.</charAction> Maybe aloof isn't my style.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He casts his gaze over to a man and the woman seen in Aunt Wu's building
                earlier, who stand in the background, the man having just offered something to the
                woman.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Woman">
         <charAction>From afar; delighted.</charAction> Oh, a panda lily!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The couple embraces. Cuts to shot of Aang, who looks impressed by this
                display.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Momo.</charAction> Did you see that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to close-up of the panda lily, the camera zooming out to show the
                couple still embracing. Aang suddenly appears between the two, pushing them away
                from each other and startling both.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Excuse me. <charAction>Pointing to the flower.</charAction> Where can a guy find one
            of those things?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to an area outside the village, a forested landscape in the
                background, Mt. Makapu standing magnificently behind the trees. Cuts to the side of
                the mountain, Aang leaping upward along the rocky outcrops.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> I can't believe you're dragging me all the way
            up here for a stupid flower.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not just any flower, a panda lily. I've seen it in action and boy, does it
            work.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Sokka scaling the mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Flowers are fine once you're married, but at this early stage, it's critical that
            you maintain maximum aloofness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But my heart is telling me to get this flower, <charAction>Looks up toward the rim
                of the mountain.</charAction> and Aunt Wu said if I trusted in my heart, I will be
            with the one I love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> What? Don't tell me you believe in that stuff,
            too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of Aang perched on one boulder, Sokka appearing
                on-screen.</charAction> Well, Aunt Wu hasn't been wrong yet. Why should she be wrong
            about love? <charAction>Leaps upward and points in delight at the rim.</charAction>
            There! On the rim!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the rim from the center of the volcano's peak, several
                lilies growing. Aang appears on-screen, picks a panda lily and smells it. He opens
                his eyes and gasps in horror. Cuts to a view of the crater, which is nearly filled
                to the brim with lava. Sokka appears beside Aang and also looks
                horrified.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Oh no. <charAction>Cuts to overhead shot of the
                volcano.</charAction> Aunt Wu was wrong.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He drops the panda lily which floats down into the lava, a flame appearing
                in its wake. Cuts to an overhead shot of the volcano, the camera shifting downward
                to show Aang and Sokka on the rim, clearly shocked at the view. Cuts to shot from
                inside the volcano, Aang and Sokka looking downward at the sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Those people all think they're safe! We've got to warn them!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's no time to walk! <charAction>Whips out his glider.</charAction> Grab on!
                <charAction>He pulls Sokka forward, who shouts in surprise and the two take
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of rim as they disappear over the edge, mounted on the glider.
                Cuts to shot of the treetops, Aang and Sokka appearing on-screen. Cuts to overhead
                shot of the village, as they fly toward it rapidly. Cuts to shot of Katara standing
                before the entrance of Wu's building clearly irritated. Aang and Sokka walk up to
                her, having now landed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shyly, raises hand slightly.</charAction> Hi, Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Can you believe she won't let me in? And after all
            the business I've given her?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But she doesn't even charge.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know, but still ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, we have other things to worry about. Aunt Wu was wrong about the
            volcano.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slightly irked, raises finger accusingly.</charAction> Sokka, you tried
            to convince me she was wrong before. It's going to take an awful lot to change my mind
            -</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Her eyes widen in surprise, and she lurches forward as an explosion is
                heard and the volcano rumbles violently. Cuts to shot of the entire group, who is
                slightly shaken. Cuts to shot of her and Aang looking up at the volcano, both their
                backs turned, gray smoke is emitting from the peak of the mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Oh no.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the villagers mingling about in the courtyard,
                Aang, Katara and Sokka among them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Urgently.</charAction> Everyone, that volcano is gonna blow any second!
            Aunt Wu was wrong!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Village Woman">
         <charAction>Not buying his claim.</charAction> Yeah, yeah, we know you don't believe
            in Aunt Wu, Mr. science and reason lover.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Stepping forward.</charAction> If you won't listen to him, maybe you'll
            listen to me. I want to believe Aunt Wu and her predictions as much as you do, but my
            brother and Aang saw the lava with their own eyes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Unmoved.</charAction> Well, I heard Aunt Wu's prediction with my own
            ears.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Leaps onto the awning of a nearby building; urgently.</charAction>
            Please listen to us! You are all in danger! And we have to get out of here! You can't
            rely on Aunt Wu's prediction, <charAction>Cuts to shot of villagers who gaze up at him,
                seemingly listening.</charAction> you have to take fate into your own
            hands!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Another explosion is heard from the volcano. The villagers seem mildly
                alarmed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look! <charAction>Points to the volcano.</charAction> Can your fortune telling
            explain that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the volcano, smoke rising from the top in great
                plumes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man with Red Shoes">
         <charAction>Amused.</charAction> Can your science explain why it rains?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Turns to him; yells angrily.</charAction> Yes! Yes, it can!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the courtyard as the villagers walk away,
                oblivious to the danger. Cuts to shot of Katara and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> They just won't listen to reason.
                <charAction>Aang leaps down from the awning.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Brightening.</charAction> But they will
            listen to Aunt Wu!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I know that's the problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, it's about to become the solution. We're taking fate in our own hands. First,
            I need to borrow Aunt Wu's cloud reading book.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to Sokka and Katara, who stand in front of Aunt Wu's
                building, trying to act casual. Sokka flashes an innocent smile. The camera pans
                upward to the top of the building. Aang appears over the rooftop, along with Momo,
                and and climbs downward onto the porch of the highest story. Cuts to overhead shot
                of Aunt Wu's chamber. Cuts to shot of one corner of the room, where Aang is peering
                in various drawers for the book. Momo chirps.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Shhh! We don't want anyone to hear us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of him as he continues to snoop about, his back facing the
                camera. Meng's reflection appears in the mirror hanging over the dresser. Aang sees
                this reflection and turns around, startled. He stands up straight, Momo hiding
                behind his back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh, I didn't see you there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> You don't like me, do you? <charAction>Her ears
                droop down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Of course I like you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Downcast.</charAction> But not the way I like you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh, I guess not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">It's okay. It's just really hard when you like someone, but they don't think of you
            that way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Casting sad glance to the side.</charAction> I know what you
            mean.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> She's beautiful, by the way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blushes and looks at her, surprised.</charAction> Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of the two standing in the room.</charAction> That Water
            Tribe girl. I can see why you like her so much. <charAction>Clasps hands together,
                counts on her fingers.</charAction> She's sweet, she's a bender <charAction>Cuts to
                shot of Meng.</charAction> and her hair seems so manageable. <charAction>While
                saying this last part, she tries to smooth down her braids only for them to
                immediately stick up again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't worry. You're going to meet a great guy who's going to completely fall for
            you. I know it. <charAction>Places a hand on her shoulder comfortingly; turns to
                leave.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">Thanks. <charAction>Holds up hand in alert.</charAction> Wait! Don't you want this?
                <charAction>Aang looks surprised; Meng hands him the cloud reading book, revealing
                she had had it in her possession the whole time.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">How did you know?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Nervously playing with her fingers.</charAction> I've kind of been
            stalking you. <charAction>Smiles sheepishly.</charAction> Heh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blushing.</charAction> Oh, thanks ... I guess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot to shot of Appa flying through the clouds with Aang and Katara
                on his back, Aang at the reins, Katara seated in his saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Clouds are made of water and air, so between the two of us, we ought to be able to
            bend them into any shape we want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Reading Aunt Wu's book.</charAction> I found it. The symbol for volcanic
            doom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She turns the book around, but keeps her hand placed on the image for
                volcanic doom, obscuring the person's view of the symbol. A cloud passes over the
                screen, signaling the change of scene. The cloud cover clears, depicting both Aang
                and Katara standing on Appa's saddle. In synchronization, they raise their arms
                upward, preparing to shape the clouds. Cuts to shot of Appa sailing through the sky;
                he leans over on his side and sprawls out his legs, dipping into the clouds below.
                Cuts to shot of the villagers below, viewing the changing cloud formations. Cuts to
                shot of the clouds; Appa appears from beneath one of the clouds and flies upward,
                Aang and Katara seen mounted on his saddle. The bison emerges from the top of a
                cloud. Cuts to Katara, who swivels around, a smile spread across her face. Cuts to
                Aang, who swings his arms in a circular motion, using airbending to shape the
                formation. Cuts to shot of Appa flying in the sky that is now rapidly changing.
                Below, the villagers look up to see the clouds shifting. Sokka brings Aunt Wu over
                to her stage. He points to the sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aunt Wu, look! Something is happening in the clouds.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Quizzically.</charAction> That's very strange. It shouldn't ...
                <charAction>A shadow falls over her face as the sky darkens; suddenly
                terrified.</charAction> Oh my!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a view of the new skull-shaped cloud that Aang and Katara formed.
                Cut to a view of a mountain spewing smoke into the air. The screen pans down to the
                village before cutting to a shot where Aang is addressing the crowds.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We still can save the village if we act fast. <charAction>Gesturing toward Sokka,
                who stands on the pagoda.</charAction> Sokka has a plan.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Making motions with his arm.</charAction> Lava is gonna flow downhill to
            this spot. If we can dig a deep enough trench we can channel all the lava away from the
            village to the river.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">If any of you are earthbenders, come with me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Twins from earlier in the episode.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Poi">
         <charAction>Raising hand.</charAction> I'm an earthbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ping">
         <charAction>Raising hand.</charAction> I'm not!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Everybody else grab a shovel <charAction>As another explosion resonates over the
                village, everyone stumbles before regaining balance.</charAction> Come on! We've
            gotta hurry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The crowd disperses very fast, now desperate to put Sokka's plan into
                action. A few cries of urgency are uttered. Cut to overhead shot of the ground
                outside the town during twilight, a deep trench is beginning to form. Team Avatar
                and the town's people labor to dig the trench, using both earthbending and manual
                means. Cuts to shot of two earthbenders, who make motions with their arms and legs.
                Cuts to overhead shot of a portion of the trench as two large boulders are cleared
                out of the way. Cuts to shot from inside the trench as villagers continue their
                labor; Appa is seen transporting loose boulders from the scene, using a net attached
                to his body. Another explosion makes a cut to the mountain again, now lava is
                spewing out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Resuming work.</charAction> Dig faster! Dig faster!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As lava begins to flow down the volcano in the background, the shot cuts to
                Poi as he runs and sweeps his arms forward. Cuts to overhead shot of the trench, the
                bank of the river lying just ahead. A torrent of boulders is cleared and sent down
                the river as Poi creates a channel toward the river. Cuts to shot of the villagers
                standing inside the trench. Aang leaps onto the edge of the trench. In the
                background, the lava steadily creeps further down the mountain toward the
                village.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Everyone needs to evacuate! We'll come for you when it's safe!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Everyone runs. Momo arrives and puts a small rock on the edge of the trench
                and lands on Aang, who pets him before also running away from the edge. Cut to the
                volcano as lava is erupting from its peak. A stream of stream of the burning liquid
                is coursing down the mountain and into the forest. The scene cuts to Aang, Sokka,
                and Katara; their faces illuminated by the approaching lava as they watch anxiously,
                ash falling down upon them. The scene switches to a view of the village gate. An
                eerie reddish light emerges from the forest with its source, the approaching lava,
                close behind. As it passes the gate, the burning substance causes the structure to
                catch fire and crumble down. Unwavering and all-consuming, the lava continuous its
                descent through the cemetery, destroying several headstones as it passes. Reaching
                the trench, the lava falls in the ditch, though the steady incoming river of lava
                quickly threatens to overflow the trench. Cut to the group on the safe side of the
                trench.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's too much! It's gonna overflow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Another explosion rocks the village. Cut to the volcano, where a huge
                column of lava and smoke explodes out of the peak. Burning rocks begin to rain down
                in addition to the ash. Katara and Sokka begin to run for safety but turn to see
                Aang has not moved. A huge boulder falls out of the sky and lands in the trench,
                throwing up a fountain of lava. A massive wave of lava begins to head toward the
                village. Cut to Aang, who is rushing forward with a furious face. He propels himself
                into the air and begins to airbend. As the lava begins to overflow, Aang blows the
                lava straight up, not allowing it to advance on the village. Finally, he draws in a
                mighty intake of breath and expels it, airbending it as it exits, cooling all the
                lava to stone. Aang relaxes and assumes a meditation pose. Cut to Katara and Sokka
                watching in surprise, their backs to the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Man, sometimes I forget what a powerful bender that kid is. <charAction>Katara's
                expression changes at this, remembering Aunt Wu's words about her future
                marriage.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Wait, what did you just say?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> Nothing, just that Aang is one powerful
            bender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara's and Sokka's view of Aang and back to shot of
                Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slowly widens her eyes in realization; as if having an
                epiphany.</charAction> I suppose he is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to the volcano, smoking, but no longer erupting. Cuts to a view of the
                square where Aunt Wu and the town's people, including the Calm man, have assembled.
                A tall, jagged wall-like formation of cooled lava towers over the square. Aang
                stands in front of Aunt Wu, offering her back the cloud book he took.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> By the way, we kind of borrowed your
            book.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">So you messed with the clouds, did you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Wu grabs the book in anger while Katara looks guilty and Sokka smiles and
                points at her, indicating that she had a part in the cloud manipulation,
                too.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">
         <charAction>Laughs in amusement.</charAction> Very clever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No offense, but I hope this taught everyone a lesson about not relying too much on
            fortune telling.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Calm man">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> But Aunt Wu predicted the village wouldn't be
            destroyed and it wasn't. She was right, after all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Gets near the Calm man's face, through gritted teeth.</charAction> I
            hate you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Holding Sokka by the shoulders and leading him away.</charAction> It's
            okay, Sokka. Everything's going to be all right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of Aang and Wu.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Can I ask you something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">Of course, honey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> You didn't really see love in my fortune, did
            you? You just told me what I wanted to hear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Wu">I'll tell you a little secret, young airbender. <charAction>Gestures to the
                sky.</charAction> Just as you reshaped those clouds, <charAction>Cuts to shot of
                Aang, who smiles; off-camera.</charAction> you have the power to shape your own
            destiny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang smiles. Cut to shot of Appa and Team Avatar. Meng stands in front of
                Appa. Aang airbends himself onto Appa's saddles; Katara is at the
                reins.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Brightly.</charAction> Goodbye everyone! It was so nice to meet you!
                <charAction>To Meng.</charAction> Take care, Meng.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Meng">
         <charAction>Waving.</charAction> Take care! <charAction>Appa turns away. Cuts to
                Meng's face, whose smile disappears and is replaced by a frown.</charAction>
            Floozy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
