<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="56">The Ember Island Players</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Tim Hedrick</writer>
      <writer>Josh Hamilton</writer>
      <writer>John O'Bryan</writer>
      <date>2008-07-18</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins at Ozai's home on Ember Island. Cut to overhead shot of
                a courtyard where Aang and Zuko practice firebending using synchronized fire blasts.
                Cut to ground-level shot of the two as they create sweeping arcs of fire that
                dissipate into the ground. They each raise an arm and leg, sending forth streams of
                fire, before leaning forward and sending forth another stream of fire. Cut to closer
                shot of Aang and Zuko as they stand upright, assuming a final fighting stance before
                closing their eyes, relaxing their postures, and taking a deep breath. Toph and
                Katara are seen in the background, sitting on steps nearby. Zuko and Aang bow to one
                another, and the latter stretches his arms and walks away. Cut to Katara and Toph,
                who is lying down on the ground, relaxing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Doesn't it seem kind of weird that we're hiding from the Fire Lord in his own
            house?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I told you, <charAction>Cut to Zuko sitting on a dry fountain and wiping his head
                with a cloth.</charAction> my father hasn't come here since our family was actually
            happy. And that was a long time ago. It's the last place anyone would think to look for
            us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide-view of the courtyard from where Katara and Toph are sitting,
                their backs to the screen. Sokka and Suki enter on-screen from afar, Sokka holding a
                rolled-up piece of paper.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You guys are not gonna believe this! There's a play about us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Cut to close-up of her and Sokka.</charAction> We were just in town and
            we found this poster! <charAction>Sokka shows the poster for the play to the team. It
                depicts Katara, Aang, and Sokka with Zuko's scarred face in the
                background.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What? How is that possible?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Listen to this ... <charAction>Turns the poster toward him.</charAction>
                "The Boy in the Iceberg> is a new production from
            acclaimed playwright Pu-on Tim, <charAction>Cut to a close shot of the poster as the
                camera pans up.</charAction> who scoured the globe gathering information on the
            Avatar, from the icy South Pole to the heart of Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Shot changes to
                show Team Avatar.</charAction> His sources include singing nomads, pirates,
            prisoners of war, and a surprisingly knowledgeable merchant of cabbage."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">"Brought to you by the critically acclaimed Ember Island Players."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Recalling a memory.</charAction> Ugh! My mother used to take us to see
            them. They butchered Love Amongst the Dragons> every
            year!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, do you really think it's a good idea for us to attend a play about
            ourselves?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Persuasively.</charAction> Come on, a day at the theater? This is the
            kind of wacky time-wasting nonsense I've been missing! <charAction>He holds up the
                poster anxiously and smiles sheepishly; Katara looks away, appears
                nonplussed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to nighttime at the theater. Cut to inside the theater to show the
                stage and curtain. The camera zooms out to show the balcony as Toph, Katara, and
                Aang arrive, with Aang wearing a hat to cover his head tattoos. Toph and Katara sit
                down; Zuko sits next to Katara as Aang tries to sit next to her. Aang stands back
                up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Zuko; points to his seat and tries to act casual.</charAction> Hey,
            uh ... I wanted to sit there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Removing his hood.</charAction> Just sit next to me. What's the big
            deal?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I was just, I wanted to ... okay. <charAction>Sits down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Suki sit in the row behind the rest of Team Avatar.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Why are we sitting in the nosebleed section? My feet can't see a thing from up
            here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Don't worry, I'll tell your feet what's happening.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The curtain rises to reveal a set representative of the South Pole seas.
                Actress Katara and Actor Sokka are rowing their boat along. Cut to Katara who looks
                thrilled to see herself onstage, and Sokka grabs her shoulder, pointing at her,
                himself, and the stage excitedly. Cut to shot of Actress Katara, an older, more
                robust woman wearing Water Tribe garments.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Sokka, my only brother! We constantly roam these icy
            South Pole seas, and yet never do we find anything fulfilling!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to Actor Sokka, a thin, lanky man.</charAction> All I want is a full
            feeling in my stomach! I'm starving!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The audience laughs. Cut to Sokka and Katara as their faces fall; they look
                at each other, confused. Cut to angled shot of the stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">Is food the only thing on your mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to shot of the actor.</charAction> Well, I'm trying to get it out of
            my mind and into my mouth! I'm starving! <charAction>Audience
            laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Leans forward in his seat; clearly annoyed.</charAction> This is
            pathetic! My jokes are way funnier than this! <charAction>Extends his arm in a dramatic
                gesture.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Laughing.</charAction> I think he's got you pegged!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to the stage where Actress Katara now stands in the
                canoe.</charAction> Every day, the world awaits a beacon to guide us, yet none
            appears! <charAction>Cut to close-up of the actress who holds her hand out and clasps
                her hands together dramatically.</charAction> Still, we cannot give up hope! For
            hope, <charAction>Begins to cry.</charAction> is all we have! And we must never
            relinquish it, even ... <charAction>Sniffs and falls back into a sitting
                position.</charAction> even to our dying breath! <charAction>Leans over the side of
                the canoe and buries her face in her hands, crying.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the team, Suki holding her hand over her mouth to suppress a laugh
                and Sokka looking over at Katara with an amused smile, while Toph and Zuko are
                enjoying the play.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>With crossed arms, displeased.</charAction> Well, that's just silly. I
            don't sound like that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Elated.</charAction> Oh man! This writer's a genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actress Katara still slumped over the side of the canoe. An
                iridescent light suddenly appears from above and she turns her head upward, shocked.
                Cut to shot of the stage where a model iceberg can be seen, the vague shadow of a
                figure visible from behind. The two actors stand up in the canoe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">It appears to be someone frozen in ice, perhaps for a hundred years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Closer shot of the silhouette swaying from side to side inside the
                iceberg prop.</charAction> But who? Who is the boy in the iceberg?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang who smiles and leans forward in his seat. Cut to close-up of
                the model iceberg where Actress Katara stands before the silhouetted figure, Actor
                Sokka hosting himself onto the prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">Waterbend! Hi-yah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She performs a karate chop, mimicking waterbending. The silhouette
                disappears from view and the prop splits in half, sending forth a jet of steam. An
                actress, meant to portray Aang, leaps up on screen and poses, winking and with one
                hand on hip. The actress is visibly wearing a flesh-colored cap over her hair to
                portray herself as bald; the cap also bears the airbending mastery tattoo. She wears
                an excessive amount of blush on her cheeks and her overall physiognomy and demeanor
                clearly display her femininity.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of the actual Aang who momentarily closes his eyes and cringes
                in disbelief before leaning forward over the railing even more, eyes bugging out.
                Cuts back to the actors on stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">Who are you, frozen boy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Laughs; in a high-pitched voice.</charAction> I'm the Avatar, silly,
            here to spread joy and fun! <charAction>She leans toward Actress Katara, laying a finger
                on her lips, and also motions toward Actor Sokka before standing upright and
                spreading her arms out in a cheery gesture.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait, is that a woman playing me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A crude, costumed-version of Appa suddenly bursts up from behind the trio
                of actors; loud festival music previously heard in the episode "Avatar Day" is
                presently played. The replica of Appa sways from side to side before leaping off the
                iceberg prop. Cut to a wide shot of the stage as the three actors wearing the bison
                costume, only their legs visible, land to the right of the stage, run across to the
                left side, and finally behind the iceberg prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Gasps.</charAction> An airbender! <charAction>Clasps her hands to her
                chest.</charAction> My heart is so full of hope, <charAction>Drops down on one knee
                emotionally.</charAction> that it's making me tearbend! <charAction>Begins to cry
                and grabs on to Actress Aang's leg. Cut to close-up of Actress Katara who continues
                to bawl dramatically. Cut back to shot of the entire trio.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">My stomach is so empty, that it's making me tearbend!
                <charAction>Throws his arms up hopelessly before dropping to his knees, clutching on
                to Actress Aang's other leg, and crying.</charAction> I need meat! <charAction>Cut
                to close-up of Actor Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Stoops down, puts her arm around Actor Sokka's shoulders, and points
                upward.</charAction> But wait! Is that a platter of meaty dumplings? <charAction>Cut
                to actual Aang whose head and arm rest lazily on the railing,
                unimpressed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to shot of the trio, Actress Aang now sitting down, her legs
                dangling over the edge of the iceberg prop. Both Actress Katara and Actor Sokka are
                kneeling down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Excitedly; shielding his eyes with his hand and turning his head,
                searching for the alleged dumplings.</charAction> Ooh, where, where?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Laughs and swings arm jovially.</charAction> Did I mention that I'm an
            incurable prankster? <charAction>Crosses her legs as the audience
            laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to wide shot of Team Avatar. Aang extends his arm toward the stage,
                angry with the actress' bad portrayal.</charAction> I don't do that! That's not what
            I'm like! And I'm not a woman! <charAction>Throws hands up in
                frustration.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Laughs and turns to face Aang.</charAction> Oh, they nailed you, Twinkle
            Toes! <charAction>Continues to laugh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to stage where the trio of actors and iceberg prop are no longer
                present; the scene continues to depict the South Pole seas. A model Fire Nation ship
                prop glides onto stage from the left; a man portraying Prince Zuko stands at the bow
                of the ship, garbed in Zuko's outfit from Book One and peering through a telescope.
                The actor portraying Iroh stands at the helm.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of Actor Iroh, a very rotund, round-faced man sporting a
                slightly exaggerated imitation of the real Iroh's hairstyle, complete with a
                top-knot, beard, and sideburns.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Iroh">
         <charAction>Looking towards Actor Zuko, at ease.</charAction> Prince Zuko, you
                must try this cake! <charAction>Holds up a platter of
                cake with one slice missing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actor Zuko looking through the telescope. He wears a headpiece that
                sports the ponytail Zuko once wore, albeit slightly exaggerated, and Zuko's scar;
                the replicated scar, while realistic, is worn over the wrong eye.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Determined.</charAction> I don't have time to stuff my face!
                <charAction>Lowers his telescope and turns to Actor Iroh.</charAction> I must
            capture the Avatar to regain my honor! <charAction>Faces out into the audience,
                clutching his hand in a fist assertively.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Iroh">
         <charAction>Cut to wide shot of the model ship.</charAction> Well, while you do
            that, <charAction>Actor Zuko looks at him, annoyed.</charAction> maybe I'll capture
            another slice. <charAction>He holds the cake up higher before bringing it toward his
                face and proceeding to gobble it down ravenously and noisily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns his view from Actor Iroh, in disgust.</charAction> You sicken
            me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of Katara and Zuko in their seats, both with their arms
                crossed. Zuko appears displeased with his character portrayal while Katara looks at
                him with a smug smile.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Gestures toward the stage.</charAction> They make me look totally stiff
            and humorless.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Complacently amused.</charAction> Actually, I think that actor's pretty
            spot on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>In protest; holding his arms out.</charAction> How could you say
            that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the bow of the model ship where Actor Zuko has resumed peering
                through his telescope. Actor Iroh stands behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Iroh">
         <charAction>Completely at ease.</charAction> Let's forget about the Avatar and get
            massages!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns toward his uncle, leaning forward menacingly;
                shouting.</charAction> How could you say that?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara and Zuko; the former continues to smile smugly as the latter
                slumps down in his seat, defeated and dismayed to find her claim
                accurate.</description>
      <description>Fade to a background drawing of the Southern Air Temple. The camera pans
                down to show Actress Aang searching, and finds a tail behind a bush
                prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">Hey look, I think I found something! <charAction>Tiptoes to the bush. Actor Sokka
                scratches his head while Actress Katara shrugs. Actress Aang picks up the Momo prop,
                a rabbit-monkey puppet.</charAction> It's a flying rabbit-monkey! I think I'll name
            him, Momo! <charAction>Laughs; using puppet.</charAction> Hi everybody, I love you!
                <charAction>The audience laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ugh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actress Suki, holding up two fans. She lifts them up. Actor Sokka
                enters in the Kyoshi Warriors' uniform.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Pointing to his backside.</charAction> Does this dress make my butt look
            fat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Audience laughs, as does Suki. Sokka gives her an embarrassed look. </description>
      <description>Cut to Actor Bumi with an Omashu background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Bumi">Riddles and challenges you must face, <charAction>Camera pans back to show the whole
                stage.</charAction> if you are ever to leave this place!
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Aang dodges a swaying rock while a goat gorilla chases Actor Sokka
                across stage. Actress Katara stands amidst a jennamite prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Lifting up a piece of the jennamite prop.</charAction> Ugh! Oh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara gives a disgusted look and sticks out her tongue. Cut to the stage
                with a pirate ship background with the Team Avatar players in center stage. The
                pirates enter the stage from both side holding weapons in the air and attack them.
                The Team Avatar players slip away, with Actress Katara holding a large scroll. They
                tiptoe off stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Why did you have to steal that waterbending scroll?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Crying.</charAction> It just gave me so much hope! <charAction>Katara
                narrows her eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a stage hand holding a sheet of metal, which he shakes to make a
                sound effect. Cut to the stage to show Actress Aang tied to a platform guarded by
                six Fire Nation soldiers. Actor Zuko stands in front of the platform.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">The Avatar is mine! <charAction>Looking of stage.</charAction> Wait, who's
            coming?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Blue Spirit">
         <charAction>Jumps on stage holding two swords and has a large mask.</charAction> I'm
            the Blue Spirit, the scourge of the Fire Nation, here to save the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Blue Spirit walks across the stage waving his swords. The guards fall
                down and Actor Zuko runs around the platform and throws a red strip of paper to
                symbolize firebending. The Blue Spirit points a sword at Actor Zuko, who runs
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">My hero! <charAction>Jumps on top of the Blue Spirit's large
            mask.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Blue Spirit walks off stage. Zuko and Aang frown, giving each other an
                embarrassed look. </description>
      <description>Fade to a stagehand using a crank to lower the actors. Actress Katara and
                Actor Jet appear on a small rope platform. Actress Katara cries.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Jet">Don't cry, baby! Jet will wipe out that nasty town for you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A large blue banner pulled by a stagehand dressed in black crosses the
                stage. Actress Katara and Actor Jet ascend on their platform.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">Oh Jet, you're so bad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Both exit. Katara appears embarrassed. Toph laughs. </description>
      <description>Fade to the team traveling on a large Appa prop with mountains painted in
                the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Gasps.</charAction> Look! It's the Great Divide! The biggest canyon in
            the Earth Kingdom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Eh, let's keep flying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a stagehand dropping a bag of fake snow on stage in one spot. Cut to
                Actor Sokka and Actress Yue with a Northern Water Tribe background
                painting.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Don't go, Yue! You're the only woman who has taken my mind off of food!
                <charAction>Kisses Yue. Gags.</charAction> Wait, did you have pickled fish for
            dinner?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Yue">Goodbye, Sokka! I have important moon duties to take care of! <charAction>Exits on
                the moon prop.</charAction> And yes, I did have pickled fish!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> You never told me you made out with a Moon
            Spirit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">[Placing a finger on Suki's lips] Shhh! <charAction>Tearing up.</charAction> I'm
            trying to watch! <charAction>Suki, disgusted by Sokka's act, looks away, and folds her
                arms.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to miniature Fire Nation ships being pulled across the stage by ropes.
                Actress Aang, wearing a Koizilla costume, stomps on them. She waves a doll of
                Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> The Avatar is back to save the day! Yay!
                <charAction>Actress Aang stomps three more miniature ships before tripping over her
                Koizilla costume and falling.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Curtain drops. The audience cheers and Toph laughs. All the other members
                of Team Avatar appear disgusted. Zuko puts on his hood.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to outside the theater. The camera pans to Team Avatar sitting on a
                flight of stairs during intermission.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Unimpressed</charAction> So far, this intermission is the best part of
            the play.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walks down the stairs holding a bag of flaming fire flakes and sits next
                to Suki.</charAction> Apparently, the playwright thinks I'm an idiot who tells bad
            jokes about meat all the time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Hint of sarcasm.</charAction> Yeah, you tell bad jokes about plenty of
            other topics.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Eats a fire flake.</charAction> I know!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> At least the Sokka actor kind of looks like you.
                <charAction>Sokka becomes furious over Aang's remark while Suki gleefully
                smiles.</charAction> That woman playing the Avatar doesn't resemble me at
            all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I don't know, you are more in touch with your feminine side than most guys.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Standing up, angrily.</charAction> Argh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Relax, Aang. They're not accurate portrayals. It's not like I'm a preachy crybaby
            who can't resist giving overemotional speeches about hope all the time.
                <charAction>Everyone looks at her.</charAction> What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turns around and sits down. Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, that's not
            you at all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Listen friends, it's obvious that the playwright did his research. I know it must
            hurt, but what you're seeing up there on that stage is the truth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to a painted background with Earth Kingdom buildings. The Team Avatar
                players stand next to a large rock.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">Well, here we are in the Earth Kingdom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Opens up her miniature air glider prop.</charAction> I'd better have a
            look around to see if I can find an earthbending teacher! <charAction>Jumps up into the
                air with a cable lifting her up.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">This is it, this must be where I come in!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Aang flies around the theater, over the audience, and returns to
                the stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">I flew all over town, but I couldn't find a single earthbending master!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Joyfully</charAction> Here it comes ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Toph">[<charAction>Enters the stage from a trapdoor beneath the rock prop and holds it
                above his head.</charAction> You can't find an earthbending master in the sky, you
            have to look underground! <charAction>Throws away the prop.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, Sokka, Suki, and Katara laugh. Zuko looks up from a piece of paper
                and stunned, drops the paper. And Toph is still looking eager.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">Who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Toph">
         <charAction>Spits.</charAction> My name's Toph, <charAction>Flexes.</charAction>
            because it sounds like tough, and that's just what I am! <charAction>Audience
                laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Wait a minute, <charAction>Picks at her ear with her pinky.</charAction>
         <charAction>confused</charAction>] I sound like a guy. A really buff guy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Well Toph, what you hear up there is the truth. It hurts, doesn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Are you kidding me? I wouldn't have cast it any other way! [<charAction>Laughs as
                Katara looks away in dismay.</charAction> At least it's not a flying bald lady!
                <charAction>Camera pans to Aang, who turns toward the stage in
                annoyance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">So, you're blind? <charAction>Waves hand in front of Actor Toph's
            eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Toph">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> I can see you doing that. I see everything that you
            see, except I don't "see" like you do. I release a sonic wave from my mouth.
                <charAction>Screams very loudly at the Team Avatar players. The audience and Team
                Avatar grimace at the scream; Aang claps his hands over his ears, Zuko grips the
                railing in front of him, Suki and Sokka hug each other in terror, and Katara grits
                her teeth while Toph looks excited.</charAction> There. I got a pretty good look at
            you. <charAction>Actress Aang and the audience claps.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a stagehand operating a light. The shot changes to show the Actors
                Zuko and Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Iroh">Zuko, it's time we had a talk ... <charAction>Points to Zuko, who now wears a large
                wig.</charAction> about your hair, it's gone too far!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Maybe it's best if we ... split ... up! <charAction>Actors Zuko and Iroh walk away
                from each other.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Team Avatar players and Actors Zuko and Iroh cornering Actress
                Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Azula, my sister, what are you doing here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">You caught me. Wait, what's that? <charAction>Points in the distance.</charAction> I
            think it's your honor!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Where? <charAction>Everybody looks while Actress Azula escapes through a
                door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Turning to audience.</charAction> She escaped, but
                how?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to a stagehand sitting on a stool while he rotates a lever. Shot
                changes to show the a large drill prop which Actress Azula stands on while it drills
                through a wall that Actress Aang attempts stands on. One stagehands dressed in black
                clothing shakes the wall while another waves smoke onto the stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">If she continues drilling, this wall will come down for sure!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A stagehand offers Actress Aang a rock prop, which she throws at Actress
                Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">
         <charAction>Blocks the rock prop.</charAction> Haha, yes! Continue drilling! The
            city of Ba Sing Se can hide no longer!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Aang throws two more rock props at Azula. The shot changes to show
                members of the audience yawning and falling asleep.</description>
      <description>Cut to Actor Jet jumping in front of the camera. He wears googly eyes and
                waves his hook hands around. Camera zooms out to show the Team Avatar players
                surrounding Actor Jet.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">No, Jet! What did they do to you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Jet">Must ... serve ... Earth King! <charAction>Begins swinging his hook hand wildly at
                Actress Aang and Actor Sokka.</charAction> Must ... destroy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A stage hand is seen throws a hollow rock prop which floats down. Actor Jet
                falls down so that he lands underneath the prop and crawls all the way
                under.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Did Jet just ... die?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You know, it was really unclear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to Actress Katara with the stage background painted as the Crystal
                Catacombs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">I have to admit Prince Zuko, I really find you
            attractive!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Shot changes to show him sitting on a rock bench.</charAction> You don't
            have to make fun of me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">But I mean it! <charAction>Sits down with Actor Zuko.</charAction> I've had eyes for
            you since the day you first captured me! <charAction>Zuko and Katara inch away from each
                other, slightly uncomfortable. Aang narrows his eyebrows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Wait, I thought you were the Avatar's girl!
                <charAction>Aang nods.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> The Avatar? <charAction>Stands up and walks toward
                Actor Zuko.</charAction> Why, he's like a little brother to me!
                <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> I certainly don't think of him in a romantic way.
                <charAction>Aang grows concerned.</charAction> Besides, how could he ever find out
            about ... this? <charAction>Actress Katara and Actor Zuko embrace and hold hands while
                Actress Katara pops up one leg. Aang gets up.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Oh, you're getting up? <charAction>As Aang
                leaves.</charAction> Can you get me some fire flakes? <charAction>Puts his arm
                around Suki, but whispers to Aang again.</charAction> Ooh, and fire gummies!
                <charAction>Puts his arm back around Suki, who looks slightly
            annoyed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actor Zuko standing between Actor Azula, who has a Fire Nation flag
                behind her, and Actor Iroh, who has an Earth Kingdom flag behind him. A light shines
                on Actor Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">Well, my brother, what's it going to be? Your nation, or a life of
            treachery?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Iroh">
         <charAction>Stops drinking from a cup.</charAction> Choose treachery, it's more fun!
                <charAction>Winks and gives a thumbs up sign.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actor Zuko walks toward Actor Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">No way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">
         <charAction>Pushes Actor Iroh over and walks to Actress Azula.</charAction> I hate
            you, Uncle! You smell, and I hate you for all time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Earth Kingdom flag falls on Actor Iroh as Actress Azula and Actor Iroh
                exit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> You didn't really say that, did you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I might as well have.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actress Mai, who pulls a sword out of her hair and gives it to a
                ninja, who takes a guard away. The shot changes to show the stage is set up to
                resemble the Earth King's throne room. Actress Ty Lee jumps to the other guard,
                kisses her finger and touches the guard's shoulder, causing him to fall over.
                Actress Azula jumps behind Actress Ty Lee and they pose. The audience applauds.
                Actress Aang jumps in from behind the set.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">Avatar State, yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The stage light shines on Actress Aang, causing her tattoos and eyelids to
                glow. A stagehand runs across the stage and ties a rope to Actress Aang. Actress
                Aang closes her eyes while the rope lifts her into the air. Actress Azula jumps on
                stage from behind the smoke.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">Not if my lightning can help it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Azula throws a blue streamer at Actress Aang. Actress Aang peeks
                from behind her closed eye and grabs blue streamer, shaking and screaming in feigned
                pain. The audience looks at the scene in shock. Actress Aang's limp body is slowly
                lowered to the stage. Actresses Ty Lee and Mai pose on both sides of Actress Azula,
                who stands in front of Actress Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">The Avatar is no more!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Audience applauds loudly, while Team Avatar again gives disgusted looks. </description>
      <description>Fade to outside the theater, where everyone except Aang is present for the
                second intermission.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">It seems like every time there's a big battle, you guys barely make it out alive. I
            mean, you guys lose a lot!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You're one to talk, Suki. Didn't Azula take you captive? That's right, she
            did!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Looks at Sokka seriously.</charAction> Are you trying to get on my bad
            side?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm just saying ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Does anyone know where Aang is?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">He left to get me fire gummies, like, ten minutes ago. And I'm still
            waiting!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm gonna check outside.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang standing alone on a balcony. Katara enters and walks up to
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Are you all right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angered.</charAction> No, I'm not! I hate this play! <charAction>Yanks
                his hat off and throws it on the ground.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know it's upsetting, but it sounds like you're overreacting.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Overreacting? If I hadn't blocked my chakra, I'd probably be in the Avatar State
            right now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the rest of Team Avatar inside the building. A kid wearing an Aang
                costume runs by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Suki, what are the chances you can get me backstage? I got some jokes I want to give
            to the actor me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Seriously.</charAction> I'm an elite warrior who's trained for many
            years in the art of stealth. <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> I think I could get you
            backstage! <charAction>Sokka and Suki leave.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>To Zuko, after observing everyone's reactions.</charAction> Geez,
            everyone's getting so upset about their characters. Even you seem more down than usual,
            and that's saying something!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You don't get it, it's different for you. You get a muscly version of yourself,
            taking down ten bad guys at once, and making sassy remarks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, that's pretty great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But for me, it takes all the mistakes I've made in my life, and shoves them back in
            my face. My uncle, he's always been on my side, even when things were bad. He was there
            for me, he taught me so much, and how do I repay him? With a knife in his back. It's my
            greatest regret, and I may never get to redeem myself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Sits down next to him.</charAction> You have redeemed yourself to your
            uncle. You don't realize it, but you already have.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">How do you know?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Because I once had a long conversation with the guy, and all he would talk about was
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, and it was kind of annoying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Oh, sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">But it was also very sweet. All your uncle wanted was for you to find your own path,
            and see the light. Now you're here with us. He'd be proud. <charAction>Punches Zuko on
                the shoulder.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Ow! What was that for?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">That's how I show affection.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The same boy with the Aang costume comes by and sees Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young boy">Your Zuko costume's pretty good, but your scar's on the wrong side. <charAction>Runs
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">The scar's not on the wrong side! <charAction>Covers his face with his
                hood.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to backstage as the actors talk with each other and prepare their
                costumes. Sokka and Suki peek backstage and spot Actor Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">He's coming this way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka jumps out in front of Actor Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Can I help you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Actually, I think I can help you. I'm a big Sokka fan, but I don't think you're
            representing him quite as well as you could be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Starts walking away.</charAction> Aww no, another fan with
            ideas.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Runs in front of him.</charAction> Just hear me out. <charAction>Pulls
                out some cards.</charAction> Here's something I think the real Sokka would say.
                <charAction>Clears throat.</charAction> What does the cabbage merchant use to fix
            his cabbages? A cabbage patch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki gives herself a face palm in the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> That's actually pretty good! Let me see those!
                <charAction>Takes the cards from Sokka. Reads one and laughs.</charAction> "A rocky
            relationship" ... not bad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Puts his arm around Actor Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> Also, don't be
            afraid to make up some phrases, especially before an attack. Something like ... "Flying
            kick-a-pow!". <charAction>The two begin to walk away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Who are you, anyway?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm just a guy who likes comedy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the full moon. The shot changes to show Katara and Aang alone on the
                balcony.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, did you really mean what you said in there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">In where? What are you talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">On stage, when you said I was just like a ... brother to you, and you didn't have
            feelings for me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I didn't say that. An actor said that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But it's true, isn't it? We kissed at the Invasion, and I thought we were gonna be
            together. But we're not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, I don't know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Why don't you know?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Because, we're in the middle of a war, and, we have other things to worry about.
            This isn't the right time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, when is the right time?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, I'm sorry, but right now I'm just a little confused.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang tries to kiss Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I just said I was confused! I'm going inside. <charAction>Exits the
                balcony.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ugh, I'm such an idiot! <charAction>Puts down his head on the balcony
                railing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to back inside the theater. Aang returns to the rest of the group and
                sits in the back row with Suki and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Here's what you missed ... we went to the Fire Nation, and you got better, and
            Katara was the Painted Lady, and I got a sword, and I think Combustion Man died. Oh,
            look, the Invasion's about to start! Shhh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actresses Katara and Aang standing on one of the
                submarines.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Katara">I just wanted to let you know, Aang, that I'll always love you. Like a
            brother.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Punching the air.</charAction> I wouldn't want it any other
            way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two shake hands. Actress Aang opens his miniature glider and flies up
                via a rope. Actress Katara waves. Aang curls up and uses his hat to cover his face.
                Actress Katara and Actors Toph and Sokka looking around on top of the
                submarine.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">Hey Toph, would you say you and Aang have a "rocky relationship"?
                <charAction>Audience laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Laughs hysterically at Suki and Aang. Lifts up Aang's hat.</charAction>
            I told him to say that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">I hope everyone's ready for the Invasion! Slap-a-pow! <charAction>The audience and
                Sokka laugh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The curtain rises, two stagehands clad in black finish pushing the Royal
                Palace prop and run off stage. Actress Katara and Actors Toph and Sokka enter from
                the sides of the stage, while Actress Aang is dropped in from above the
                stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">We finally made it to the Royal Palace, but no one's home!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Enter Actor Zuko, stage right and Actor Sokka raises his
                boomerang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Actually, I'm home, and I want to join you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Sokka">
         <charAction>Lowers his boomerang.</charAction> I guess we have no choice. Come on!
                <charAction>All exit stage left, except for Actress Aang, who is lifted off
                stage.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stands up and stretches.</charAction> I guess that's it. The play's
            caught up to the present now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">Wait, the play's not over!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sits back down.</charAction> But it is over, unless ...
                <charAction>Dramatically.</charAction> this is the future.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Actor Ozai on stage. The shot changes to show him standing on the
                Royal Palace prop. An orange lantern held by a small cable with paper flames slowly
                moves across the stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Ozai">With the energy harnessed from that comet, no one will be able to stop ...
                <charAction>Lifts his hands in the air.</charAction> the Fire Nation!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Azula enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">Father, Zuko and the Avatar are at the Palace. They're trying to stop you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Ozai">You take care of Zuko. I shall face the Avatar myself! <charAction>Disappears behind
                a smokescreen.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actor Zuko jumps on stage and a rope lowers Actress Aang on stage as he
                holds his miniature glider prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Aang! You find the Fire Lord, I'll hold her off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The cable lifts Actress Aang off stage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">You are no longer my brother. You are an enemy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">No! I am the rightful heir to the throne!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">We'll see!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Azula pulls out her blue streamer and snaps it at Zuko who ducks
                out of the way. Actor Zuko holds two red streamers and jumps to the other side of
                Actress Azula. He throws his two red streamers at her and Actress Azula jumps over
                him. Actress Azula raises her hand not holding the blue streamer. Five red paper
                resembling flames shot from the ground starting at Actress Azula, the last one
                covering Actor Zuko so that only his silhouette can be seen.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Zuko">Honor! <charAction>He drops off stage through a trapdoor with the
                flames.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actress Azula bows. The audience cheers. Zuko looks worried and the rest of
                Team Avatar looks at him. The shot changes to show the stage, which has small paper
                flames fluttering upstage. Actress Aang walks across the stage and looks around
                while Actor Ozai sits on his throne beneath the Sozin's Comet prop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Ozai">So, you have mastered all four elements?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Pointing her staff prop at him.</charAction> Yeah, and now you're going
            down!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Ozai">No! It is you who are going down! <charAction>Stands
                up.</charAction> You see, you are too late! The comet is already here,
                <charAction>Actress Aang looks in concern at the audience. Aang widens his
                eyes.</charAction> and I'm unstoppable!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Actor Ozai wields two red streamers. He attacks Actress Aang, who jumps out
                of the way. Actress Aang opens her glider, which now has two small blue banners pop
                out. She twirls the weapon. Actor Ozai circles his streamers while Actress Aang
                jumps over him with the help of a rope. She tries to get close to Actor Ozai, but
                Actor Ozai makes her back away using his red streamers. Actress Aang jumps over
                Actor Ozai, who fires a constant stream of red streamers at her. When Actress Aang
                lands, Actor Ozai sends a large red sheet painted as fire at her. A black clad
                stagehand lets go of the prop and runs away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Aang">
         <charAction>Becomes wrapped in the fire blanket.</charAction> Noooo ...!
                <charAction>Falls to the stage with her eyes closed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actress Azula">It is over, Father. We've done it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Actor Ozai">Yes! We have done it! The dreams of my father, <charAction>Large fire sheets rise
                behind him and a platform lifts him up.</charAction> and my father's father, have
            now been realized! <charAction>A Fire Nation flag drops.</charAction> The world ... is
            ... mine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The audience, except Team Avatar, cheers loudly and gives a standing
                ovation. Team Avatar is noticeably concerned by the events.</description>
      <description>Fade to outside the theater, as Team Avatar is walking away, all of them
                showing annoyed looks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">That ... wasn't a good play.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'll say.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No kidding.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">Horrible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You said it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walking with Suki.</charAction> But the effects were decent.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
