<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="9">The Waterbending Scroll</title>
      <director>Anthony Lioi</director>
      <writer>John O' Bryan</writer>
      <date>2005-04-29</date>
      <location nation="earth">Seedy Merchants Pier</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>Scene opens with the camera zoomed out showing Appa flying in above the
                mountains with a few viewable trees, carrying Aang, Katara, Sokka, and
                Momo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aang is pacing around on Appa's saddle, breathing heavily.</charAction>
            Would you sit down? <charAction>Turns around from his perch on Appa's head.</charAction>
            If we hit a bump, you'll go flying off. What's bugging you anyway?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> It's what Avatar Roku said. I'm supposed to
            master all four elements before that comet arrives.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In a sarcastic, amused tone while facing Aang.</charAction> Well, let's
            see. You pretty much mastered airbending and that only took you a hundred and twelve
            years. I'm sure you can master three more elements by next summer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frightfully.</charAction> I haven't even started waterbending and we're
            still weeks away from the North Pole. What am I gonna do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Grabs Aang's arm.</charAction> Calm down, it's going to be okay.
                <charAction>Aang sits down in front of her.</charAction> If you want, I can try to
            teach you some of the stuff I know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> You'd do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Nods and looks over the side of Appa's saddle.</charAction> We'll need
            to find a good source of water first.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grinning; sarcastically.</charAction> Maybe we can find a puddle for you
            to splash in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Momo standing in front of a large
                waterfall and river.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frowning beside Aang and Katara's ecstatic faces.</charAction> Nice
            puddle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa flies down into the river and creates a huge splash that soaks and
                almost knocks Momo of the rock he is standing on, turns over, and floats on his
                back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Takes off his shirt, smiling.</charAction> Yeah! Don't start without me,
            boy! <charAction>Begins to run toward the water.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Somewhat blankly.</charAction> Remember the reason we're here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stops short and looks at Katara.</charAction> Oh right. Time to practice
            waterbending. <charAction>Puts his clothes back on.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Great. So what am I supposed to do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You could ... clean the gunk out of Appa's toes. <charAction>Hands Sokka a branch
                with a bushel of leaves at the end.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frowns and crosses his arms.</charAction> So, while you guys are playing
            in the water, I'm supposed to be hard at work picking mud out of a giant bison's
            feet?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiles; somewhat cheerfully.</charAction> Mud and bugs!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay. <charAction>Takes stick and walks over to Appa who is floating in the
                water.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Zuko's ship in the ocean. On the deck, Zuko is practicing
                firebending with his  Lieutenant Lee when the boat turns and they are thrown to one
                side on their backs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up of his face; he glares at the tower.</charAction> Someone's
            changing our course.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a crew member steering the ship at the top of the
                boat.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Storming in, yelling.</charAction> What is the meaning of this mutiny?
            No one told you to change course! <charAction>Shows Iroh and the rest of the crew
                playing Pai Sho behind them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Actually, someone did. I assure you, it is a matter of utmost importance, Prince
            Zuko. <charAction>Scratches beard.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Hopefully.</charAction> Is it something to do with the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Even more urgent. It seems, I- <charAction>Rubs forehead in stress.</charAction> -I
            have lost my lotus tile. <charAction>Moves a piece of his across the Pai Sho
                board.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Lotus tile?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">For my Pai Sho game. Most people think the lotus tile insignificant, but it is
            essential for the unusual strategy that I employ.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>In disbelief.</charAction> You've changed our course for a stupid lotus
            tile?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">See, you, like most people, underestimate it's value. Just give me ten minutes to
            check the merchants at this port of call. <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Hopefully,
            they will have the lotus tile in stock and I can get on with my life. <charAction>Zuko
                breathes fire up at the ceiling in anger and Iroh smiles.</charAction> I'm lucky to
            have such an understanding nephew.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The room fills with smoke of Zuko's outburst, clouding the scene from
                view.</description>
      <description>Cut to a scene of a content Appa floating in the river while Sokka stands
                on his stomach and brushes in between his toes with the branch.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, don't get too happy. You've got to do me next. <charAction>Appa moans
                happily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows Katara and Aang by the shore.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This is a pretty basic move, but it still took me months to perfect. So don't get
            frustrated if you don't get it right away. <charAction>She moves her hands back and
                forth and makes small waves in the water, while Aang looks up, smiling.</charAction>
            Just push and pull the water like this. The key is getting the wrist movement
            right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Like this? <charAction>Does the hand movements
                Katara is doing, but nothing is happening yet.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Kindly.</charAction> That's almost right. If you keep practicing I'm
            sure eventually—</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey, I'm bending it already! <charAction>Shows Aang making much bigger waves than
                Katara's on his first try.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Wow, I can't believe you got that so quickly. It
            took me two months to learn that move.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shrugs shoulders.</charAction> Well, you had to figure it all on your
            own. I'm lucky enough to have a great teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> Thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, what's next?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This is a more difficult move. I call it streaming the water. <charAction>She moves
                her hands and raises a stream of water from the river into the air and moves it
                around.</charAction> It's harder than it looks, so don't be disappointed if-
                <charAction>Shows Aang already controlling a stream of water, moving it around and
                above his body and neatly coiling it back into the river, much to Katara's
                dismay.</charAction> Nice work. <charAction>She frowns.</charAction> Though the
            over-the-head flare was unnecessary.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sorry. <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Well, don't stop now! Keep 'em
            coming!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks up sadly.</charAction> Well I kind of know this one other move,
            but it's pretty hard. I haven't even totally figured it out yet. The idea is to create a
            big, powerful wave. <charAction>She moves her hands up, shaking, and starts to get a big
                mass of water to rise out of the river, but it pops before forming into anything
                substantial.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, like this? <charAction>He raises his hands and creates a massive wave that
                towers over their heads.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Still working on cleaning up Appa, he looks up and stares at Aang's wave
                crashing toward him in fear.</charAction> Aang?! <charAction>The wave throws Sokka
                off into the water and his head slowly rises out, annoyed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Looks like I got the hang of that move! What else
            do you got?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angry at Aang's quick success.</charAction> That's enough practicing for
            today.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Head still sticking out of the water.</charAction> Yeah, I'll say!
                <charAction>Points to the left.</charAction> You just "practiced" our supplies down
            the river. <charAction>Shows a group of bags floating away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking guilty.</charAction> Uh, sorry. <charAction>Smiles
                worriedly.</charAction> I'm sure we can find somewhere to replace all this
            stuff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">My life was hard enough when you were just an airbender. <charAction>Sinks back
                underwater.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to Katara, Sokka, and Aang walking through the streets of a city
                market and port. Shows many armed men staring at the trio. Sokka and Katara look
                nervous while Aang looks around in wonder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walking back from alleyway with a bag over his shoulders.</charAction>
            We've got exactly three copper pieces left from the money that King Bumi gave us. Let's
            spend it wisely.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh, make that two copper pieces, Sokka. I couldn't say no to this whistle!
                <charAction>Pulls out a white whistle that looks like a bison, takes a huge breath
                and blows into it, but it barely makes a sound.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pulls out fingers over his ears after expecting a loud
                noise.</charAction> It doesn't even work. <charAction>Aang stops blowing when Momo
                squawks at him.</charAction> See? Even Momo thinks it's a piece of junk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No offense Aang, but I'll hold the money from now on. <charAction>Aang hands her the
                two copper coins.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to the other side of the port where a man is talking in front of his
                boat docked in the water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">
         <charAction>Moving hands and shouting excitedly.</charAction> Earth Nation! Fire
            Nation! Water Nation! So long as bargains are your inclination, you're welcome here!
            Don't be shy, come on by! <charAction>Sokka, Katara, and Aang walk by and he runs up to
                them.</charAction> Oh! You there, I can see from your clothing that you're
            world-traveling types. Perhaps I can interest you in some exotic curios?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Walks back to the man.</charAction> Sure! What are curios?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">
         <charAction>Looks confused and thinks.</charAction> I'm not entirely sure. But we
            got 'em! <charAction>Puts his hand on Aang's shoulder and smiles, walking him into the
                ship.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to the inside of the boat where strange collectibles are lined up on
                shelves on the walls. Aang, Katara, and Sokka walk in.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looks up close at an item on a shelf, confused.</charAction>
            Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara stares at an ornate monkey statue on one of the shelves
                eerily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>Standing in a dark doorway as Aang passes by with Momo on his
                back.</charAction> I've never seen such a fine specimen of lemur. <charAction>Walks
                into the light, an iguana parrot on his shoulder.</charAction> That beast would
            fetch me a hefty sum if you'd be interested in bartering. <charAction>The iguana parrot
                squawks at them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Grabbing Momo.</charAction> Momo's not for sale.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows Katara walking over to a shelf where a number of scrolls are kept.
                She grabs one with the waterbending symbol on it and opens it to see lines of
                waterbending diagrams and writing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Look at this, Aang. It's a waterbending scroll!
                <charAction>Aang walks over.</charAction> Check out these crazy moves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turns to the captain, excited.</charAction> Where did you get a
            waterbending scroll?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>Slams his hand onto the scroll and pulls it away.</charAction> Let's
            just say I got it up North, at a most reasonable price, free. <charAction>Rolls the
                scroll back up and puts it away back in its shelf.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Turns around and looks at the captain from the other side of the
                room.</charAction> Wait a minute ... Sea loving traders, with suspiciously acquired
            merchandise, <charAction>Raises eyebrows, almost yelling.</charAction> and pet reptile
            birds? <charAction>Turns around to Oh, almost spitting in his face.</charAction> You
            guys are pirates!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">
         <charAction>Puts his arm around a terrified Sokka's shoulders.</charAction> We
            prefer to think of ourselves as "high risk traders."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to Katara holding their two copper pieces next to Aang, with the
                captain on the other side of the counter they are leaning on.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">So, how much for the, uh, traded scroll?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">I've already got a buyer, a nobleman in the Earth Kingdom. <charAction>Voice turns
                less serious.</charAction> Unless of course, you kids have two hundred gold pieces
            on you right now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turns around and whispers to Katara.</charAction> I know how to deal
            with these guys, Katara. Pirates love to haggle. <charAction>Katara drops the final
                coins in his hand.</charAction> Watch and learn. <charAction>Walks over to the
                counter, leans against it, and talks in a pirate voice.</charAction> Let's say to
            the price of, one copper piece! <charAction>Smiles, and dramatically presents the single
                coin.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>Laughs hysterically.</charAction> The price is two hundred gold pieces.
            I don't haggle on items this rare.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Still smirking and talking like a pirate.</charAction> Okay, two copper
            pieces!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>Aggravated.</charAction> It's not as amusing the second time,
            boy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Aang, can we get out of here? I feel like we're
            getting weird looks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Aye, we be casting off now! <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts back to outside, Aang, Katara, and Sokka are walking off the boat and
                back down the street.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What was that all about, Katara?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, I was just starting to browse through their boomerang collection.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried, holding her arms.</charAction> I'll just feel a lot better once
            we get away from here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts back to the pirate ship. Oh is running across the deck looking for
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">Hey you! Get back here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Calmly turns around.</charAction> Well, well. Look who's come to their
            senses. Told you the haggling would pay off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, the group of armed pirates jump out of the boat and run to Aang,
                Katara, and Sokka, whispering menacingly and swinging their weapons.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Scared.</charAction> I don't think these pirates are here to trade with
            us. <charAction>Turns around and runs, Aang and Sokka follow and the pirates chase
                behind them. Half of the group runs down one street while the other goes down the
                one next to it.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">This way. Let's cut 'em off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Turning a corner with Aang and Katara.</charAction> Whoa!
                <charAction>Katara freezes a puddle behind them that a pirate slips
            on.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to peaceful scene of the cabbage merchant with his cart of cabbages in
                an alleyway. Sokka, Katara, and Aang run past him and almost knock his cart over.
                Aang sends a blast of wind that throws the cart into the group of pirates behind
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> My cabbages! This place is worse than
            Omashu!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Group of pirates jump out of another street and chase Aang, Sokka, Katara,
                and Momo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate">I hope that lemur of yours has nine lives!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">
         <charAction>Him and the pirates corner them in the dead end of a
                street.</charAction> Now, who gets to taste the steel of my blade first?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No thanks. <charAction>Spins and hurls a blast of air at the pirates that send them
                backward, and runs toward them with his glider out.</charAction> Grab on
            tight!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang! I thought we were running away from the pirates! <charAction>Jumps on to
                Aang's glider with Sokka and they lift off into the air.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Just hang on! <charAction>Flies over the pirates' heads and into the
                distance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts back to their camp by the river, where Aang, Sokka, and Katara stand
                by the shore.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Putting his glider away.</charAction> I used to kind of look up to
            pirates, but those guys are terrible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Mischievously.</charAction> I know. That's why I took this.
                <charAction>Holds out the waterbending scroll they saw in the
            shop.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> No way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Isn't it great?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No wonder they were trying to hack us up! You stole their waterbending
            scroll!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Jokingly.</charAction> I prefer to think of it as high risk
            trading.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Good one, Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, where do you think they got it? They stole it from a waterbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It doesn't matter. You put all of our lives in danger just so you could learn some
            stupid, fancy splashes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">These are real waterbending forms. You know how crucial it is for Aang to learn
            waterbending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walks away.</charAction> Whatever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, what's done is done. We have it, we might as well learn from it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to show Zuko and Iroh standing in the market
                place.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I've checked all the shops on this pier. Not a lotus tile in the entire
            marketplace.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's good to know this trip was a complete waste of time <description>for
                everyone</description>!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Quite the contrary. I always say, the only thing better than finding something you
            are looking for <charAction>Crew members begin to walk past carrying Iroh's
                purchases.</charAction> is finding something you weren't looking for at a great
            bargain! <charAction>A crew member walks past the two playing a tsungi
                horn.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You bought a tsungi horn?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">For music night on the ship. Now, if we only had some woodwinds.
                <charAction>Pointing to the ship.</charAction> Oh, this place looks promising!
                <charAction>The monkey statue is shown again.</charAction> Oh, that is handsome!
            Wouldn't it look magnificent in the galley?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">
         <charAction>To pirate captain.</charAction> We lost the Water Tribe girl and the
            little bald monk she was traveling with.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning.</charAction> This monk, did he have an arrow on his head?
                <charAction>Iroh turns around, making a face similar to the
            monkey's.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts show Katara looking at the scroll.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I just want to try this one move first and then it's all yours. <charAction>Gives it
                to Aang.</charAction> Here, hold it open for me. The single water whip. Looks
            doable. <charAction>Attempts the move, but ends up hitting herself in the
                forehead.</charAction> Ow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Ha, ha, ha!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Glaring at Sokka.</charAction> What's so funny?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm sorry, but you deserved that. <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> You've been
            duped; she's only interested in teaching herself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Aang will get his turn once I figure out the water
            whip. <charAction>She tries again, but hits Momo instead, who screeches.</charAction>
            Ugh, why can't I get this stupid move?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You'll get it. <charAction>Katara glares at him.</charAction> You just gotta shift
            your weight through the stances. <charAction>He tries and does it perfectly on the first
                try.</charAction> There, see, the key to bending is—</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Screaming.</charAction> Will you please shut your air hole? Believe it
            or not your infinite wisdom gets a little old sometimes! Why don't we just throw the
            scroll away since you're so naturally gifted! <charAction>Sokka glares at
                her.</charAction> What? <charAction>She looks back at Aang, who has tears in his
                eyes.</charAction> Oh my gosh, Aang, I am so sorry, I don't know what came over me.
            But you know what, it won't happen again. <charAction>She gives the scroll to
                Aang.</charAction> Here, this is yours. I don't want to have anything to do with it
            anymore.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's okay Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What about Momo? He's the real victim here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Bends down to pet Momo as he rubs his hind end.</charAction> I'm sorry,
            Momo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">And what about me? There was that time you—</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No more apologies!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera fades to show a much smaller boat being launched out of Zuko's
                ship. The camera fades again to show the boat and the pirate ship sailing down a
                river.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">Shouldn't we stop to search the woods?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We don't need to stop. They stole a waterbending scroll, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">Mm-hm.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Then they'll be on the water.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades to show Katara, Sokka, and Aang sleeping by the campfire.
                Katara quietly takes the scroll and sneaks away from the camp. However, when she
                turns around she comes face-to-face with Momo, who starts chattering.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Shhh, Momo! Go back to sleep. Shh!
                <charAction>The camera fades to show her standing by the river, attempting but
                failing to perfect the water whip, frustrated.</charAction> Ugh, ugh, ugh! Shoot!
            Come on water, work with me here! Okay, what if I just, ow! Stupid scroll!
                <charAction>The pirate captain and Zuko are shown hearing her.</charAction> Okay
            Katara, shift your weight through the stances. <charAction>She drops the water again and
                hears the ship pulling up onto the river bank. She peaks through the bushes to see
                what the noise was, and gasps upon seeing the pirates. She turns to run, but it
                grabbed by a pirate.</charAction> No! Let go of me! <charAction>She bends water up
                into the pirate's face, and he releases her, she runs but is grabbed again on the
                wrists by Zuko.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He glares at her as she looks frightfully at him.</charAction> I'll save
            you from the pirates.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to show Katara tied to a tree with Zuko standing in front of
                her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Tell me where he is and I won't hurt you or your brother.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Furiously.</charAction> Go jump in the river!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Try to understand. I need to capture him to restore something I've lost, my honor.
                <charAction>Katara jerks her head away from Zuko.</charAction> Perhaps in exchange I
            can restore something you've lost. <charAction>He holds her mother's necklace up to her
                neck.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">My mother's necklace! How did you get that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I didn't steal it, if that's what you're wondering. <description>Tell
                me</description> where he is. <charAction>Points at Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">Enough of this necklace garbage! You promised a scroll!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I wonder how much this is worth ... <charAction>The pirates gasp as he takes it out
                and holds it over a fire in his hand.</charAction> A lot, apparently. Now you help
            me find what I want, you'll get this back, and everyone goes home happy. Search the
            woods for the boy and meet back here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">Fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to the campsite, where Sokka is waking up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Notices Katara's missing.</charAction> Huh? Where did she go?
                <charAction>Looks through the bag.</charAction> I don't believe it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Yawns.</charAction> What's wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">She took the scroll! She's obsessed with that thing. It's just a matter of time
            before she gets us all in deep- <charAction>Yells as a pirate throws a rope around his
                arms and drags him forward. He rolls away and charges at the pirate while another
                pirate captures Aang in a net and drags him away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate">I got him, come on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh, what? I'm not good enough to kidnap? Ah! <charAction>The pirate shoots another
                net at Sokka and drags him away too.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts back to the place where Zuko and the pirates are gathered. The pirates
                are holding Aang and Sokka, who are tied up. Sokka is struggling with the
                ropes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Nice work.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, this is all my fault.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No Katara, it isn't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yeah, it kind of is. <charAction>Katara glares at Iroh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>To the pirate captain.</charAction> Give me the boy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">You give us the scroll.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You're really gonna hand over <description>the Avatar</description> for a stupid
            piece of parchment?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Don't listen to him, he's trying to turn us against each other!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>Turns to Aang.</charAction> Your friend is the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Sure is, and I'll bet he'll fetch a lot more on the black market than that fancy
            scroll.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Shut your mouth, you Water Tribe peasant!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, Sokka, you really should shut your mouth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm just sayin' it's bad business sense. Think how much the Fire Lord would pay for
            the Avatar. You guys would be set for life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> Keep the scroll; we can buy a hundred with the
            reward we'll get for the kid. <charAction>The pirates turn to
            leave.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You'll regret breaking a deal with me. <charAction>He and two of his soldiers send a
                blast of fire at the pirates. The pirates jump back and Oh runs out, throwing smoke
                bombs and jumping into the cloud as the fight ensues. Some of the soldiers run out
                to Sokka and Aang, who are struggling with their ropes, but are stopped by several
                pirates. Momo runs down the tree and frees Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Thanks, Momo. I owe you a bushel of apples. <charAction>She runs to join the fight.
                Aang is shown lost in the smoke, a thrown knife narrowly misses him and cuts through
                his ropes. Zuko finds his way out of the smoke cloud and hides the scroll behind his
                back, but the pirate captain sees him and the two begin to fight. The scroll flies
                into the air and his caught by Momo, the iguana parrot sees him and hits Momo. The
                scroll flies back down to the ground. A knife narrowly misses Sokka's head, and he
                uses it to cuts the ropes on his hands.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> Aang, are you there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm over here! Follow my voice!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Where? I can't find you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm right here! <charAction>Airbends the dust away, revealing the pirates
                surrounding him, and immediately airbends it back around himself.</charAction> Uh,
            never mind! I'll find you! <charAction>Sokka climbs out of the dust cloud on his hands
                and knees. Aang vaults over him in a full sprint.</charAction> Run! <charAction>They
                find Katara, who is trying to push the pirate boat back into the water.</charAction>
            Katara, you're okay!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Help me get this boat back in the water so we can get outta here. <charAction>They
                join her in trying to push the boat, but can't.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We'd need a team of rhinos to budge this ship.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">A team of rhinos, or two waterbenders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to Aang and Katara pushing and pulling the water until the boat rises
                up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Everybody in!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to show Iroh breaking up the fight between the pirate captain and
                Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Are you so busy fighting you cannot see your own ship has set sail?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We have no time for your proverbs, Uncle!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It's no proverb! <charAction>Points to Team Avatar who has hijacked the pirate
                ship.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">Bleeding hog monkeys! <charAction>Zuko laughs while pointing at him. His laughter
                dissipates as the pirates hijack his own boat. The pirates taunt him and the screen
                pans to a steaming Zuko.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Hey! That's my boat! <charAction>Goes chasing
                after the hijacked boat.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Pondering.</charAction> Maybe it should be a proverb ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Off camera.</charAction> C'mon, Uncle! <charAction>Iroh runs after
                Zuko.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka, can't you make it go any faster?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I don't know how. This thing wasn't made by the Water Tribe!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Several of the pirates jump onto the ship, but are quickly swept away by
                Aang's waterbending. Determined, Katara performs a perfect water whip to throw the
                last pirate off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey, you did the water whip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I couldn't have done it without your help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka is shown being held in place by two pirates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Would you two quit congratulating each other and help me out?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo is shown still being chased by the iguana parrot; he flies up to the
                top mast and entangles the bird in the ship's flag. Sokka is shown being thrown by
                one of the pirates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">That's good ... <charAction>Aang lands behind him and airbends him and the other
                pirate off the ship before jumping down to Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing.</charAction> Aang, look! <charAction>The ship is shown headed
                toward a huge waterfall.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh no ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Oh comes up behind him with a knife, Aang turns and blows the bison
                whistle. Oh stands confused while Sokka comes up behind him and pushes him off the
                ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Have you lost your mind? This is no time for flute practice! <charAction>Katara and
                Aang stare in horror at the approaching waterfall.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We can stop the boat! Aang, together, push and pull the water! <charAction>They
                create a small Whirlpool that stops the boat.</charAction> It's working, it's
            slowing down! We're doing it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">But we have another problem. <charAction>Zuko's boat is shown sailing straight
                toward their ship. The boat rams into the ship and Sokka, Aang, and Katara are
                forced to jump as the boat goes over the falls.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Together">Jump! <charAction>Appa is shown flying toward them. They land on him and fly to
                safety.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding up the whistle.</charAction> I knew a bison whistle would come
            in handy! Thanks Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, we owe you one. <charAction>Appa roars and the scene cuts to show Zuko running
                to the cliff in horror at the fact that his boat has gone over the
                falls.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">My boat!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> Prince Zuko, you're really going to get a kick
            out of this. That lotus tile was in my sleeve the whole time! <charAction>Has a big
                smile on his face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko snatches the lotus tile and furiously throws it down the
                waterfall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts back to Appa flying through the clouds.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, I still owe you an apology. You were just so good at waterbending without
            really trying. I got so competitive that I put us all in danger, I'm sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's okay Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Besides, who needs that stupid scroll anyway?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding the scroll. Sarcastically.</charAction> Is that really how you
            feel?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The scroll!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Puts his hand in front to keep Katara from grabbing it.</charAction>
            First, what did you learn?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Stealing is wrong. <charAction>Snatches scroll.</charAction> Unless it's from
            pirates.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Laughing.</charAction> Good one, Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
