<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="22">The Cave of Two Lovers</title>
      <director>Lauren MacMullan</director>
      <writer>Joshua Hamilton</writer>
      <date>2006-03-24</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to show a cliff with a small body of water, where Team
                Avatar is residing. The camera pans downward and cuts to where Sokka is relaxing
                peacefully, floating on a large leaf in the water with Momo sleeping on his stomach,
                while Katara and Aang are facing each other while practicing
                waterbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>With his hair covering his eyes.</charAction> You guys are going to be
            done soon, right? We have a lot of ground to cover if we're going to make it to Omashu
            today.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Rises from her hunched-over position; turns to face Sokka
                smugly.</charAction> What? Like you're ready to go right now, naked guy?
                <charAction>Smiles at him smugly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I could be ready in two minutes. Seriously, <charAction>Pulls back the hair covering
                his eyes.</charAction> whenever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So you were showing me the octopus form?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns her attention back to Aang.</charAction> Right, let me see your
            stance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang assumes a defensive stance. After careful consideration, Katara walks
                over to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Walks under his right arm.</charAction> Your arms are too far apart.
                <charAction>Positions his arms closer together.</charAction> See, if you move them
            closer together, you protect your center. You got it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blushing.</charAction> Oh, yea ... thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Walks away and assumes a fighting stance.</charAction> Okay, let's see
            what you got.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang bends the water, creating a globule which eventually transforms into
                eight whip-like water tentacles. He carefully maneuvers them, fending off shards of
                ice that Katara repeatedly sends at him by throwing them away or dodging them. At
                length, he manipulates one of the tentacles, curling it around her leg, gripping it
                firmly and pulling on it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Proudly.</charAction> You make a fine octopus, Pupil Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to where Aang dances playfully, suspended in a globule of
                water shaped like an actual octopus. Suddenly, music can be heard in the distance.
                The group witnesses a strange group of nomads playing music on instruments and
                singing, approaching them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Singing.</charAction> Da, da, da. Don't fall in love with the traveling
            girl. She'll leave you broke and brokenhearted. <charAction>Cuts to shot of the team
                standing in the lake. Sokka unexpectedly falls off his leaf into the water. Cuts to
                nomads. Chong stops singing and points at the group.</charAction> Hey, river
            people!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're not river people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Puzzled.</charAction> You're not? Well then what kind of people are
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Just ... people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Aren't we all, brother?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Walks over and says accusingly.</charAction> Who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">I'm Chong and this is my wife, Lily. We're nomads, happy to go wherever the wind
            takes us! <charAction>He suddenly strums his lute-like instrument in a crazy fashion
                much like a rock star strums crazily on their guitar.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Starts out with a somewhat puzzled tone, but changes it to an excited
                one.</charAction> You guys are nomads? That's great! I'm a nomad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Just as excitedly.</charAction> Hey, me too!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blankly.</charAction> I know ... you just said that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Oh. <charAction>Noticing Sokka.</charAction> Nice underwear ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close shot of Sokka, who is only wearing his swimsuit; Aang and
                Katara are standing behind him. Sokka's eyes bulge at the sudden realization that he
                is wearing very little in front of complete strangers. He grabs Momo and places him
                strategically over his underwear and slides rapidly off the screen. The scene
                switches to a forest landscape, where Zuko and Iroh are now living as fugitives. The
                camera shows a close-up of Iroh's face, as he gasps and stares in awe at a red and
                white flower. Cuts to full view of him and an area behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Emerging from the bushes, now sporting short, black hair.</charAction> I
            didn't find anything to eat! I can't live like this! I wasn't meant to be a fugitive.
                <charAction>Raises fists in the air and yells at the sky.</charAction> This is
            impossible! <charAction>Looking over at Iroh.</charAction> Uncle, what are you
            doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Cuts to Iroh who dotes over the flower. Zuko appears behind
                him.</charAction> You're looking at the rare white dragon bush. Its leaves make a
            tea so delicious, it's heartbreaking. That, or it's the white jade, which is
            poisonous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We need food, not tea. I'm going fishing. <charAction>Walks
            away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Dreamily.</charAction> Hmm ... delectable tea? <charAction>More
                suspiciously.</charAction> Or deadly poison?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to where Team Avatar and the band of nomads are lounging
                nearby Appa, whose fur is braided. Chong is casually strumming his lute. Sokka
                approaches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Wearing a wreath of pink flowers on his head.</charAction> Hey, Sokka,
            you should hear some of these stories. These guys have been everywhere!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Stops playing.</charAction> Well not everywhere, Little Arrowhead. But
            where we haven't been, we've heard about through stories and songs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">They said they'll take us to see a giant night crawler!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Moku">
         <charAction>Lying on the ground; in a dreamy voice.</charAction> On the way, there's
            a waterfall that creates a never-ending rainbow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look, I hate to be the wet blanket here, but since Katara is busy, I guess it's up
            to me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara shoots him a glare as Lily braids her hair.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We need to get to Omashu. No sidetracks, no worms and definitely no
            rainbows.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Wow, sounds like someone has a case of destination fever. You're worried too much
            about where you're going.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lily">You got to focus less on the "where" and more on the "going". <charAction>She makes
                gestures with her hand, accidentally tugging on Katara's
            braid.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Impatiently.</charAction> O. Ma. Shu!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka's right. We need to find King Bumi, so Aang can learn earthbending somewhere
            safe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Sounds like you're headed to Omashu.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka smacks his forehead in frustration.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">There's an old story about a secret pass right through the mountains.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Is this real or a legend?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Oh, it's a real legend. And it's as old as earthbending itself. <charAction>Begins
                strumming his lute and singing.</charAction> Two lovers, forbidden from one another,
            the war divides their people and the mountain divides them apart! Built a path to be
            together! <charAction>Stops playing.</charAction> Yeah, I forget the next couple of
            lines, but then it goes ... <charAction>Resumes singing.</charAction> Secret tunnel!
            Secret tunnel! Through the mountains, secret, secret, secret, secret tunnel!
            Yeah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A shot showing everyone around Appa, including the nomads. who had been
                dancing and clapping.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Unamused while folding his arms.</charAction> I think we'll just stick
            with flying. We've dealt with the Fire Nation before. We'll be fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, thanks for the help, but Appa hates going underground. <charAction>Flashing a
                smile.</charAction> And we need to do whatever makes Appa most comfortable
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to a mountainous cliffside where Fire Nation soldiers are
                attacking the team by launching fireballs at them as they desperately try to escape
                on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Commander">
         <charAction>Pointing at the trio on Appa.</charAction> Launch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Several catapults are activated, launching an assault of fireballs at the
                team, who manages to narrowly avoid them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Team Avatar">Ahhhh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to the trio, covered in ash and scorch marks, casually
                strolling past the nomads.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pointing forward.</charAction> Secret love cave, let's go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to the forest, where Zuko has arrived from his fishing
                expedition. When the camera pans upward, it is revealed that he has only managed to
                spear a single, tiny fish which flaps about helplessly on the large branch he used
                for a fishing pole. Cuts to Iroh hunched over, his back to the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko, <charAction>Cut to a wide, overhead shot of Zuko standing behind
                Iroh.</charAction> remember that plant I thought might be tea?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You didn't ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I did ... <charAction>Turns around.</charAction> and it wasn't. <charAction>Reveals
                himself to be swollen and covered in red marks.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut back to Zuko who drops the branch out of shock.</charAction>
            Ahh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Surprisingly calmly.</charAction> When the rash spreads to my throat, I
            will stop breathing. <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> But look what I found.
                <charAction>Iroh holds out his arm to reveal berries.</charAction> These are bacui
            berries, known to cure the poison of the white jade.
                <charAction>Unenthusiastically.</charAction> That, or maka'ole berries that cause
            blindness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Grabbing branch of berries and hurling it into the bushes.</charAction>
            We're not taking any more chances with these plants! We need to get help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">But where are we going to go? <charAction>Kneeling down and scratching his rash
                vigorously.</charAction> We're enemies of the Earth Kingdom and fugitives from the
            Fire Nation. <charAction>Camera zooms in on his reddened leg.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">If the Earth Kingdom discovers us, they'll have us killed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Rises.</charAction> But if the Fire Nation discovers us, we'll be turned
            over to Azula.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They look at each other and pause briefly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Nodding and walking away with Iroh.</charAction> Earth Kingdom it
            is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to where Team Avatar and the band of nomads are
                journeying to the tunnels along a wide street surrounded by the ruins of a
                temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How far are we from the tunnel?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Actually, it's not just one tunnel. The lovers didn't want anyone to find out about
            their love, so they built a whole labyrinth!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Halts in his tracks; in shock.</charAction> Labyrinth?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> Oh, I'm sure we'll figure it out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lily">All you need to do is trust in love ... according to the curse.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka, who had resumed walking, halts once more. The others pass by him.
                After several moments, he flinches in terror.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In a somewhat whining voice.</charAction> Curse!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera pans to the dark entrance of the cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Hey-hey! We're here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of inscription on the side of the cave
                entrance.</charAction> What exactly is this curse?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">The curse says that only those who trust in love can make it through the caves.
            Otherwise, you'll be trapped in them forever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lily">And die.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Oh yeah, and die. <charAction>Brightening.</charAction> Hey, I just remembered the
            rest of that song! <charAction>Stands before the entrance and strums lute, while singing
                an ominous line in a low voice.</charAction> And die!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That's it! There's no way we're going through some cursed hole!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Moku">
         <charAction>Turns head to observe gray smoke rising from the horizon, which he
                proceeds to point at.</charAction> Hey, someone's making a big campfire!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>In a serious tone.</charAction> That's no campfire, Moku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grimly.</charAction> It's Fire Nation. They're tracking us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Making sure he understands.</charAction> So all you need to do is trust
            in love to get through these caves?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">That is correct, Master Arrowhead.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns to stare at Katara, who has her back to him. Her clothes and
                hair sway slightly as a breeze passes by. The camera closes up to his face, his eyes
                shining in adoration.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> We can make it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Gesturing to the cave; somewhat commanding.</charAction> Everyone into
            the hole!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all begin to enter the cave. Cuts to a close-up of Appa as he groans.
                Several Fire Nation tanks rumble across the terrain toward the entrance of the
                tunnel and pause once they reach the mouth of the cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Commander">Hold on! It's too dangerous. Haven't you heard the song? Just close them in. The
            mountain will take care of the rest.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The tanks fire rotating grappling hooks from canisters into the tunnel and
                release them after a few moments, unleashing a myriad of boulders. The scene
                switches to where the group has begun navigating their way through the tunnels only
                to turn and witness the entrance being closed off. Appa begins to frantically paw
                the walls of the tunnel.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's okay, Appa. We'll be fine. I hope.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We will be fine. All we need is a plan. Chong, how long do those torches
            last?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> Uh, about two hours each.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lily">
         <charAction>Lighting the rest of the torches in her hand.</charAction> And we have
            five torches, so that's ten hours!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grabbing torches and stomping out the fire.</charAction> It doesn't work
            like that if they're all lit at the same time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lily">Oh, right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm going to make a map to keep track of exactly where we've been. Then we should be
            able to solve it like a maze and get through.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Aang look at each other with unsure expressions. The scene
                changes to a village. Camera cuts to a hospital before switching to the inside of
                the building. One doctor is treating a man with what appears to be a cupping
                treatment. The man grits his teeth in pain. The camera pans over to where a girl is
                treating Iroh's allergic reaction. Zuko is seated on a bench.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">
         <charAction>Wringing cloth.</charAction> You two must not be from around here. We
            know better than to touch the White Jade, much less make it into tea and drink it.
                <charAction>Flicks Iroh's hand away when he scratches his
            rash.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>The girl moves away from the camera's eye, revealing Iroh to be in an
                even worse condition than before with the rash having spread to his face and his
                cheeks swollen.</charAction> Whoops!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">So where are you traveling from?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Nervously; rises from his seat as she moves his hand down so she could
                wash it.</charAction> Yes, we're travelers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">Do you have names?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Names? Of course we have names. <charAction>Song turns to see Iroh scratching and
                glares at him, before slapping his hand away.</charAction> I'm, uh ... Lee and this
            is my Uncle, uh ... Mushi?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Shoots him angry look. Cuts to shot of Song taking a lotion from a jar.
                She begins slathering it over the inflamed areas.</charAction> Yes, my nephew was
            named after his father, so we just call him Junior. <charAction>Leans over to the side
                to give Zuko a pleased smile.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko glares angrily at Iroh and moves his finger across his neck signaling
                that he's dead meat, but abruptly halts and puts his hands behind his back when Song
                turns to look at him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">Mushi and Junior, huh. My name is Song. You two look like you could use a good meal.
                <charAction>Slaps Iroh's hand away when he goes to scratch his rash.</charAction>
            Why don't you stay for dinner?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Looking away.</charAction> Sorry, but we need to be moving on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">
         <charAction>Screwing the cap back on the lid.</charAction> That's too bad.
                <charAction>Gives an innocent smile.</charAction> My mom always makes too much roast
            duck.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Where do you live exactly?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to the dark tunnel where Sokka is standing with a map in
                his hands, the map taking up most of the screen. He tilts it to the side a few times
                before drawing it closer to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, this is the tenth dead end you've led us to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This doesn't make sense. We already came through this way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">We don't need a map. <charAction>Sokka passes by him.</charAction> We just need
            love. The little guy knows it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, but I wouldn't mind a map also.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cuts to an overhead shot of the group standing in the dark cave before
                switching to Sokka who looks up from the map.</charAction> There's something strange
            here. There's only one explanation. <charAction>Cuts to shot of the rest of the group
                before switching to Sokka who turns to face the camera.</charAction> The tunnels are
            changing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A wave of surprise passes over everyone as the tunnels shake. The scene
                cuts to nighttime to a house. Cuts to a shot of an open-wall dining room where Zuko
                and Iroh are sitting around Song's kitchen table.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song's mother">
         <charAction>Setting down a platter of roast duck and taking a seat.</charAction> My
            daughter tells me you're refugees. We were once refugees ourselves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> When I was a little girl, the Fire Nation raided our
            farming village. All the men were taken away. That was the last time I saw my
            father.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up of the prince.</charAction> I haven't seen my father in many
            years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">
         <charAction>Sorrowfully.</charAction> Oh, is he fighting in the War?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko hesitates. Iroh is seen slurping up a bowl of noodles.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sets down dish.</charAction> Yeah. <charAction>Looks away in
                dismay.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to the cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Frantically.</charAction> The tunnels, they're a-changin'. It must be
            the curse! I knew we shouldn't have come down here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Right, if only we listened to you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hold up a hand in warning.</charAction> Everyone be quiet.
            Listen.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Sokka looking into the dark tunnel, his back to the camera.
                A low snarl can be heard from within the darkness of the tunnel. Momo flees from his
                shoulder. Sokka suspiciously holds the torch up to the tunnel to inspect the strange
                sound. Suddenly, a wolfbat flies from the darkness of the cave toward the camera,
                causing everyone to panic.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">It's a giant flying thing with teeth!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Moku">
         <charAction>The creature lands. Off-camera.</charAction> No! It's a
            wolfbat!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The wolfbat takes off again. In a frenzy, Sokka swats at the creature with
                the lit torch. Several hot cinders are thrown about and land on Appa's skin. Yelping
                in pain, the bison begins running around the tunnel, releasing a discharge of rocks
                and debris. Aang quickly airbends Sokka and the band of nomads out of the way of the
                falling rocks. He races toward Katara and pushes her out of the way. The camera cuts
                to where he and Katara rise from the impact and witness the division of the tunnel.
                Meanwhile, Sokka attempts to dig his way through the barrier that divides the two
                groups.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Yeah, it's no use. We're separated. But at least you have us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Horrified.</charAction> Nooooo!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He resumes digging through the rocks only to have a pile of debris fall on
                him. The scene changes to where Zuko is sitting on Song's front porch. Song comes
                outside and sits beside him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">Can I join you? I know what you've been through. We've all been through it.
                <charAction>Witnessing Zuko's scar.</charAction> The Fire Nation has hurt
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She reaches out to touch his scar only to have Zuko push her hand
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">
         <charAction>Compassionately.</charAction> It's okay. They've hurt me, too.
                <charAction>Pulls up pants leg to reveal burn scars on her
            leg.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko casts her a surprised look upon seeing this. The scene cuts to where
                Chong and his group are singing much to Sokka's annoyance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Singing as he and the nomads pass the angry warrior.</charAction> Oh,
            don't let the cave-in get you down! <charAction>Cuts to shot of him.</charAction> Don't
            let the falling rocks turn your smile into a frown! <charAction>He goes off-screen and
                Moku passes by, nudging Sokka.</charAction> When the tunnels are darkest, that's
            when you need a clown, hey! <charAction>Re-enters.</charAction> Don't let the cave-in
            get you down, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka scowls at this. The scene changes to Aang and Katara who are making
                their way through the tunnels.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> Aang, look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Running up to a solid rock door.</charAction> We found the
            exit!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two struggle to open it. Appa is seen in the background, snorting and
                preparing to charge. The two look at each other in alarm before running away as Appa
                charges at the door forcefully. Cuts to the opposite side of the entrance as the
                door creaks open and to a wider shot of the room as the stone doorway loosens and
                rolls off to the side. Katara jumps into the room only to have her look of hope
                change into one of disappointment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This isn't the exit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Walking to her side.</charAction> No. It's a tomb.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out on the ominous looking tomb, Appa grunting behind the
                duo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It must be the two lovers from the legend; that's who's buried here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">These pictures tell their story.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara gestures with the torch toward at the panels along the tomb,
                speaking about each one in turn. Aang and Katara exchanged glances and Katara
                narrates the story. The first image is that of a mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> They met on top of the mountain that divided
            their two villages ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two figures, a man dressed in red and a woman in blue, meet atop the
                mountain. They take each other's hands, though they swiftly let go, and a Chinese
                character appears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> The villages were enemies, so they could not be
            together ... <charAction>Character flashes red as the background turns grim and
                dark.</charAction> but their love was strong and they found a way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two hills appear; on the closer one is the man, while the woman kneels on
                the one farther away. Though their faces cannot be seen in detail, it is obvious
                that they long for the other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> The two lovers learned earthbending from the
            badgermoles; they became the first earthbenders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The painting of a badgermole is shown, as well as that of the young couple
                beginning to create the labyrinth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> They built elaborate tunnels, so they could
            meet secretly. <charAction>The pattern of a labyrinth appears.</charAction> Anyone who
            tried to follow them would be forever in the labyrinth. <charAction>The couple
                kisses.</charAction> But, one day, the man didn't come <charAction>Cuts to a shot of
                the woman alone, looking startled.</charAction> - he'd died in the war between the
            two villages. <charAction>Arrows fly by the screen. The woman is seen weeping by a
                grave.</charAction> Devastated, the woman unleashed a terrible display of her
            earthbending power - she could have destroyed them all ... <charAction>The woman is seen
                displaying her immense earthbending power.</charAction> but, instead, she declared
            the war over. <charAction>Cuts to shot of the woman standing on a hill surrounded by the
                two villages.</charAction> Both villages helped her build a new city where they
            would live together in peace. <charAction>Shows picture of the current-day
                Omashu.</charAction> The woman's name was Oma and the man's name was Shu.
                <charAction>The characters for "Oma" appear followed by the character for "Shu".
                Flashback ends.</charAction> The great city was named Omashu as a monument to their
            love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two look at each other momentarily before turning around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Reading the inscription on the relief in the wall.</charAction> Love is
            brightest <charAction>Cuts to shot of a carving of the couple kissing.</charAction> in
            the dark.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, on the other side of the cave, Sokka glares at the map while
                Momo comically perches on the top of his head. The map takes up most of the shot
                until Sokka lowers it. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Moku">Oh, great! Your plans have led us to another dead end!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the entire group standing before a wall of rubble,
                before switching to Sokka and Moku, with Sokka glaring accusingly at the
                nomad.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Defensively.</charAction> At least I'm thinking of ideas and trying to
            get us out of here, Moku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Whoa, whoa, wait a minute. We're thinking of ideas‌>?
            Because I've had an idea for, like, an hour now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily; spreads arms out dramatically.</charAction> Yes! We're all
            thinking of ideas!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Well, then listen to this: If love is the key out of here, then all we need to do is
            play a love song! <charAction>Begins playing song much to Sokka's
            dismay.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, in the tomb of the two lovers, Katara studies the portrait of
                the two lovers and the inscription while Aang stands off to side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">How are we going to find our way out of these tunnels?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I have a crazy idea.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Curiously.</charAction> What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hesitant. Walks away, slightly embarrassed.</charAction> Never mind.
            It's too crazy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, what is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I was thinking ... the curse says we'll be trapped in here forever unless we trust
            in love ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Right ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns to face him and gestures to the portrait.</charAction> And here,
            it says, "Love is brightest in the dark," and has a picture of them kissing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Utterly confused and lost.</charAction> Where are you going with
            this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shyly, blushing.</charAction> Well, what if we ... kissed?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Very surprised.</charAction> Us ...
            kissing‌>?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">See? It was a crazy idea.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Dreamily.</charAction> Us ... kissing ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Fake-jokingly.</charAction> Us kissing. What was I thinking? Can you
            imagine that‌>?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Fake-jokingly.</charAction> Yeah. <charAction>Awkwardly
                laughs.</charAction> I definitely wouldn't want to kiss you!
                <charAction>Beat.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Insulted.</charAction> Oh, well! I didn't realize it was such a horrible
            option. <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Sorry I suggested it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Realizing his mistake.</charAction> No, no, I mean ... if there was a
            choice between kissing you and dying ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Disgusted.</charAction> Ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Desperately.</charAction> What? I'm saying is I would rather kiss you
            than die - that's a compliment.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Enraged.</charAction> Well, I'm not sure which I'd rather do!
                <charAction>Slams the torch into his hand and storms away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Miserably.</charAction> What is wrong with me ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He walks away, the screen darkening in his wake. The scene changes to where
                Chong and his nomads are playing love songs, the camera panning down to show the
                group walking past.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Singing.</charAction> Even if you're lost, you can't lose the love
            because it's in your heart ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka slaps his forehead once more. The scene changes where we now see Zuko
                and Iroh preparing to depart from Song's house. They stand outside, dozens of
                fireflies in the air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Thank you for the duck. It was excellent.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song's mother">You're welcome. It brings me pleasure to see someone eat my cooking with such ...
            gusto.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Pats his stomach in a contented manner.</charAction> Much
            practice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns to leave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Junior, where are your manners? You need to thank these nice people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns and bows.</charAction> Thank you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Song">I know you don't think there's any hope left in the world, but there is hope. The
            Avatar has returned.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Bitterly.</charAction> I know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He leaves, but stops as he comes across an ostrich horse. Quietly, he walks
                over to the animal, unfastens it from its post and leads it away. The camera cuts to
                a shot from Song's front yard. Zuko appears on screen, riding the
                animal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">What are you doing? These people just showed you great kindness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">They're about to show us a little more kindness. Well?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Disappointed and reluctant, Iroh mounts the ostrich horse and the two ride
                away, leaving Song upset. She quietly closes the screen door to the house. The scene
                switches to the cave where Aang and Katara are still wandering about hopelessly,
                their torch ready to burn out at any moment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We're going to run out of light any second now, aren't we?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I think so ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Then, what are we going to do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What can we do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She silently walks over and grabs hold of his hand. Aang smiles up at her.
                The camera cuts to a close-up of Katara's face. The two are seen leaning into one
                another as the last of the torch light fades. Suddenly, the ceiling of the cave
                lights up revealing thousands of glowing crystals gleaming overhead. Meanwhile,
                Sokka and the band of nomads are journeying through the cave when they hear low
                growls. The camera zooms in on a dark tunnel where several wolfbats come into the
                light, racing toward them. Sokka waves his hands frantically in an attempt to scare
                them off. The creatures fly straight past him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Hey! You saved us, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, they were trying to get away from something!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">From what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The caves rumble. Cuts to an overhead shot of the group as a wall of rock
                crumbles. Without warning, two giant badgermoles burst through the caves, causing
                the group to panic. One badgermole closes its hands together in a prayerful manner,
                closing off a tunnel behind it with earthbending. The camera shifts right across the
                group and cuts to the other badgermole which pounds the ground with its paws and
                raises a wall of earth, blocking off the exits. Cuts to an overhead shot of the cave
                where one badgermole is seen using earthbending to create a split in the earth
                between the nomads and Sokka.</description>
      <description>Cuts to Sokka who tries to avoid the badgermole's swipes. He is blown back
                several feet and starts hastily backing away, his fingers hitting a string on the
                lute in the process, producing a musical note. Cuts to a close-up of a badgermole
                who cocks its head curiously. The creatures quiet down as he picks up the lute and
                begins playing a tune.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Hey, those things are music lovers!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Singing nervously.</charAction> Badgermoles coming toward me. Come on
            guys, help me out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Singing.</charAction> The big, bad badgermoles who earthbend the
            tunnels, hate the wolfbats, but love the sounds!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to Aang and Katara who are standing underneath the
                ceiling of glowing crystals, their hands linked.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">They're made of some kind of crystal. They must only light up in the dark.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's how the two lovers found each other. <charAction>Gestures with her hand along
                the ceiling.</charAction> They just put out their lights and followed the crystals.
                <charAction>Sees the exit.</charAction> That must be the way out! <charAction>The
                two hug.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, uh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She runs toward the exit. Aang stares after her before shaking his head and
                smiling. He and Appa follow close behind. They make their way out of the cave and
                into the outdoors. Appa bounds out of the tunnel and flops onto his back, tongue
                lolling out in content.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What about Sokka?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two seem a bit concerned at first, but a rumbling is heard. Cuts to an
                overhead shot of the exit where at that moment, Sokka and the band of nomads emerge
                from the cave, riding atop badgermoles. Debris flies everywhere and Aang and Katara
                shield themselves from the rubble. The camera pans upward to Sokka riding atop one
                of the creatures, waving, Momo flying about.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the cave, the camera panning to the left. Sokka
                dismounts the badgermole and approaches Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How did you guys get out?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Just like the legend said, we let love lead the way. <charAction>Smiles
                sheepishly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Really? We let huge, ferocious beasts lead our way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He turns to the badgermoles and waves to them as they slowly plod their way
                into the cave again. Two walls of rock rise up where the badgermoles re-entered the
                cave. The camera pans to where Momo is seemingly communicating with Appa, telling
                him of his journey through the caves. Appa seemingly roars in response to the lemur.
                Katara is seen hugging her brother.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Why is your forehead all red?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">
         <charAction>Talking about Aang.</charAction> Nobody react to what I'm about to tell
            you: I think that kid might be the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka smacks his forehead, enlarging the red spot while Chong looks at him
                in curiosity. Meanwhile, Aang confronts the other nomads.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So are you guys going to come to Omashu with us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Moku">Nope.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay. Thanks for everything, Moku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The band of nomads begins walking away. The camera pans to where Chong is
                seen placing a necklace of flowers around Sokka's neck.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Sokka, I hope you learned a little something about not letting the plans get in the
            way of the journey. <charAction>Hugs him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Irritated yet blushing.</charAction> Just play your songs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chong">Hey! Good plan! <charAction>Begins playing his lute and singing. Cuts to shot of
                Team Avatar.</charAction> Even if you're lost, you can't lose the love because it's
            in your heart. Da, da, da ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Chong is singing, Aang shoots a look at Katara, Sokka crosses his
                arms and Katara blushes. The camera pans upward and fades to a scene later in the
                day where the trio is heading up the mountainside to Omashu.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>From afar.</charAction> The journey was long and annoying, but now you
            get to see what it's really about: the destination. <charAction>Close-up of
                him.</charAction> I present to you the Earth Kingdom city of O- <charAction>Pauses
                abruptly.</charAction> Oh no ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shifts to behind him where they soon discover that Omashu has
                been captured and placed under Fire Nation rule. Ominous music is heard as a
                close-up of the entrance draped with a Fire Nation flag is shown.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
