<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="35">The Tales of Ba Sing Se</title>
      <director>Ethan Spaulding</director>
      <writer>Joann Estoesta</writer>
      <writer>Lisa Wahlander</writer>
      <writer>Andrew Huebner</writer>
      <writer>Gary Scheppke</writer>
      <writer>Lauren MacMullan</writer>
      <writer>Katie Mattila</writer>
      <writer>Justin Ridge</writer>
      <writer>Giancarlo Volpe</writer>
      <date>2006-09-29</date>
      <location nation="earth">Ba Sing Se</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>Scene fades to an exterior shot of Team Avatar's house. Shot cuts to a
                mirror, in front of which, Aang, whose head is covered with shaving cream, shaves
                his head with his shaving tool. Camera pans left to show Sokka in the mirror to show
                he has little facial hair, which he cuts off using the end of his machete. He clicks
                his tongue. Camera pans left again to show Katara in the mirror as she fixes
                together her hair loopies. Once they are placed, she smiles and the shot cuts back
                to show the whole room, with them all in front of the mirror. Scene changes to a
                dark room, where Toph lies on her bed, her blanket sloppily lying over her and her
                hair in a mess. Light cuts through the darkness as the door opens, and Katara enters
                the room and gasps at the sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Toph! Aren't you gonna get ready for the day?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph gets up, causing her messy hair to fly around. She spits on a nearby
                vessel which spins upon impact. Cut to Katara's face as she looks shocked, before
                cutting back to Toph as she gets to her feet and brushes a large amount of dust off
                her sleeping dress.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I'm ready.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're not gonna wash up? You've got a little dirt on your ... everywhere,
            actually.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You call it dirt, I call it a healthy coating of earth!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hmm ... <charAction>Thinking.</charAction> You know what we need? A girl's day
            out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Do I have to?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It'll be fun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the outside of a large building, where Toph and Katara stand near
                the entrance. Two women in robes walk out and smile at each other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">The Fancy Lady Day Spa? <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Sounds like my kinda
            place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Are you ready for some serious pampering?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Sure, Katara, whatever you say. As long as they don't touch my feet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two girls walk inside the building. Cut to inside of the building,
                where Katara sits smiling, having her feet scrubbed. Shot cuts again to a close-up
                of Toph's dirt-filled foot as the attendant tries to scrape the massive amounts of
                dirt off her feet. Shot cuts to a close-up of Toph's angry face.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a hallway inside the spa as suddenly an explosion erupts
                from one of the doorways, due to which, the frame becomes crumpled. An attendant
                flies out and hits the opposite wall, Toph having earthbent out of annoyance. Scene
                changes to Toph and Katara taking mud baths. An attendant with arms full of fresh
                towels walks over to Toph. Cut to Toph's face as she inhales air, and exhales,
                earthbending the mud on her face, creating a scary appearance, which scares the
                attendant, who runs away. Katara and Toph laugh, as the mud around Toph's mouth
                forms a large smile.</description>
      <description>Scene changes to a pile of rocks in a sauna which Toph and Katara are
                occupying. Toph kicks the ground, bending another rock from another pile, making it
                fly onto the pile of hot rocks. Katara, using waterbending, splashes the hot rocks
                with some water creating steam. They both sigh in relief. Scene changes to Toph, who
                has a lot of make-up on her face walking through the streets of Ba Sing
                Se.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Well, that wasn't so bad. I'm not usually into that stuff but I actually feel ...
            girly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm glad. It's about time we did something fun together.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the two crossing a bridge over a creek. As they do, they
                pass three girls going the other direction. Shot cuts to Katara and Toph from behind
                the girls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Girl with umbrella">Wow, great make-up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Girl with umbrella">For a clown!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The three girls laugh, Toph's smile is replaced by a frown as she and
                Katara stop walking. Katara puts her arm over Toph's shoulder, attempting to console
                her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Don't listen to them, let's just keep walking.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to the face of Star, who is one of the three girls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Star">I think she looks cute. Like that time we put a sweater on your pet poodle
            monkey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Third girl">Good one, Star.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Let's go, Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> No, no, that was a good one. Like your
            poodle monkey. <charAction>She laughs.</charAction> You know what else is a good one?
                <charAction>She earthbends the bridge, removing a circular part above which the
                three girls are standing, causing the girls to fall into the creek below. Cut to
                Katara's face from the hole.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Now that was funny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara waterbends a wave that sweeps the girls as they scream. Cut to a
                shot of Toph walking away from the bridge as Katara jogs to catch up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Those girls don't know what they're talking about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">It's okay. One of the good things about being blind, is I don't have to waste my
            time worrying about appearance. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Toph's
                face.</charAction> I don't care what I look like. I'm not looking for anyone's
            approval. I know who I am. <charAction>She stops walking, and she cries a
                bit.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's what I really admire about you, Toph. You're so strong, and confident, and
            self-assured. <charAction>Toph sniffs.</charAction> And I know it doesn't matter, but
            ... <charAction>Keeps her palm on Toph's shoulder.</charAction> You're really
            pretty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Turning to Katara, smiling.</charAction> I am?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yeah, you are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to show both of them walking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I'd return the compliment, but I've no idea how you look like. <charAction>Katara
                laughs.</charAction> Thank you, Katara. <charAction>She punches Katara's shoulder,
                her way of showing affection.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to an overhead shot of a marketplace in Ba Sing Se. Cut to a
                shot of the street, as Iroh goes toward a shop to buy a basket, and examines a
                basket kept.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shop owner">If this is for a romantic picnic, may I suggest this lavender one? <charAction>He
                points to another basket.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No, it's not a romantic picnic, but it is a special occasion. <charAction>He hands a
                coin to the owner, and takes the basket. As he goes, he sees a vase that contains a
                moon flower. He slides the vase into the shade, which causes the flowers to bloom
                instantly.</charAction> The moon flower likes partial shade. <charAction>He bows to
                the shop owner and walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Iroh examining another shop which sells musical instruments.
                The sound of a crying child catches Iroh's attention and he turns around to see a
                boy sobbing the middle of the street and his mother trying to console
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Boy's mother">Shhh. It's okay. Shhh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>He takes an instrument from the shop, and starts singing, walking toward
                the boy. Iroh gets down on one knee near the boy as he begins to sing.</charAction>
            Leaves from the vine, falling so slow. Like fragile, tiny shells, drifting in the foam.
            Little soldier boy, come marching home. Brave soldier boy, comes marching home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The boy's frown instantly turns to a smile as he reaches up and pulls
                Iroh's long beard, causing Iroh to groan while the boy laughs. Iroh smiles and pats
                his beard. The boy's mother takes her son by the hand and leads him away as Iroh
                stands and looks at them with a smiling look on his face.</description>
      <description>Scene changes to a courtyard as Iroh enters. Four boys are in the
                courtyard, playing earthbending ball. One of the boys hits the ground with his foot
                and the ball shoots up and comes back down. He kicks it and follows up with some
                earthbending. A patch of earth rises to create a path for the ball as it rolls
                along. Another player earthbends to stop the ball before it reaches the goal. This
                causes the ball to launch up and into the direction Iroh is standing. He dodges the
                ball just in time, but the ball breaks through the window directly behind where he
                was. A crash and a loud voice can be heard from inside.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huge round angry face">Hey!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It is usually best to admit mistakes when they occur, and seek to restore
            honor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Loud noises are heard and all five of them look up, startled. Shot cuts to
                show the window as a very large body and head are visible through the
                hole.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Huge round angry face">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> When I'm through with you kids, the window won't
            be the only thing that's broken.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">But not this time. Run!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh and the kids run away in all directions. Shot cuts to Iroh, running
                down the marketplace street quickly. He hides in an alley, places the basket down,
                and the shot changes to a shot of him looking around the corner to see if he is
                being chased. He is surprised to hear someone talking to him. Shot cuts to behind
                Iroh, where a man holding a knife is trying to mug him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">You, give me all your money!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera pans down to show Tycho's poor stance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">I'm mugging you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> With that stance?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">
         <charAction>Looks at his stance in a confused manner.</charAction> Huh? What're you
            talking about? Just give me your money, old man!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>He shakes his head.</charAction> With a poor stance, you are unbalanced,
            and you can be easily knocked over. <charAction>He quickly grabs the arm of the mugger
                and disarms him, while pushing his attacker and knocking him to the ground. He
                smiles, while twirling the dagger in his hand, and helps Tycho to his
                feet.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Hands the knife back to Tycho.</charAction> With a solid stance, you are
            a much more serious threat. <charAction>Iroh demonstrates a proper stance, which Tycho
                attempts to imitate, but is still not assuming the correct form. Iroh walks over to
                him and holds his head still while he adjusts the man's stance with a light
                kick.</charAction> Much better! But to tell you the truth, you do not look like the
            criminal type.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">I know. I'm ... <charAction>He sighs.</charAction> I'm just confused.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to a close-up of Tycho's hands holding a cup, while Iroh pours
                some hot tea for the man.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">So you really think I could be a good masseur?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Of course!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to show the two still in the alley, sitting on the ground sharing
                some tea and talking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Tycho">This is so great. No one has ever believed in me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> While it is always best to believe in oneself, a
            little help from others can be a great blessing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a shot of a tree on a hill within the city as the sun is
                setting. Leaves fall from the tree as Iroh approaches it. Iroh places the basket he
                had purchased earlier down and removes his hat. He rests on his knees and piles some
                rocks at the tree's base. He removes several things from the basket and places them
                at the bottom of the tree, near to the pile of stones. He pulls out a sheet of paper
                and looks at it for a few seconds, closing his eyes, before placing it down as well.
                Finally he pulls two incense sticks, and lights them with his fingers by
                firebending. Shot cuts to show that Iroh has made a small memorial for his deceased
                son, Lu Ten.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Happy birthday, my son. <charAction>Cut to his face, as he starts to
                cry.</charAction> If only I could have helped you. <charAction>He sings, but his
                voice cracks due to him crying.</charAction> Leaves from the vine, falling so slow.
            Like fragile, tiny shells, drifting in the foam. Little soldier boy, come marching home.
            Brave soldier boy, comes marching home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera zooms out, and fades to a message saying, "In honor of Mako,"
                referring to Mako Iwamatsu.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to an overhead shot of Ba Sing Se, as Aang flies on his
                glider, searching for Appa. Shot cuts to a street, as Aang lands on it, twirling his
                glider back into a staff. Shot cuts to Aang walking down the street, which is lined
                on both sides with various cages and pens built into the rock. Aang passes each pen
                and looks in to see different creatures looking sad and depressed, his expression
                matching theirs. He stops for a few seconds and looks up into a cage with a group of
                dragon flies. Shot cuts to him looking down into another pen which is a pit to see
                an elephant mandrill lying on the ground, very bored. Shot cuts to a tigerdillo
                gnawing at the bars that keep him in. It looks up as Aang approaches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Kneeling on one knee and holding his hand out.</charAction> Hey there,
            fellow. You look hungry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The tigerdillo roars, causing Aang to jump back in surprise. The creature
                curls up into a ball and rolls in its pen as the zookeeper, Kenji, walks behind
                Aang, sweeping.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">They are hungry. <charAction>Shot cuts to Kenji and Aang walking around in the
                zoo.</charAction> The Dai Li won't give me any money because the kids stopped
            coming. And the kids won't come because my zoo's nasty and broke.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at a cage.</charAction> What kinda animal is that?
                <charAction>They both stop walking.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">Oh, that's a rabaroo. I wish I could get her a big open prairie like she likes.
                <charAction>Shot cuts to the depressed rabaroo.</charAction> I'd let her hop away to
            happiness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Let's do it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Say again?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's a big open space right outside the walls of the city.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">But how're you gonna transport all these wild critters?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't worry, I'm great with animals.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a vessel being broken with a loud crash by some hog
                monkeys, who are wreaking havoc in one of the shops in the city, throwing pottery
                and breaking things. The owner comes in swinging a broom in an attempt to save his
                shop and manages to send one of them flying. Shot cuts to the creatures fleeing the
                shop and into the street just as an elephant mandrill comes stampeding down it while
                people run for their lives. Another group of people come running out of an alley
                covering their heads to escape the dragon flies that fly over them. A platypus bear
                enters the street and stands on its hind legs, swinging and growling as more people
                scream and run away. It pursues a group down an alley, as a tigerdillo comes rolling
                in and runs off in another direction. Cut to a shot of the rabaroo devouring
                cabbages from a pile. The shot cuts back to show that the creature is eating from
                the cabbage merchant's cart who is desperately trying to save his
                cabbages.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">My cabba- <charAction>He is interrupted by a rabaroo looking at him with a cabbage
                in her mouth. She chews it, and returns to the cart to eat more. The merchant throws
                down the cabbages he holds in his hand, and goes back.</charAction> Oh, forget
            it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to some dragonflies harassing people on a street, as Aang
                runs from the rooftops of the houses, descends onto the street, and helps the people
                using airbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He scratches his head.</charAction> This was so much easier in my
            head.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang suddenly gets an idea, and snaps his fingers, as he pulls out the
                bison whistle from his shirt. He throws the whistle into the air, and using
                airbending, inhales a great amount of air. He catches the whistle, and blows it.
                Shot cuts to an overhead shot of Ba Sing Se to show a soundwave being emitted from
                where Aang is and through the city as the whistle's sound spreads. Shot cuts to the
                hog monkeys wreaking havoc, who hear the sound and run off. The dragonflies, who are
                harassing people, hear the sound and go to its source. The rabaroo, still devouring
                cabbages as the cabbage merchant sobs in the background, leaves the cart as she
                hears the whistle as well.</description>
      <description>Shot cuts to Aang riding his air scooter down a street blowing the bison
                whistle. Cut to an alley, as Aang flies by on the main street, with a group of
                creatures following him, and a very slow turtle seal bringing up the rear. Shot cuts
                to Kenji talking with two guards at the wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">But you have to open this gate.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">Or what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">
         <charAction>He points to a large stampede of creatures following Aang.</charAction>
            Or that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a brief shot of the creatures following Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard #2">
         <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Open the gate!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Both the guards run in opposite directions, as the gate is opened. Shot
                cuts to show the gates opening from the street, as Aang flies down with the animals,
                before cutting to an overhead shot of the same. Aang stops blowing the whistle,
                jumps off his air scooter, on onto his glider, as the animals go out through the
                gate. The creatures go through the opening as he soars up and over the wall. On the
                other side, the creatures are shown coming out of the opening and starting to spread
                out in all directions as they run. Shot cuts to show Aang soaring down behind the
                running animals and hopping onto his air scooter again. As he rides, he punches the
                ground causing a large wall of earth to rise as he rides in a large circle creating
                a pen to block the running animals. Once he finishes, he jumps off his scooter and
                lands in the center of the pen he made. He earthbends again, causing a square
                portion of the ground to descend and creates a small pit. He turns around and brings
                his arms up high to cause some large pillars of earth to rise, making plateaus,
                turns, and punches outward which makes more walls to separate the
                animals.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the guards and Kenji going out, amazed. A group of kids,
                laughing and smiling, push past them and run toward the zoo. Shot cuts to show the
                entire the new zoo as people move around the newly formed pens and look the animals.
                Shot cuts to show the rabaroo drinking from a pond before looking up at one of the
                guests as three young rabaroos poke up from its pouch. Cut to Aang speaking with the
                zookeeper beside one of the pens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, Mr. Zookeeper, how do you like your new facilities?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">Excellent job, Avatar. You should think about working with animals for a
            living.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks behind him as a guest's voice catches his
                attention.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young guest">
         <charAction>Pointing into one of the pens.</charAction> Mommy, Miss Snowflake got
            out of the house again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a hissing cat in one of the pens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Adult guest">Fluffykins? <charAction>Cut to a guest's face.</charAction> What are you doing down
            there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to show Fluffykins hissing at the elephant mandrill it is sharing
                the pen with. Cut back to Kenji and Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kenji">On second thought, you should probably stick to saving people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang laughs at Kenji's statement.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Sokka walking down a candle-lit street at night. Bored, he
                pulls his boomerang from its sheath, throws it into the sky, and catches it as it
                comes back. Shot cuts to him walking past a building and into the alley beside it.
                Sokka passes through some men struggling with their ostrich horses, and by the
                windows of the building, as he hears voices from inside. Intrigued, he turns and
                sticks his head inside the window.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What's this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot cuts to show that the room is the Five-Seven-Five Society's
                classroom. There is a lady on the stage reciting her haiku to the rest of the
                ladies.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lady on stage">Through all the long night, winter moon glows with bright love, sleet her silver
            tears.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Looking pleased.</charAction> Ahh, poetry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to the alley, as the ostrich horse, who is still struggling with
                his handler, kicks backward and hits Sokka in his back, sending him through the
                window, and inside the room. The ladies look at him and shriek,
                startled.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Collecting himself and removing the window frame.</charAction> I am so
            sorry. Something struck me in the rear. I just ... wound up ... here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The ladies laugh, and clap at Sokka's unintended haiku. Sokka first looks
                surprised, but grins widely. Their teacher, Macmu-Ling, gets up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Macmu-Ling">Five, seven, then five, syllables mark a haiku. <charAction>She bows her
                head.</charAction> Remarkable oaf.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Thinking for a moment.</charAction> They call me Sokka, that is in the
            Water Tribe. <charAction>Counting five syllables on his fingers.</charAction> I am not
            an oaf. <charAction>The ladies laugh at his haiku.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Macmu-Ling">Tittering monkey, in the spring he climbs treetops, and thinks himself tall.
                <charAction>She narrows her eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ladies">Oooooh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You think you're so smart, with your fancy little words, this is not so
            hard.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ladies">Oooooh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Macmu-Ling">
         <charAction>She walks up to the stage.</charAction> Whole seasons are spent,
            mastering the form, the style, none calls it easy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ladies">Oooooh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I calls it easy. Like I paddle my canoe, I'll paddle yours too! <charAction>Turns
                around and paddles his behind, as the ladies laugh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Macmu-Ling">There's nuts and there's fruits. <charAction>She takes a plum from her sleeve, drops
                it to the ground, and squashes it.</charAction> In fall the clinging plum drops,
            always to be squashed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Making arm movements.</charAction> Squish, squash, sling that slang. I'm
            always right back at ya, like my ... <charAction>He draws his boomerang.</charAction>
            boomerang! <charAction>The class laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An annoyed Macmu-Ling walks off the stage and back to her seat as Sokka
                turns to the class again and raises his arms up to silence the laughter, as he
                unsheathes his boomerang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Making more arm movements.</charAction> That's right, I'm Sokka, it's
            pronounced with an "okka", young ladies, I rocked ya!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>This time, however, his "haiku" is not cheered at, instead being met with
                silence. Sokka stares at the class, as the annoyed and angry class does the vice
                versa. Cut to the ladies' angry faces. Cut back to Sokka, as he counts the number of
                syllables in his "haiku", and realizes that his last line contained six syllables
                instead of five by counting on his fingers. A large security guard approaches and
                catches him by the collar.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Bringing Sokka to his face.</charAction> Uh, that's one too many
            syllables there, bub.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Picking up Sokka completely, he throws him head first across the room and
                out the door. Outside, he hits the ground with a thud and sits up holding his
                head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Poetry ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to an exterior shot of the Pao Family Tea House. Cut to a
                shot of the inside where Zuko walks down the shop with a tray of cups, and looks
                behind at a girl. He walks up behind his uncle who is on a ladder, stacking things
                on a shelf behind the counter.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle, we have a problem. <charAction>Iroh descends from the ladder.</charAction>
            One of the customers is on to us. Don't look now but there is a girl over there at the
            corner table. <charAction>Cut to a shot of a girl sitting in the corner of the shop,
                drinking tea.</charAction> She knows we're Fire Nation. <charAction>Iroh looks at
                the girl, but is quickly pulled back by Zuko.</charAction> Didn't I say don't
            look?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot of the girl.</charAction> You're right, Zuko. I've seen
            that girl in here quite a lot. Seems to me she has quite a little crush on you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Bewildered.</charAction> What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">
         <charAction>She hands Zuko some coins, which he puts on a table.</charAction> Thank
            you for the tea. What's your name? <charAction>Iroh slightly smiles at the
                question.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning back.</charAction> My name's Lee. My uncle and I just moved
            here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Hi Lee, my name's Jin. Thank you and ... well, I was wondering if you would like to
            go out sometime. <charAction>Zuko is stunned.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Before the stunned Zuko can respond.</charAction> He'd love to!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Great. I'll meet you in front of the shop at sundown.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jin walks away, as Iroh throws his arms on a bewildered Zuko's shoulders,
                with a large smile as he glares at him. Cut to an exterior shot of the tea shop at
                evening, as Zuko comes out, his hair combed. He walks out into the middle of the
                street and looks around as Jin emerges from an alley beside the shop and walks up to
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Hey. Well, look at you. <charAction>She ruffles his hair.</charAction> You look so
            cute.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He stops Jin from ruffling his hair.</charAction> It took my uncle ten
            minutes to do my hair.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jin grabs Zuko by the arm and drags him as he glances once back at the
                teashop. Cut to a town square where several people stand around doing various
                activities. Cut to the Zuko and Jin who are eating at a restaurant, Jin sipping tea
                while Zuko pokes at his last meatball with his chop sticks, not looking at
                Jin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">So, how do you like the city so far?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">
         <charAction>Sipping tea; intrigued.</charAction> What do you like to do for
            fun?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Nothing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Waiter">
         <charAction>Addressing Zuko.</charAction> Excuse me, sir. Would you and your
            girlfriend care for dessert‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He yells in an assertive tone, pounding the table.</charAction> She is
            not my girlfriend!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The restaurant becomes silent as everyone's attention focuses on Zuko. The
                waiter walks away and Zuko laces his fingers and looks at Jin, who is slurping down
                a large bite of noodles from a bowl. Zuko stares at the sight in surprise for a
                moment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You have ... quite an appetite for a girl. <charAction>He fiddles his thumbs
                awkwardly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">
         <charAction>Uncomfortably.</charAction> Umm ... thanks? So, Lee, where were you and
            your uncle living before you came here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Umm ... well, we've been traveling around for a long time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Oh. Why were you traveling so much?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We were ... uh, part of this traveling circus.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Really? What did you do? Wait, lemme guess. <charAction>She thinks for a moment and
                quickly points at him.</charAction> You juggled!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko folds his arms and looks annoyed.</charAction> Yes, I
            juggled.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">I've always wanted to learn how to juggle. <charAction>She holds out some
                objects.</charAction> Can you show me something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko looks awkward and worried, but he takes the objects in his hand, and
                throws them one by one in the air. He is unable to catch them, and one of the
                objects falls on his head, breaking into many pieces.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I haven't practiced for a while. <charAction>Wipes the pieces of the objects from
                his hair.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">It's all right. Hey, I want to show you one of my favorite places in the
            city.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a street in the city, with Jin leading Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">I'm so excited for you to see the Firelight Fountain. The lamps make the water
            sparkle and reflect in the pool in the most beautiful way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She leads Zuko into an open area with a large fountain and several posts
                with candles on top surrounding it in a circle. However, the candles are not
                lit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">I can't believe it! They aren't lit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a brief overhead shot of the fountain, before cutting to Zuko and
                Jin. He looks at her before looking at the fountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Close your eyes, and don't peek.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jin closes and covers her eyes as Zuko walks out, holds his hands together,
                and closes his eyes as he prepares. A close-up of Zuko's face shows his eyes
                opening, as he begins firebending. Using his pointer and middle fingers on each
                hand, he shoots small bursts of flame in all directions at the candles to light
                them. Once finished, he stands straight and looks at Jin, still with her palms
                covering her eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Okay, now you can look.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">
         <charAction>Removes her palms from her eyes.</charAction> Oh, wow, <charAction>Cut
                to a shot showing the candles lit. Jin looks at Zuko, amazed. She walks up to him,
                looking at the candles.</charAction> What happened? How did they light? What did
            you? <charAction>She looks at a smiling Zuko.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They both turn to look at the fountain. As Zuko looks at them, Jin brushes
                her hand through her hair, smiles at him, and holds his hand. Zuko turns to look at
                the girl smiling at him. They both turn to be face to face and as Jin begins to lean
                in for a kiss, Zuko quickly draws a piece of paper which he holds between their
                lips.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I've brought you something. <charAction>Jin becomes surprised.</charAction> It's a
            coupon for a free cup of tea.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Lee, this is so sweet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He takes a few steps back.</charAction> Don't thank me – it was my
            uncle's idea. He thinks you're our most valuable customer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">Your uncle is a good teacher. <charAction>She walks close to him and turns his head
                toward her.</charAction> I have something for you too. Now it's your turn to close
            your eyes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko closes his eyes, Jin goes closer to him and kisses him before
                pulling back slightly. Zuko returns the kiss, but immediately jumps back away from
                her. He stands for a second, looking at her before turning his back and beginning to
                walk away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jin">What's wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Stops for a moment.</charAction> It's complicated. I have to go.
                <charAction>He walks off, leaving a disappointed Jin.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to the tea house, as Iroh is looking out from the windows at
                the street, waiting for Zuko. The door opens, as Zuko walks inside, being
                silent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">How was your night, Prince Zuko?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko walks into a room and slams the doors shut behind him without replying
                to Iroh. Iroh looks after him for a second with a confused look before turning back
                to the window to continue his work. He turns back when he hears Zuko opening the
                doors. Shot cuts to show Zuko's face in the crack between the two
                doors.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It was nice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He closes the doors again. Shot cuts to a smiling Iroh, who resumes his
                work.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a very tall tree, so tall that it towers above the clouds.
                Appa flies up through the clouds and over to the tree. Shot cuts to show many fruits
                hanging from vines on the tree. Appa hovers underneath these and Momo, who was
                sitting on the sky bison's head, flies up and begins eating some fruit and tosses
                some down to Appa who eats them. As Momo continues to chew on one of the fruits,
                Appa suddenly roars very loudly.</description>
      <description>The screen flashes white and shot cuts to Momo asleep on the windowsill of
                Team Avatar's house. Startled by the thunder that woke him from his dream, Momo
                leaps up into Sokka's Earth Kingdom bag that is hanging nearby. After some seconds,
                he pokes his head up and realizes he has some white fur lying on his head. Momo
                sniffs the fur, and shot cuts to a shot of Appa and Momo flying to indicate this is
                what Momo is thinking of. Appa roars again, and shot cuts back to Momo, as he
                chatters and realizes to whom the fur belongs.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the house form the lawn, with Momo visible through the
                window. A shadow that is very similar to Appa's crosses the ground. Cut back to Momo
                as he wraps the bunch of fur around one of his front legs, and soars out the window
                of the house and into the yard to investigate if this shadow belongs to the sky
                bison. As he emerges from a tree he flew up into, he realizes that the shadow is a
                cloud's. Disappointed, he holds his arm up and looks at the fur tied to it, but
                chatters a bit as he notices something. Shot cuts to show that on the other side of
                a house's roof, is what appears to be the head and horns of Appa. When Momo flies
                closer, however, he finds out it was only a tree with white leaves and branches
                sticking out in a way similar to Appa's horns. Momo lands on one of these branches
                and his ears drop in disappointment.</description>
      <description>Scene changes to a street as Momo soars above it. He lands on a water
                barrel, and begins to drink from it. As he does, his wagging tail accidentally
                knocks over a stick sitting nearby. It falls to the ground with a noise that alerts
                three pygmy pumas who were rummaging in the garbage nearby. The pygmy pumas growl at
                Momo and suddenly pounce on him. Momo manages to dodge and runs into a box with an
                opening big enough for him but not enough for the panthers. The three pumas surround
                the box and growl, with two of them trying and catch the lemur through the openings.
                Momo manages to escape from an opening in the back of the box and flies away. The
                pygmy pumas chase him by running on rooftops, as one of them manages to push him to
                the ground. After hitting the ground, Momo gets to his feet and runs on foot into a
                group of people, and the pumas do not follow their prey into the
                crowd.</description>
      <description>Momo is picked up by a man in the crowd and has a green little hat stringed
                to his head. He is tossed inside the circle of the people where two monkeys are
                already dancing to the beat of an organ grinder. After standing for a moment, Momo
                dances along. The crowd all cheer and clap for the dance, and the pumas stalk the
                lemur outside the circle of people, looking in between the legs at their prey. One
                of the monkeys jumps onto Momo's head and balances with its hand, the other doing
                the same on the first monkey's head, as Momo struggles to keep
                balance.</description>
      <description>Just as Momo is about to lose his balance, the pumas roar and attack him.
                Momo flees again, but this time as he tries to fly away, one of the pumas grabs him,
                which slows him down. The other two panthers jump on and grab onto Momo, and all
                four creatures crash into the ground. When the dust clears, Momo is pinned to the
                ground by one of his the predators while the other two stand ready to strike their
                catch. However, before they can, a net flies in, captures all four of them, and
                drags them off.</description>
      <description>Scene changes to the animal control officer placing Momo into a cage and
                locking it by placing a peg in to prevent the doors from opening. As the cart begins
                to move, Momo rubs the clump of Appa fur still tied to his arm against his face.
                Scene changes to an overhead shot of a small one-storied building, before cutting to
                inside the building, to show chicken meat. The cart has been pulled up inside the
                building. The butcher hits a log of wood with his knife. Shot cuts to shows the
                animal catcher and the butcher arguing, but their dialogue is only gibberish, as it
                is from Momo's perspective. Shot cuts to the three pygmy pumas, who are lying in the
                cage next to Momo, scratching at their cage and growling. Momo reaches through the
                bars and removes the peg that holds his cage shut. As he pushes the cage open and
                begins to run away, he stops and looks back. The pygmy pumas stare at him sadly from
                their cage. Sympathetically, Momo leaps back onto the cart and begins to remove the
                peg to free them. Cut to the two men approaching, but when the men reach the cart,
                they find both cages deserted as right behind them, as Momo and the panthers make
                their escape on the rooftops.</description>
      <description>Fade into a scene on the roofs of the city, as Momo and his three new
                friends sit and watch the clouds. One of the panthers is affectionately rubbing
                against Momo. Suddenly, one of the panthers uses its mouth to remove the bunch of
                Appa's fur from Momo's arm. The panther with the fur runs off, with the other two
                pumas following, and Momo, chattering loudly, follows them as well. The panthers
                lead Momo through the streets of Ba Sing Se till finally one of them places the
                bunch of fur on a footprint shaped on the ground. Momo lands on the hole as the
                pumas run off. Momo looks at this strange hole and realizes that it is actually a
                footprint made by Appa. Chattering, Momo lies down on the ground holding the bunch
                of fur. The camera zooms back to show the panthers sitting nearby, watching as the
                rain begins to fall on Momo, lying on the large footprint. Fade to
                credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
