<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="21">The Avatar State</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <writer>Elizabeth Welch Ehasz</writer>
      <writer>Tim Hedrick</writer>
      <writer>John O'Bryan</writer>
      <date>2006-03-17</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to show a gray sky as the camera moves back and down
                toward the Southern Air Temple where Aang is caught in a dream. In it, he is running
                about the Southern Air Temple. He comes across the room where he had found Monk
                Gyatso's skeleton in real life and instead sees his own self in the Avatar State.
                The personage of himself turns to glare at him angrily. Camera cuts to a terrified
                Aang, wind blowing past him. Cuts to a view of Sokka and Katara huddled behind a
                rock, watching the Avatar State Aang as he sends a forceful gust of wind that blows
                the real Aang back. He falls into the room in the Fire Temple he had visited to
                speak to Roku. The doors to the room open and reveal the personage of Aang in the
                Avatar State, who breathes fire and splits the floor in half. The real Aang falls
                through and lands on a Fire Navy ship in the Northern seas. The monstrous koi fish,
                called Koizilla, created when he and La had fused together during the Siege of the
                North appears before him, the personage of him inside. The Kozilla makes a downward
                cutting motion, and the personage does the same before a blinding white appears and
                the dream ends. Aang awakes from it and leaves the room where the gang is sleeping,
                exiting through a stairway. Katara awakens and catches sight of him
                leaving.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Aang ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a shot of Aang standing by the ledge of the Water Tribe
                ship on which they are sailing. Katara approaches him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Do you want to talk about it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nah, just a nightmare. I was in the Avatar State, but I was outside my body watching
            myself. It was scary. I was scary. <charAction>Closes eyes and bows his head; Katara
                puts her hand on his shoulder.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to daybreak. Pakku is on the ship with two Water Tribe
                members and the gang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Holds up flask.</charAction> Katara, I want you to have this.
                <charAction>Closes up on flask.</charAction> This amulet contains water from the
            Spirit Oasis. The water has unique properties. Don't lose it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Accepts amulet and hugs Pakku.</charAction> Thank you, Master
            Pakku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Hands Aang box of scrolls.</charAction> Aang, these scrolls will help
            you master waterbending. But remember, they're no substitute for a real master.
                <charAction>Aang looks up at Katara, who is sitting on Appa and looks
                back.</charAction> Sokka ... <charAction>Pats him on shoulder, leaving him
                dismayed.</charAction> take care, son. <charAction>To the entire gang while pointing
                out in a direction.</charAction> Fly straight to the Earth Kingdom base to the east
            of here. General Fong will provide you with an escort to Omashu. There, you will be safe
            to begin your earthbending training with King Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa, yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>As they fly away.</charAction> Say hi to Gran-Gran for me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switches to a village. Iroh is lying on a table, getting a relaxing
                massage at a resort.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">This is what I've been missing. Who knew floating on a piece of driftwood for three
            weeks with no food or water, and sea vultures waiting to pluck out your liver could make
            one so tense? <charAction>Looks at the clearly unhappy Zuko, walks over to him, and sits
                down on the ground.</charAction> I see. It's the anniversary, isn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>In a brooding tone.</charAction> Three years ago today, I was banished.
            I lost it all. <charAction>Looks up.</charAction> I want it back. I want the Avatar, I
            want my honor, my throne. I want my father not to think I'm worthless. <charAction>Looks
                on regretfully.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm sure he doesn't. Why would he banish you if he didn't care? <charAction>Zuko
                gets up and walks away; he grimaces soon after; to the massagers.</charAction> Uh,
            that came out wrong, didn't it? <charAction>They look at each other in
                confusion.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to a Fire Nation ship. Several men bow as a royal
                carriage is brought out. Within the carriage is Princess Azula, the daughter of
                Ozai, niece of Iroh, and sister of Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Stepping out of the carriage and walking down the line of
                soldiers.</charAction> My brother and my uncle have disgraced the Fire Lord, and
            have brought shame on all of us. You might have mixed feelings about attacking members
            of the Royal Family. I understand. But I assure you, if you hesitate, I will not
            hesitate to bring you down. Dismissed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldiers leave. The captain runs up to Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Princess, I'm afraid the tides will not allow us to bring the ship into port before
            nightfall.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I'm sorry, captain, but I do not know much about the tides. Could you explain
            something to me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Of course, Your Highness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Do the tides command this ship?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">I'm afraid I don't understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You said the tides would not allow us to bring the ship in. <charAction>In a sharper
                tone.</charAction> Do the tides command this ship?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">No, princess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">And if I were to have you thrown overboard, would the tides think twice about
            smashing you against the rocky shore?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> No, princess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Runs fingers through her bangs.</charAction> Well then, maybe you should
            worry less about the tides who have already made up their mind about killing you, and
            worry more about me, who's still mulling it over. <charAction>Turns to face the captain
                angrily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">I'll pull us in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He leaves. Cuts to a close-up of Azula, who glares and narrows her eyes in
                suspicion. The scene switches to the team flying on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Rises to view their destination.</charAction> There it is!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The gang arrives at General Fong's base, where he and his soldiers are
                waiting.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">Welcome, Avatar Aang! <charAction>Cuts to shot of the team stretching after riding
                on Appa.</charAction> I am General Fong, and welcome, to all of you great heroes!
            Appa, Momo, brave Sokka, the mighty Katara ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pleased.</charAction> Mighty Katara? I like that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fireworks go off, launched by the soldiers using
                earthbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Viewing the display.</charAction> Not bad, not bad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to inside the base, where General Fong and the team are
                sitting in a spacious discussion room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Camera view depicts entire room.</charAction> Avatar Aang, we were all
            amazed at the stories of how you singlehandedly wiped out an entire Fire Navy fleet at
            the North Pole. <charAction>Closes up to Fong, stroking his beard.</charAction> I can't
            imagine what it feels like to wield such devastating power. It's an awesome
            responsibility.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> I try not to think about it too much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Avatar, you're ready to face the Fire Lord
            now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> What? No I'm not!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Holds out her hand in reasoning.</charAction> Aang still needs to master
            all four elements.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">Why? With the kind of power he possesses, power enough to destroy hundreds of battle
            ships in a matter of minutes, he could defeat the Fire Lord now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">But sir, the thing is, Aang can only do those things when he's in the Avatar
            State.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">See, it's this special state where-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Sharply.</charAction> I'm well aware! Your eyes and tattoos glow and
            you're able to summon unbelievable power. Without you, we'd be slaughtered before we
            even reach their shores. <charAction>Looks at map and guides finger from the location of
                the base to the location of the Fire Nation Capital.</charAction> But with you
            leading the way, as the ultimate weapon, we could cut a swath right through to the heart
            of the Fire Nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Doubtfully.</charAction> Right, but, I don't know how to get in or out
            of the Avatar State, much less what to do once I'm there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">So, it's decided then. I'll help you figure out how to get into the Avatar State and
            then you'll face your destiny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>The group rises; angrily.</charAction> No, nothing's decided. We already
            have a plan. Aang's pursuing his destiny his way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">Well, while you take your time learning the elements, the War goes on. May I show
            you something? <charAction>Leads Aang to a window.</charAction> That's the infirmary,
            and those soldiers are the lucky ones. <charAction>Several soldiers are injured and
                walking slowly.</charAction> They came back. Every day, the Fire Nation takes lives.
            People are dying, Aang! You could end it, now. Think about it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang averts his eyes to the side, looking unsure. The scene changes to
                Azula's ship, where she is training. She stands perfectly straight, holding her
                fingers in her hand. The camera cuts to where Lo and Li are sitting, overseeing her
                training. Cuts to shot of Azula, as she moves her arms in a circular motion,
                generating lightning and firing the bolt into the sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lo">Almost perfect.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Li">One hair out of place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Close-up of her face as she pushes a loose strand of hair
                away.</charAction> Almost isn't good enough!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She repeats her actions, generating lightning again and firing it off into
                the distance. Cuts to a shot of Iroh, who suddenly awakens from a nap, sits up and
                peers in curiosity. The scene changes to nightfall at Fong's base.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">General Fong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">Come in, Aang. Have you thought about our discussion?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm in. I'll fight the Fire Lord.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to where Aang has entered a room with several plain beds,
                where the team is resting for the night.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sits on his bed.</charAction> I told the general I'd help him, by going
            into the Avatar State.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sits up.</charAction> Aang, no! This is not the right way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Resting on his bed with his arms behind his head.</charAction> Why not?
            Remember when he took out the Fire Navy? <charAction>Widens his eyes.</charAction> He
            was incredible!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">There's a right way to do this. Practice, study, and discipline!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Casually.</charAction> Or just glow it up and stop that Fire
            Lord!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Rises and throws her hands up in surrender.</charAction> If you two meat
            heads want to throw away everything we've worked for, fine, go ahead and glow it up!
                <charAction>Exits.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, I'm just being realistic! I don't have time to do this the right
            way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang casts a mournful look. The scene changes to the next day where Fong,
                the team, and another soldier are sitting in an outdoor room. The soldier is pouring
                tea in a cup.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">
         <charAction>Drops white food item into the teapot.</charAction> This rare
            chi-enhancing tea is a natural stimulant. In an ordinary warrior, it improves strength
            and energy ten-fold. In you, it may induce the Avatar State.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ten-fold energy, huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang drinks the tea, causing his eyebrows to twitch slightly. The camera
                pans downward to the same scene where Aang is riding rapidly on an air scooter,
                hyper from the energy boost.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Quickly in a high-pitched voice.</charAction> Is it working? Is it
            working? I can't tell! Somebody tell me if I'm in the Avatar State 'cause I don't have a
            good view of myself! Am I talking too loud?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sitting on the floor, tired out by Aang's actions.</charAction> I guess
            he could talk the Fire Lord to death.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang hits a pillar and falls backward. The scene switches to where Aang is
                sitting on the ground, Sokka standing a few feet away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Maybe I can shock you into the Avatar State.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I love surprises!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera cuts to view from Aang's perspective, Katara covering his eye with
                her hands. She uncovers his eyes to reveal Sokka towering over Aang, his head
                instead replaced with Momo's, who screeches. Aang screams and glances at his arrow
                tattoos.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding up hands.</charAction> Still not glowing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to view of the entire team as Sokka steps backward, loses his balance
                and falls to the ground off camera. Fong shakes his head in dismay. The scene
                changes to a dimly lit room where Aang is standing, wearing an outfit consisting of
                a Water Tribe cloak, an Earth Kingdom hat with leaves coming out of the top, part of
                a Fire Nation soldier outfit and what appears to be a belt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oracle">You are wearing a ceremonial piece of clothing from each of the bending nations. Now
            I will join the four elements into one! Water <charAction>Pours jug of water into the
                bowl.</charAction>, earth <charAction>Pours in bowl of dirt.</charAction>, fire
                <charAction>Takes nearby torch and throws it in.</charAction>, air!
                <charAction>Releases air gust from wooden contraption.</charAction> Four elements
            together as one!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The oracle raises the bowl and flings the contents at Aang, coating him in
                mud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> This is just mud!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oracle">
         <charAction>Quizzically.</charAction> So ... do you feel anything?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang raises his finger, catching everyone's interest, only to sneeze,
                causing mud to fly everywhere, coating Fong, Katara, and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Rubs mud from face.</charAction> We have to find a way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to Zuko and Iroh's place of stay, the room dark inside.
                Several various shells fall from a bag onto the table. The camera pans up to where
                Iroh is standing at the table, picking up and examining the different
                shells.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Holds up one shell.</charAction> Look at these magnificent shells!
                <charAction>Picks up a conch.</charAction> I'll enjoy these keepsakes for years to
            come.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We don't need any more useless things! You forget, we have to carry everything
            ourselves now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>From the corner, sitting at the table; calmly.</charAction> Hello,
            brother. Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What are you doing here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Holds up a shell in her hand.</charAction> In my country, we exchange a
            pleasant hello before asking questions. <charAction>Rises and walks toward Zuko and
                Iroh.</charAction> Have you become uncivilized so soon, Zuzu?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Don't call me that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Clearly upset.</charAction> To what do we owe this honor?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Hmmm ... must be a family trait. Both of you so quick to get to the point.
                <charAction>Breaks the shell she was holding with her fingertips, leaving Iroh
                angry.</charAction> I've come with a message from home. Father's changed his mind.
            Family is suddenly very important to him. He's heard rumors of plans to overthrow him;
            treacherous plots. Family are the only ones you can really trust. <charAction>Pauses
                briefly.</charAction> Father regrets your banishment. He wants you home.
                <charAction>Silence.</charAction> Did you hear me? You should be happy. Excited.
            Grateful. I just gave you great news.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm sure your brother simply needs a moment.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Furiously.</charAction> Don't interrupt, Uncle! <charAction>To
                Zuko.</charAction> I still haven't heard my thank you.
                <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> I'm not a messenger. I
            didn't have to come all this way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Father regrets? He ... wants me back?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I can see you need time to take this in. I'll come to call on you tomorrow. Good
            evening.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She exits, leaving Zuko to ponder what has just been said. Meanwhile, at
                Fong's base, Aang and Katara stand on a balcony, the sun setting over the
                horizon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Can we talk about something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cuts to side-shot of Aang and Katara.</charAction> Do you remember when
            we were at the air temple and you found Monk Gyatso's skeleton? It must have been so
            horrible and traumatic for you. I saw you get so upset that you weren't even you
            anymore. <charAction>Closes up to Katara.</charAction> I'm not saying the Avatar State
            doesn't have incredible and helpful power ... but you have to understand ... for the
            people who love you, watching you be in that much rage and pain is really
            scary.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm really glad you told me that. But I still need to do this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Upset.</charAction> I don't understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cuts to overall view of Aang and Katara.</charAction> No, you don't.
            Every day, more and more people die. I'm already one hundred years late. Defeating the
            Fire Lord is the only way to stop this war. I have to try it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> I can't watch you do this to yourself. I'm not
            coming tomorrow. <charAction>Begins to exit.</charAction> Good night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> Good night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to nightfall at Zuko and Iroh's house. Cuts to inside the
                house.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Packing belongings.</charAction> We're going home! After three long
            years, it's unbelievable!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Staring out the window thoughtfully.</charAction> It
                is unbelievable. I have never known my brother to regret
            anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Did you listen to Azula? Father's realized how important family is to him!
                <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> He cares about me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Turns to face Zuko and holds out arms in gesture.</charAction> I care
            about you! And if Ozai wants you back, well, I think it may not be for the reasons you
            imagine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns his back to Iroh.</charAction> You don't know how my father feels
            about me. You don't know anything!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko, I only meant that in our family, things are not always what they
            seem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns to face Iroh.</charAction> I think you are exactly what you seem!
            A lazy, mistrustful, shallow old man who's always been jealous of his brother!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko walks away, leaving Iroh saddened. Meanwhile, Aang is caught in
                another dream. The dream takes place in the Southern seas on Zuko's ship, where the
                Avatar State Aang rises from the water, riding a water vortex, similar to the way
                Aang did in the beginning of the series. The personage lands on deck and sweeps away
                the real Aang with waterbending. The personage turns to Zuko and performs the same
                downward, cutting motion as seen in previous dreams before the dream abruptly ends
                and Aang awakens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sits up in his bed.</charAction> Sokka! Sokka, wake up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't think we should be trying to bring on the Avatar State.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You sure?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly.</charAction> Okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Do you think the general will be mad?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What can he say? You're the Avatar. Who knows better than you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang lies back on his bed, resting his head on his arms. The next morning,
                we cut back to Zuko, who is getting ready to return home. He descends a stone
                staircase, carrying his bags.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Holding up his hand in motion and running down the staircase after
                Zuko.</charAction> Wait! Don't leave without me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns around, smiles and sets down pack.</charAction> Uncle! You've
            changed your mind!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Family sticks together, right? <charAction>Lays hand on Zuko's
                shoulder.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene flashes back to a shot of Zuko's father, Ozai, resting his hand
                on his son's shoulder years ago. Flashes back to present day.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We're finally going home!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He resumes his descent. The camera closes up on Azula's ship sitting in the
                harbor. Closes up to Iroh, looking on with suspicion. The scene switches to the
                discussion room in Fong's base.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Humbly.</charAction> The thing is, I don't think we'll ever be able to
            trigger it on purpose. So I guess that's it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> You sure I can't change your mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sure. I can only reach the Avatar State when I'm in genuine danger.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">I see. I was afraid you'd say that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He blasts his entire desk at Aang using earthbending, sending him soaring
                across the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang! <charAction>Attempts to come to his aid, only to be held down by two
                soldiers.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The impact sends Aang crashing through the wall and flying out of the
                building. He breaks his fall with airbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Walks over toward the hole that was created from the impact and points
                to Aang.</charAction> Men! Attack the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of Aang being surrounded by several earthbending
                soldiers, some riding on ostrich horses. Fong jumps out of the building and hits the
                ground, sending a rock wave at Aang which sends him back further.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Slyly.</charAction> I believe we're about to get results.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera focuses on soldiers, who prepare to fire large earth coins at
                Aang using earthbending. Cuts to a shot of Aang, looking nervously about him. The
                camera zooms out to a shot of him and his attackers before switching to a soldier,
                who sends an earth coin at him. Aang avoids two oncoming coins and soars in the air
                parallel to the ground between two more coins that are thrown at him. He lands
                safely to the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking about cautiously.</charAction> I'm not your enemy! I won't fight
            you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He jumps into the air as four earth coins are sent his way, crashing into
                each other. As Aang begins his descent, another earth coin is sent skidding toward
                him; the coin crashes into one of the four stationery coins. Aang lands on the
                ground where the coin was standing just moments ago. Two of the other stationery
                coins are closed together. The camera cuts to a shot of Aang trapped inside the
                holes of the earth coins, rolling speedily away. An earthbender breaks the coins,
                crumbling them to bits. Aang lands on the ground, rises and faces the rest of the
                soldiers.</description>
      <description>Meanwhile, Sokka, who was being held down by the two soldiers, raises his
                feet and steps on their bare feet forcefully. The two soldiers release their grip
                and fall forward onto the ground in pain while Sokka runs away to aid
                Aang.</description>
      <description>Outside, Aang narrowly avoids two earth coins sent at him, one flying above
                him, one flying below him. Two more earth coins are sent from opposite sides of the
                ring, threatening to crush him. Aang manages to escape by dodging through the holes
                in the coins just as they collide together and fall to the ground.</description>
      <description>Riding an air scooter, Aang zigzags past several soldiers who attempt to
                slow him down by conjuring up rock walls in his path. Two soldiers riding ostrich
                horses chase after him as Aang rides past and scales up the wall of the base. As he
                is seen riding up the wall on the air scooter, the two soldiers use earthbending to
                propel themselves upward. Aang's air scooter runs out of air and he begins running
                up the wall, the two soldiers following him in hot pursuit. Cuts to a top view of
                Aang scaling the wall, only to narrowly dodge two spears coming his
                way.</description>
      <description>He falls to the ground. The two soldiers land on the wall and descend to
                the ground after him. Aang somersaults forward as he avoids their spear attacks yet
                again. He lands onto the ground, an earth coin embedded into it. The earth coin is
                suddenly sent upward and dragged forward, Aang being trapped in its hole. The earth
                coin lands in front of Fong.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">You can't run forever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You can't fight forever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fong leaps forward and crushes the earth coin, just as Aang jumps to avoid
                the attack. Dust from the impact is sent flying toward the screen. The scene changes
                to where Zuko and Iroh are approaching Azula's ship. The camera pans upward and
                focuses on a shot of Azula standing quietly on top of a ramp leading up to the ship.
                Royal Procession guards stand on either side of them as they walk, forming an aisle.
                Iroh averts his eyes suspiciously between the guards. They reach the ship and bow;
                the guards behind them walk forward and close the aisle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Brother! Uncle! Welcome! I'm so glad you decided to come.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a side-shot of Iroh, opening his eyes slightly and
                casting a suspicious glance at the guards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Are we ready to depart, Your Highness?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Sweetly.</charAction> Set our course for home, captain.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Wistfully.</charAction> Home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">
         <charAction>He walks up the ramp with Zuko and Iroh following him and raises his
                hand in gesture.</charAction> You heard the princess! Raise the anchors! We're
            taking the prisoners home!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The captain widens his eyes in realization at his mistake and looks at
                Azula. Zuko and Iroh stop, looking surprised. Cut to Azula with a look of surprise
                on her face. The camera rushes to her face as her expression turns to fury. Cut back
                to the captain, his eyes wide.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Your Highness, I ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko, his eyes widening. Cuts to a close-up of Iroh, who narrows his
                eyes to the left and suddenly begins attacking the guards. He pushes them off the
                edge of the walkway and sends fire blasts their way. Cuts to a side-shot of Zuko, as
                he stomps furiously up the ramp and throws the captain off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You lied to me! <charAction>Cut to Azula, who appears
            confident.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Smugly.</charAction> Like I've never done that before.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She turns her back to him and walks away, as two guards standing near her
                shoot fire blasts at Zuko. Zuko crosses his arms and spreads them outward,
                deflecting the attacks and shouts as he charges onto the ship. The scene changes to
                Aang, who avoids three earth coins that slam onto the ground, threatening to crush
                him. He runs to the left of the screen as another coin rolls his way. The scene
                changes to the team's bedroom, where Katara is lying on her bed, listening to the
                noises outside.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I wonder what crazy thing they're trying to do now. <charAction>Momo, who is
                sleeping on a pillow, raises his head before going back to sleep. Katara hears
                another rumble outside and grows worried.</charAction> Maybe we should just make
            sure Aang's okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She rises from her bed. The camera cuts to a shot of the base tower and
                pans downward to show Katara and Sokka running down opposite stairways. They meet up
                at the bottom of the base.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Frantically.</charAction> What's going on?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">The general's gone crazy! He's trying to force Aang into the Avatar State!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka pulls out his boomerang and throws it as Katara runs off. Cuts to a
                shot of a soldier, who is hit by the boomerang and falls to the ground in a daze,
                knocking over the earth coin in the process. Cuts to Aang, who is being chased by
                another soldier mounted on an ostrich horse. The head of the spear the soldier was
                holding is suddenly snapped off. He slows down, stunned at this. Cuts to a shot of
                Katara summoning a water whip.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Approaching the ostrich horse carefully.</charAction> Good ... bird ...
            horse thingy ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka mounts it and the animal begins galloping away, leaving Katara
                standing in the arena. The camera zooms out to Fong. Several earth coins are
                summoned, rolling toward Katara before coming to a standstill.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Looking back at Aang, who has managed to escape up a
                stairway.</charAction> Maybe you can avoid me ... but she can't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldiers rotate the earth coins so that their flat sides face Katara.
                The camera zooms out to the entire arena, the coins forming a triangular pattern
                around Katara. The waterbender sends a water whip at Fong, who summons up dust
                pillars that deflect the water and turn it to mud. He uses earthbending to begin
                sinking her into the ground. She twists around, buried knee deep.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Struggling to break free.</charAction> I can't move!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Worried; clenches his fists.</charAction> Don't hurt her!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He leaps onto the ground and sends a gust of wind at Fong, who summons an
                earth wall to block the attack. Fong brings down the earth wall and sinks Katara
                into the ground further, this time burying her waist deep.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Riding the ostrich horse.</charAction> Katara! No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He gallops toward her, but Fong sinks the animal's feet into the ground,
                flinging Sokka off the ostrich horse. Sokka slams into the hole of an earth coin,
                leaving him dangling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Desperately and clutching onto Fong's arm.</charAction> Stop this! You
            have to let her go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">You could save her if you were in the Avatar State!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Tears forming around his eyes.</charAction> I'm trying ... I'm
            trying!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Frantically.</charAction> Aang, I'm sinking! <charAction>Twists around
                again and is buried chest deep.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Demanding.</charAction> I don't see glowing! <charAction>Lowers his
                right arm and begins closing his hand into a fist; Katara becomes buried neck
                deep.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Desperately.</charAction> Please!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Falling to his knees, begging.</charAction> You don't need to do
            this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Scornfully.</charAction> Apparently, I do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He clenches his fist tight, sinking Katara completely. She cries out in
                fear before being completely buried in the ground. Aang leaps forward and attempts
                to save her, however, he falls short. Closes up on Aang, as his arrow tattoo begins
                to glow a bright white. He turns his head to face Fong, the Avatar State now
                triggered.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Triumphantly.</charAction> It worked! It worked!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An air blast is sent his way and his triumphant expression soon becomes one
                of fear as he realizes the situation. Cuts to Aang, who performs the downward
                cutting motion as seen in his previous dreams and pushes Fong back with a powerful
                air blast. Fong lands roughly on the ground. Cuts to Aang, who begins rising on an
                earth vortex.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to Zuko, who leaps onto the deck of the ship and blasts
                the two guards off the ship with two fire blasts. He lands on deck. The camera zooms
                out to where Azula is standing patiently several feet away, her back turned to him.
                Focuses on Azula, who smirks. Cuts to Zuko, who clenches his fists and prepares fire
                daggers. Cuts to Iroh, who continues to attack the guards on the
                walkway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Pushes several guards away; grabs one and wrestles him.</charAction>
            Zuko! Let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He hurls the guard over the edge and steps to the side to avoid another
                guard's attack and push him aside. Cuts back to Zuko, who charges at Azula with fire
                daggers. Zooms out to where he attempts to strike Azula, only for the princess to
                acutely dodge all of his blows. Cuts to close-up of her as she smirks at her
                brother. Zooms out to both siblings as Zuko keeps attacking and Azula keeps
                avoiding. Zuko brings down his right hand to land another blow, however, Azula
                manages to push him away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You know, Father blames Uncle for the loss of the North Pole. And he considers you a
            miserable failure for not finding the Avatar! <charAction>Cuts to Zuko, who is panting
                heavily.</charAction> Why would he want you &gt;back home,
            except to lock you up <charAction>Cuts back to Azula.</charAction> where you can no
            longer embarrass him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko conjures up two fire daggers again. He leaps into the air and sends a
                powerful fire blast at Azula using his foot. She jumps and lands safely on the deck
                several feet away. Zuko charges at her as she rises to her feet. After dodging
                several more attacks, she manages to scrape his forehead with her fingernails,
                leaving three scratch marks on his temple. Zuko falls back a few feet from the
                impact and yells as he charges at her again.</description>
      <description>The two continue to duel, eventually making their way up a stairway that
                leads to the central control area of the ship. Azula manages grab hold of Zuko's
                arm. A few seconds pause as the two stand silently, Zuko widening his eyes in alarm.
                Cuts to a side-shot of the stairway where Azula knocks him to his feet with a blue
                fire blast. Zuko lands roughly at the bottom of the stairwell. Cuts to a shot from
                Zuko's perspective, the screen slightly blurred to show the effects of the blow. The
                camera travels upward from side to side before landing on Azula, who moves both her
                arms in a circular motion, generating lightning. Cuts to shot of her readying the
                attack and firing the bolt at her brother, only for Iroh to step in suddenly, grab
                hold of her right hand and redirect the lightning, causing it to strike a far-off
                cliff side. He bends her downward and kicks her off the ship. Azula lands in the
                water below with a splash. Cuts to Zuko and Iroh, who run away from the
                ship.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to Fong's base, where Aang is rising on the earth vortex,
                still under the control of the Avatar State.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Pleading.</charAction> Avatar Aang! Can you hear me? Your friend is
            safe! <charAction>Brings Katara back above ground; cuts to close-up of her as she looks
                up at Aang in misery.</charAction> It was just a trick to trigger the Avatar State
            ... <charAction>Cuts back to Fong, who smiles maniacally.</charAction> and it
            worked!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang swivels about on the vortex and lands on the ground forcefully,
                causing a flurry of dust to spread. Fong is sent back several feet while Katara
                remains rooted to the ground where she was. Cuts to the left of the arena where
                several soldiers are standing, a torrent of dust rumbling their way. The dust clears
                to reveal the ground broken and in ruins. Cuts to right of the arena, where several
                soldiers on ostrich horses stand. The dust torrent passes over them and clears,
                revealing that side in ruins. Cuts to another area of the base, where several houses
                lie. Again, the torrent passes over, leaving the houses considerably
                damaged.</description>
      <description>Cuts to Aang, who is still under the influence of the Avatar State. His
                spirit is seen leaving his body and rising into the air. Cuts to bird's-eye view of
                the base as Roku's dragon, Fang passes by, Avatar Roku and Aang riding atop the
                beast.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Looking at Aang.</charAction> It's time you learned.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They fly higher above the dusty clouds. Cuts to side shot of the dragon,
                many small figures seen floating in the distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Cuts to Roku.</charAction> The Avatar State is a defense mechanism,
            designed to empower you with the skills and knowledge of all the past Avatars.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to Avatar Kyoshi, who stands surrounded by rocky mountain terrain. Her
                eyes glow for a moment and she assumes a fighting stance. The camera zooms out to
                reveal two large earthen statues, somewhat resembling badgermoles. She performs a
                series of moves which cause the statues to rise into the air, and send them past
                toward the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">The glow is the combination of all your past lives, focusing their energy through
            your body.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of Avatar Kuruk, riding atop a raft in the middle of the
                ocean. His eyes glow momentarily before he raises his arms and summons a gigantic
                tsunami-like wave. He is seen rapidly riding atop the wave toward the screen. Cuts
                to Avatar Yangchen, who stands in a grassy field surrounded by a forest area. Her
                eyes glow briefly as she swings her arms and swivels around, conjuring powerful
                winds. The camera zooms out to the entire field and the forest blown violently by
                the wind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">In the Avatar State, you are at your most powerful, <charAction>Cuts to Avatar
                Szeto, who summons lava spouts from four volcanoes; the lava washes over the screen
                and the scene cuts back to Roku and Aang.</charAction> but you are also at your most
            vulnerable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What do you mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">If you are killed in the Avatar State, <charAction>The figures of him and the
                Avatars in the background are blown away like dust.</charAction> the reincarnation
            cycle will be broken <charAction>Shows the line of Avatars with Aang standing at the
                end; the Avatars begin to fade away in succession down the line.</charAction> and
            the Avatar will cease to exist.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang is shown with a worried look on his face. The scene cuts to the base
                where Fang flies over Fong's base. Cuts to Aang's body, surrounded by a dome of air.
                Fang flies downward, head first, passing through Aang's body and into the ground.
                Aang's spirit is brought back to his physical self and he exits the Avatar
                State.</description>
      <description>He falls to the ground weak and surveys the damage he caused to the base.
                Cuts to the ruins of the arena, houses destroyed and earth coins flung about. Cuts
                to Katara, completely unharmed from the whole ordeal, who approaches Aang and hugs
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Embracing her; regretfully.</charAction> I'm sorry, Katara. I hope you
            never have to see me like that again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">
         <charAction>Triumphantly.</charAction> Ha! Are you joking? That was almost perfect!
                <charAction>Thoughtfully.</charAction> We just have to find out a way to control you
            when you're like that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slightly angry.</charAction> You're out of your mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fong">I guess we'll figure it out on the way to the Fire Nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka appears behind the general, riding the ostrich horse. He raises his
                club and strikes the general on the head, which knocks him out cold.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Anybody got a problem with that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldiers shake their heads. Zooms out to the gang, several soldiers and
                Fong, who lies on the ground motionless.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">Do you still want an escort to Omashu?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Casts the group a look of annoyance.</charAction> I think we're all
            set.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The group leaves the base on Appa. The scene changes to the village resort.
                Azula is seen standing on the balcony of one of the residential buildings. Two Royal
                Procession guards stand in the background to protect her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Holds up wanted poster of her brother and uncle.</charAction> Anyone who
            harbors these traitors will face the wrath of the Fire Lord! <charAction>She lays a hand
                on the balcony, causing the two massagers to cower in fear; cuts to close-up of
                her.</charAction> There will be no place left to hide!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to a riverside. The shadowy reflections of two figures on
                the run can be seen in the water. Cuts to view of the river bank and the area nearby
                as Zuko and Iroh run frantically. Cuts to riverbank as the two stop and fall to the
                ground, catching their breath.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I think we're safe here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot from Zuko's perspective as he pulls out a small dagger. Cuts
                to close-up of Zuko holding the dagger, its blade reflecting the sunlight. Cuts
                briefly to Iroh, who closes his eyes, seemingly aware of his nephew's actions. He
                casts a look at Zuko, who holds the knife under his ponytail. Cuts to close-up of
                his ponytail, as he slices it off with the knife. He holds it in his hand and looks
                at it for a moment before passing the knife to Iroh, who cuts off his topknot. Cuts
                to Zuko's hand, as he releases his ponytail. Cuts to the surface of the river, as
                the two topknots are released and float down the river. The camera zooms out to
                where Zuko and Iroh stand quietly on the bank of the river.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
