<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="18">The Waterbending Master</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Michael Dante DiMartino</writer>
      <date>2005-11-18</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to show a koala otter calmly floating on its back on the
                water, purring slightly. Noticing something approach to its right, it turns its
                head, chirps, and dives under water as a large shadow passes it by. It turns out to
                be Appa flying overhead.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Hanging lazily over the back of Appa's saddle; grumpily.</charAction>
            I'm not one to complain, <charAction>Side-view shows Appa flying just above the
                water.</charAction> but can't Appa fly any higher?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka's words barely left his lips as Appa loses more altitude and his paws
                drag through the water momentarily, before rising slightly again. Cut to a shot from
                Appa's saddle, showing a bored Katara popping herself up on her elbows, staring into
                nothingness in front of her, and a peeved Aang looking back from atop Appa's
                head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Irritably.</charAction> I have an idea! Why don't we all get on your
                <charAction>Points angrily at Sokka; Katara briefly looks at Aang, but resumes her
                stare in front of her.</charAction> back and you could fly us to the North
            Pole?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Back-view of Sokka looking over his shoulder;
                sarcastically.</charAction> I'd love to. <charAction>Points to his
                back.</charAction> Climb on everyone, <charAction>Shakes his rear.</charAction>
            Sokka's ready for take off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A chirping Momo hops on his back, making Sokka shoot an angry glare at the
                animal. Cut back to the shot of Katara and Aang, with the latter still staring
                angrily at Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Waving her hands up and down while shifting looks between Aang and
                Sokka.</charAction> Look, we're all just a little tired and cranky because we've
            been flying for two days straight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal shot, Momo is now on his lap; annoyed.</charAction> And for
            what? We can't even find the Northern Water Tribe. <charAction>Cut to a wide side-shot,
                revealing Appa floating along a vast ocean of only water and ice.</charAction>
            There's nothing up here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara and Aang, with the former having laid down her head in
                boredom, letting it rest on her hands. She looks up in wonder when a slushing sound
                can be heard. Cut to a frontal shot of Appa, while the water in front of him
                suddenly rises and solidifies to ice spikes. Cut to a frontal shot of Aang screaming
                in fright, his eyes wide in horror, as he violently yanks the reins to this right in
                an attempt to avoid the sudden obstacle. Cut to a side-view of a growling and
                turning Appa. Cut to the siblings yelling in fright as they hold on for dear life to
                the sides of the saddle. Cut to a back-shot of a swerving Appa, who suddenly shoots
                up as another ice spike manifests right in from of him. A close-up shot of his
                underside shows that he was not quick enough, and part of the ice attaches itself to
                his leg, freezing instantly. His momentum causes the ice to break, but he is thrown
                off balance and catapulted away. Frontal shot of Katara and Sokka who loudly scream
                in fright. Cut to a wider shot of Appa spiraling toward the camera, before switching
                to an overview shot of him landing into the water, throwing it up high. As he turns
                upright again, the water around him instantly freezes, and he is locked in place.
                Cut to the surrounding ice spikes from which Water Tribe boats appear, each carrying
                several waterbenders, surrounding the team. Cut to a surprised looking Katara and an
                alarmed looking Sokka who is reaching for his boomerang atop the
                saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">They're waterbenders! <charAction>Happily.</charAction> We found the Water
            Tribe!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a more far-off shot of the scene, revealing Appa to be frozen in the
                water, with six Water Tribe boats surrounding him.</description>
      <description>The scene switches to a Fire Navy base in the Fire Nation harbor. The
                camera cuts to inside a guarded tent, where Zhao is standing before a map of the
                Avatar World.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">He's heading north. The Northern Water Tribe. The Avatar needs to master
            waterbending. He's looking for a teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Li">
         <charAction>Impatiently.</charAction> Then what are we waiting for? Let's go get
            him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Patience, Captain Li. This isn't some little Earth village we can just march into.
            The Water Tribe is a great nation. There's a reason they've survived a hundred years of
            war. The frozen tundra is treacherous, the landscape itself is an icy fortress. We'll
            need a massive invasion force.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to the North Pole where the group is being escorted to
                the Northern Water Tribe. The magnificent wall of the city comes into view much to
                everyone's amazement.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Pointing excitedly.</charAction> There it is!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>In awe.</charAction> The Northern Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> We're finally here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A portion of the icy wall is lowered, allowing them to enter into the city.
                Canal workers use waterbending to transport the group into the city.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Fascinated.</charAction> I can't believe how many waterbenders live up
            here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Katara.</charAction> We'll find a master to teach us, no
            problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The team passes through the channels of the city, catching the attention of
                several civilians who run over to spectate them. Aang waves happily at the people.
                As they continue their trek inward, Sokka notices a young lady going by on a boat,
                capturing his attention. He blushes at the sight of her and leaps onto Appa's tail
                as she pulls away from view.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This place is beautiful.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah ... she is ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to nightfall, where Zuko's ship is docked in a port.
                Members of the crew have gathered for music night on the ship. Lieutenant Jee plays
                a lute as Iroh sings. Several other crew members play instruments or
                dance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Singing.</charAction> Winter, spring ... Summer, and fall ... Winter,
            spring ... Summer, and fall ... Four seasons ... four loves ... Four seasons ... for
            love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The music stops as they notice Admiral Zhao boarding the ship, along with
                two soldiers. The crew looks in surprise at the admiral. A high-pitched chord emits
                from the lute. The scene switches back to the Northern Water Tribe, where Team
                Avatar is being honored with a feast, hosted by the tribe's chief. Men play drums
                and a giant crab is set in a pool of water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">Tonight, we celebrate the arrival of our brother and sister from the Southern Tribe.
            And they have brought with them, someone very special, someone whom many of us believed
            disappeared from the world until now ... the Avatar! <charAction>Crowd applauds and
                cheers.</charAction> We also celebrate my daughter's sixteenth birthday. Princess
            Yue is now of marrying age!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Thank you, Father. May the great Ocean and Moon Spirits watch over us during these
            troubled times!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">Now, Master Pakku and his students will perform!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Pakku and two students bend significant blobs of water, captivating Aang
                and Katara. They merge the three blobs into one stream, bending it around each
                other. Yue approaches Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hi there. Sokka, Southern Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Smiling and bowing slightly.</charAction> Very nice to meet you.
                <charAction>They nervously share an awkward silence for a
            moment.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> So ... uhhh ... you're a princess, huh?
                <charAction>She nods and smiles.</charAction> You know, back in my tribe, I'm kind
            of like a prince, myself. <charAction>Shot pans left to reveal
            Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hopping in on the conversation; teasingly.</charAction> Ha, prince of
            what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">A lot of things! Do you mind? I'm trying to have a conversation here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> My apologies, Prince Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, it looks like I'm going to be in town for a while. I'm thinking ... maybe we
            could ... do an activity, together?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Slightly confused; laughs.</charAction> Do an activity?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Embarrassed while sweating, Sokka stuffs food in his mouth. Screens widens
                to the left to show Katara clearly enjoying her brother's attempt at
                courting.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Very smooth ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a long shot of the plaza fountain. In front of it stand the Chief,
                Master Pakku and Aang. Arnook and Aang go to Pakku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">Master Pakku, meet your newest student, the Avatar. <charAction>Aang
                bows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Just because you're destined to save the world, don't expect any special
            treatment.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">My friend and I can't wait to start training with you! After we relax for a couple
            of days.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">If you want to relax, then I suggest visiting a tropical island. If not, I'll see
            you both at sunrise. Good night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back on Zuko's ship. Iroh enters Zuko's room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">For the last time, I'm not playing the tsungi horn!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No, it's about our plans. There's a bit of a problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I'm taking your crew.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to a shocked Zuko.</charAction> What?! <charAction>Turns around to
                face Zhao.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I've recruited them for a little expedition to the North Pole.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle, is that true?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm afraid so. He's taking everyone ... <charAction>Putting his arm over his face in
                woe.</charAction> even the cook.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Sorry you won't be there to watch me capture the Avatar. But I can't have you
            getting in my way again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Cuts to a furious Zuko. Zuko charges at Zhao in anger, but Iroh cuts him
                off.</charAction> No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao notices a pair of swords on the wall. Cut to a close-up of Zhao's
                face, swollen in anger as he recognizes the blades. He flashes back to the Rescue in
                Pohuai Stronghold, where the same swords were wielded by the previously-unknown Blue
                Spirit. He takes one off the wall; cut to Zuko's face, his eyes wide and mouth open,
                clearly recognizing the danger he is in. Iroh, visible over Zuko's shoulder, does
                not. Cut back to Zhao, who begins practicing with the sword he has removed from the
                wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I didn't know you were skilled with broadswords, Prince Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm not. They're antiques. Just decorative.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Have you heard of the Blue Spirit, General Iroh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Just rumors. I don't think he is real.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">He's real, all right. <charAction>He hands the broad sword to Iroh.</charAction>
            He's a criminal, and an enemy of the Fire Nation. But I have a feeling justice will
            catch up with him soon. <charAction>Zhao moves to exit the cabin.</charAction> General
            Iroh, the offer to join my mission still stands ... if you change your mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The next morning, at the Northern Water Tribe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> I've waited for this day my whole life. I
            finally get to learn from a real waterbending master!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Pakku is bending a stream of water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good morning, Master Pakku!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Drops the water, and speaks in an annoyed tone.</charAction> No, please,
            march right in. I'm not concentrating or anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uhhh ... This is my friend, Katara. The one I told you about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I'm sorry, I think there's been a misunderstanding. You didn't tell me your friend
            was a girl. In our tribe, it is forbidden for women to learn waterbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot panning up Katara's body, her face clearly reflecting the
                anger she feels.</description>
      <description>Cut to a long, overhead shot of the Northern Water Tribe city, looking back
                from the main wall to the citadel. Cut back to a close up of Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What do you mean you won't teach me? I didn't
            travel across the entire world so you could tell me no!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But there must be other female waterbenders in your tribe!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Here, the women learn from Yagoda to use their waterbending to heal. I'm sure she
            would be happy to take you as her student, despite your bad attitude.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't want to heal, I want to fight!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I can see that. But our tribe has customs, rules.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Furious.</charAction> Well, your rules stink!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Also just as angry.</charAction> Yeah, they're not fair! If you won't
            teach Katara, then ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Then what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Then I won't learn from you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Well, have fun teaching yourself! I'm sure you'll do a great job.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Wait! Aang didn't mean that! <charAction>Goes to Aang.</charAction> You can't risk
            your training for me. You have to learn from Master Pakku, even if he is a big
            jerk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang nods. Katara exits.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Why don't we get started, then? <charAction>Aang gets hit with a water blast from
                him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In another part of the city. Sokka catches up with Princess
                Yue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Princess Yue, good morning! How about that picnic last night? Boy, your dad sure
            does know how to throw a party.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">I'm happy you enjoyed yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, it wasn't as much fun after you left. <charAction>They both
                blush.</charAction> So, I'm still hoping we can see more of each other.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Do an activity, you mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yes ... at a place ... for some time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> I'd love to. I'll meet you on that bridge tonight.
                <charAction>Points at a bridge.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Great! I'll see you– Ah! <charAction>Falls into the water.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Climbs out of the water.</charAction> That's okay, it was worth it. See
            you tonight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Fire Navy base.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I'm very impressed. You all seem highly qualified for the mission I have in
            mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The pirate captain pulls a small chest toward him and opens it, a dim glow
                radiating from within. Pirate Barker Oh takes a piece of gold from the chest and
                bites down on it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">That's some tasty gold.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pirate captain">What do you need us to do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I believe you're acquainted with Prince Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the Northern Water Tribe, where Katara enters the healing
                hut.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Uhhh ... Hi. Are you Yagoda?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">Are you here for the healing lesson?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks at all the young girls, and speaks in a disappointed
                tone.</charAction> I guess I am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">Welcome ... welcome!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at Pakku's class. Aang is working with a stream of
                water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">You're moving the water around, but you're not feeling the push and pull.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm trying ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">
         <charAction>Slurps some soup.</charAction> Maybe that move is too advanced for you.
            Why don't you try an easier one?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang slams down the water in frustration. Back at the healing hut, Katara
                starts a conversation with Yagoda.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Thanks for the lesson.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">So, who's the lucky boy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">Your betrothal necklace. You're getting married, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Ah ... No. I don't think I'm ready for that yet.
            My grandmother gave my mother this necklace and my mother passed it down to me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">I recognize this carving! I don't know why I didn't realize sooner; you're the
            spitting image of Kanna!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Wait, how do you know my Gran-Gran's
            name?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">When I was about your age, I was friends with Kanna. She was born here in the
            Northern Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">She never told me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">Your grandmother had an arranged marriage with a young waterbender. He carved that
            necklace for her.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">If Gran-Gran was engaged, why did she leave?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yagoda">I don't know. That's always been a mystery to me. She left without saying
            goodbye.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Later that night, at Zuko's ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Crew member">Good luck!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Inside Zuko's room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot of Prince Zuko lying in bed in the foreground of his
                cabin. The door opens and Iroh sticks his head in. Entering.</charAction> The crew
            wanted me to wish you safe travels.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Bitterly.</charAction> Good riddance to those traitors.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It's a lovely night for a walk. Why don't you join me? It would clear your head.
                <charAction>No response.</charAction> Or just stay in your room and sit in the dark.
            Whatever makes you happy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The pirates make their way onto Zuko's ship, bringing up blasting
                jelly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oh">Careful with the blasting jelly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Hearing the noise.</charAction> Uncle? Uncle, is that you?
                <charAction>Walks around the ship.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The fuse to the blasting jelly is lit. The ship explodes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko! <charAction>Runs back to see the ship destroyed.</charAction> Zuko
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the North Pole. Sokka goes to meet Yue, who is looking out over the
                bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hi, Princess Yue. I made you something. I carved it myself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows her a roughly-crafted creature.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">It's a bear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Actually, it's supposed to be a fish. <charAction>Flips the carved creature
                around.</charAction> See, it has a fin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Oh. I'm sorry, I made a mistake. I shouldn't have asked you to come here.
                <charAction>Runs away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka is left stunned. He throws the fish into the water. Cut to the team's
                place of stay.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">How's warrior training going? <charAction>Sokka kicks his bag.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That bad?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, it's Princess Yue. I don't get it, one minute she wants to go out with me, and
            the next, she's telling me to get lost. <charAction>Changing the topic.</charAction> So,
            how's waterbending training?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Master Poophead won't teach her because she's a girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Why don't you just teach her, Aang?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Why didn't I think of that? At night, you can
            teach me whatever moves you learn from Master Pakku! That way, you have someone to
            practice with, and I get to learn waterbending! Everyone's happy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm not happy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But you're never happy. Come on, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Outside, near the water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Bending up some water.</charAction> Master Pakku said this move is all
            about sinking and floating. <charAction>Sends the water to her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Bending the water.</charAction> I got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The water suddenly shoots upward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That was amazing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That wasn't me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Master Pakku has caught them. He takes the water, freezes it, and sticks
                the ice crystals into the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I was just showing Katara a few moves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">You have disrespected me, my teachings, and my entire culture.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sorry, I ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">You are no longer welcome as my student.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The next morning, the three meet with Chief Arnook, Master Pakku, and
                Arnook's family members.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">What do you want me to do? Force Master Pakku to take Aang back as his
            student?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yes ... please!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Arnook">I suspect he might change his mind, if you swallow your pride and apologize to
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I'm waiting, little girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No. <charAction>Begins cracking the ice inadvertently.</charAction> No way am I
            apologizing to a sour old man like you! <charAction>Two pots
            shatter.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uhhh ... Katara?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'll be outside if you're man enough to fight me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yue gasps. Katara angrily walks out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sure she didn't mean that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah, I think she did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Fire Navy base. Zhao meets with Iroh over tea.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I'm devastated to hear about Prince Zuko. Just ... devastated.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">The Fire Lord will not be pleased when he learns who was responsible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">You know who was behind the attack?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yes ... pirates. We had a run-in with them a while back. They wanted
            revenge.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Sips his tea.</charAction> So, have you reconsidered my offer?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Yes, I accept. It will be an honor to serve as your general. To the Fire
            Nation!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">To victory!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the Northern Tribe. The three head outside, looking for
                Pakku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Are you crazy, Katara? You're not going to win this fight!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Takes off her coat.</charAction> I know! I don't care!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You don't have to do this for me. I can find another teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm not doing it for you! Someone needs to slap some sense into that guy!
                <charAction>Pakku comes down.</charAction> So, you decided to show up?
                <charAction>Pakku walks away.</charAction> Aren't you going to fight?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Go back to the healing huts with the other women where you belong.
                <charAction>Katara tightens her fist and sends water whips at him. Pakku
                halts.</charAction> Fine. You want to learn to fight so bad? Study closely!
                <charAction>He bends two streams of water from nearby pools and sends them both at a
                charging Katara, who falls back. He joins the two streams together, encircling both
                Katara and himself in a forceful ring of water.</charAction> Don't worry, I'm not
            going to hurt you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara edges away from the ring and redirects the water away. The resulting
                blast hits Sokka. Pakku builds an ice wall in defense, which Katara slides up. She
                lands onto a nearby post. He melts the ice and directs the full blast at her.
                However, Katara freezes her feet down and is able to direct the blast
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Determined.</charAction> You can't knock me down!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Some of the crowd cheers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Go, Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara charges at him; Pakku draws up a wall of ice, which she quickly
                liquefies. She attempts to land blows, but Pakku ducks them all. He whips water and
                throws her into a pool, earning the approval of other members of the
                crowd.</description>
      <description>Katara emerges from pool, shakes out her hair, and summons a small pillar
                of ice, where she proceeds to send a series of ice discs at her opponent. Pakku
                breaks up most of them using his wrists. The camera closes up to a slow-motion shot
                of one coming very close to hitting him. He looks at her in irritation. Katara, now
                back on the ground, attacks by sending a stream of water at him. However, Pakku
                generates it into a larger stream of water and sends it full force at her. Katara is
                sent back several feet. A close-up shot of her shows her bent over, breathing hard.
                She rises suddenly and sends two snow pillars down at him which Pakku turns to a
                dusty mist of snow. The mist clears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Well, I'm impressed. You are an excellent waterbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But you still won't teach me, will you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara bends over sharply, sending a wave of ice at Pakku, who merely
                raises himself onto an ice pillar. He proceeds to liquefy the pillar, charging
                straight at Katara, who sends a powerful stream of water his way. Pakku avoids the
                attack, instead managing to freeze Katara's stream of water which he slides across.
                He surges past her and strikes her down, knocking her necklace off in the process.
                Katara falls roughly to the ground as Pakku lands onto the rim of a pool, bends a
                tower of water and manipulates the stream overhead his opponent. He deftly freezes
                the water into several ice shards, which he sends down at Katara. She becomes
                trapped in the flurry of frozen daggers and appears still for a moment. The crowd
                gasps in horror; one child looks away in fear. Katara lifts her head and begins to
                struggle, attempting to break free as Pakku casually strolls away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">This fight is over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Come back here. I'm not finished yet!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Yes, you are. <charAction>Notices the necklace.</charAction> This is my necklace
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No, it's not. It's mine! Give it back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I made this sixty years ago for the love of my life ... for Kanna.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Unfreezing the ice; surprised.</charAction> My Gran-Gran was supposed to
            marry you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Fire Navy base. The ships are set to begin the trek north. On
                board, Iroh meets up with Zuko, who is disguised as a shipman.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Our plan is working perfectly. Zhao doesn't suspect a thing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You didn't have to do this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No nephew of mine is going to stow away on a ship without some backup.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Thank you, Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A door opens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Someone's coming. Stay hidden until we get to the North Pole and the Avatar will be
            yours. Good luck. <charAction>The two head their separate ways.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes back to the North Pole.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">I carved this necklace for your grandmother when we got engaged. I thought we would
            have a long, happy life together. I loved her.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But she didn't love you, did she? It was an arranged marriage. Gran-Gran wouldn't
            let your tribe's stupid customs run her life. That's why she left. It must have taken a
            lot of courage.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yue cries and runs away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> Go get her.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka exits. Later that night, he catches up with her on the
                bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">What do you want from me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nothing. I just want you to know, I think you're beautiful, and, I never thought a
            girl like you would even notice a guy like me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">You don't understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, no. See, that's the thing. I think I do understand now. You're a Princess, and
            I'm ... I'm just a Southern peasant.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">No, Sokka ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's okay. You don't have to say anything. I'll see you around, okay?
                <charAction>Yue grabs him and kisses him.</charAction> Okay, now I'm really
            confused. Happy, but confused.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">I do like you, a lot. But we can't be together, and not for the reason you think.
            It's because ... I'm engaged. <charAction>She pulls down the collar of her coat and
                shows him her betrothal necklace.</charAction> I'm sorry. <charAction>Runs
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The next morning, at Pakku's class. Aang turns a blob of water into a
                stream and awkwardly sends it off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">Not bad, not bad. <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Keep practicing and maybe you'll
            get it by the time you're my age.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns around, annoyed, but quickly smiles when he notices Katara
                coming up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hey, Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pakku">What do you think you're doing? <charAction>Pause as Katara looks up.</charAction>
            It's past sunrise. You're late.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good to see you here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You, too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Fire Navy fleet. Zhao and Iroh stand on top of the lead
                ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">My fleet is ready. Set a course for the Northern Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a panning overhead shot, which reveals dozens of Fire Navy ships
                firing up their engines in preparation to launch the final assault on the Northern
                Water Tribe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to white, followed by credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
