<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="40">The Crossroads of Destiny</title>
      <director>Michael Dante DiMartino</director>
      <writer>Aaron Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2006-12-01</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>Ostrich horses are drinking water from a river as Appa, Aang, and Sokka fly
                over them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, what kind of trouble is Katara in?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know. In my vision, I just knew she needed help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It would be nice if your Avatar powers could be just a little more specific from
            time to time. <charAction>He looks down and notices a mound of earth passing nearby,
                heading to the wall.</charAction> What is that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They fly down and follow the mound. Toph is seen still earth surfing. Aang
                and Sokka come down beside her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Need a ride?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph becomes startled at the sound of Sokka's voice and falls backward off
                of the mound. Sokka and Aang cringe upon seeing her fall. Scene changes to Azula
                speaking to the Dai Li.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>While pacing back and forth.</charAction> The Earth King and the Council
            of Five do not trust the Dai Li. They imprisoned your leader, Long Feng. Soon they will
            turn on all of you and eliminate you. Seizing power today is a matter of life and death.
                <charAction>As she talks, an agent with a mustache starts looking nervous and
                slightly lowers his head.</charAction> This coup must be swift and decisive. The
            Earth King and each of the five generals must be taken out simultaneously. Long Feng has
            placed you in my command while we overthrow the government. <charAction>Walks over to
                her left, to another agent with a tiny, vertical scar on his right cheek. When she
                nears him, she stares sideways at the agent while still addressing all the
                agents.</charAction> If I sense any disloyalty, any hesitation, any weakness at all,
                <charAction>She stops right in front of the scarred agent.</charAction> I will snuff
            it out. <charAction>She continues walking, with the eyes of the now nervous scarred
                agent following her.</charAction> That is all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Dai Li leave, and Azula walks up to Ty Lee, who is pouring
                tea.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Nice speech, Azula. It was pretty and poetic, but also scary in a good way.
                <charAction>She hands the cup to Azula. Camera pans over to a close-up of
                Mai.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Amused.</charAction> Yeah. I thought you were going to make that one guy
            pee his pants.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">There are still a few loose ends. The Avatar, and my brother and uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene fades to outside the Royal Palace, where Zuko and Iroh begin walking
                toward it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Many times I imagined myself here, at the threshold of the palace.
                <charAction>Camera pans to show the Earth Kingdom Emblem above the palace
                doors.</charAction> But I always thought I would be here as a conqueror. Instead, we
            are the Earth King's personal guests, here to serve him tea. Destiny is a funny
            thing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It sure is, Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes back to Appa, Toph, Aang, and Sokka still flying back to the
                Palace. Toph is seen holding onto Sokka's arm so she does not fall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">So how did it go with the guru? Did you master the Avatar State?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks down and thinks back to what Guru Pathik said before he
                left.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">If you leave now, you won't be able to go into the Avatar State at all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades back to the present.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm great! It went great with the guru. I completely mastered the Avatar State.
                <charAction>He laughs nervously and looks down.</charAction> Yeah.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes back to the Royal Palace, where Zuko and Iroh are sitting at
                a table in a room, waiting for the Earth King. Iroh pours some tea into a
                cup.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What's taking so long?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Maybe the Earth King overslept.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Dai Li agents begin to circle around the two.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Something's not right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula walks past the Dai Li and comes in front of her brother outside the
                circle of Dai Li agents.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's tea time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He quickly stands up.</charAction> Azula!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Have you met the Dai Li? They're earthbenders, but they have a killer instinct
            that's so firebender. I just love it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera pans over to show Iroh picking up his cup of tea.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Did I ever tell you how I got the nickname "The Dragon of the West"?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I'm not interested in a lengthy anecdote, Uncle. <charAction>She looks at her nails
                condescendingly.</charAction>]</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It's more of a demonstration, really.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh begins drinking his tea. Zuko looks over at him and smiles before
                going behind him. Iroh begins breathing fire. Cut to a corridor outside the room as
                a fire blast makes a hole in the wall, allowing Iroh and Zuko to escape. The Dai Li
                agents begin shooting some rock gloves at them, but miss as Zuko and Iroh turn
                around the corner. Iroh generates lightning and destroys the wall in front before
                jumping down, yelling, into a bush below. Zuko stops at the edge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Come on! You'll be fine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No! I'm tired of running! It's time I faced Azula!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns around and walks back. Iroh smacks his head upon hearing this
                and runs away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You're so dramatic. What? Are you going to challenge me to an Agni Kai?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Yes! I challenge you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">No thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko shoots a fire blast toward her, but two Dai Li agents intervene and
                pull up a section of the floor, making a wall. They shoot some rock gloves at Zuko's
                feet, making him lose his balance. He puts his right hand down, but another rock
                glove traps that one. Azula turns around smiling and walks away as the agents
                capture him. Scene changes to inside the throne room, where Sokka, Toph, and Aang
                confront Kuei. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">Katara's fine. You have nothing to worry about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But, in my vision, I felt so sure she was in trouble.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">Well, she met with the Council of Generals to plan the invasion, and since then, she
            been off with your friends, the Kyoshi Warriors.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">See, Aang? She's with Suki. They're probably back at our apartment right now talking
            about make-up or something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay. Maybe you're right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">Believe me, if there was any danger at all, Bosco's animal instincts would sense
            it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bosco lifts up his head from sleeping to look at the three. Scene changes
                to inside the Crystal Catacombs, where Katara is pacing back and forth. She stops
                pacing upon hearing a hole open up above.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dai Li agent">You've got company.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He throws Zuko in, who rolls down and lands in front of
                Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Zuko!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara's shocked face becomes an angry one as Zuko sits up, looking back at
                her with surprise, and the hole closes behind him. The scene changes to Toph, Aang,
                and Sokka reaching their house on Appa. The three jump off and run inside to see if
                Katara was in there. Momo runs up to them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Momo!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo climbs up Aang onto his shoulders. Toph looks around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">There's no one else here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara is in trouble! I knew it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh, no!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Wait! Someone's at the door. [<charAction>Someone knocks on the door a second
                later.</charAction> Actually, I know who it is. It's an old friend of mine.
                <charAction>She walks over to the door and opens it, showing Iroh behind the
                door.</charAction> Glad to see you're okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I need your help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Aang become shocked and angry upon seeing him, and get into a
                fighting stance. Toph calmly smiles and waves at him. Momo flies away upon seeing
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You guys know each other?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I met him in the woods once and knocked him down. <charAction>Iroh smiles sheepishly
                and rubs the back of his head.</charAction> Then he gave me some tea and some very
            good advice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">May I come in? <charAction>Toph nods, and he walks in before turning to the
                group.</charAction> Princess Azula is here in Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">She must have Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">She has captured my nephew as well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Then we'll work together to fight Azula, and save Katara and Zuko.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Approaching Aang and pointing at him.</charAction> Whoa there! You lost
            me at "Zuko".</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I know how you must feel about my nephew. <charAction>Moving forward to place his
                hands on Sokka's shoulders.</charAction> But believe me when I tell you that there
            is good inside him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pushing Iroh away.</charAction> "Good inside him" isn't enough! Why
            don't you come back when it's outside him too, okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara's in trouble. All of Ba Sing Se is in trouble. Working together is our best
            chance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka understands, and nods. Iroh begins walking back to the
                door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I brought someone along who might help us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all walk outside. Toph puts a couple earth pillars around the nervous
                Dai Li agent and makes him stand up. Iroh walks over to him and takes the gag off
                his mouth, revealing this to be the scarred agent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captured agent">Azula and Long Feng are plotting a coup! They're going to overthrow the Earth
            King!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">My sister! Where are they keeping Katara?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captured agent">In the Crystal Catacombs of Old Ba Sing Se, deep beneath the palace.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh, Aang, Toph, and Sokka run away to help Katara and the Earth King,
                leaving the captured agent bound. Scene fades to the jail where Long Feng is. He
                meditates in his cell while a Dai Li agent informs him of what is going
                on.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Head of the Dai Li">The movements of the Earth King and all the generals have been plotted out
            step-by-step.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Good. And the Fire Nation princess is cooperating?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Head of the Dai Li">Oh, yes. More than cooperating. She's really taken charge. She's terrifying and
            inspirational at the same time. It's hard to explain.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Dai Li agent walks away. Scene changes to inside the Crystal Catacombs,
                where Katara is yelling at Zuko, who sits with his back turned.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Why did they throw you in here? <charAction>Zuko says nothing.</charAction> Oh,
            wait, let me guess. It's a trap. So that when Aang shows up to help me, you can finally
            have him in your little Fire Nation clutches!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns his head to look at her, turns back, and looks at the ground
                again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Continuing to lament.</charAction> You're a terrible person! You know
            that? Always following us! Hunting the Avatar! Trying to capture the world's last hope
            for peace! But what do you care? You're the Fire Lord's son. Spreading war and violence
            and hatred is in your blood!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Looks back at her.</charAction> You don't know what you're talking
            about!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I don't? How dare you! You have no idea what this
            war has put me through! <charAction>Sits down.</charAction> Me personally!
                <charAction>She sits down and touches her necklace, begins to cry.</charAction> The
            Fire Nation took my mother away from me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He turns around to face Katara.</charAction> I'm sorry.
                <charAction>Pauses. Katara is now sobbing.</charAction> That's something we have in
            common.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara looks back, surprised, and wipes away the tears from her eyes. The
                scene changes to Toph feeling the ground below, finding the Crystal
                Catacombs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Well, what'd you know? There is an ancient city down there. But it's deep.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She makes a tunnel through the ground, beginning to lead to the catacombs.
                Sokka is seen thinking of a plan.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We should split up. Aang, you go with Iroh to look for Katara and the angry jerk,
                <charAction>Remembers Iroh is there and places his left hand on Iroh's right
                shoulder.</charAction> no offense.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Shrugging.</charAction> None taken.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">And I'll go with Toph to warn the Earth King of Azula's coup.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Iroh are seen walking through the tunnel down to the Catacombs.
                Iroh is bending a small fire for light, and Aang is earthbending the way
                down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So, Toph thinks you give pretty good advice, and great tea!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">The key to both is proper aging. What's on your mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang earthbends again before replying.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, I met with this guru who was supposed to help me master the Avatar State and
            control this great power, but to do it, I had to let go of someone I love.
                <charAction>He and Iroh stop.</charAction> And I just couldn't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Perfection and power are overrated. I think you were very wise to choose happiness
            and love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Earthbends again.</charAction> What happens if we can't save anyone and
            beat Azula? Without the Avatar State, what if I'm not powerful enough?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I don't know the answer. Sometimes, life is like this dark tunnel. You can't always
            see the light at the end of the tunnel, but if you just keep moving, <charAction>Aang
                earthbends the rocks away one last time. Iroh's fire blows out. He
                smiles.</charAction> you will come to a better place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera pans over a large area of the Catacombs. Scene changes to Toph and
                Sokka climbing the stairs, with Momo flying behind them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">There's General How!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka puts his arm out in front of Toph and pulls her behind a pillar.
                General How continues walking toward the stairs. The Dai Li agents can be seen
                hiding beside the pillars before putting cuffs on his wrists and pulling him down to
                his knees. Another agent drops in front of How.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="How">What's going on here?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dai Li agent">You're under house arrest.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">The coup is happening right now! We've gotta warn the Earth King!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka, Toph, and Momo run to head to the Earth King. One of the generals is
                seen walking when some chains fly up and trap him. General Sung is taken by some
                chains into a dark area. Two other generals are seen in their headquarters when the
                Dai Li toss some chains to circle around their legs and pull them up. Scene changes
                to the throne room, where Toph, Sokka, and Momo have just reached the Earth
                King.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Thank goodness we're in time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">In time for what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Yeah. What are you in time for, <charAction>Cartwheels to Sokka, standing just
                inches from his face.</charAction> cutie?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He begins to sweat and places his hand behind his head in discomfort.
                Nervously.</charAction> Uh, I'm kinda involved with Suki.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Who?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph knocks her away from Sokka with earthbending, in which she flips up
                above them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">They're not the real Kyoshi Warriors!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Kuei gasps, surprised.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Sorry to disappoint you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She shoots some of her daggers at Toph, who uses an earth shield to stop
                them, and kicks the shield to Mai, who jumps over it. However, just as Mai lands,
                Toph brings up another pillar, knocking Mai over. Toph smiles confidently. Ty Lee
                comes up in front of Sokka, laughing. She starts trying to jab him, but he evades
                all of them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Oooh, it's like we're dancing together!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula is seen holding Kuei at flame-point.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Gravely.</charAction> This fight is over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph and Sokka surrender, and Ty Lee chi blocks them. Momo tries flying
                away, but a Dai Li agent traps him with a rock glove. Azula shoves Kuei down the
                steps leading to his throne.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Get them all out of my sight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph, Sokka, Kuei, and Bosco are all taken to prison. Long Feng walks into
                the room, looking grim, with some Dai Li agents behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Now comes the part where I double cross you. Dai Li, arrest the Fire Nation
            princess! <charAction>None of the Dai Li agents move, to Long Feng's
                disappointment.</charAction> I said arrest her! <charAction>Short pause. They still
                do nothing.</charAction> What is wrong with you?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's because they haven't made up their minds. <charAction>Long Feng snaps his head
                toward Azula.</charAction> They're waiting to see how this is going to end.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">What are you talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I can see your whole history in your eyes. You were born with nothing, so you've had
            to struggle, and connive, and claw your way to power. But true power, the divine right
            to rule, is something you're born with. The fact is, they don't know which one of us is
            going to be sitting on that throne, and which one is going to be bowing down.
                <charAction>Long Feng looks worried.</charAction> But I know, and you know.
                <charAction>She sits down on the throne and crosses her legs.</charAction>
            Well?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">
         <charAction>His worried look turns into fright, then into a look of submission. He
                walks up and bows to her</charAction>.] You've beaten me at my own game.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Don't flatter yourself! You were never even a player.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to Zuko and Katara in the Crystal
                Catacombs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">[<charAction>Apologetic.</charAction> I'm sorry I yelled at you before.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It doesn't matter.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's just that for so long now, whenever I would imagine the face of the enemy, it
            was your face.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">My face? I see. <charAction>He touches his scar.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No, no, that's-that's not what I mean. <charAction>Approaches
            Zuko.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's okay. I used to think this scar marked me. The mark of the banished prince,
            cursed to chase the Avatar forever. But lately, I've realized I'm free to determine my
            own destiny, even if I'll never be free of my mark.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe you could be free of it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I have healing abilities.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It's a scar, it can't be healed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Holds up a vial.</charAction> This is water from the Spirit Oasis at the
            North Pole. It has special properties, so I've been saving it for something important.
                <charAction>Moves in front of Zuko.</charAction> I don't know if it would work, but
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara puts one hand on Zuko's scar. Zuko closes his eyes, only to be
                interrupted by Aang and Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks surprised at seeing Zuko alone with Katara. As Katara hugs him,
                he briefly smiles at her, then looks over Katara's shoulder to glare at Zuko. Cut to
                Zuko, who gets a hug from Iroh, and glares back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, I knew you would come. <charAction>She hugs Aang again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle, I don't understand. What are you doing with the Avatar? <charAction>Points to
                Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Saving you, that's what.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko growls and takes one confrontational step in Aang's direction, but
                Iroh stops him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko, it's time we talked. <charAction>To Aang and Katara.</charAction> Go help you
            other friends. We'll catch up with you. <charAction>They walk away, Katara looks back at
                Zuko, who is looking sadly to the side, before moving on.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Hurt.</charAction> Why, Uncle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You're not the man you used to be, Zuko. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> You are
            stronger and wiser and freer than you have ever been. And now you have come to the
            crossroads of your destiny. <charAction>Close-up to Zuko's face.</charAction> It's time
            for you to choose. It's time for you to choose good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko contemplates what his uncle is telling him, he yells as crystals
                grow to encase Iroh. He assumes a fighting position to prepare for the intruders. A
                different shot shows Azula along with two Dai Li agents sliding down from the sides
                of the chamber.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I expected this kind of treachery from Uncle. <charAction>Cut to Iroh, still trapped
                in crystals. Cut to a side shot, where Zuko protects his uncle.</charAction> But
            Zuko, Prince Zuko, you're a lot of things, but you're not a traitor, are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Release him immediately.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's not too late for you, Zuko. You can still redeem yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> The kind of redemption she offers is not for
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Why don't you let him decide, Uncle? <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> I need you,
            Zuko. I've plotted every move of this day, <charAction>Makes a fist.</charAction> this
            glorious day in Fire Nation history, and the only way we win is together. At the end of
            this day, you will have your honor back. You will have Father's love. You will have
            everything you want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zuko, I am begging you. <charAction>Close-up of Zuko's face as he focuses from Azula
                back to Iroh.</charAction> Look into your heart and see what it is that you truly
            want. <charAction>Zuko resumes contemplating.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">You are free to choose.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She gestures at the two Dai Li agents to leave, who earthbend themselves
                out. Azula leaves to follow Aang and Katara. The camera cuts to Zuko multiple times
                as he contemplates his choice. He drops his head. Cut to Aang and Katara running
                through the Crystal Catacombs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We've got to find Sokka and Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An intense shot of blue fire attacks them from behind. Aang stops it using
                earthbending, but the impact forces him backward a few steps. The camera zooms back
                toward Azula, the source of the blast, with smoke trailing from her fingertips.
                Katara uses waterbending to stop another attack, then sends a wave crashing toward
                Azula, who vaporizes the water with firebending. The mist from the vaporized water
                allows Azula to jump onto a crystal and firebend two blasts of blue fire. Together,
                Aang and Katara use waterbending to stop the blasts. Azula finishes her jump by
                landing on a rock pillar. Aang uses earthbending on the pillar, and Azula gasps once
                she notices the pillar crumbling. She jumps off and lands between Katara and Aang.
                She points at both of them, preparing to attack or defend herself.</description>
      <description>An orange fire blast lands in the middle of the standoff, and they look to
                see the source of the fire blast to be Zuko. Zuko looks from Azula to Katara and
                Aang, choosing who to attack. When he looks at Azula, she is glaring back at him. He
                then looks at Aang, who gasps once he realizes Zuko will attack him. Zuko firebends
                at him, and Aang uses airbending to jump away from the blast. Azula smiles at this
                and starts dueling with Katara, and Zuko furiously throws multiple fire blasts at
                Aang. The scene changes to Kuei, Sokka, and Toph in a prison cell. Sokka looks out
                the door's barred window.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">See any Dai Li agents nearby?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nope, all clear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph cracks her knuckles and places her hands against the cell door,
                preparing to metalbend it. Cut to outside the prison cell in the where the door
                crumples and gets thrown away from the doorway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Let's go. <charAction>Sokka grabs the Earth King's hand and follows
                Toph.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">
         <charAction>While being guided by Sokka.</charAction> I'm not leaving without
            Bosco!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Zuko and Aang fighting. Aang airbends the air currents around
                him to make a human-shaped gust of air at Zuko, knocking him down. Aang attacks Zuko
                with more airbending, but Zuko maneuvers around the attacks and gets back up on his
                feet. He fires more blasts at Aang who is clinging on to a rock pillar. Aang jumps
                onto a clump of crystals to avoid the attack. Furious, Zuko summons a greater blast
                of fire. Aang earthbends some crystals to protect him, but the crystals shatter,
                sending Aang flying to another clump of crystals. Zuko uses fire whips to attack
                Aang once again, but Aang jumps to another patch of crystals and Zuko keeps
                attacking.</description>
      <description>Cut to Azula landing on a puddle of water running toward Katara, who sends
                a aharp wave of water at Azula that very nearly hits her face, but cuts her hair
                instead, startling her. Cut back to Zuko, who is still using his fire whips to
                attack Aang, who is now jumping along the cave's ceiling. Aang kicks down a
                stalactite and follows it, using earthbending to increase its impact and sending
                Zuko flying, bouncing off the ground into a small wall of crystals. The scene
                focuses on Azula and Katara. Katara waterbends at Azula, knocking her down. Azula
                slowly gets back up into a fighting stance as Katara encases herself in water. One
                water tentacle captures Azula's hand as she struggles to attack her, and another one
                captures her foot after another failed attack. Katara then lifts Azula up, who yells
                in fear. Zuko frees his sister using firebending to break the tentacles. Azula gets
                up and briefly smiles at Zuko in gratitude, then looks toward the crater Aang had
                created with the stalactite. Aang crawls out, exhausted. Azula runs toward Aang. Cut
                to Zuko and Katara fighting. Katara still has water whips on her hands and Zuko
                starts using his fire whips.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I thought you had changed! <charAction>She grunts.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I have changed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko fires another blast. Cut to Azula and Aang standing opposite each
                other. A closer shot of Azula and Aang as they prepare to fight. Azula uses
                firebending to charge at Aang. Aang earthbends crystals around him into a crystal
                encased armor and charges at Azula. Azula stops, and uses her firebending to break
                Aang's crystal armor and send him flying back into an old building. Cut to Mai, Ty
                Lee, and Bosco in the Earth King's throne room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>To Bosco.</charAction> Come on, it's easy. You just walk on your front
            paws instead of your rear ones. <charAction>She demonstrates.</charAction> Like
            this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, the floor traps Ty Lee's hands, causing  and her feet when they
                touch the ground. Bosco starts clapping. The view changes to reveal Kuei, Toph, and
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> That is a nice trick.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka takes out his boomerang and Toph earthbends a large block of the
                ground in preparation to fight against Mai. The camera zooms toward
                Mai.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Uninterested, knowing she does not stand a chance.</charAction> Just
            take the bear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Bosco.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">
         <charAction>Runs to Bosco.</charAction> Bosco! <charAction>Bosco growls
                happily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes back to Zuko and Azula both fighting Katara. Hopelessly
                outnumbered, Katara gets knocked down. Aang jumps from the old building and earth
                surfs toward Zuko and Azula to stop them from attacking Katara, with a fiercely
                determined look on his face. However, a Dai Li agent appears and jumps in front of
                Aang's surf, sending him flying off. Aang yells as he falls. More Dai Li agents
                gather behind Zuko and Azula. Katara starts regaining her focus and Dai Li agents
                surround her. Katara uses the octopus form to defend herself. Aang stands up in a
                fighting stance, but his determined face quickly turns into one of
                despair.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's too many. <charAction>He looks at Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">
         <charAction>From Aang's memory.</charAction> The only way is to let her go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sorry, Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Closing his eyes, he turns away from Azula and Zuko and earthbends a
                crystal shelter tent. Aang starts meditating. Inside Aang's mind, a giant version of
                himself in the Avatar State, the Avatar Spirit, holds an airbending sphere with a
                normal-sized version of himself in the Avatar State. Back in the crystal shelter,
                Aang enters the Avatar State and the crystal shelter starts glowing, alerting those
                outside. Inside the shelter, Aang opens his glowing eyes and breaks the crystal
                above him. The camera shows Katara looking up to Aang, now rising in to the air,
                with hope. But before Aang can let Katara go and control the Avatar State, a bolt of
                lightning strikes him in the back. Cut to Azula's eyeball watching Aang getting
                struck, before it zooms out to show her smiling menacingly in a lightning summoning
                position with her fingers smoking. The Avatar Spirit lets go of Aang and falls out
                of the plane of existence. As Aang falls down, Katara, tears now falling down her
                face, creates a wave to catch Aang. The wave knocks down the Dai Li agents and Zuko.
                She looks down at Aang's lifeless body and back up with tears in her eyes. Zuko and
                Azula prepare to attack Katara, but a blast of fire stops them. Iroh, the source of
                the blast, jumps down from the wall of the cave and shields Aang and Katara from
                Zuko and Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You've got to get out of here! I'll hold them off as long as I can!
                <charAction>Fires some blasts at Zuko and Azula.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara walks away slowly with Aang's body to a waterfall, and she uses
                waterbending to lift herself and Aang's body up its path. Iroh holds off the Dai Li
                agents, taking blows of earthbending, until after Aang and Katara leave. He submits
                to the Dai Li, who use earthbending to encase him in crystals. Azula is triumphantly
                smirking next to Zuko, both looking at Iroh. Iroh is looking back at Zuko, then
                closes his eyes and turns away. Cut to Bosco, Kuei, Toph, Sokka, Aang, and Katara
                riding on Appa. Appa moans sadly. Cut to a closer shot of Katara placing Aang's body
                on Appa. Katara opens the vial around her neck and uses water healing on Aang's
                wounded back. The rest of Team Avatar, Kuei, and Bosco all look sadly and in
                anticipation. The glowing from the spirit water stops, and Katara starts crying,
                assuming that it was not enough to save Aang. Aang's tattoos glow for a second and
                Aang groans. Katara, overcome with joy that Aang is alive, looks at him, who smiles
                a little, and she holds him closer. Cut to the Earth King's throne room with Azula
                sitting down at the throne with Zuko at her left.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">We've done it, Zuko. It's taken a hundred years, but the Fire Nation has conquered
            Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I betrayed Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">No, he betrayed you. <charAction>She stands up from the throne.</charAction> Zuko,
            when you return home, Father will welcome you as a war hero.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But I don't have the Avatar. What if Father doesn't restore my honor?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">He doesn't need to, Zuko. <charAction>She puts a hand on Zuko's
                shoulder.</charAction> Today, you restored your own honor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko looks turns away, uncertain of himself. Cut to an aerial view of Ba
                Sing Se. Cut to Appa's passengers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">The Earth Kingdom ... has fallen.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans down to show Katara, who sits next to an unconscious Aang,
                and looks up. Appa flies over the walls of Ba Sing Se. Fade to
                credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
