<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="2">The Avatar Returns</title>
      <director>Dave Filoni</director>
      <writer>Michael Dante DiMartino</writer>
      <writer>Bryan Konietzko</writer>
      <date>2005-02-21</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Water. Earth. Fire. Air. Long ago, the four nations lived together in harmony. Then,
            everything changed when the Fire Nation attacked. Only the Avatar, master of all four
            elements, could stop them, but when the world needed him most, he vanished. A hundred
            years passed, and my brother and I discovered the new Avatar, an airbender named Aang.
            And although his airbending skills are great, he has a lot to learn before he's ready to
            save anyone. But I believe Aang can save the world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens onto the yellowing sky as the flare Aang accidentally
                launched in the previous episode soars lazily through the air in the distance. The
                camera pans downward to show the figures of Aang and Katara appearing over the
                horizon. The Southern Water Tribe villagers have gathered in the snow, waiting for
                the duo's return. Cut to a shot of Aang and Katara approaching the village and the
                gathered villagers that stand outside the village walls. The children become
                overjoyed upon seeing Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Village kids">
         <charAction>Joyfully.</charAction> Yay! Aang's back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Some of them run over to him while the others remain cheerful in the crowd.
                The camera pans up from the children to the adults, revealing more stern and
                offended expressions. The children reach Aang and Katara, crowding around him
                gleefully, and Aang responds kindly. Switch to a shot of Sokka, who breaks from the
                line of villagers and steps forward toward Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I knew it! <charAction>Accusingly points a finger
                at Aang as he and Katara draw closer.</charAction> You signaled the Fire Navy with
            that flare! You're leading them straight to us, aren't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Protesting.</charAction> Aang didn't do anything! It was an
            accident.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sheepishly, as Katara glares at Sokka.</charAction> Yeah. We were on the
            ship and there was this booby trap, and, well -- <charAction>Awkwardly rubs his
                head.</charAction> -- we booby-ed right into it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Katara, you shouldn't have gone on that ship!
            Now we could all be in danger!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sorrowfully.</charAction> Don't blame Katara. I brought her there. It's
            my fault.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angry and triumphant, having found an excuse.</charAction> Aha! The
            traitor confesses! Warriors, away from the enemy. <charAction>The children begin to
                sadly walk away.</charAction> The foreigner is banished from our village.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritably, clenching her fists.</charAction> Sokka, you're making a
            mistake.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stubbornly persisting in his anger.</charAction> No, I'm keeping my
            promise to Dad. <charAction>Pointing to Aang.</charAction> I'm protecting you, from
            threats like him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Aang is not our enemy!
                <charAction>Continues in a calm, soothing voice.</charAction> Don't you see? Aang's
            brought us something we haven't had in a long time: fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Fun?! We can't fight firebenders with
            fun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Optimistically.</charAction> You should try it sometime.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Get out of our village!
                <description>Now!</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pleading.</charAction> Grandmother, please.
                <description>Don't</description> let Sokka do this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">
         <charAction>Gravely.</charAction> Katara, you knew going on that ship was forbidden.
            Sokka is right. I think it best if the airbender leaves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Outraged.</charAction> Fine! Then I'm banished, too! <charAction>Drags
                Aang away.</charAction> Come on Aang, let's go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Demanding.</charAction> Where do you think
                <description>you're</description> going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> To find a waterbender. Aang is taking
                me to the North Pole.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confusedly.</charAction> I am? <charAction>Brightening.</charAction>
            Great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Katara! Would you really choose him over your tribe? <charAction>Shows shot of the
                entire Southern Water Tribe.</charAction> Your own family?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A side-view-shot shows that Katara had stopped in her tracks, right between
                Appa and her tribe. Close-up of Katara, who looks down sorrowfully as Aang
                approaches her with a sad look upon his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Understanding.</charAction> Katara, I don't want to come between you and
            your family.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Upset.</charAction> So, you're leaving the South Pole? <charAction>In a
                quieter tone.</charAction> This is goodbye?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks for penguin sledding with me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Still in that quiet tone.</charAction> Where will you go?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Guess I'll go back home and look for the airbenders. <charAction>He places one hand
                on Appa, but is suddenly struck with realization.</charAction> Wow, I haven't
            cleaned my room in a hundred years. Not looking forward to
                <description>that.</description>
         <charAction>He uses his airbending to hop onto Appa's head.</charAction> It was nice
            meeting everyone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically, with arms crossed.</charAction> Let's see your bison fly
            now, <description>air boy.</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Encouragingly.</charAction> Come on Appa, you can do it.
            Yip-yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang flicks the reins, but Appa merely rises and growls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> Yeah, I thought so!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Water Tribe girl">
         <charAction>Runs from crowd to stand next to Katara with tears in her
                eyes.</charAction> Ahhh! <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Aang, don't go! I'll
            miss you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> I'll miss you, too. <charAction>Looks at Katara, who
                frowns back at him, her eyes saddened while her hair loopies sway in the
                wind.</charAction> Come on, boy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa turns and plods away, disappearing over the hill. The young girl sighs
                and trudges back to the village, while Katara remains standing in the snow. Kanna
                walks up to her granddaughter.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">
         <charAction>Consoling tone.</charAction> Katara, you'll feel better after you-
                <charAction>Katara quickly turns around and cuts her off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Rounding on Kanna and interrupting her, her voice full of empassioned
                rage.</charAction> You happy now? <charAction>Gestures in the direction Aang took
                off.</charAction> There goes my <description>one </description>chance at becoming a
            waterbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She marches away furiously, leaving Kanna looking saddened. Meanwhile,
                Sokka coaches the young boys to prepare for battle just outside the
                village.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">All right, ready our defenses! The Fire Nation could be on our shores any moment
            now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Water Tribe boy">
         <charAction>Stopping and dancing around.</charAction> But I gotta ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Authoritatively, a twinge of annoyance in his voice; he points onward,
                ushering the boy in that direction.</charAction> And no
            potty breaks!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to a snowy landscape dotted by several ice formations.
                The camera pans to the right, where Aang and Appa are resting in an ice formation,
                Appa lying lazily on his back in the lower section and Aang resting above him. Appa
                grunts.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sorrowfully.</charAction> Yeah, I liked her too. <charAction>Catches
                sight of Fire Nation ship advancing toward the Southern Water Tribe;
                gasps.</charAction> The village! <charAction>He slides off the ice formation onto
                the ground.</charAction> Appa, wait here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa responds by merely grunting lazily. The scene changes to where Sokka
                prepares for battle inside a Water Tribe tent. He dons gloves, boots, bindings, and
                applies face paint. After necessary preparations, he puts his boomerang away on his
                back.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to Zuko's ship, where servants are seen helping the Fire
                Nation prince to put on his Fire Nation outfit, complete with a red helmet ending in
                a sharp point. Through all this, Zuko never moves a muscle.</description>
      <description>Cut back to Sokka kneeling inside the tent, grabbing his club. He glances
                at a candle that flickers as he exits.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to an overhead shot of the village, the camera panning
                upward to the low-stooping wall surrounding the town. Sokka is seen standing atop
                the wall, overlooking the foggy horizon. Cut back to a shot of the village where a
                mother is seen squatting beside her child, but she suddenly jerks up upon hearing a
                loud, cracking noise. Her son gasps for air and the surrounding villagers also turn
                around in fright to see what the source of the noise was. Kanna, sitting on a log by
                a camp fire, rises and gasps for air. Suddenly, the ground begins to quake and a
                rumbling sound is heard in the distance. Kanna gasps louder this time and her face
                contorts in horror. Switch to a shot of Sokka's feet where bits of the wall are
                cracking and breaking off. A mother carrying her child slowly backs away in fright.
                A watchtower on the wall is shaking under the pressure of the trembling, and
                completely collapses.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disappointed at the tower's collapse.</charAction> Oh man!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of inside the village where the citizens are beginning to
                flee from the scene. Katara runs up and looks up at her brother still standing atop
                the wall, and her look turns to one of horror. Cut to a shot of the wall from her
                perspective; an enormous shadow of the bow of Zuko's ship comes into view. Camera
                closes in on Sokka's face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Horrified.</charAction> Oh maaan ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A side-view of the ship approaching the village, cutting through the icy
                sea. Switch to a shot of Kanna standing in the snow, looking up in terror at the
                vessel while backing up slightly. Villagers pass her in their haste to get to safety
                and the shadow of the large ships descends over her. Cut to a close-up of the ship's
                bow as it plows through the snowy shores, splintering the ground. Sokka looks up,
                terrified by the large ship. The ship's approach creates a large crack that quickly
                travels toward the village and over the wall. Cut to Katara helping her grandmother
                into a tent, when she hears a frightened scream. She gasps in terror when she
                realizes that the sound came from a small boy, kneeling on the ground. The fissure
                is rapidly approaching him, but Katara quickly runs over and scoops up the child
                before the ground splinters underneath. She sets the child down again in front of a
                tent which he quickly enters, and Katara turns back to view her
                brother.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hysterically.</charAction> Sokka, get out of the way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Sokka standing on the wall, the bow of the ship plowing
                through the snow. Sokka raises his club in defense, ready to strike. Before he can
                make his move, however, the bow crumbles a large portion of the wall into snowy
                ruins. The snow slides downward, pushing Sokka several feet back before he lands to
                a halt. With a loud hiss of steam, the ship has come to a halt as well. Switch to an
                overview shot of the entire village.</description>
      <description>Cut back to the villagers, who now curiously come out of hiding and are
                staring in complete shock at the large vessel. The camera pans to the right toward
                Katara, who is looking at the ship with her mouth open; she gasps. Sokka also gasps
                when he catches sight of the bow of the ship opening and creaking forward in a burst
                of steam, forming a walkway. He backs up and falls to the ground once the bow hits
                the ground with a loud thud. The villagers gather closer around for support and
                several people even cover their eyes. Katara takes a step back upon noticing the
                shape of three figures cloaked in the mist.</description>
      <description>Cut to the top of the walkway, where Prince Zuko emerges from the mist, two
                guards following close behind him. Cut to the villagers huddled together and Sokka,
                who kneels in the snow in front of them, ready to defend his tribe. The camera cuts
                to shot of the top of the walkway and pans downward. Prince Zuko descends from the
                ship along with the two guards. Sokka lets out a battle cry and charges at the
                prince with his club to the ready. Switch to a side-view of the walkway, where now
                even more soldiers trudge down while Sokka is traveling his way upward. When he
                reaches Zuko, the prince merely kicks the club to his left and, without ever resting
                his leg on the ground, kicks Sokka over to his right, sending him into the snow,
                where his head becomes trapped. The warrior desperately tries to free himself as
                Zuko continues on his way to the village, followed by six more men. Katara covers
                her mouth in shock upon witnessing her brother's quick defeat.</description>
      <description>Shift to a shot of the villagers, as Zuko and his men stand before them.
                Zuko approaches. He passes to the right when he does not seem to find what he is
                looking for and stops in front of Katara, who is clutching Kanna.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Where are you hiding him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko surveys the crowd of villagers, who fall completely silent. Without
                warning, he extends his arm out into the crowd and grabs Kanna, holding her by the
                hood of her parka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shaking Kanna; annoyed.</charAction> He'd be about this age, master of
                all elements?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He shoves Kanna forcefully back into the crowd. The elderly woman shudders
                in fear and embraces Katara, while Katara shoots an angry glare at Zuko. Receiving
                no response, Zuko swings his arm out and releases an arc of fire that passes just
                over the heads of the people, causing them to cover their heads and cry out in
                fear.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I know you're hiding
            him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Sokka's club lying in the snow. Sokka runs over and picks
                it up, most of his war paint having come off at this point. He lets out another
                battle cry as he charges toward the prince. Cut to a shot of Zuko, his back facing
                the camera. He swiftly turns around just as Sokka approaches. He ducks under Sokka's
                wide swing and hurls the warrior forward. Sokka lands on his rear in the snow and is
                quickly forced to dart from his spot when Zuko fires a blast at him. He spins to the
                side and tosses his boomerang at the enemy who barely manages to miss getting hit by
                the weapon. Zuko growls and glares at Sokka in anger at the near hit; he follows the
                course of the weapon until it vanishes before looking back at Sokka in anger. One of
                the village boys tosses Sokka a spear.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Village boy">Show no fear!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka handily catches the weapon and charges at Zuko once more. The camera
                cuts to a shot from Sokka's perspective as he faces him head-on. Zuko breaks of
                pieces of the spear with his forearms, pulls the remains of the weapon out of
                Sokka's hands and pokes him thrice in the head with the blunt end. Sokka falls to
                the ground as Zuko snaps the spear in two and tosses the pieces to the ground on
                both of his sides. Cut to shot of Sokka, who rubs his head in pain, before switching
                back to a head shot of Zuko. A sparkle of light shines briefly in the distance and
                Sokka's boomerang spins into view, unnoticed by Zuko. The weapon strikes Zuko on the
                back of his helmet with a loud cling; he is momentarily pushed forward by the
                unexpected blow. Zuko rearranges his helmet and growls at Sokka. The boomerang has
                plummeted into the ground in front of Sokka's feet. Enraged, Zuko readies two fire
                daggers.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of Aang, who is seen rapidly riding on a penguin toward the
                battle scene. He holds his glider horizontal on the animal and he has a determined
                look on his face. His tongue is out of his mouth in pure concentration. Cut to shot
                of Zuko's backside. The camera closes in on Zuko as Aang takes his feet out from
                underneath him, tossing Zuko off his feet; speeding past, Aang soars into the air as
                the prince lands on his face, his legs in the air. He spins around a few times
                before coming to a halt in front of his men, his helmet landing on his rear as they
                watch.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of cheering villagers, as Aang rides speedily toward them,
                still mounted on the penguin. Cut to shot of the children, who cheer upon his
                arrival. They are showered in snow as Aang rides past, however, after giving each
                other silent, unamused looks for a few seconds, they begin cheering once again,
                shaking the snow off. Switch to a shot of a group of several other villagers,
                including Kanna, Katara, and Sokka. Aang comes to a halt before them. The penguin
                crawls out from under him, tossing him off. Aang falls on his rear, blinking
                stupidly. Aang smiles at the penguin when the animal quacks at him before waddling
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cheerfully, despite the present situation.</charAction> Hey, Katara.
            Hey, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Moodily.</charAction> Hi, Aang. Thanks for coming.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks back at the Fire Nation soldiers, where Zuko just got back on
                his feet again. Upon his signal, his men spread out, surrounding Aang while Zuko
                assumes a fighting stance. Shift to an overhead shot of Aang assuming a fighting
                stance as well, his staff held firmly in front of him as he is being surrounded by
                the soldiers. He sweeps the ground side-to-side with his staff, showering the men
                with snow. He subsequently slams the ground, sending a rush of snow at Zuko who
                braces for the impact. After being sprayed with snow, and heating it up so it would
                melt off, Zuko looks up angrily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Looking for me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You're the airbender? You're the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang resumes his fighting stance. Switch to a close-up of the
                siblings.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Aang?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Bewildered.</charAction> No way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Overview shot of Zuko and Aang moving about in a circular pattern, both
                awaiting the attack of the other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I've spent years preparing for this encounter. Training, meditating.
                <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You're just a child!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Calmly, tilting his head to one side with a somewhat confused
                expression.</charAction> Well, you're just a teenager.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko launches a series of fire blasts at Aang in anger at the remark, who
                defends himself by twirling his staff, dissipating the flames. Cut to overhead shot
                of the area, Zuko attacking Aang, the villagers watching directly behind him. Zuko
                fires another blast at Aang, who twirls his staff once again to ward the attack off.
                Cut to a shot of the villagers, who cower as the flames stream through the air over
                their heads. Aang widens his eyes in horror at the sight of the frightened villagers
                and immediately ceases to defend himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">If I go with you, <charAction>He holds his staff in front of him as an offer, making
                sure Zuko understands that he does not wish to continue fighting.</charAction> will
            you promise to leave everyone alone?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a side-view of the area, Zuko's men still surrounding
                him, spears poised. After a brief moment of hesitation, Zuko erects himself and nods
                in agreement. Aang is apprehended by Zuko's men, who take his staff. Katara runs
                forward as they lead Aang away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> No! Aang, <description>don't</description> do
            this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprisingly calm.</charAction> Don't worry, Katara. It'll be okay.
                <charAction>He gasps when he is shoved on the walkway. Katara's face contorts with
                sadness and fright.</charAction> Take care of Appa for me until I get back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Boarding the ship up the walkway. Determined.</charAction> Head a course
            for the Fire Nation. I'm going home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the villagers looking up at the ship, Aang standing at the
                top of walkway. Switch to a more up-close shot of him smiling weakly, surrounded by
                Fire Nation soldiers. Cut to shot of Katara who looks up, tears in her eyes, before
                changing back to a shot of Aang who now frowns as the bow rises and closes. The
                screen blacks out as the bow is locked into place with a thud.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to later in the day; an overview shot of the village
                reveals the wreckage the ship, now gone, has left behind. A woman drops a pile of
                firewood onto the ground next to a camp fire in a rather melancholy manner. Several
                villagers surround the collapsed wall, surveying the damage and trying to repair the
                collapsed watch tower by digging it out. Several others work together to help put up
                a fallen tent. Cut to shot of the Southern shores where Katara is standing on the
                edge in the distance. The camera closes in on where she is standing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sokka is seen in the background, carrying a pack as she speaks on a
                determined tone.</charAction> We have to go after that ship, Sokka. Aang saved our
            tribe, now we have to save him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Katara, I --</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Making arm gestures to emphasize her words while she speaks in an
                objective tone.</charAction> Why can't you realize that he's on our side?
                <charAction>Cuts to shot of her and her brother, her back to the
                screen.</charAction> If we don't help him, no one will. I know you don't like Aang,
            but we owe him and --</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cutting her off.</charAction> Katara! <charAction>Slightly
                annoyed.</charAction> Are you gonna talk all day, or are you comin' with
            me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka gestures to a canoe floating in the water. Katara immediately grins
                and gasps in happiness.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Running over to her brother.</charAction> Sokka! <charAction>She gives
                him a hug.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Inviting.</charAction> Get in, we're going to save your
            boyfriend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> He's not my --</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shrugging, nonchalant.</charAction> Whatever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">
         <charAction>Accusingly.</charAction> What do you two think you're doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two siblings turn around, look at her and try to act as innocently as
                possible; Sokka grins broadly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">
         <charAction>Smiling warmly.</charAction> You'll need these. <charAction>Kanna holds
                up their sleeping bags.</charAction> You have a long journey ahead of you.
                <charAction>The siblings glance at each other in surprise. Kanna walks over to face
                Katara.</charAction> It's been so long since I've had hope, but you brought it back
            to life, my little waterbender. <charAction>Hugs Katara and who at the end takes the
                sleeping back out of her hands; to Sokka.</charAction> And you, my brave warrior, be
            nice to your sister.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Kanna hugs Sokka, who, slightly embarrassed, pats her back.</charAction>
            Yeah, okay Gran. <charAction>He smiles broadly when she releases
            him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kanna">Aang is the Avatar. He's the world's only chance. You both found him for a reason.
            Now your destinies are intertwined with his.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two siblings look at each other uneasily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pointing at the ready canoe.</charAction> There's no way we're going to
            catch a warship with a <description>canoe.</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans up to reveal Appa appearing over an icy hill on the
                horizon. He makes his presence known by growling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Brightly.</charAction> Appa! <charAction>Begins running toward the
                bison.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> You just looove taking me out of my comfort zone,
            don't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes, showing a side-view of Zuko's ship as it makes its way
                through the icy waters. Aang, Zuko, Iroh and some of Zuko's men are standing on
                deck. Aang's hands are bound behind his back while Zuko holds Aang's
                staff.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">This staff will make an excellent gift for my father. <charAction>Inspects the staff
                further.</charAction> I suppose you wouldn't know of fathers, being raised by monks.
                <charAction>To his soldiers.</charAction> Take the Avatar to the prison hold,
                <charAction>Handing the staff to Iroh.</charAction> and take this to my
            quarters.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh takes the staff and looks at it for a moment while Zuko walks
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Turns to one of Zuko's men and gives him the staff;
                casually.</charAction> Hey, you mind taking this to his quarters for me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The firebender accepts the staff and Iroh walks away. Aang is pushed
                forward by two of the soldiers and he grunts as they roughly shove him ahead. A
                side-view shows how Aang is being taken below while Iroh and the firebender carrying
                Aang's staff are walking toward a door leading to the upper decks. A close-up of
                Aang as his group begins descending a staircase leading to compartment beneath the
                deck. Cut to a shot from Aang's point of view as he descends the staircase, the
                outside world disappearing from view. He tries to keep an eye on his staff for as
                long as possible.</description>
      <description>The scene switches for a moment to an overview shot of the ship as it makes
                its way through the water, flanked by large icebergs, before changing back to the
                cuffed Aang walking through a corridor on the lower deck. He walks down a corridor,
                one soldier before him, one following after him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slyly.</charAction> So, I guess you've never fought an airbender before.
            I bet I could take you <description>both </description>with my hands tied behind my
            back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Firebender">
         <charAction>Unamused.</charAction> Silence.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The party stops and Aang observes the soldier in front of him preparing to
                unlock a door. As the guard in front of him begins to unlock the cell, Aang inhales
                deeply and unleashes a powerful breath, stunning both of them. The firebender before
                him slams into the door subsequently knocked out from the impact. Aang is sent
                several feet back, slamming into the guard behind him. They both fly back even
                further, where they crash into the stairs. The soldier behind Aang is also knocked
                out by the impact, while Aang propels himself onto the deck and kicks open a door
                using airbending. He quickly runs down the hallway, panting heavily. He tosses a
                frightened look over his shoulder, afraid that he is being followed. Cut to a shot
                of the helmsman overlooking the deck. A soldier emerges from the lower deck and
                addresses him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Firebender">The Avatar has escaped!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The helmsman immediately turns around and runs off the
                screen.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to on overview shot of the seas where Katara and Sokka
                sit atop Appa, who still has not gone airborne, but is instead swimming in the
                water. The camera moves closer and Appa growls. Katara is sitting on top of Appa's
                head, while Sokka rests in the saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Unamused.</charAction> Go. Fly. <charAction>Katara glances annoyed at
                her brother.</charAction> Soar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pleading as Appa growls again.</charAction> Please, Appa. We need your
            help. Aang needs your help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Blandly.</charAction> Up. Ascend. Elevate.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka doesn't believe you can fly, but I do, Appa. <charAction>Strokes
                Appa.</charAction> Come on, don't you want to save Aang? <charAction>Appa
                grunts.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What was it that kid said? Yee-haw? Hup-hup? Wah-hoo? Uh ... Yip-yip?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka startles at the sudden movement that last command brought with it as
                it seemingly prompts Appa. Cut to a shot of his head bobbing in the water as he
                grunts and beats the water with his tail. After what appears to be a brief running
                start, he takes flight and soars through the air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Thrilled.</charAction> You did it, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Ecstatically looking over the rim of the saddle.</charAction> He's
            flying! He's flying! Katara, he's -</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Katara, who smirks at her brother. Seeing this, Sokka tries
                to play it cool.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> I mean, big deal. He's flying.
                <charAction>Brightens quickly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows a shot of Appa rising higher into the sky.</description>
      <description>The scene changes back to the Fire Nation ship, where Aang is frantically
                running through the corridors. He stops in his tracks and yells when he encounters
                three soldiers standing with swords drawn in the middle of the
                corridor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You haven't seen my staff around, have you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The three men prepare to attack him, but before they can make a move, Aang
                sprints across the hallway at the speed of wind, along the floor and the walls,
                spiraling in circular patterns past the soldiers, through their legs, and manages to
                escape, leaving the soldiers looking dumbfounded.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Off camera.</charAction> Thanks anyway!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He continues racing through the hallways of the ship and encounters a
                single guard when he rose another deck. The soldier fires a blast at Aang, who leaps
                forward. A slow-motion shot depicts Aang somersaulting over the soldier and using
                the sharp tip of his helmet to cut his bindings, thus freeing him. The soldier falls
                over from the impact and Aang proceeds down the hall. The young Avatar races through
                the interior, opening two doors leading to various compartments of the ship. Upon
                opening the third door, he finds Iroh sleeping blissfully, snoring. He begins
                closing the door, his mouth still visible through the crack.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Sorry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the interior of another room, the entranceway open wide. Aang is
                seen running past the doorway only to slow down and trace his way back upon catching
                sight of his glider. Close-up of his face that brightens upon recognition of the
                object, and he dashes through the open door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">My staff!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang enters the room, the door closing behind him. Cut to the interior of
                the room, where Zuko stands by the door, having clearly waited to corner Aang. Aang
                looks surprised upon hearing the sound of the closing door. He turns around, his
                face falling upon seeing the prince standing in the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Looks like I underestimated you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>After a slight pause, Zuko assumes a fighting stance and fires a blast at
                Aang, who yells and narrowly avoids the attack. Zuko fires again, forcing Aang into
                the corner of the room. Cut to Aang, who pants heavily from alarm. Zuko fires once
                more; Aang spins around out of the corner and against the back wall. He ducks to
                avoid another fire blast. Cut to Zuko standing in the middle of the room, Aang
                managing to roll over directly behind his opponent. Aang deftly manages to stay
                behind Zuko, utilizing circle-walking. Zuko spins around, desperately attempting to
                land a blow.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the deck and cabin of the ship, the window of
                the room where the battle is occurring illuminating two consecutive times from the
                fire blasts. Cut back to inside the room, where Aang uses airbending to try and
                deter another one of Zuko's attacks by catching his flames in a current of air.
                After extinguishing yet another one of his attacks, Aang uses Zuko as a stepping
                stone. He pushes himself off against his head and creates an air scooter in mid-air
                that he uses to ride around the room and over the walls and ceiling, as Zuko resumes
                attacking.</description>
      <description>He avoids Zuko's repeated attacks; however, the prince manages to dissipate
                the air scooter by shattering it with a flame arc. Aang is smacked against the wall
                underneath a hanging tapestry. He quickly pushes himself up under the tapestry to
                avoid another fire blast. When he emerges at the top, he grabs the tapestry off its
                hooks and wraps it around Zuko's body, tangling him momentarily. This brief
                intermission gives Aang enough time to grab his glider and he turns around to face
                his opponent, pointing the end of the staff at Zuko, who destroys the tapestry with
                firebending. Zuko assumes a fighting stance, while Aang looks on with alarm. Cut to
                shot of the entire room, as Aang uses airbending to propel a mattress lying in a
                corner toward Zuko. The mattress slams into the Fire Nation prince, sending him
                colliding into the wall, before falling onto the mattress. Aang propels the mattress
                upward, sending Zuko slamming into the ceiling of the room. Aang makes a break for
                it before the mattress touches the ground again. Zuko and the mattress fall to the
                floor, and Zuko remains lying face down upon it. Cut to shot of Zuko, who raises his
                head and glances around the empty room, fuming.</description>
      <description>Cut to the main control room of the ship. The wheel of the hatch located
                toward the back of the room begins spinning rapidly. The hatch opens with a small
                tornado of air and Aang emerges. Cut to a shot of the rest of the control room, a
                man at the helm. Cut to Aang, who leaps from the hatch and runs across the room,
                leaping over a table and past the man who looks up in surprise. He exits the room
                and runs onto the upper deck of the ship. Cut to an overhead shot of the upper deck
                as Aang happily spreads his arms and welcomes the fresh air. He throws his staff
                over the balcony which opens into a glider and begins soaring away. He appears
                successful until Zuko appears on screen, leaping forward, his arms extended outward.
                While yelling, Zuko manages to grab hold of Aang's ankle. Cut to shot of Aang, whose
                expression of triumph turns into one of despair as he begins losing altitude,
                struggling to maintain the weight of the extra, unexpected person.</description>
      <description>The two plummet down to the lower deck of the ship and land with a crash.
                They bounce a few times before coming to a halt. Aang's glider closes again to a
                staff. Both lie on the deck for a moment. Close-up of Zuko's eyes, as they narrow in
                anger. Zuko begins rising, a look of persistence on his face. Aang rises and assumes
                a fighting stance, looking very unsure of himself. Before the fight could begin,
                Appa's growl distracts both fighters. Aang averts his gaze and catches sight of Appa
                heading toward the ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> What is that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of Appa, Katara and Sokka mounted on his
                saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Ecstatic.</charAction> Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He turns around to face Zuko and manages to deflect a firebending attack by
                spinning his glider around like a baton. However, he propels himself by accident
                into the air and lands on the ledge of the deck. He leans precariously over the
                side, unsteadily balancing himself, but manages to regain his balance only for Zuko
                to fire another blast at him. He twirls his glider again to deflect the attack. Two
                more blasts are fired his way before he loses his grip on his glider and the object
                spins away. The staff falls several feet away. Aang ducks, spins and leaps out of
                the way of blasts and lands on the very ledge, struggling to keep his balance. Zuko
                hurls more fire blasts his way. Aang holds up his hands in defense, but the last
                blast seemingly knocks him out cold and he falls backward off the ship into the
                water, where he slowly sinks. Cuts to shot of Katara riding atop Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Horrified.</charAction> Aang! No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Aang, as he sinks further underwater.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Aang! Aang! Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to close-up of Aang, his eyes closed, seemingly unconscious. Suddenly
                his eyes open, glowing a bright white, along with his arrow tattoos, and he frowns
                angrily. He steadies himself in the water and begins swiveling around, a waterspout
                forming around him. He rockets upward and erupts from the surface, riding a
                humongous spinning water vortex.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Zuko's ship being overshadowed by the waterspout. Switch
                to a bird's-eye view of the deck, Aang appearing on screen atop the vortex. Zuko
                looks up in horror. Cut to a shot of the upper deck as Aang lands, summoning the
                water behind him. Camera closes up on him, his eyes and tattoos still glowing, as he
                brings his hands around behind his head. The water swirls around him, forming a
                protective circle, before spreading outward, knocking Zuko and several soldiers off
                their feet. Cut to a shot of the side of the ship as Zuko falls over the edge and
                shouts in surprise. Switch to Sokka and Katara leaning over the side of Appa's
                saddle watching in shock.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Did you see what he just did?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Impressed.</charAction> Now that was some
            waterbending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Aang on the deck, as he collapses onto the ground from
                exhaustion, his eyes and tattoos ceasing to glow. Appa growls and lands on the deck.
                Katara and Sokka slide down and quickly run toward the unconscious
                Avatar.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> Aang! Are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She kneels down, holding Aang with Sokka following close
                behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> Hey, Katara. Hey, Sokka. Thanks for
            coming.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, I couldn't let you have all the glory.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> I dropped my staff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Rising.</charAction> Got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka runs over, grabs a hold of the glider and lifts it only to see Zuko's
                hand firmly gripping the other end. Sokka appears horrified as Zuko attempts to pull
                himself upward onto the deck. The two struggle for a bit before Sokka pokes Zuko
                repeatedly in the head with the end of the staff the way Zuko did earlier with him.
                Zuko grunts and falls backward as he lets go of the staff. He falls off the side of
                the ship, but manages to grasp the anchor chain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Triumphantly.</charAction> Ha! That's from the Water Tribe!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches over to Appa, who rises from a puddle of water after
                Katara helped Aang to climb atop his head. Katara still stands beside the large
                beast while Aang lies on top of his head. Cut to three soldiers, who rise after
                being knocked down by Aang's water attack and menacingly approach her. Katara takes
                a step back and slowly and precariously bends a stream of water from the puddle,
                causing the men to slow down and gasp in surprise. She swings her arms around in an
                attempt to whip them, however, only succeeds in freezing a channel of water behind
                her on the deck, encasing Sokka's legs in ice in the process.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Complaining.</charAction> Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldiers resume their approach. Katara turns around, her back facing
                them and draws another stream of water. She closes her eyes tightly, swings her arms
                behind her and turns around to see one of the soldiers completely frozen in a casing
                of ice, his arm extended outward to her, still twitching in effort to grab her. She
                backs away slowly, but turns around and quickly runs toward Appa. She begins
                mounting Appa, while Sokka is trying to cut himself free by smashing his icy chains
                with his boomerang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Urgently.</charAction> Hurry up, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Muttering to himself, as he uses his boomerang to chip the
                ice.</charAction> I'm just a guy, with a boomerang. <charAction>He frees his left
                foot.</charAction> I didn't ask for all this flying and
                <description>magic!</description>
         <charAction>He manages to break free and races up Appa's tail.</charAction> Yip-yip!
            Yip-yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka mounts Appa, who grunts and takes flight, flying past the cabin of
                the ship. Iroh emerges on deck, having just woken up from a nap.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Rubbing eyes and staring up at Appa in surprise.</charAction> Duh?
            Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Appa, who soars away from the ship, while Iroh helps Zuko, grunting
                angrily with effort, to heft himself back onto the deck.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Shoot them down!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overview shot of Appa gaining altitude before switching back to
                Zuko and Iroh standing on deck. Together, they synchronize a firebending move and
                fire a powerful blast at the bison. Sokka and Katara stare at the incoming attack in
                horror, while Aang leaps onto the saddle. He opens the small tail wing of his staff
                and swings his glider around, using a powerful swipe of air to redirect the fireball
                into a nearby cliff side. The impact causes an avalanche of snow and ice to begin
                falling. Cut to Zuko, who looks up in horror at the event, raising one arm
                protectively. The front of the ship becomes buried in a mass of snow and ice, while
                Appa climbs higher and higher. Switch to a scene of the trio, who laugh as they
                escape successfully. Aang waves goodbye as Appa disappears around the
                cliff.</description>
      <description>Switch to an overview shot of the ship with its bow stuck in the ice.
                Close-up of Zuko, who is seen bending over in rage on the deck with Iroh erecting
                himself in the background. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Good news for the Fire Lord. The Fire Nation's
            greatest threat is just a little kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko lifts his head and rises while his uncle is speaking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Holding back rage.</charAction> That "kid", Uncle, just did
                <description>this.</description>
         <charAction>Cuts to a shot of the damaged ship, the whole front covered in ice and
                snow.</charAction> I won't underestimate him again. <charAction>Yells his order to
                the soldiers and points at the piles of snow.</charAction> Dig the ship out and
            follow them!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shift to a shot of three Fire Nation soldiers using their firebending to
                melt the icy encasings coating the three soldiers who were Katara's
                victims.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Slightly embarrassed.</charAction> As soon as you're done with
            that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera closes up on Zuko eyes as he looks up in anger and
                determination.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to an overview shot of the clouds. Cut to a side-view of
                Appa, who soars lazily in the sky while the sun is beginning to set. Aang is perched
                on the rim of the saddle, while Sokka and Katara sit at the back of
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Bewildered.</charAction> How did you do that?! With the water? It was
            the most amazing thing I've ever seen!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Quietly, slightly downcast, sitting on the edge of the
                saddle.</charAction> I don't know. I just sort of ... did it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Curious, but serious.</charAction> Why didn't you tell us
                you were the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Because ... <charAction>Turns away slightly; saddened.</charAction> I never wanted
            to be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the entire team sitting on Appa's saddle, as a dark cloud
                passes overhead, shadowing their figures. Cut to a wider shot of Appa flying in the
                sky, shafts of sunlight streaming through the clouds. Switch back to a closer shot,
                showing Aang in front, looking downcast over the side with Sokka and Katara in the
                background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But Aang, the world's been waiting for the Avatar to
            return and finally put an end to this war.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Downcast.</charAction> And how am I going to do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">According to legend, you need to first master water, then earth, then fire,
            right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at Katara.</charAction> That's what the monks told me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Brightening a bit.</charAction> Well, if we go to the North Pole, you
            can master waterbending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turning to face her, smiling and brightening up completely.</charAction>
            We can learn it together!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Faces her brother; cheerfully.</charAction> And Sokka, I'm sure you'll
            get to knock some firebender heads on the way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Content.</charAction> I'd like that. I'd
                reeally like that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Optimistically.</charAction> Then we're in this together!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cheerfully, pulling out a rolled up scroll.</charAction> All right, but
            before I learn waterbending, we have some serious business to
            attend to. <charAction>He uses airbending to situate himself onto the saddle and unrolls
                the scroll, revealing a map of the Avatar World.</charAction> Here, here and
            here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While stating this, he points to three locations, two in the Earth Kingdom,
                one in Air Nomad territory.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Curiously.</charAction> What's there? <charAction>Points to one of the
                locations.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Points to the location in Earth Kingdom.</charAction> Here, we'll ride
            the hopping llamas. <charAction>Points to the location in Air Nomad
                territory.</charAction> Then waaay over here, we'll surf on the backs of giant koi
            fish. <charAction>Katara and Sokka stare at him in wonder.</charAction> Then back over
            here, we'll ride the hog monkeys. <charAction>The siblings glance at each
                other.</charAction> They don't like people riding them, but that's what makes it
            fun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Aang, as he smiles enthusiastically, his eyes widened with
                excitement. Cut to a wide shot of Appa flying peacefully in the sky, sunbeams
                breaking through the clouds behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
