<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="31">The Desert</title>
      <director>Lauren MacMullan</director>
      <writer>Tim Hedrick</writer>
      <date>2006-07-14</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shows a wide-view of the desert. Team Avatar looks in every
                direction over the vast ocean of sand for Appa. The camera halts as Aang and Toph
                come into view. Aang turns around to face Toph angrily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Enraged.</charAction> How could you let them take Appa?! ‌ Why didn't
            you stop them‌?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Aang's angry face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Defensively.</charAction> I couldn't! The library was sinking! You guys
            were still inside and-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang interrupts Toph as he walks over to her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Still enraged.</charAction> You could've come to get us. I could've
            saved him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Turns to face him slightly.</charAction> I can hardly feel any
            vibrations out here. The sandbenders snuck up on me and there wasn't time for –</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Snaps at Toph in a harsh way.</charAction> You just didn't care! You
            never liked Appa! You wanted him gone!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks extremely furious at Toph as Katara walks over to him. She puts
                her hand on his shoulder to try and calm him down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, stop it. You know Toph did all she could. She saved our lives.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera moves to Sokka, who is still looking out into the
                desert.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Who's going to save our lives now? We'll never make it out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang irately walks away from the rest of the group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's all any of you guys care about, yourselves! You don't care whether Appa is
            okay or not!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're all concerned, but we can't afford to be fighting now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In a cold, hard tone.</charAction> I'm going after Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang flies off. Katara calls after him, running to the place he took
                off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, wait!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a view from the sky, showing Aang flying away from the rest of the
                group who stand by the large crater created by the disappeared library. Cut back to
                Katara, who is still looking in the direction Aang took off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We'd better start walking. We're the only people who know about the solar eclipse.
            We have to get that information to Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The group starts walking in the same direction as Aang took off to, with
                Katara leading the way, followed by Sokka. Toph closes the ranks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You think if we dig out the giant owl, he'll give us a ride?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko and Iroh riding on their ostrich horse. Iroh fake-moans in
                pretend pain at every step the ostrich horse takes, clasping his left
                arm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Maybe we should make camp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No please, don't stop just for me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a front view of Zuko and Iroh. Iroh theatrically lets out several
                more groans of pain. Zuko pull at the reins, annoyed by the performance displayed by
                his uncle. As they dismount, the ostrich horse is alarmed by something. Zuko
                immediately takes on a firebending form, ready to defend himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> What now?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Rough Rhinos ride through the thicket at both sides of the road Zuko
                and Iroh were traveling on. Mongke's rhino steps the ground forcefully breaking the
                surface. Mongke is shown, pulling back the reigns. Zuko keeps up his defensive
                position, looking at the men that surrounded them. Iroh's face clears up as he
                stands up and places a hand on Zuko's shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Colonel Mongke! What a pleasant surprise!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">If you're surprised we're here, then the Dragon of the West has lost a few
            steps.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Rough Rhinos prepare themselves for battle, each readying their own
                weapon of expertise.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You know these guys?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Sure. Colonel Mongke and the Rough Rhinos are legendary. Each one is a different
            kind of weapon specialist. <charAction>The camera cuts to each member of the Rough
                Rhinos.</charAction> They are also a very capable singing group.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Mongke, who has his fist raised, ready for
                firebending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">We're not here to give a concert. We're here to apprehend fugitives!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>While rubbing his arm.</charAction> Would you like some tea first? I'd
            love some. How about you, Kahchi? I make you as a jasmine man. Am I right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mongke">Enough stalling! Round 'em up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera shows an overhead view of the situation. Cut to Ogodei swinging his
                ball and chain at Iroh, who kicks it away. The chain wraps itself around the leg of
                Kahchi's rhino. Iroh tumbles over the ground, dodging two fire blasts. He rises back
                up and hits the rhino in the rear, making it dash away, yanking Ogodei off his rhino
                and dragging him along. Iroh waves goodbye as he watches them go.</description>
      <description>Vachir shoots a lit arrow at Zuko. He quickly reacts by knocking the arrow
                away and releasing a fire blast, burning a hole in the surprised archer's
                bow.</description>
      <description>Mongke joins the fight by directing some fire blasts at Iroh. Iroh deflects
                each and every one of them. As Mongke is busy with Iroh, Zuko runs up and jumps on
                the back of the Rhino. With two spinning fire kicks, he sends Colonel Mongke
                flying.</description>
      <description>Iroh runs up to the ostrich horse, jumps on and rides toward Zuko, who
                awaits him, standing on the Rhino of Colonel Mongke. As he jumps on, Yeh-Lu
                immediately starts the pursuit. He throws a grenade at the fleeing ostrich horse. It
                explodes right in front of it, but Iroh and Zuko ride through the explosion's
                smoke.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It's nice to see old friends.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Too bad you don't have any old friends that don't want to attack you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Grasping his shoulder again as he racks his brain in search of an
                answer.</charAction> Hmmm ... Old friends that don't want to attack me ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara, Sokka and Toph, all exhausted and dehydrated, still
                wandering through the desert. Sokka stops to take Momo off his back and use his
                wings to create some shade, causing Toph to crash into him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Can't you watch where you're ... <charAction>His
                eyes widen in comprehension as he sees who bumped into him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Right. Sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara turns around to encourage the others.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Come on guys, we've got to stick together.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka's clothes stick to Toph. He tries to free himself by pushing her
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">If I sweat anymore, I don't think sticking together will be a problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An irritated Toph places her hand on Sokka's face and pushes him to the
                ground, freeing them both.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Katara, can I have some more water?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay, but we've got to try to conserve it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara bends three small blobs of water out of her pouch and into the
                mouths of Sokka, Toph and Momo. Sokka circulates the water in his mouth before
                swallowing it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>As he points to his mouth.</charAction> We're drinking your bending
            water. <charAction>He tries to define the taste of the water, smacking his lips.
                Disgustedly he exclaims.</charAction> You used this on the swamp guy! Urch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">It does taste swampy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo lets out a sad cry in protest of the water's flavor, after also
                smacking his lips. Katara sadly puts the cork back on her water sack.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sad tone.</charAction> I'm sorry, it's all we have.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Not anymore! Look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara looks in the direction Sokka's pointing. He walks over to the cactus
                and cuts off a piece with his machete. He happily drinks the fluid that's inside
                while Momo crawls over to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> Sokka, wait! You shouldn't be eating strange
            plants!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She drags Toph along on her arm as she runs toward Sokka. He and Momo are
                quenching their thirst with plenty of cactus juice. He cuts open another part of the
                cactus, excitedly offering its content to a skeptic looking Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">There's water trapped inside these!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Backing away from Sokka and the cactus.</charAction> I don't know
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>While cactus juice drips off his chin.</charAction> Suit yourself. It's
            very thirst quenching though.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He gives Katara a big smile like a true salesman. Cut to close-up of his
                left eye as his pupil dilates rapidly. He tries to shake off the feeling by rapidly
                shaking his head. He starts to trip.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In a strange echoing voice.</charAction> Drink cactus juice. It'll
            quench ya! Nothing's quenchier. <charAction>He crawls over the ground as a caterpillar
                before jumping back to the front, pushing his face toward the camera with a big
                smile.</charAction> It's the quenchiest!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara gives Sokka a very weird look. She grabs his cactus juice and pours
                it away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay, I think you've had enough.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Who lit Toph on fire?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara wants to react on Sokka's comment, but is distracted by a sound in
                the sky. She looks up to see Momo flying around in circles, increasing his speed,
                before plummeting into the ground, head first. Katara picks up and cradles the
                unconscious animal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Can I get some of that cactus?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Wrapping her arm around Toph's shoulders.</charAction> I don't think
            that's a good idea. Come on, we need to find Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara leads Toph away. Sokka stays behind, staring blankly at the sky.
                Katara retraces her steps and pulls Sokka along by his arms. Cut to an overview shot
                of the endless desert.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In awe.</charAction> How did we get out here in the middle of the
            ocean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara sighs as the scene cuts to Aang flying over the desert in search of
                Appa. He blows his bison whistle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa! <charAction>He glides down and lands on a dune.</charAction> Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera circles around Aang. While he stares across the horizon, it
                begins to dawn on him that he is not going to find his friend out here. The tears
                well up in his eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No ... <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Overcome by anger, he slams his staff on the ground, creating a large
                mushroom-shaped cloud of sand. Dust that was kicked up by Aang's blow washes over
                Katara, Sokka and Toph as they climb over another dune.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What is that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">What? What is what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's a giant mushroom! <charAction>Very excited.</charAction> Maybe it's
            friendly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Let's just keep moving. I hope Aang's okay ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Katara leads Toph away, Sokka starts to worship the mushroom by waving
                his arms up and down, back and forth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Friendly mushroom! Mushy giant friend!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the village with the Misty Palms Oasis at the border of the
                desert.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">Yeah, a little barefoot blind girl and her friends passed through here a few days
            ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">Did they give you any indication where they were headed‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">Maybe you could give me a little incentive‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man makes the money sign with his fingers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">You suggesting I break your fingers‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man quickly hides his hand behind his back and points with the other
                one toward the desert.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">They went in the desert! Too bad there's almost no chance they survived.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">That's okay, 'cause she's wanted dead or alive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man quietly backs away from Xin Fu and Yu</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">No she's not! I'm certain her father wants her alive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">Hey, look ... Fire Nation wanted posters!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yu follows Xin Fu's lead and examines the wanted posters. A poster of Zuko
                and Iroh is surrounded by posters of Aang, the Blue Spirit, Jeong Jeong and
                Chey.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">So?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Xin Fu looks at Zuko and Iroh as they walk toward the tavern.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">So, look who's here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara, Toph and Sokka. It is nearly twilight and they are still
                walking in a single file through the desert. A shadow passes over their heads and
                Aang lands behind them, kicking up a small cloud of sand. As the sand clears, Aang
                is still down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm sorry, Aang. I know it's hard for you right now but ... we need to focus on
            getting out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She walks over to him and puts a hand on his shoulder to comfort him. He
                pulls away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Hopelessly.</charAction> What's the difference? We won't survive without
            Appa. We all know it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Encouraging.</charAction> Come on, Aang. We can do this if we work
            together. Right Toph?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">As far as I can feel, we're trapped in a giant bowl of sand pudding. I got
            nothin'.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hopeful.</charAction> Sokka? Any ideas how to find Ba Sing Se?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka and Momo lie side by side on their backs, arms and legs stretched
                out. Sokka smiles blissfully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pointing up at the sky.</charAction> Why don't we ask the circle
            birds?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara directs her gaze to the sky and sees four buzzard wasps circling
                above their heads. She looks at every other member in the team. Aang still sits down
                sulking and Toph staggers a bit. Sokka sniggers a bit while Momo lazily claws at the
                buzzard wasps.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Grabs her head in annoyance.</charAction> Ugh ... We're getting out of
            this desert, and we're going to do it together! Aang, get up. Everybody, hold hands. We
            can do this. We have to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She takes one more look at the buzzard wasps in the sky before pulling Aang
                along by his staff. Aang holds on to Toph's hand and she holds on to Sokka's in
                turn. A big grinning Sokka pulls Momo along by his tail, who lazily tries to fly in
                the other direction.</description>
      <description>The sun is setting as they all stagger up a large dune, with Katara still
                in the lead.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I think we should stop for the night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The rest of the group sighs and falls down of exhaustion.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Is there any more water?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This is the last of it. Everyone can have a little drink.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka crawls toward Katara with Momo riding on his back when she begins to
                bend the water out of her pouch. Momo leaps forward at the water, causing it to fall
                in the sand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Theatrically panics, grabbing his head in despair.</charAction> Momo,
            no! You've killed us all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara calmly holds her hand over the moist spot of sand and begins to bend
                the water back into her pouch, before giving it to Toph to drink.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No, he hasn't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Relieved.</charAction> Oh, right. Bending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, let me see the things you got from the library.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He immediately backs away and defensively grabs his back full of
                scrolls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Offended.</charAction> What?! I didn't steal anything! Who told you
            that? <charAction>Pointing an accusing finger at Momo.</charAction> It was you! You
            ratted me out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, I was there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara takes the bag from Sokka and start to examine the
                scrolls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> It doesn't matter. None of those will tell us where
            Appa is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No, but we can find out which way Ba Sing Se is. We can use the stars to guide us.
                <charAction>She pulls out a map of the stars.</charAction> That way we can travel at
            night when it's cool and rest during the day.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She turns around and sighs at the sight of the rest of the group. They are
                all lying there, exhausted from the long walk and their grief for the loss of
                Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Just try to get some sleep. We'll start again in a few hours.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to Zuko and Iroh sitting at a table in the tavern at the Misty Palms
                Oasis.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No one here is going to help us. These people just look like filthy
            wanderers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">So do we. <charAction>Pointing at something behind Zuko.</charAction> Ah, this is
            interesting. I think I found our friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko turns around to see where Iroh is pointing at, the camera pans over
                his shoulder to reveal an old man sitting at a Pai Sho table.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You brought us here to gamble on Pai Sho?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I don't think this is a gamble.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko and Iroh walk toward the Pai Sho table. The camera zooms toward Xin Fu
                and Yu, who are sitting on a bench at the other side of the tavern. Xin Fu jumps up
                with the intention to grab them, but Yu places a hand on his shoulder to restrain
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">Let's take them now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">This place is full of desperate characters. If they find out we're collecting a
            bounty, we might have to fight them all just to keep our prize. Patience.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Iroh and Zuko approaching the Pai Sho table.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">May I have this game?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">
         <charAction>Gesturing Iroh to sit down.</charAction> The guest has the first move.
                <charAction>Iroh places the lotus tile in the center of the board.</charAction> I
            see you favor the white lotus gambit. Not many still cling to the ancient ways.
                <charAction>He cups his hands toward Iroh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Those who do can always find a friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He copies the gesture of the old man, also cupping his hands toward
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">Then let us play.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The old man places a tile on the board, quickly followed by a tile placed
                by Iroh. Seemingly without even looking at what the other person is doing, the two
                man quickly place their tiles on the board. Zuko sits down and watches intently as
                the two man place one tile after the other. When they are done, their tiles form the
                shape of a lotus flower.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">Welcome, brother. The White Lotus opens wide to those who know her secrets.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What are you old gasbags talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I always tried to tell you that Pai Sho is more than just a game.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh rolls a tile over his knuckles and clutches it.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Xin Fu and Yu. Xin Fu ran out of patience and jumps
                up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">I'm not waiting all night for these geezers to finish yapping! <charAction>He walks
                over to the Pai Sho table, followed by Yu.</charAction> It's over! You two fugitives
            are coming with me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">
         <charAction>Quickly places himself before Iroh and Zuko, preventing Xin Fu and Yu
                from reaching them.</charAction> I knew it! You two are wanted criminals with a
            giant bounty on your heads!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I thought you said he would help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Places a hand on Zuko's shoulder to reassure him.</charAction> He is.
            Just watch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">
         <charAction>To Yu and Xin Fu.</charAction> You think you're going to capture them
            and collect all that gold?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man in the bar">Gold?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Every person in the bar looks up when they hear the word 'gold'. Some of
                them stand up, pulling a knife, ready to attack.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">Uh ... Maybe we shouldn't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera shows a close-up of a grinning Xin Fu. As he moves toward Zuko and
                Iroh, two men jump in front of him to block his path. With a reverse roundhouse
                kick, the earthbender bends a rock from the ground and easily pushes them out of his
                way.</description>
      <description>Yu readies himself for battle. He sinks the first person to charge him into
                the ground. Meanwhile Xin Fu kicks two sandbenders away while he is lifting another
                one up in the air and holding a fourth one back with his other hand. After he kicks
                another sandbender away, he twists his waist, sending the two men he is holding
                flying. One of them crashes into the wall behind the bar.</description>
      <description>When there is no one left to fight, Xin Fu and Yu realize that their prey
                has escaped during the chaos. Xin Fu growls in frustration and slams his two fists
                on the ground, erecting a giant pillar of earth under a downed sandbender, shooting
                him out of the window and against a palm tree.</description>
      <description>Cut to a scorpion walking over a rock. The camera shows how Momo is patting
                the sand he used to cover up Sokka while he is sleeping. He jumps away as Katara
                approaches Sokka to wake him up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Come on, get up. We need to go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka drowsily sits up and smiles like a drunken idiot. Toph also erects
                herself, smacking her lips.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yesterday my mouth tasted like mud. Now it just tastes like sand. I never thought
            I'd miss the taste of mud so much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara goes to Aang to wake him up, but he interrupts her before she can
                touch him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm awake. I couldn't sleep.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Well, we need to get moving if we want to get out of this sand pit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Katara spot something large in the sky. He quickly sits up. Cut to
                a shot of a large, bison shaped object floating by the bright, full moon. Aang's
                expression brightens up in an instant.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Joyfully.</charAction> Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Appa‌? But why would Princess Yue need him‌? She's the moon! <charAction>Grabs
                Momo's tail, using it to rub his cheek.</charAction> She flies by herself!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A closer shot of the floating object reveals that it is just a small desert
                cloud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> It's just a cloud. Wait! A cloud! <charAction>Offers
                her pouch to Aang.</charAction> Here, fly up and bend the water from that cloud into
            my pouch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang gives Katara an angry look before snatching the offered water pouch
                out of her hands. The group gazes at him as he quickly passes two times over the
                cloud. The few remains of the cloud evaporate. He throws the pouch at Katara when he
                lands and she peeks in.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> Wow ... there's hardly any in here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Lashes out.</charAction> I'm sorry, okay! It's a desert cloud; I did all
            I could! What's anyone else doing?! <charAction>Pointing his staff at
                Katara.</charAction> What are you doing‌?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She returns his attack with a shocked look on her face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Trying to keep everyone together. Let's just get moving. We need to head this
            direction.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara looks at her charts once more and leads the group in the chosen
                direction. They are walking silently through the desert, until Toph trips and falls
                flat on her face. Aang and Katara are looking at Toph, while Sokka and Momo just
                stand there, staring blankly to the sky. Toph sits up and rubs her right
                foot.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Ow! Crud! I am so sick of not feeling where I'm going! <charAction>Pointing toward
                the little rocklike shaped object she tripped over.</charAction> And what idiot
            buried a boat in the middle of the desert‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">A boat‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara runs over to inspect the object.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Believe me, I kicked it hard enough to feel plenty of vibrations.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka turns around, swinging like a string puppet, to see what Katara is so
                excited about. Katara begins to rub of the sand of the object that appears to be
                made of wood. Aang steps forward, suggestively holding up his staff. As soon as
                Katara backs away, Aang swings his staff around, creating a mighty gust of wind,
                revealing a boat of some sort. Katara crawls aboard and examines it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's one of the gliders the sandbenders use! And look! It's got some kind of compass
            on it! <charAction>Tapping the compass.</charAction> I bet it can point us out of here!
            Aang, you can bend a breeze so we can sail it. We're going to make it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot of Sokka laughing childishly while burying Momo in the
                sand.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a small village at the edge of the desert, where Zuko and
                Iroh follow the Pai Sho player into a flower shop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">It is an honor to welcome such a high-ranking member of the Order of the White
            Lotus. Being a Grand Master, you must know so many secrets.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Now that you played Pai Sho, are you going to do
            some flower arranging, or is someone in this club going to offer some real
            help‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You must forgive my nephew. He is not an initiate and has little appreciation for
            the cryptic arts.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Pai Sho player leads Iroh toward a door with a peephole in it. He
                knocks two times. A man slides open the small window in the door and peeks
                through.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Florist">Who knocks at the garden gate‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">One who has eaten the fruit and tasted its mysteries.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh smiles as the door opens to let him and the Pai Sho player through.
                When Zuko attempts to follow them, the door slams shut in front of him. He looks at
                the door with a pout when Iroh opens the small window.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm afraid it's members only. Wait out here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An annoyed Zuko frowns and crosses his arms as he rests against a nearby
                table. He leans over to sniff the plant on the table.</description>
      <description>Switch to a shot of the desert where the sand-sailer is making great speed.
                Katara navigates it through the desert, while Aang's driving it forward using strong
                gusts of wind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The needle on this compass doesn't seem to be pointing north according to my
            charts.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara places her charts over the compass. Sokka sits beside her, dangling
                his legs over the edge and holding Momo by the tail, who glides in the opposite
                direction.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Dreamily.</charAction> Take it easy little lady. I'm sure the sand folks
            who built this baby know how to get around here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara looks annoyed at Sokka. When she focuses her attention back toward
                the horizon in front of her, she gasps in comprehension when she sees a giant rock
                in the distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's what the compass is pointing to! That giant rock! It must be the magnetic
            center of the desert.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Ecstatic.</charAction> A rock‌?! Yes! Let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hopeful.</charAction> Maybe we can find some water there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Darkly.</charAction> Maybe we can find some sandbenders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang continues to send gusts of wind into the sails of the glider,
                directing it toward the rock. Switch to a shot of the glider at the base of the
                rock. The sun's already rising when team Avatar reaches the top.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Ahhh ... Finally! Solid ground!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph happily lets herself drop flat on her back, moving her arms and legs
                back and forth, creating a rock angel. After she is done, the group starts to
                explore the caves that decorate the top of the rock. They enter a round tunnel. The
                cave's surface is covered with a yellow, gooey substance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Breathes deeply.</charAction> I think my head is starting to clear out
            the cactus juice. And look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka dips his hand in the yellow goo and tastes it, sharing his find with
                Momo. They both spit it out and Sokka makes a disgusted gagging noise.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Tastes like rotten penguin meat! Awww, I feel woozy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> You've been hallucinating on cactus juice all
            day and then you just lick something you find stuck to the wall of a cave‌?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I have a natural curiosity.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I don't think this is a normal cave. This was carved by something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah ... look at the shape.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Close-up of her feet.</charAction> There's something buzzing in here.
                <charAction>Camera pans up to her.</charAction> Something that's coming for
            us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shows how the group runs out of the cave, back into the open.
                Toph and Aang scream as the first buzzard wasp emerges. Aang pulls Toph down as it
                flies over their heads. A second wasp dives directly toward the
                camera.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the giant rock from a distance, followed by a shot of the
                hive as more buzzard wasps swarm out and surround the group. Aang blasts the first
                wasp to come near them away with a strong air current.</description>
      <description>A second wasp lands on a nearby rock. The moment it touches it, Toph turns
                around to send the wasp flying again, shooting up the rock from underneath
                it.</description>
      <description>Another buzzard wasp flies between Sokka and Toph. She hears it fly behind
                her so she lifts the rock beside her and throws it in the general direction of the
                sound. The giant rock is only inches apart from crushing Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> What are you doing? That rock almost crushed
            me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Sorry, I can't tell where they are in the air!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A loud buzzing signals the passing of another wasp. Sokka readies his
                machete and runs after it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I got this one.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He ferociously swings his weapon back and forth at the
                camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, there's nothing there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans back. He lowers his machete, looking around in search for
                his imagined foe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I guess my head's not as clear as I thought.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of a crouched up Momo. In the background, Katara backs a
                few steps in Aang's direction.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We have to get out of here! I'm completely out of water to bend!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A buzzard wasp swoops in from the sky and snatches up a screeching Momo as
                it flies away from the hive and the benders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Momo! I'm not losing anyone else out here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Full of anger, he takes off on his glider in hot pursuit of Momo and the
                wasp. Katara and Sokka watch him go.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Come on, we're going down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They descend along a narrow ledge. Katara leads Toph by hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Toph, shoot a rock right there. Fire!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara places Toph in the right direction. Toph kicks up some rocks and
                shoots them forward. The incoming buzzard wasp is shot down, taking several blows to
                the head. Sokka cheers, swinging his machete in the air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah! You got it! She got it, right‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yes. Now let's move.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara leads Toph on as they start to run along the ledge.</description>
      <description>Shift to a close-up of Aang. He is still chasing the buzzard wasp that took
                Momo. A grave expression casts shadows on his face. He dives, emerging again
                straight underneath the wasp. As he turns, he directs a strong gust of wind at the
                wasp with a kick of his leg. The gust forces the wasp to release Momo out of its
                clutches. Momo tumbles down, but quickly regains control and begins to soar next to
                Aang. Aang looks from Momo toward the rising sun at the horizon. With an angry
                glare, he notices that the wasp is getting away. Aang glides down, flying close to
                the ground. Using the speed of his descent, he closes his glider and swings his
                staff down. A powerful wall of air splits the sand, racing toward the escaping wasp.
                The animal is hit in mid air, knocking it to the ground. With a dark glare, Aang
                just stares at the downed wasp before walking back in the direction of the giant
                rock. Momo follows him quickly, frightened by this merciless outburst of
                power.</description>
      <description>Cut back to a shot of the giant rock, where buzzard wasps circle around
                Sokka and the rest, who've reached the sand-sailer at the base by now. Katara looks
                over Toph's shoulder, acting as her eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">On your left!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph reacts immediately and shoots a rock at her left. The buzzard wasp
                takes the rock full in the chest, shrieking on impact before tumbling
                down.</description>
      <description>The camera pans out, showing many more wasps hovering in the air. Suddenly,
                gigantic pillars of sand rise from the ground and scare off the swarm. Katara, Sokka
                and Toph lower their arms they had lifted to shield their heads from the sand. As
                the wind blows the dust away, the camera pans to the left, revealing several
                sandbenders. Aang lands before Katara, Sokka and Toph, ready to face the
                sandbenders.</description>
      <description>Cut back to a shot of the flower shop in the desert village, where a
                sleeping Zuko is startled by the squeaking of the door. Iroh steps through as Zuko
                takes on a defensive stance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What's going on? Is the club meeting over‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Everything is taken care of. We're heading to Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh and Fung bow to each other in respect.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Ba Sing Se? ‌Why would we go to the Earth Kingdom capital‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fung">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> The city is filled with refugees. No one will
            notice two more.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">We can hide in plain sight there. And it's the safest place in the world from the
            Fire Nation. Even I couldn't break through to the city. <charAction>Happily shrugs his
                shoulders.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A bell signals that someone has entered the shop. A young man approaches
                the group, holding up some papers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="White Lotus member">I have the passports for our guests, but there are two men out on the street looking
            for them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Xin Fu and Yu can be seen through a small window in the door of the flower
                shop. They are holding up a wanted poster that depicts Iroh and Zuko to man walking
                by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">You seen these guys‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shift back to a shot of the base of the giant rock, where the leader of the
                sandbenders confronts Aang and the rest.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sha-Mo">What are you doing in our land with a sandbender sailer? ‌ From the looks of it, you
            stole it from the Hami tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We found the sailer abandoned in the desert. We're traveling with the Avatar.
                <charAction>She gestures at Aang. The leader's eyes widen a bit at this
                information.</charAction> Our bison was stolen and we have to get to Ba Sing
            Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A young man to the right of the leader takes a step forward and
                aggressively addresses Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">You dare accuse our people of theft while you ride in on a stolen sand
            sailer‌?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Toph's misty, green eye, narrowing as she hears the young man's
                voice.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sha-Mo">Quiet, Ghashiun. No one accused our people of anything. If what they say is true, we
            must give them hospitality.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">Sorry, father.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph's eye widens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I recognize the son's voice. He's the one that stole Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Are you sure?‌</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I never forget a voice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang's tunic flutters around him as he charges forward, threateningly
                brandishing his staff toward Ghashiun.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> You stole Appa! Where is he? ‌What did you do to
            him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ghashiun cowers back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">They're lying! They're the thieves!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With an angry frown and a growl of frustration, Aang smacks his staff on
                the ground, obliterating one of the sandbender's sailers with a powerful blade of
                air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Enraged.</charAction> Where is my bison‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes again to the flower shop, where a man exits the door,
                pulling two big flowerpots on a wooden wagon. After he leaves, Xin Fu and Yu walk
                toward the door. Xin Fu slams the door open with such ferocity that an overhanging
                plant comes crashing down. He shoves Zuko's and Iroh's wanted poster under the nose
                of the florist.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">Hey you, where are these men‌? I got a tip that they're in your shop.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Florist">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> As you can see, no one is here but us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">We know all about your secret back room. <charAction>To Xin Fu.</charAction> Kick it
            down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Xin Fu charges the door like a mad bull and knocks it down along with the
                surrounding wall, with one mighty kick.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Florist">Hey! That room is for flowers only!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">Some unlucky soul has an incomplete Pai Sho set.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Yu picks up a lotus tile that lies in the center of the room and shows it
                to Xin Fu, who angrily knocks it out of his hands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">Let's go back to finding the girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to the man pulling the wooden wagon with the two large
                pots over some dunes. Zuko's and Iroh's head emerges from underneath the flowers.
                They briefly peek around before sinking back into their pots.</description>
      <description>Cut back to the desert where Aang is confronting the
                sandbenders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You tell me where he is now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>To emphasize his order, Aang sends a strong blast of air toward another
                sailer. The sandbenders watch in shock as it blows up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sha-Mo:">
         <charAction>To Ghashiun.</charAction> What did you do‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">I-It wasn't me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You said to put a muzzle on him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Enraged.</charAction> You muzzled Appa‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang's eyes and tattoos start to glow as he enters the Avatar State. With a
                swing of his staff, he destroys the last of the sandbender's sailers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">I'm sorry! I didn't know that it belonged to the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>With the voices of all the Avatars.</charAction> Tell me where Appa
            is!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ghashiun">
         <charAction>Frightened.</charAction> I traded him! To some merchants! He's probably
            in Ba Sing Se by now! They were going to sell him there! <charAction>The sandbenders
                raise their hands as if to ward off the Avatar's bright, angry glare.</charAction>
            Please! We'll escort you out of the desert! We'll help however we can!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The wind around Avatar Aang starts the swirl, as his anger is reaching its
                peak. Sokka pull Toph along with him as he starts to make a break for it, running
                away from his enraged friend.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Just get out of here! Run!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang drops his staff. The wind around him forms a fast moving sphere,
                knocking up sand high into the sky. As everyone runs away, Katara stays put, staring
                sadly at the ground. The sandstorm engulfs her and Aang completely, obscuring them
                from the sight of the others. They brace themselves as the whirlwind swoops over
                them.</description>
      <description>Aang's air sphere slowly lifts him up in the air, his teeth clenched and
                his hands cramped with rage. Katara grabs his right arm, preventing him from rising
                any further. The terrible face of an outraged Avatar looks down upon her, only to be
                met by Katara's sincere, sad expression. She pulls him back to the ground and
                presses him close against her chest. Sokka and Toph lower their arms as the wind
                becomes less violent. Tears are streaming down the Avatar's glowing eyes. Katara
                tries her best to hold on as her own tears well up. The air sphere slowly dissolves
                away as Aang leaves the Avatar state. His rage subsides to make room for pure,
                heartbreaking sadness.</description>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
