<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="11">The Great Divide</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>John O' Bryan</writer>
      <date>2005-05-20</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>Opening shot of the sun setting behind some tall rock outcroppings. The sky
                is mostly cloudy and the clouds reflect the light of the dying sun. Pan down to show
                a patched up tent being jostled about from the inside. A rolled up tarp lies next to
                the tent. Sokka is inside a tent, trying to assemble it. Sokka can be heard grunting
                and fussing about as he tries to finish setting up the shelter. Katara walks in the
                frame, her back to the camera, with a pile of fire wood in her arms.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Um, aren't you forgetting the tarp?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Right, got it ... <charAction>Tosses the wrapped up tarp inside the
                tent.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, you're supposed to put the tarp on top&gt; of the
            tent. You know, so we don't get rained on? <charAction>Cut to an overhead shot of the
                two, Sokka gesturing widely as he replies to his sister.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Ordinarily, you'd be right, but seeing how it's the dry season, you're not. Besides
            that tarp makes a pretty warm blanket.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But what if it does rain?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Spreading his arms wide in exasperation.</charAction> What if it
            doesn't? Then I would have put up the tarp for nothing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're infuriating!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Katara, why don't you worry about gathering firewood, because that kindling is
            looking pretty sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Well, if you don't like my firewood-
                <charAction>Throws the sticks at Sokka who shields himself from the wood. He stands
                in anger after the hail of sticks subsides.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Fine by me, if you're not gonna do your job-
                <charAction>He tears the tent down and the two stare at each other angrily as Aang
                approaches.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay, I got the grub if you guys got the- <charAction>The siblings turn away from
                each other in anger with their arms folded.</charAction> hey, where's the campfire?
            And what happened to the tent?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Why don't you ask Miss Know-It-All, Queen of the Twigs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh yeah? Well, you're Mister Lazy Bum, King of the <charAction>Picks up and throws a
                twig at Sokka's head.</charAction> Tents! <charAction>Sokka turns around, looking
                angrily at her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Okay, listen guys, harsh words won't solve
            problems, action will. Why don't you just switch jobs?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sounds good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>At the same time.</charAction> Whatever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Grinning while gloating.</charAction> You see that? Settling feuds and
            making peace, all in a day's work for the Avatar. <charAction>Turns his head to see Momo
                and Appa fighting over a watermelon. Momo continuously tries to fly away with it,
                while Appa pins it down. Aang takes the melon and uses airbending to slice it. Momo
                seems to be complaining about how he got the much smaller half and Appa got the
                bigger half.</charAction> Come on, Momo, that's fair. Appa's got five stomachs.
                <charAction>Appa eats his half of the melon.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades to show the group standing on the edge of a huge
                canyon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There it is, guys, The Great Divide.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>In awe.</charAction> Wow, I could just stare at it forever.
                <charAction>Zoom backward to show Sokka in the foreground.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay, I've seen enough.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">How can you not be fascinated Sokka? This is the largest canyon in the entire
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Then I'm sure we'll be able to see it very clearly from the air while we fly
            away.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">
         <charAction>Shoving past Sokka.</charAction> If you're looking for the canyon guide,
            I was here first!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ooh, canyon guide? Sounds informative.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">Believe me, he's more than a tour guide, he's an earthbender, <charAction>Oblivious
                to the fact that Sokka is behind him, mocking him.</charAction> and the only way in
            and out of the canyon is with his help, and he's taking my
            tribe across next.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Calm down, we know you're next.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">You wouldn't be so calm if the Fire Nation destroyed your home and forced you&gt; to
            flee! My whole tribe has to walk thousands of miles to the capital city of Ba Sing
            Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're a refugee!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">Huh, tell me something I don't know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A large group of poorly dressed people is shown walking toward
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Is that your tribe?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">It most certainly is not! That's the Zhang tribe, a bunch of low-life thieves.
            They've been the enemies of my tribe for a hundred years. <charAction>Whistles to
                them.</charAction> Hey, Zhangs! I'm saving a spot for my tribe so don't even think
            about stealing it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Where are the rest of the Gan Jin? Still tidying up their camp site?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">Yes, but they sent me ahead of them to hold a spot.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">I didn't know the canyon guide took reservations.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">Ha, of course you didn't! That's the ignorance I'd expect from a messy
                Zhang.&gt; So unorganized and ill-prepared for a journey. <charAction>The
                Zhang tribe members yell out in protest behind them. Katara and Aang look at each
                other worriedly, but turn around to see a large pile of rocks being levitated up and
                thrown away. The canyon guide stands behind where the rocks used to
            be.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">Sorry about the wait, youngsters. Who's ready to cross this here canyon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Uh, one of them, I think. <charAction>Camera pans left to reveal the Zhang and the
                scout.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">
         <charAction>Rushing forward.</charAction> I was here first, my party's on their
            way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">I can't guide people who aren't here. <charAction>Cut to a wider shot showing the
                Zhang filing past the three kids and the fuming Gan Jin scout.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> Guess you guys will have to make the trip
            tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shifts to a close-up the scout, whose eyes twitch in anger. The
                camera zooms backward and pans left to reveal another tribe entering the canyon
                entrance area. The scout points to them in triumph.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">Wait, here they come! <charAction>A group of clean, finely dressed people are shown
                coming toward them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>To the canyon guide.</charAction> You're not seriously gonna cave into
            these spoiled Gan Jins? I mean we're refugees too! And we've got sick people that need
            shelter.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">I ... uh ... well ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin tribesman">We've got old people who are weary from traveling.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Sick people get priority over old people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Maybe you Zhangs wouldn't have so many sick people if you weren't such
            slobs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">If you Gan Jins weren't so clean, you wouldn't live to be so old.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Over the two arguing tribes.</charAction> Well Aang, ready to put your
            peace-making skills to the test?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know, a fight over chores is one thing, but these people have been feuding
            for a hundred years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Stepping forward.</charAction> Everybody listen up! This is the Avatar,
            and if you give him a chance, I'm sure he can come up with a compromise that will make
            everyone happy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh, you could share the earthbender and travel
            together?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Absolutely not! We'd rather be taken by the Fire Nation than travel with those
            stinking thieves!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">We wouldn't travel with those pompous fools anyway! <charAction>The two tribes begin
                to shout at each other again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> All right here's the deal, you're all going down
            together and Appa here will fly your sick and elderly across! Does that seem fair?
                <charAction>Both leaders nod in agreement, and the scene fades to show the sick and
                elderly boarding Appa.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Appa.</charAction> Sorry, Appa, you'll have to do this on your
            own.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, this feuding tribe stuff is serious business. Are you sure it's a good idea
            getting involved in this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Grinning broadly.</charAction> To tell you the truth, I'm not sure. But
            when have I ever been?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">He's the Avatar, Sokka, making peace between people is his job.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> His job's gonna make us cross this whole canyon
            on foot isn't it? <charAction>Cut to an overhead wide shot of the two tribes and the
                others.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">Okay, now comes the bad news. <charAction>Cut to a frontal shot of the
                guide.</charAction> No food allowed in the canyon, it attracts <charAction>He makes
                motions with his hands to illustrate the skittery monsters that might lurk in the
                canyon.</charAction>
            dangerous predators. <charAction>Both tribes yell out in
                protest.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin Leader">No food?! This is ridiculous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">Oh, you babies can go a day without food? Would you rather be hungry, or dead?
                <charAction>He raises an earth pillar to tower over the rest. He continues, cupping
                his hands to his mouth to amplify his voice.</charAction> Now, we're heading down in
            ten minutes. All food better be in your gut or in the garbage!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Zhang tribe quickly whips out and shoves food into their mouths, which
                stands in stark contrast to the Gan Jin tribe, who eat slowly with
                chopsticks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To the people on Appa.</charAction> Appa's going to take good care of
            you 'till we get there. <charAction>To Appa.</charAction> See you on the other side,
            buddy! Yip yip! <charAction>Appa roars and takes off. The camera fades to show both
                groups of people climbing down into the canyon. The tour guide earthbends to form a
                bridge in a gap in the path.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nice bending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">The job's much more than bending, kid. Folks want information. <charAction>Turns to
                the travelers.</charAction> Many of you are probably wondering how canyons are
            formed. Experts tell us this canyon was most likely carved into the ground by earth
            spirits who were angry at local farmers for not offering them a proper
            sacrifice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Sokka look up in fear as an avalanche of rocks comes falling
                toward them, and the canyon guide earthbends it away from them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">He he he, guess the spirits are still angry! Hope you all brought
            sacrifices.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wide shot of the canyon floor and the canyon wall on the right
                side of the screen. The view pans slowly rightward before cutting to a closer,
                overhead shot of the group now at the bottom of the switchback trail. They have just
                entered the canyon floor. The guide stands in front of the two tribes and the kids.
                Katara, Aang, and Sokka look at each other in exasperation and the scene fades to
                show them standing at the bottom of the canyon next to a huge boulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">Okay, everyone stand clear of the wall. <charAction>He throws the boulder and
                destroys the bridge he had made earlier.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Why'd you do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">These people are fleeing the Fire Nation, aren't they? Gotta make sure we can't be
            followed. We'll be safe now. <charAction>Yells out, as he is picked up by a huge animal.
                Aang blows away the dust to reveal a canyon crawler.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We gotta help him! <charAction>He throws his boomerang at the crawler, which drops
                the canyon guide and comes after Sokka instead.</charAction> Okay, now we gotta help
                me! <charAction>Katara comes to his aid and does a water
                whip on the crawler, but she is quickly thrown aside. Aang jumps down and sends a
                multiple blasts of air at the crawler and drives it away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To the canyon guide.</charAction> What was that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">
         <charAction>On the ground.</charAction> Canyon crawler. <charAction>Groans in
                pain.</charAction> And there's sure to be more!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Your arms, they're broken!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">Without my arms, I got no bending. In other words-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We're trapped in this canyon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera fades to show them grouped together.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I thought the whole point of ditching our food was so we wouldn't have to deal with
            things like canyon crawlers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">It's the Zhangs! They took food down here even after the canyon guide told them not
            to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">What? If there's anyone who can't go without food for a day, it's you pampered Gan
            Jins!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">I hope you're happy. We're stuck in this canyon with no way out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Why don't you thank yourself, food hider?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Look, sticking together is the only way to-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">I'm not walking another step with the likes of them!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Now there's something we can agree on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To the canyon guide.</charAction> Any ideas?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">No bendng ... we need to get out of this canyon ... I won't die down here! I won't
            become part of the food chain!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">See! We're going to become part of the food chain because of you! <charAction>Points
                to Zhangs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Sure, unjustly blame the Zhangs like you always do!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Gladly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Enough! I thought I could help you guys get along,
            but I guess that's not gonna happen. <charAction>Jumps onto a tall rock.</charAction> We
            should split up, Gan Jins on this side and Zhangs on that side. We'll travel in two
            separate lines. <charAction>The two leaders nod at each other and start walking. Aang
                jumps down to Sokka and Katara.</charAction> Sokka, you go with the Zhangs and
            Katara, you go with the Gan Jins. See if you can find out why they hate each other so
            much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They split up and the camera pans to show them walking separately. The
                scene changes to show Sokka in the Zhang camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, you guys aren't going to put up your tarps?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">What for? Its the dry season.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Exactly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Besides, we like to use the tarp as a blanket.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Finally, someone gets it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara is shown at the Gan Jin camp, where they are putting up tarps over
                their tents.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You really think it'll rain?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">No, but you can never be too careful, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara smiles and the camera fades to nightfall, where they are sitting
                around their campfire. The Gan Jin leader looks around and pulls a piece of bread
                out of his sleeve. Katara looks stunned to see all the other tribe members doing the
                same.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Would you care for some bread, Katara?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">So it was you guys who had food!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Oh come now, you really think that tribe of thieves isn't smuggling food? Why should
            my people go hungry when the sneaky Zhangs are stuffing their faces?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hesitates.</charAction> Well, I guess it's okay if everyone's doing it.
                <charAction>Takes the bread and eats it.</charAction> So, why does your tribe hate
            the Zhangs so much?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">You seem like a smart girl Katara, I bet you would enjoy hearing some history.
                <charAction>Fades to show a large gate with a finely dressed man running toward it.
                Voice-over.</charAction> The patriarch of our tribe, Jin Wei, was an earthbender
            warrior who was assigned an important duty, transporting our sacred orb from the great
            eastern gate, to the great western gate. Taking the orb from the east to the west
            represents the sun's rising and setting. It was our tribe's ancient redemption ritual.
            But as he approached the gate, Jin Wei was attacked by one of the Zhang, a vermin named
            Wei Jin, who looked at the orb with envy. That coward Wei Jin knocked Jin Wei to the
            ground, and stole our sacred orb. <charAction>Camera goes back to the Gan Jin leader's
                face.</charAction> Our people have never forgotten. You can never trust a
            Zhang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara glares at the Zhang's camp and the scene fades to show the Zhang
                tribe and Sokka sitting around the campfire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> Care for some meat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Would I! <charAction>Takes the meat and bites down hungrily.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">I know what you must be thinking, we're horrible for endangering everybody by
            bringing food down here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hm-hmm.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">The Gan Jin think so badly of us, they probably assumed we brought food in and
            decided to bring food in themselves. That's why we brought food in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Still eating.</charAction> Hmm.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Our conflict with the Gan Jin goes back over a hundred years. <charAction>Fades to
                show a poorly-dressed man running through a large gate. Voice-over.</charAction> Our
            forefather Wei Jin was leaving the western gate of our village, when he saw a figure in
            the distance. It was a man of the Gan Jin tribe, Jin Wei, collapsed on the ground. Noble
            Wei Jin stopped to help him. Jin Wei was transporting a sacred orb, a very powerful
            relic used in his tribe's redemption ritual. Wei Jin tried to tend to the man's wounds
            but Jin Wei insisted the orb was more important, and asked him to take it back to his
            tribe. Kind Wei Jin promised to send help for the man as soon as he could, but as Wei
            Jin crossed the border to return the orb into Gan Jin territory, he was arrested.
            Instead of thanking him for his kind and selfless deed, they sentenced him to twenty
            long years in prison. <charAction>Back to Zhang leader.</charAction> We Zhangs will
            never forget that injustice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That's just terrible. <charAction>Looks at her piece of meat.</charAction> You gonna
            finish that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to show Aang sitting with Momo far from both camps.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sure would be nice to be sitting around one of those campfires, telling stories and
            laughing. Its okay Momo, we'll be out of here soon enough, and then we can eat our
            weight in leechi nuts! <charAction>Momo jumps up and snatches a bug out of the air, he
                eats part of it before offering the rest to Aang.</charAction> Nah, I'll wait for
            the leechi nuts.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">
         <charAction>Slowly approaching Aang.</charAction> Lonely isn't it, being
            impartial?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I wish I could help these people get along, but it just seems impossible. Anyhow, I
            guess our biggest problem is getting out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">I'm not so sure the two problems are unrelated.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks away sadly and the scene fades to show the two tribes traveling
                again in daylight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">All clear, we're almost to the other side.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jumps down to Katara and Sokka.</charAction> Katara, Sokka, will these
            people cooperate long enough to get out of the canyon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't think so, Aang, the Zhangs really wronged the Gan Jins. They ambushed Jin
            Wei and stole the sacred orb.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What are you talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah Katara, what are you talking about? Wei Jin didn't steal the orb, he was
            returning it to their village gate and was wrongfully punished by the Gan Jin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Not punished enough if you ask me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Over Sokka's frustrated growls.</charAction> Okay, okay I get it! Now I
            need your help, I need everyone together at the base of the canyon wall. <charAction>He
                takes off on his glider and the scene fades to show him landing between the two
                tribes.</charAction> Please everyone, as soon as we get out of here we can eat and
            then go our separate ways, but I need you all to put your heads together and figure out
            a way up this cliff.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Maybe the Zhang can climb the wall with their long disgusting fingernails.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Oh sorry, I forgot that to the Gan Jin unclipped fingernails is a crime punishable
            by twenty years in jail!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Why, you dirty thief!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">You pompous fool!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The tribes began to argue loudly again, accompanied by Katara and
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> Guys, focus! How many times do I have to say it?
            Harsh words won't solve problems, action will!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Perhaps the Avatar is right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Yes, perhaps he is. <charAction>Aang grins happily at this.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Harsh words will never solve our problems.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Action will!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They both draw their swords and Aang yells in surprise, as they clash their
                swords.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">To the death! And let this be the end of this rivalry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You know, I take it back. Harsh words aren't so bad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two leaders ignore him as they begin to fight. They are evenly matched,
                and continue until Aang blows them apart with a strong gust of air. The two tribes
                go flying backward, revealing a large amount of hidden food.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Is that ... food? Everyone smuggled food down
            here? Unbelievable! You guys put our lives in danger because you couldn't go without a
            snack for a day? You're all awful! <charAction>He looks in wonder at a custard tart, and
                his stomach growls.</charAction> So hungry. Is that an egg custard in that tart?
                <charAction>He turns to see dozens of canyon crawlers approaching, and they all try
                to flee.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh no, that's a lot of canyon crawlers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Taking out his boomerang.</charAction> We barely survived one!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">They're coming back for me! They've had a taste and they're coming back for
            me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, wait. <charAction>Stops him as he runs forward.</charAction> I don't care
            about this stupid feud, I just want us to get out of here alive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Me too. I only took their side 'cause they fed me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to show Aang fighting off the canyon crawlers, and soon has
                them all in a pile. The crawlers pick themselves up and target the refugees. Though
                Aang, Katara, Sokka, and the tribe leaders fight hard to hold them off, they are
                vastly out numbered. Aang looks around to see the crawlers eating the food out of
                the bags.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> Everybody, watch me and do what I do!
                <charAction>He distracts a crawler with a piece of food, leaps on its back, and
                throws a bag over its snout. The two tribes mimic him, working
                together.</charAction> Now follow me! We're riding out of this hole!
                <charAction>Aang ties a huge bag of food onto a stick and uses it to guide the
                crawlers up the canyon wall.</charAction> Everyone, get off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>Jumping off a crawler.</charAction> We made it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As soon as all the people have made it up the cliff, Aang throws the bag
                back down, and the crawlers follow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">I never thought a Gan Jin could get his hands dirty like that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">And I never knew you Zhangs were so reliable in a pinch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Perhaps we're not so different after all. <charAction>They both smile at each other
                and Aang sighs in relief.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Too bad we can't rewrite history. You thieves stole our sacred orb from Jin Wei!
                <charAction>Draws his sword.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>Draws her sword.</charAction> You tyrants unjustly imprisoned Wei Jin
            for twenty long years!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sighs in frustration.</charAction> Wait a second ... Jin Wei? Wei Jin? I
            know those guys!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">Yes, yes, we're all aware of the story.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I mean I really knew them. I might not look it, but
            I'm a hundred and twelve years old. I was there one hundred years ago on the day you're
            talking about. <charAction>Scene fades to show the two men facing each other.
                Voice-over.</charAction> There seems to be a lot of confusion about what happened.
            First of all, Jin Wei and Wei Jin weren't enemies. They were brothers, twins in fact,
            and they were eight; and most importantly, they were just playing a game! The sacred orb
            from the legend, that was the ball! And the eastern and western gates were the goal
            posts. Jin Wei had the ball and was running toward the goal when he fell and fumbled it.
            Wei Jin didn't steal the ball, he picked it up and started running it toward the other
            goal, but he stepped out of bounds, so the official put him in the penalty box. Not for
            twenty long years but for two short minutes. <charAction>Fades back to
                Aang.</charAction> There was no stealing and no putting anyone in imprison, it was
            just a game.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">You're saying the sacred orb was actually a sacred ball?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nope, just a regular ball.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin man">What about our tribe's redemption ritual?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's what the game was called, redemption. As soon as you got the ball from one
            end to the other, everyone would yell "redemption"! <charAction>The tribe leaders look
                at each other skeptically.</charAction> Don't get me wrong, Wei Jin was kind of a
            slob and Jin Wei was a little stuffy, that much is true. But they respected each other's
            differences enough to share the same playing field.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">
         <charAction>To the Gan Jin leader.</charAction> I suppose it's time we forget the
            past.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">
         <charAction>Bowing.</charAction> And look to the future.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Zhang leader bows back and Aang looks at them happily. The scene fades
                to show them standing with Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good to see you, boy. Did you miss me? <charAction>Appa licks Aang as the Gan Jin
                leader approaches.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">I cannot thank you enough, Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Covered in Appa's slobber.</charAction> Well, you know I try.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gan Jin leader">
         <charAction>Recoils in disgust.</charAction> Ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to show the two tribes standing together.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhang leader">Let us travel to the Earth Kingdom capital as one tribe. <charAction>Both tribes
                cheer as they start walking.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Canyon guide">
         <charAction>Running forward.</charAction> I'm going too! I'm sick of this
            place!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That's some luck you knew Jin Wei and Wei Jin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You could call it luck. Or you could call it lying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Flabbergasted.</charAction> What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I made the whole thing up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You did not! <charAction>In devilish
                admiration.</charAction> That is so wrong.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Now where is that custard tart? I'm starving!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
