<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="4">The Warriors of Kyoshi</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Nick Malis</writer>
      <date>2005-03-04</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens, depicting a clear, starry night sky, the camera panning
                downwards to the open sea where Zuko's ship sails through the water. Cut to shot of
                inside Zuko's bedroom, the camera panning to the right to portray the entirety of
                the room. Zuko is seen meditating in his cabin, his back to the camera. The glow of
                the four candles situated on a table steadily increases and decreases in time with
                the prince's relaxed inhalations and exhalations. Cut to frontal shot of Zuko
                sitting peacefully with his eyes closed, the four candles in view, continually
                brightening and dimming. Cut to side-view shot of Zuko's head, the door to his cabin
                in view. Iroh cracks open the door and peeks through while Zuko opens his
                eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> The only reason you should be interrupting me, is
            if you have news about the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Pushes open the door completely and enters the room, holding a rolled up
                scroll in his hands.</charAction> Well, there is news, Prince Zuko, but you might
            not like it. Don't get too upset.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to shot of the prince sitting motionless, still assuming his
                meditative stance, his back to the camera. Calmly.</charAction> Uncle, you taught me
            that keeping a level head is a sign of a great leader. Now, whatever you have to say,
            I'm sure I can take it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Zuko, Iroh tugging his small beard in the
                background.</charAction> Okay then. <charAction>Hesitatingly.</charAction> We have
            no idea where he is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The flames of the candles suddenly erupt in a fiery mass, brushing the
                ceiling and obscuring Zuko from sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Enraged.</charAction> What!?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider shot of the room as Zuko rises to his feet, enraged. Iroh
                shields his face from the flames, and merely withdraws a fan from his robe and
                begins waving it to cool himself down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You really should open a window in here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He snatches the scroll from Iroh's hand.</charAction> Give me the map!
                <charAction>He unrolls it, scanning over the parchment.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Well, there have been multiple sightings of the Avatar, but he is impossible to
            track down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Desperately.</charAction> How am I going to find him, Uncle?
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of the map in Zuko's hand, several locations marked down
                with zigzagged lines connecting each point; Voice-over.</charAction> He is clearly a
            master of evasive maneuvering.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot of his map fades to a shot of the team's own map, minus the
                zigzagged lines, Sokka holding it in his hands. Cut to shot of him pouring over the
                map and questioning Aang's navigational skills.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> You have no idea where you're going, do
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of the entire group mounted on Appa. The siblings are riding in
                his saddle while Aang sits atop his head, looking back. Appa's fur seems dirty and
                disordered.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well ... <charAction>Happily.</charAction> I know it's near water.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene cut to overhead view of Appa flying over a vast body of
                water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> I guess we're getting close then.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of Katara, who is preoccupied with sewing a hole in Sokka's
                pants, Aang glancing over at her from atop Appa's head, Momo perched on his
                shoulder. He concocts an idea to impress her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Momo, marbles please. <charAction>Close-up of Momo who dives into his shirt and
                emerges, handing Aang two small, gray marbles.</charAction> Hey Katara, check out
            this airbending trick!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Using airbending, Aang manages to spin the two marbles quickly along an
                equatorial plane as he grins happily. Cut to side-view of Aang and Katara, Katara
                taking no notice and continues to sew.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly, still focusing on her task at hand.</charAction> That's
            great, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed, stops performing the trick.</charAction> You didn't even
            look.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks over Aang and attempts to show enthusiasm.</charAction> That's
            great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> But I'm not doing it now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to shot of Katara and Sokka seated on Appa's saddle. Sokka waves his
                arm breezily at Aang as if he is trying to shoo him away.</charAction> Stop bugging
            her, airhead. You need to give girls space when they do their sewing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close side-view shot of Katara as she casts her brother an annoyed
                glare; irritably.</charAction> What does me being a girl have to do with
            sewing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot of Sokka lazily resting with his arms behind his
                head.</charAction> Simple. Girls are better at fixing pants than guys and guys are
            better at hunting and fighting and stuff like that. <charAction>Cut back to an annoyed
                Katara.</charAction> It's just the natural order of things.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Suddenly smiles. Sarcastically.</charAction> All done with your pants!
                <charAction>Shows that the pants are still ripped.</charAction> And look what a
            great job I did!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara angrily tosses the pants in his direction. Cut to shot of Sokka as
                the pair of pants hit him in the face, covering it. He quickly scrambles to free
                himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Protesting and pleading.</charAction> Wait! I was just kidding.
                <charAction>Sticks one arm through the large hole in his pants.</charAction> I can't
            wear these! Katara, please!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a frontal view of Aang with the duo in the background.
                Enthusiastically.</charAction> Relax, Sokka. Where we're going, you won't need any
            pants.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang yanks Appa's reins to the left, his tongue sticking out of the corner
                of his mouth. Appa picks up speed as he flies right passed the camera. Cut to an
                overview shot of an island covered with mountains. Switch to a far off shot of a
                beach, where Appa has landed and Team Avatar has dismounted.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We just made a pit stop yesterday. Shouldn't we get a little more flying done before
            we camp out?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to close frontal view of Aang who is looking at something, his hand
                held against his brow. The siblings stand in the background.</charAction> He's
            right. At this rate, we won't get to the North Pole until spring.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Camera moves back to reveal Appa as well. Innocently.</charAction> But
            Appa's tired, aren't you boy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa does not react at all apart from a mild grunt, which comes across less
                than convincing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Nudges Appa against his front leg with his elbow.</charAction> I
                said, >aren't you boy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa puts slightly more enthusiasm behind his response the second time by
                grunting louder and opening up his mouth wide as if he was yawning.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aang smiles over his shoulder at the duo. Sarcastically.</charAction>
            Yeah, that was real >convincing.<charAction>Somewhat
                fearfully.</charAction> Still, hard to argue with a ten-ton magical
            monster.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Runs toward the shore, takes a sharp breath and points.
                Excitedly.</charAction> Look!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overview shot of the bay. Aang is standing on the beach, pointing
                and looking at the water where an elephant koi jumps out the water and back in,
                creating a giant splash. Switch to a shot of the two siblings staring in awe at the
                giant fish. Cut to a view from behind Sokka and Katara with Aang visible between the
                back of their heads.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> That's why we're here. <charAction>Starts to
                disrobe while more koi fish jump out of the water in the background.</charAction>
            Elephant koi, and I'm gonna ride it. Katara, you've got to watch me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a side-view of the coastline as Aang runs up and dives in. As soon
                as he submerges, he jumps out again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Cold!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to Katara and Sokka, still standing on shore, they exchange glances
                while Appa walks away, clearly taking interest in something else. Sokka makes a
                circular motion with his left hand around near his left temple, signaling to his
                sister that he thinks Aang is crazy. Cut back to Aang who is swimming toward the
                deep waters of the bay where the koi fish are. He dives under and immediately
                appears again, now holding on to the back fin of one of these giant animals as it
                jumps out of the water before diving again. Cut back to the siblings. Katara smiles
                broadly and impressed at the sight of Aang riding the koi fish while Sokka stares at
                the scene with an uninterested look upon his face and his arms crossed. Cut to a
                broader view, Sokka and Katara are with their back toward the camera. Momo is
                jumping excitedly up and down as Aang's koi fish reappears again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Switch to a close-up of Aang atop the fish's back, waving at his
                friends.</charAction> Hahaha, hahaha!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to Katara who enthusiastically waves back.</charAction>
            Whooh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a frontal view of Aang riding the koi. Two other koi jump out of
                the water behind him to the left and right. Aang is still laughing loud with
                excitement as they race through the water. Cut to an overview shot of the bay as the
                three koi playfully jump out the water before diving. Switch to an underwater shot
                of Aang and the fish. Cut to a shot of Katara and Sokka on the beach. Momo is still
                excitedly jumping up and down while Katara addresses her brother who still has his
                arms crossed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> He looks pretty good out there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Unimpressed.</charAction> Are you kidding? <charAction>Lazily gestures
                at Aang in the water.</charAction> The fish is doing all the work.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Notices something behind Sokka and runs off screen.</charAction> No,
            Appa. Don't eat that! <charAction>Appa grunts.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to a widely smiling Aang atop the fish, presumably in an
                attempt to impress Katara. Switches to off the shore from his perspective as Katara
                runs off inland. Close-up of Aang's disappointed face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed, the smile having faded off his face.</charAction> Oh man
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the water, the backs of the three koi fish in
                view. Two koi fish suddenly change direction, including Aang's, swerving to the
                bottom-right of the screen, leaving behind one koi fish that continues to race
                forward. The camera pans up, the dark shadow of a large body appears beneath the
                water's surface directly behind the koi fish. Switch to a close shot of
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> There's something in the water!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of one koi fish as it attempts to leap out of the water only to
                be pulled back under the surface by something unknown. Cut to a frontal shot of Aang
                still surfing on the koi fish's back, smiling widely, unaware of the danger. Katara
                reappears next to her brother again while Momo is screeching in alarm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> What's wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang's in trouble. Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Get out of there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang who grips the dorsal fin of the fish, his smile having now
                faded. He looks surprised at the commotion on the shore. Cut to shot of the shore
                from his perspective, Katara and Sokka motioning for him to exit the water by
                flailing their arms and calling to him from far away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Get back here, Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to a shot of Aang, who, believing them to be cheering him on,
                waves only to suddenly be hurled off the koi fish, into the water when the koi fish
                is being pulled under.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Flailing his arms and legs.</charAction> Whaaaahh! Aaaah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide-open shot of the lake, Aang plunging into the water as the koi
                fish he was mounted atop disappears under the water. Cut to Aang who resurfaces and
                gasps for breath as the massive dorsal fin of the unknown creature emerges from the
                surface directly behind him. Cut a wider shot of entire dorsal fin and a shot of
                Aang who turns around, suddenly alarmed by the sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frightened.</charAction> Whaaaahh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to wide-view shot of the lake, the dorsal fin of the creature swerving
                off to the side as Aang uses airbending to run across the surface of the lake at
                lightning speed. Cut to a frontal shot of a heavily panting Aang fleeing the scene,
                his feet treading water, the creature following him in hot pursuit. Cut to overhead
                shot of the lake, Aang a mere speck in the water, a trail of white foam behind him,
                the creature gaining on him. Cut to shot of Sokka and Katara standing on the shore.
                Sokka suddenly grows alarmed as Aang collides straight into him, having reached the
                shore safely. Cut to shot of the entire lake and shore as the dorsal fin of the
                creature disappears beneath the surface. Katara runs to where her brother and Aang
                have come to a halt. Cut to shot of Sokka leaning against a tree trunk, a trail
                marking where his body slid across the ground. Aang is seen dressing himself as
                Katara and Momo approach the two.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What was that thing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stands up and wipes his hands together.</charAction> Well, let's not
            stick around to find out. Time to hit the road.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans upward to where several female warriors clad in green
                kimonos descend from the treetops ambushing the trio. The women quickly encircle the
                group and take them out. Cut to Sokka who is being pulled back and knocked over.
                Switch to a shot of Katara with Aang in the background. Katara is pulled by her arm.
                As she leans in to maintain her balance, someone pulls her parka over her head and
                pulls her down. Aang is distracted by Katara's struggles, giving the opportunity to
                another female warrior to grab him by his collar. Momo flies up screeching from his
                shoulder, only to be quickly caught in a bag, only his head still protruding. Cut to
                a shot of the ground when a bound and blindfolded Momo, Aang, Katara, and Sokka are
                thrown on the ground in a line, each grunting when they hit the ground. They are
                surrounded by the female warriors.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Or, we could stay a while.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera switches to a shot of the beginning of a snowy path. The camera
                pans up, revealing that the path leads to a village in the distance. Cut to a shot
                of the back of a man while the scene pans to the left. The man addresses Aang,
                Sokka, and Katara who are still blindfolded and tied to a large wooden pole. The
                bagged Momo stands on the ground in front of Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> You three have some explaining to do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves even further to the left, revealing the back of one of the
                woman dressed in green that ambushed the group earlier.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> And if you don't answer all our questions,
            we're throwing you back in the water with the Unagi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up of the blindfolded Sokka. Challenging.</charAction> Show
            yourselves, cowards!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A gloved hand, the forearm dressed in a leather band with a gold insignia
                on top of it, removes the blindfold. The scene switches to Sokka's point of view.
                Five girls in green kimonos and wearing white and red face paint are standing in
                front of him. Cut to a side-view shot, panning to the right.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aggressively.</charAction> Who are you? Where are the men who ambushed
            us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Stepping forward, gesturing heavily with her clenched fist.
                Indignantly.</charAction> There were no men. We ambushed you. Now tell us, who are
            you and what are you doing here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Closer side-view shot of Sokka who stares at them in
                disbelief.</charAction> Wait a second, <charAction>He amusingly glance to his right
                to where Aang stands as if he is looking for confirmation. Mockingly.</charAction>
            there's no way that a bunch of girls took us down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Grabs Sokka by his collar. Angrily.</charAction> A bunch of girls, huh?
            The Unagi's gonna eat well tonight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Leans forward in her bonds. Pleading and apologetically.</charAction>
            No, don't hurt him! He didn't mean it. My brother is just an idiot sometimes.
                <charAction>Suki released Sokka, but still stares at him in
            dismay.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's my fault. <charAction>The three teenagers looks surprised at Aang's words. The
                camera pans the left to reveal a sorrowfully looking Aang.</charAction> I'm sorry we
            came here. I wanted to ride the elephant koi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Cut to a frontal view of Oyaji. Angrily.</charAction> How do we know
            you're not <charAction>Points at the bound three.</charAction> Fire Nation spies? Kyoshi
            stayed out of the war so far. And we intend to keep it that way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut back to Aang, a brightened expression on his face.</charAction> This
            island is named for Kyoshi? I know Kyoshi!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Humorless.</charAction> Ha! How could you possibly know her?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to Oyaji's point of view as the camera pans up. At the top of the
                wooden pole stands a statue of a tall woman holding two stretched open fans. She is
                dressed in a similar outfit as the female warriors that ambushed the
                group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">Avatar Kyoshi was born here four hundred years ago. <charAction>Close-up of the face
                of the statue. The colors have faded away a bit, but it is still clear that Kyoshi
                wears the same white face paint, with the red accentuated eyes as the modern Kyoshi
                Warriors wear.</charAction> She's been dead for centuries.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang who looks pensive at the statue before looking at the ground
                in front of him. He speaks in a soft, calm voice while the camera slowly zooms in on
                him.</charAction> I know her because I'm the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Suki and Oyaji with the other Kyoshi Warriors standing in
                the background. Oyaji looks shocked at Aang's revelation.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Not convinced by Aang's statement. Shaking her fist to emphasize her
                words.</charAction> That's impossible! The last Avatar was an airbender who
            disappeared a hundred years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and his friend from a point of view between Suki and Oyaji.
                Aang smiles sheepishly.</charAction> That's me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Cut to frontal view of Suki and Oyaji who angrily points at Aang while
                looking at Suki.</charAction> Throw the impostor to the Unagi!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki and the rest of her warriors immediately retract their metal fans from
                out of their belts and slid them open. Ready to counter any sudden attack, they
                threateningly start to move forward and surround the bound friends. Cut to a close
                shot of Katara as she leans forward in the ropes, glancing to her right where Aang
                is bound to the pole.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Aang ... do some airbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera pans to the left, passing Sokka who is looking at the female
                warriors, his mouth open in shock and stopping at Aang who looks questioningly at
                Katara for a moment. Cut to an overview shot of the scene as Aang bends over before
                pushing himself off the ground. He leaves a large dust cloud as he shoots in the
                air, stretching out his ropes, using one of the outstretched fans of the statue to
                snap them in half. Now completely free of his bonds, he tumbles elegantly over the
                statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Spectators">
         <charAction>Talking all at once.</charAction> Wow! Did you see that?
            Airbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang lands gently on the ground in front of the surprised crowd, his robes
                still fluttering in the air. Oyaji and the Kyoshi Warriors stare at him in shock. A
                lot more people have gather around to see what is going on. Unlike the female
                warriors, Oyaji and the other civilians are dressed in blue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>In awe.</charAction> It's true ... you are the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a frontal view of Aang with a serious look on his face, a
                relieved Sokka and Katara still tied up in the background to his left.</charAction>
            Now ... <charAction>He pulls his marbles out from underneath his robes.</charAction>
            check this out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He performs his trick again, letting the marbles spins around really fast
                between his hands. Grinning and blinking like a fool, he looks at the crowd, hoping
                to impress them. Cut to the cheering crowd. A young man in the front starts to emit
                a high pitched squeal while widely tossing his hands up in the air in admiration. He
                gets so overexcited that he starts to foam, fall toward the camera, and faints; the
                rest of the villagers just keep on cheering.</description>
      <description>Cut to a side-view of the harbor of Kyoshi island, where one of the village
                girls runs up a dock toward a fisherman who is fiddling with his basket of
                fish.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Little girl">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Did you hear the news? <charAction>The fisherman
                picks up his basket.</charAction> The Avatar's on Kyoshi!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fisherman">
         <charAction>Due to his utter surprise, he drops his basket.</charAction>
            Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The fisherman picks his basket up again and turns around. The scene fades
                over to a scene in a street where the fisherman delivers the basket to the
                fishmonger while passing on the news of the Avatar's whereabouts. The fishmonger
                turns around and the scene fades away again to another scene where the fishmonger
                sells one of the fish to a servant, dressed in Fire Nation red. He too passes on the
                news. When the servant turns around, the scene fades to inside Zuko's ship where the
                servant is serving the cooked fish at the table of Zuko and Iroh. Cut to a frontal
                view of Zuko as he quickly stands up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Yells on a demanding tone.</charAction> The Avatar's on Kyoshi Island?
                <charAction>Cut to a frontal shot of Iroh as Zuko addresses him while leaving the
                room. Iroh looks at Zuko as he walks away.</charAction> Uncle, ready the rhinos.
            He's not getting away from me this time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Casually points at the smoking fish in front of him.</charAction> Are
            you going to finish that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns around and snatches the plate off the table.
                Aggressively.</charAction> I was going to save it for later!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko leaves the room under the watchful eye of Iroh. As soon as Zuko is out
                of the screen, Iroh crosses his arms, turns around, and sulks.</description>
      <description>The shot switches to a close-up of Kyoshi's statue's wooden face as it is
                being repainted. The right side of her face is already done and the previous cracks
                are not visible anymore. The painter carefully reapplies her left eyebrow with black
                paint. A back view shot of the statue shows the main street of Kyoshi village with
                houses at both sides and one bigger house at the end of the street. Another villager
                is cleaning the back of the statue with a broom. The camera pans to the right until
                the big house becomes the center of the shot before cutting to a shot of Appa who
                lazily lies on his side, eating hay while two villagers are grooming him. He growls
                and chews while the camera pans the left and up to focus on three open windows of
                the main house on the first floor. Cut to a side-view of inside the house where
                Aang, Katara, and Momo are sitting at a long table. A villager places another dish
                on the already richly filled table. Aang and Momo are very excited to see the
                display of decadent desserts in front of it, but Katara supports an uneasy
                look.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Throws his arms in the air while Momo digs in and chitters.
                Ecstatic.</charAction> All right! Dessert for breakfast!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara pokes one of the squishy looking, orange puffs with a flat top in
                front of her. Cut to a frontal view of the two as a doubtful Katara picks up and
                closely investigates the dessert she just pokes. Aang on the other hand does not
                share her reluctance and starts stuffing his face, two desserts at
                once.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">These people sure know <charAction>The rest is kind of muffled out because he is
                cramming his desserts in his mouth.</charAction> how to treat an Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara still is not convinced about the deliciousness of the dessert she is
                holding. Glances at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Impressed.</charAction> Mmm ... <charAction>Offers one of the desserts
                he is holding to Katara.</charAction> Katara you've got to try these!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Puts down the orange dessert, accepts the dessert Aang offers her and
                takes a bit.</charAction> Well, maybe just a bite.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo sneaks up to Aang and snatches the dessert out of his other hand and
                quickly dashes away, who smiles at his pet. He does not let the theft bother him and
                quickly gabs another dessert in front of him while Katara munches down the piece of
                cake and reaches across the table for the same dessert Aang just took. Aang glances
                to his left, over the hunched Katara to Sokka. Momo appears between Aang and Katara
                and quickly snatches another cupcake from the table before vanishing underneath
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka, what's your problem? Eat!>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Sokka who is sitting in a corner, walking with his arms crossed
                while staring in front of him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Not hungry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aang leans backward to be able to look past Katara to Sokka; his eyes
                wide open in surprise.</charAction> But you're always hungry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wide shot of the room, Aang in front, Sokka in the back. It is
                shown that the amount of desserts has dwindled severely.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Glancing amusingly at Aang. Slightly mocking.</charAction> He's just
            upset because a bunch of girls kicked his butt yesterday.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Protesting.</charAction> They snuck up on me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Mockingly looks at her brother.</charAction> Right. And then they kicked
            your butt.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider shot of the table. Momo is lying underneath the table with
                his front paws around a bunch a pastries he collected. He is chewing while Sokka
                angrily stands up in the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Indignant.</charAction> Sneak attacks don't count! <charAction>Walks out
                of the scene with big strides. Mumbling to himself.</charAction> Tie me up with
            ropes! I'll show them a thing or two. <charAction>Comes back to the table to face Katara
                and Aang. Momo grabs some more pastries that lie around him.</charAction> I'm not
            scared of any girls. <charAction>Snatches some of the desert of the table.</charAction>
            Who do they think they are anyway? <charAction>He shoves one of the deserts in his mouth
                and stalks off again.</charAction> Mmm ... this is tasty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Front view of Aang and Katara. In the back villagers are still working on
                beautifying the statue of Kyoshi. Aang is still holding one of the sweets as he
                looks at Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What's he so angry about? <charAction>Excited.</charAction> It's great here. They're
            giving us the royal treatment!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hey, don't get too comfortable. It's risky for us to stay in one place for very
            long.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo's arm comes into view from underneath the table. He scans the table
                for new pastries to snatch.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Lowers his arm with the pastry and offers it to Momo's grasping
                paw.</charAction> I'm sure we'll be fine. <charAction>The lemur feels the desert and
                quickly snatches it out of Aang's hand.</charAction> Besides, did you see how happy
            I'm making this town? <charAction>Aang moves closer to Katara and turns around to look
                out of the window at the statue.</charAction> They're even cleaning up that statue
            in my honor!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Well, it's nice to see you excited about being the Avatar. <charAction>Slightly
                concerned.</charAction> I just hope it doesn't all go to your head.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Reassuring.</charAction> Come on, you know me better than that. I'm just
            a simple monk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang gets up and leans on the window sill so he can look better outside. As
                soon as he emerges, the villagers scream with delight and admiration for him. Aang
                looks down in surprise to see where the sound came from. The camera switches to his
                point of view and reveals a bunch a little girls cheering for him; Koko is among
                them in the front row. The camera cuts back to Aang who flashes a broad smile at the
                girls while blushing. Katara is standing behind him with her arms crossed in
                disapproval. She rolls her eyes and makes a raspberry.</description>
      <description>The shot changes to a side-view of a brownish-red bridge over a small
                creek. Aang quickly runs over it from the right to the left, trailed by four
                screaming fangirls. They run out of the picture, but Aang quickly comes back and
                traverses the bridge again, now from left to right. The girls are still following
                him, screaming loudly with the same amount of enthusiasm. They run out of the
                picture again, but once again, Aang runs back in. He runs up the bridge, but halts
                in the middle, looking from left to right as he sees that hordes of fangirls are
                trapping him on the bridge as they run up from both sides. Before they can reach
                him, the airbender leaps in the air. Cut to a closer shot of the girls in the middle
                of the bridge as they are still screaming and reaching for the sky. They gasp for
                air in admiration when they see that Aang is suspended in the air by clinging to an
                airball. The ball, however, slowly reduces in size until it vanishes completely.
                Aang looks scared as he drops down into the crowd of little girl who happily catch
                him.</description>
      <description>Switch to a shot of Aang and Koko standing serene with a waterfall in the
                background. A painter is measuring their proportions with his brush. Aang and Koko
                are obscured from sight as the artist raises his canvas and starts painting the
                outlines of Koko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Painter">
         <charAction>Muttering to himself.</charAction> Hmmm ... Painting the Avatar ...
            that's easy enough ... <charAction>He lowers the canvas and notices that another girl
                has pulled up next to Aang. Surprised.</charAction> Oh, there's another one ...
                <charAction>He obscures his models again from sight by raising his canvas and
                painting the outlines of the other girl.</charAction> Well, I'll make an adjustment
            here, and ... <charAction>He lowers the canvas to see that three more girls have joined
                Aang.</charAction> There's more ... <charAction>He obscures the Avatar and his
                fangirls from sight again with his canvas while he quickly paints Aang.</charAction>
            well that ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The painter lowers his canvas again and discovers that Aang is now
                surrounded by sixteen little girls. The camera switches to the annoyed face of the
                painter. As he stares at his models, his brush drips on his painting. Close shot of
                Aang and the fangirls as they all push and pull to be as close to Aang as possible.
                They are all smiling widely and giggling while Aang looks somewhat horrified by all
                the girls around him. A side-view of the scene shows that some girls are completely
                leaning on others in order to have a spot on the painting. The painter gets up and
                walks away without saying a word, while the tower of people crashes under its own
                weight.</description>
      <description>Switch to a shot of Aang and his fangirls back in the village. A frontal
                shot of the monk shows that he is doing push-ups while Momo is sitting on his back
                and his fangirls have lined up in a semi-circle behind him. After three push-ups,
                Aang starts to do one handed push-ups and soon switches to no handed push-ups, but
                pushing himself up with his airbending. The girls stare at him in admiration. Cut to
                a wider view as Katara walks past carrying a basket. A look of disapproval dons her
                face as she keeps on walking without even glancing at the Avatar.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a small house surrounded by trees. Sokka walks up to
                it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily grunting to himself.</charAction> I can't believe I got beat up
            by a bunch of girls.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Inside the house, six Kyoshi Warriors are training. They are performing a
                routing with a fan in perfect unison. Sokka peeks his head around the door to look
                at them. He smiles smugly and enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Condescending.</charAction> Sorry ladies, <charAction>Suki and the other
                warriors stop their exercise and close their fans. They stare at Sokka with a
                serious look on their faces.</charAction> didn't mean to interrupt your dance
            lesson. <charAction>The camera moves back, revealing that Sokka was
                stretching.</charAction> I was just looking for somewhere to get a little
            workout?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Looks at how Sokka continues his warm up.</charAction> Well, you're in
            the right place. <charAction>Cut to a side-view while Sokka is loosening up his
                hips.</charAction> Sorry about yesterday. I didn't know that you were friends with
            the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stretching his arms.</charAction> It's all right. <charAction>Mockingly
                suppressing a laugh while speaking.</charAction> I mean, normally I'd hold a grudge,
            but seeing as you guys are a bunch of girls, I'll make an exception.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> I should hope so. A big strong man like you?
            We wouldn't stand a chance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Smugly.</charAction> True. But don't feel bad. After all, I'm the best
            warrior in my village.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Keeps using sarcasm without Sokka catching on to it. Leans slightly
                toward Sokka.</charAction> Wow! Best warrior, huh? <charAction>Glances back to the
                other Kyoshi Warriors.</charAction> In your whole village? <charAction>Looks back to
                Sokka.</charAction> Maybe you'd be kind enough to give us a little
            demonstration.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Sokka as his eyes widen upon hearing the unexpected
                request.</charAction> Oh ... Well ... I mean ... I ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Turns to the other warriors.</charAction> Come on, girls! Wouldn't you
            like him to show us some moves?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera switches position and shows the other female warrior giggling
                and smiling in agreement. Switch back to a side-view of Sokka and
                Suki.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, if that's what you want, I'd be happy to. <charAction>He places his hands on
                Suki's shoulder in order to push her back a little, but she does not move a
                bit.</charAction> All right, you stand over there. Now, this may be a little tough,
            but try to block me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While he is talking, Sokka takes on a fighting stance while Suki has not
                moved a muscle from the position Sokka has put her in. Sokka bends through his knees
                and attacks the female warrior by trying to punch her. Suki does not move, but
                easily defends herself by bringing up her left arm and thrusting her closed fan
                against Sokka's shoulder. His cries out in pain and staggers backward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Rubbing his hurt right shoulder. Impressed.</charAction> Aw! Heh heh ...
            Good. Of course, I was going easy on you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Close-up of Suki's confident face.</charAction> Of course.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a side-view. Sokka is clearly annoyed and angered by Suki's arrogant
                facial expression.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He starts with a mumble, raising his tone of voice with each
                word.</charAction> Let's see if you can <charAction>Shouting while he attempts to
                hit Suki with a roundhouse kick.</charAction> handle this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki quickly dodges under Sokka's outstretched leg and pushes him off
                balance. When the Water Tribe warrior lands flat on his back with a loud thud, Suki
                lazily opens her fans to wave herself some air. Sokka, a little shocked by his
                second failure, loses his temper at the sight of Suki's defiant
                posture.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>His voice cracking in anger.</charAction> That does it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He gets up and madly charges her again. Suki quickly closes her fan and
                moves out of Sokka's way. She grabs him by the arm with her right hand, while she
                pushes against his shoulder with her left hand, quickly spinning him around. After
                two turns, she switches position and spins Sokka in the other direction. Close-up of
                Sokka's distressed face as he is powerlessly being tossed around. Switch to a wider
                shot as Suki suddenly halts Sokka so he topples forward. Before falling down, Suki
                loosens Sokka's belt and ties his left hand to his right foot behind his back in one
                swift movement. Sokka tries so maintain his balance for a while by jumping on one
                leg, but it is not long before he loses footage and smacks down flat on his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> Anything else you want to teach us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka blushes in humiliation as the Kyoshi Warriors laugh at
                him.</description>
      <description>Switch to an overview of Kyoshi Village where Aang and his fangirls are
                standing before Kyoshi's statue. The camera slowly moves toward the group before
                changing to a bird view of Aang and the girls that are looking up at the statue. One
                girl to the right of Aang is carrying a passed out Momo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There she is, girls. Me in a past life.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switches to a frog view of the statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fangirls">Ooohhh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Admiringly.</charAction> You were pretty!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang turns to look at her with a wondering look upon his face. He looks at
                the rest of his fangirls like he is searching for someone.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding up a finger to draw their attention.</charAction> Excuse me for
            a second, ladies.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The girls do not say anything, but there cheerful expression changes to one
                of disappointment.</description>
      <description>The scene switches to a frontal view of Katara who filling a pot with
                groceries. Aang comes up behind her, smiling, and gives her a gentle poke to get her
                attention.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns around in surprise, but is happy to see that the poke came from
                Aang.</charAction> Oh, good! Can you help me carry this back to the room?
                <charAction>She moves the pot toward Aang.</charAction> It's a little
            heavy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding up his hands to fob off with the offered pot.</charAction>
            Actually, I can't right now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slightly irritated.</charAction> What do you mean, "you can't?"</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I promised the girls I'd give them a ride on Appa. Why don't you come with us? It'll
            be fun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Resumed filling the pot with more vegetables.</charAction> Watching you
            show off for a bunch of girls does not sound like fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> Well, neither does carrying your
            basket.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> It's not my basket. These supplies are for our
            trip. I told you, we have to leave Kyoshi soon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Central focus on Aang.</charAction> I don't want to leave Kyoshi yet. I
            can't put my finger on it, <charAction>He puts his hand to his chin in a thinking
                posture; the camera pans to the right, showing Aang's fangirls better in the
                background.</charAction> but there's something I really like about this
            place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The fangirls giggle. Shot switches to a closer shot of the
                girls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Stomping her foot in annoyance and puts her hands on her hips, while
                another girl happily waves at Aang; irritated.</charAction> What's taking you so
            long, Aangy?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Aang and Katara; the former enthusiastically waves back at his
                awaiting fangirls, while the latter raises an eyebrow at the scene.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slightly mocking.</charAction> Aangy ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Enthusiastically.</charAction> Just a second, Koko!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastic.</charAction> "Simple monk", huh?
                <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> I thought you promised me that this Avatar stuff
            wouldn't go to your head.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It didn't. You know what I think? You just don't want to come because you're
                jealous.>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close-up; angrily.</charAction> Jealous? <charAction>More high pitched
                voice.</charAction> Of what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a broader shot. Aang moves back slightly, when an irritated Katara
                resumes to ferociously stuff the basket with more fruits.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Jealous that we're having so much fun without you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> That's ridiculous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It is a little ridiculous, but I understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara turns to Aang, towering over him with her hands trust in her sides,
                like she is about to come down on him, but reconsiders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turning away; irritated.</charAction> Urch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She grabs the heavy basket and staggers away, while Aang's fangirls run on
                screen and crowd around him, pulling him backward out of the screen.</description>
      <description>Scene switches to Sokka who is standing outside of the Kyoshi Warriors'
                training hut. He kicks away a rock before turning toward the dojo. Cut to a shot
                from inside the dojo where Suki shows a movement that is copied by the eight other
                warriors behind here. Sokka walks in and the Kyoshi Warriors interrupt their
                training to face him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Timidly.</charAction> Uh ... Hey, Suki.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Hostile.</charAction> Hoping for another dance lesson?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot of Sokka who does not know how to act.</charAction> No ...
            I ... well, let me explain.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Close-up of Suki; hostile.</charAction> Spit it out! What do you
            want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sokka looks hurt at Suki's hostility. He humbly drops to his knees in
                front of her.</charAction> I would be honored if you would teach me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Frog view of Suki; hostile.</charAction> Even if I'm a girl?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Averting his eyes.</charAction> I'm sorry if I insulted you earlier. I
            was ... wrong.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Cut to a side-view of the two; Suki has her arms crossed while looking
                down upon Sokka.</charAction> We normally don't teach outsiders, let alone
            boys.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Raises his head to face her; pleading.</charAction> Please make an
            exception. <charAction>Bowing again.</charAction> I won't let you down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Frog view; on a friendlier tone.</charAction> All right. But you have to
            follow all of our traditions.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up; eagerly.</charAction> Of course!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> And I mean all of them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The episode jumps to a few moments later when Sokka is standing in the dojo
                donned in the typical green dress of the Kyoshi Warriors and sporting the white face
                paint.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Embarrassed looking down at his wardrobe.</charAction> Do I really have
            to wear this? It feels a little ... <charAction>Lower his arms in defeat.</charAction>
            girly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">It's a warrior's uniform, you should be proud. <charAction>Closeup of Sokka, the
                camera pans down to reveal the entire uniform close by.</charAction> The silk
            threads symbolize the brave blood that flows through our veins. The gold insignia
            represents the honor of the warrior's heart.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to a broader shot, Sokka looking more comfortable wearing "a
                dress." Aang passes by the front door looking in with interest while Sokka proudly
                erects himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Proudly.</charAction> Bravery and honor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Popping in; smiling broadly.</charAction> Hey Sokka! <charAction>Sokka
                winces upon hearing his name and slants his eyes and shoulders in
                embarrassment.</charAction> Nice dress!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki turns to Aang, who speeds away, and looks back to the embarrassed
                Sokka with a content and broader smile on her face.</description>
      <description>Cut to an outside-view of Aang walking through town. Switch to a close-up
                of a small cup filled with water. Katara is sitting beside it and moving her left
                hand over the cup, bending the water inside it. The camera follows the rising of the
                water and the scene changes to a broader view of the room. Katara is looking
                concentrated at the water when Aang walks in. She moves the plume of water up and
                down, right and left.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confidently.</charAction> Katara, remember how Unagi almost got me
            yesterday?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slants up her eyes in annoyance, which Aang can't see while continuing
                to practice her bending.</charAction> Yeah.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Bragging.</charAction> Well, I'm gonna go ride it now. It's gonna be
            real dangerous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Still not looking at Aang; disinterested.</charAction> Good for
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You're not going to stop me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Still disinterested.</charAction> Nope. Have fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Crossing his arms; defiant.</charAction> I will.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Growing irritated again.</charAction> Great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Annoyed at Katara's lack of interest.</charAction> I know it's
            great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> I'm glad you know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> I'm glad you're glad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> Good! <charAction>She loses control over the water
                and it splashed back into the bowl. Katara balls her fists in
                annoyance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Emphasizing his reacting by swinging his hands.</charAction>
            Fine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang angrily turns around to walk out of the door. Before he leaves,
                however, he already glances back to Katara with a sorrowful expression on his face.
                Right after he leaves the room, Katara crosses her arms in protection and glances at
                the door, looking sad as well. She turns her head and raises her eyes in a
                combination of annoyance and regret.</description>
      <description>Cut to a bird view shot of inside the Kyoshi Warriors' training dojo where
                Sokka is performing some exercises with a fan under the watchful eyes of
                Suki.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">You're not going to master it in one day. Even I'm not that good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I think I'm starting to get it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Sokka as he performs a series of well executed moves with his
                fan.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Tah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As a last move, he closes the fan on throws it out of the dojo. The object
                flies straight into a tree, knocking down some of snow that had gathered on its
                branches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Peeks her head around the door to look at the hit tree before turning
                back to Sokka. Friendly.</charAction> It's not about strength. Our technique is
            about using your opponents' force against them. Loosen up. <charAction>Retracts her own
                fan from her belt and points it at Sokka, who takes on a battle
                position.</charAction> Think of the fan as an extension of your arm.
                <charAction>Close-up of Sokka.</charAction> Wait for an opening and then
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki charges Sokka, but he manages to evade her attack and uses the
                momentum of her speed against her, knocking her on her behind, much to her
                surprise.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Looks surprised, quickly crosses his arms and looks smug.</charAction>
            Hmm ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Quickly gets up; irritated.</charAction> I fell on purpose to make you
            feel better!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Points at Suki, exclaims ecstaticly.</charAction> I got you! Admit I got
            you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suki grabs Sokka's pointing finger and twists it, making Sokka twitch and
                grunt in pain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">Okay, it was a lucky shot. <charAction>Releases the finger while smiling broadly. On
                a more serious tone.</charAction> Let's see if you can do it again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera moves to an overview shot as the two warriors prepare to battle
                again. Suki opens her fan threateningly and starts to circle around
                Sokka.</description>
      <description>Cut to a back view scene of Aang swimming in the water, while his troop of
                fangirls can be seen on the shore in the background. Switch to a close shot of the
                six girls, either sitting or lying on the shore in boredom.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Resting her head on her hand. Bored and impatiently.</charAction> What's
            taking so long?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up; reassuring.</charAction> I'm sure it will be here any second!
                <charAction>Looking for a way to entertain the girls.</charAction> What about
            this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang takes out his marbles and spins them around between his hands with his
                airbending, smiling hopefully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Little Girl">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Not that again.
            Boring>!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>The girls stand up. Waving her arms to emphasize her
                question.</charAction> Where's Unagi? It's getting late.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Waving from the water to the girls. Pleading.</charAction> Where're you
            going? Don't leave!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Koko">
         <charAction>Holds her hands to her mouth to emphasize her yelling.</charAction>
            Sorry, Aang! Maybe next time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As the girls leave, the camera moves to a close-up of a disappointed Aang.
                He lowers himself to be partially under the water and starts blowing bubbles. Switch
                to a shot of the shore, where the last of the girls is leaving, but their place is
                taken by Katara who just arrived. Aang jumps up from the water and
                smiles.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Katara! You showed up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Somewhat concerned.</charAction> I wanted to make sure you were safe.
            You really had me worried.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Back there you acted like you didn't care.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>In a regretful voice.</charAction> I'm sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Lowering his eyes.</charAction> Me too. I did let all that attention go
            to my head. I was being a jerk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling. Puts her hands beside her mouth, yelling in a joking
                manner.</charAction> Well, get out of the water before you catch a cold, you big
            jerk!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling broadly and starts to swing toward the shore.</charAction> On my
            way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Side-view of Aang swimming to the shore, when suddenly a giant dorsal fin
                appears from out of the water behind him. Close-up of Katara as her eyes open in
                shock and she draws a sharp breath in horror. Cut back to Aang, who is, still
                oblivious to the danger behind him, swimming toward her with a smile on his face.
                Suddenly Aang is swept away by a wave and lifted out of the water, while he is
                screaming in panic. He looks around to find himself sitting on the back of Unagi as
                the monstrous eel erects itself before him, and directs a powerful jet of water to
                him. Aang withstands the water by holding on to one of the smaller dorsal fins of
                Unagi. The animal charges Aang and tries to eat him, but Aang narrowly escapes by
                catching one of Unagi's whiskers. Screaming his lungs out, he dangles from side to
                side in from of the big green eye of Unagi.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot from inside Unagi's mouth, looking out as Aang comes to a
                halt right in front of him. The enormous tongue moves from side to side in
                anticipation of the meal. Cut to a broader shot of the two as Unagi suddenly and
                violently moves his head in all directions, trying to snatch Aang of his
                whisker.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> Hang on, Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of a terrified Aang as he holds on to the whisker for dear life.
                Unagi tosses him some more from side to side, and Aang finally lets go from the
                force and speed of the throw. He is thrown through the air, still screaming loudly,
                and smacks in the water, not so far from where Katara is standing on the shore. He
                emerges back to the surface, clearly unconscious with his tongue out of his mouth.
                The camera pans up to show a heavily panting and fully clothed Katara entering the
                water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Unagi shrieks and dives under to get to his unconscious prey. Close-up of a
                worried Katara who is moving toward Aang through the water as fast as she can. The
                camera switches between shots of a rapidly approaching shadow underneath the water
                of Unagi, and a heavily panting Katara in her frantic effort to reach Aang before
                the eel. The moment Katara reaches Aang and takes him into her arm, Unagi emerges
                right in front of them. In an attempt to get away, Katara violently pushes the
                water, propelling herself and Aang backward with her waterbending; at the same time,
                Unagi snatches the water where they were just moments before. Although missing the
                duo, the impact of Unagi's attack creates a giant wave that slams Katara and Aang
                back to the rocks on shore. Angered, the animal spews power streams of water to the
                rocks before submerging again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Carefully peeking over the rock.</charAction> Zuko!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of the fast approaching ship of the banished prince. A side-view
                shows that the ship reaches shore at the same moment Unagi's large dorsal fin
                submerges completely underneath the water. Closer shot when the ship's walkway is
                lowered; a frontal shot of three riders mounted on komodo rhino's, with Zuko in the
                lead.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I want the Avatar alive.>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara crawls up some rocks to have a better view of the approaching prince
                and his soldiers. Switch to a scene of the sky that quickly pans down to reveal how
                Zuko and his man ride past Katara and Aang's hiding place. Katara protectively
                covers the body of the still unconscious Aang, while worriedly looking up and
                hearing the riders move past. When she is certain the riders have pass, Katara lays
                Aang on his back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Wake up, Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She looks around for a while before starting to move her left hand over his
                chest, while supporting his head with her right. She moves her hand from his chest
                to his mouth, and bends out the water he had swallowed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Coughing out the last of the water. In a weak voice.</charAction> Katara
            ... <charAction>Katara lovingly smiles at him with relief written all over her
                face.</charAction> don't ride Unagi. Not fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an outside shot of the Kyoshi Warriors' dojo. Inside Suki and Sokka
                are still training. Momo is hanging by his tail on one of the support beams of the
                roof. He has a collection of sweets with him which he is eating while watching the
                duo below him train. The camera moves closer to the duo on the ground, where Suki
                thrusts her hand, holding the fan forward, only to have it blocked by
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Smiling while impressed.</charAction> Not bad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka smiles back at her with confidence, when suddenly Oyaji appears in
                the door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Sokka and Suki worriedly turn to him. Alarmed.</charAction> Firebenders
            have landed on our shores! <charAction>Suki immediately runs to him while he turns to
                head back to the town.</charAction> Girls, come quickly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Protesting.</charAction> Hey, I'm not a ... <charAction>Momo jumps on
                his shoulder and pushes himself off toward the door. Conceding.</charAction> oh,
            whatever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka runs out of the room.</description>
      <description>The camera pans up to show the deserted main street of the village. Zuko
                and three other soldiers mounted on komodo rhinos are standing at the base of the
                Kyoshi statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Frog view close-up.</charAction> Come out, Avatar! <charAction>Camera
                pans from left to right, revealing how several villagers are hiding in the nearby
                houses.</charAction> You can't hide from me forever! <charAction>Camera focuses on
                the four riders while moving away from them over the main street, showing that there
                is not any movement in the village. Side-view of Zuko.</charAction> Find
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko gives the command, the camera follows how the other three rhinos
                move into town. Cut to a shot of a fan being opened on a nearby roof. Cut to a side
                shot of two rhinos with their riders as one of the Kyoshi Warriors quickly passes
                them by behind some houses. Cut to a frontal view of the three rhinos, before
                switching to a shot of the running feet of a Kyoshi Warrior atop a snowy roof. When
                she pushes herself off, the scene switches to a frog view of the three rhinos and
                there riders as three Kyoshi Warriors come jumping toward them from atop nearby
                roofs, knocking off some of the riders. A Kyoshi Warriors lands in front of the lead
                rhino and opens her fans. The rider stabs at her with his spear. She moves to the
                right, disarms the rider, and jumps up to knock him off his steed with a spinning
                kick. Suki can be seen running past in the background.</description>
      <description>Cut to a frontal view of a concentrated Suki while she runs toward Zuko.
                Switch to a back view of Suki, who moves to the left to avoid a fire blast of the
                prince. She jumps over another blast and tries to attack Zuko from the air, but he
                turns his rhino. The beast slams Suki away with a might sweep of his tail, knocking
                her down. Zuko shoots a fire blast at the downed warrior, but right before it would
                have burned her, Sokka jumps before her and decimates the flames with a sweep of his
                fan. Sokka prepares to fight Zuko, but before he can do anything, another Kyoshi
                Warrior jumps of a nearby roof and knocks a surprised Zuko of his rhino; the beast
                dashes away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I guess training's over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka glances at Suki before running to the downed prince. Close-up of Zuko
                angrily opening his eyes. The camera moves back to reveal how Sokka, Suki, and the
                other Kyoshi Warrior all take on a fighting stance. Zuko pushes himself up and
                rapidly spins around on his hand while shooting fire out of his feet, knocking the
                Kyoshi Warrior back into the house and slamming Suki against a wooden pole, where
                she collapses in pain. Zuko proceeds with a low fire kick in Sokka's direction. The
                Water Tribe Warrior jumps over the fire, but as soon as he lands again, Zuko sweeps
                his feet from underneath him. Sokka falls in his back, and Zuko jumps over him to
                the middle of the street. He angrily looks around. Camera moves back to reveal the
                completely deserted street.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Nice try, Avatar! But these little girls can't save you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up of Zuko.</charAction> Hey! Over here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns around. Close-up of a determined Aang standing at the beginning
                of the main street, holding his staff in front of him like he is challenging the
                prince.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Finally!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko commences by sending two fire balls in Aang's direction. Back view of
                Aang as he prepares to face the incoming, burning projectiles. He ducks underneath
                the first and uses his staff to decimate the next fire ball. He rapidly spins the
                staff over his head, propelling himself in the air. He lands in front of Zuko, who
                immediately kicks the staff out of his hands. Aang jumps up and lands between two
                fans of a Kyoshi Warrior that are lying on the ground. He stands up and picks us the
                fan with his airbending. Close-up of Zuko, who madly charges Aang with his fist
                already held stretched out before him. Aang spins around a few times to create a
                bigger momentum and uses the extra power of his swirl to blast Zuko in a nearby
                house with a strong blast of air. Aang looks sad and lowers the fans. He runs down
                the main street and picks up his staff along the way. Aang tosses the object in the
                air, where it snaps open into his glider and jumps on. A close-up of a saddened
                Aang, switches to the scene he is seeing: a lot of burning houses and the Fire
                Nation troops among them. Aang looks back to see the burning statue of Avatar
                Kyoshi, which saddens Aang even more.</description>
      <description>Cut to an overview shot of Katara as she is leading Koko and another
                village girl into a house.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Get inside.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang lands and Katara turns to face him as he walks over to
                her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sorrowful.</charAction> Look what I brought to this place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's not your fault.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up. Upset.</charAction> Yes, it is. These people got their town
            destroyed trying to protect me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera turns to Katara. Five little girls can be seen behind her in the
                house. Koko stands in the doorway holding Momo, whole the girl next to her peeks
                around the door frame with a worried look upon her face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Then let's get out of here. Zuko will leave Kyoshi to follow us. I know it feels
            wrong to run, but I think it's the only way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sad.</charAction> I'll call Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a Kyoshi Warrior who deflects a fire blast with her fan, and
                retaliates by throwing her other closed fan to the firebender. With a load clung,
                the object makes contact with the bender's helmet, knocking him on his behind. The
                camera moves backward through an ally. Two retreating Warriors can be soon,
                deflecting fire balls left and right, before the camera pans to the left, revealing
                Sokka and Suki squatting behind a house.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">There's no time to say goodbye.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What about, "I'm sorry?"</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> For what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up. Regretful.</charAction> I treated you like a girl when I
            should've treated you like a warrior.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Side-view.</charAction> I am a warrior. <charAction>She leans over and
                kisses Sokka on the cheek, before continuing again. A surprised Sokka touches his
                cheek where Suki just kissed him.</charAction> But I'm a girl, too. <charAction>Cut
                to shot of Sokka who blushes; cut to Suki who stands in the alleyway, her fan slid
                open to fight.</charAction> Now get out of here! We'll hold them off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka stands up and runs to Appa who was lying ready a few meters further.
                Both Momo and Sokka run up Appa's tale.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Pulling the reins.</charAction> Appa, yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa groans and takes off. A frog view shows how the bison flies over the
                burning buildings.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Back to the ship! Don't lose sight of them!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko and his men turn and run toward the coast where their ship is
                docked.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of the group flying away on Appa. Katara and Sokka are in the
                saddle, Aang on his head, and the burning village of Kyoshi is behind
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Peeking over the rim of the saddle to address a saddened Aang. Sokka is
                wiping of the face paint with his sleeve.</charAction> I know it's hard, but you did
            the right thing. <charAction>Gesturing toward the town.</charAction> Zuko would have
            destroyed the whole place if we had stayed. <charAction>Comforting.</charAction> They're
            going to be okay, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks up with a determined look on his face. The camera zooms in on
                him, when he suddenly jumps off Appa, the camera following his free
                fall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shocked; off-camera.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of the surface of the ocean as Aang plunges into the water.
                Switches back to a shot of Katara and Sokka, his face cleaned of the warrior
                make-up, peering over the edge of the saddle, wide-eyed in chock. Momo peeks over
                the rim as well beside Katara. Cut back to a shot of the surface, where a few
                ripples reveal the nearing emerging of something. The water bubbles and suddenly
                Unagi shoots out of the water with Aang on top of his head, holding his whiskers.
                After swaying about a few times, he sturdies himself atop Unagi's head and pulls the
                creature's barbels. Unagi opens its mouth wide and begins gushing water which rains
                over the town. Cut to shot of the village houses as the fires are put out by the
                rain. Cut to shot of a drenched Zuko and his men mounted on the rhinos, Zuko looking
                humiliated and his men looking surprised. Unagi ceases to gush water and launches
                Aang into the air, who is subsequently caught by an overflying Appa.</description>
      <description>Cut to shot of Oyaji viewing the spectacle from a building, his back to the
                camera. Switch to a frontal shot.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Oyaji">
         <charAction>Gratefully smiling.</charAction> Thank you, Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Side-view of Aang mounting Appa's saddle.</charAction> I know, I know.
            That was stupid and dangerous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling as Aang sits down.</charAction> Yes, it was.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang whom Katara suddenly hugs. Aang smiles and inhales deeply
                before sighing and closing his eyes, happily. Cut to shot of the ocean, Unagi
                disappearing below the surface of the water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
