<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../0_scripts_0.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="46">The Avatar and the Fire Lord</title>
      <director>Ethan Spaulding</director>
      <writer>Elizabeth Welch Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2007-10-26</date>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens with Avatar Roku emerging from behind a small wall of
                fire, and is speaking to Aang in a dream.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Aang, it's time you learn of my history with Fire Lord Sozin. <charAction>Cut to a
                close-up of Aang's face in his dream, before cutting back to Roku.</charAction> You
            need to understand how the war began, if you want to know how to end it. <charAction>Cut
                to an overhead shot of Roku's island.</charAction> Meet me on my home island on the
            day of the summer solstice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Aang, asleep, as he rolls over onto his
                side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Talking in his sleep.</charAction> Okay, Roku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Zuko, who is asleep as well, as sounds of footsteps wake
                him up, and he rushes to the hall to investigate. He opens the door, and sees a
                cloaked individual walk down the hall and disappear. Zuko begins to go after the
                individual, but notices a scroll lying on the floor. A surprised Zuko picks up the
                scroll and reads it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Reading the scroll.</charAction> You need to know the story of your
            great-grandfather's demise. It will reveal your own destiny. <charAction>He closes the
                scroll, and stares down the hallway.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to a view from the opposite end of the hallway. Zuko is still
                standing outside his bedroom. Scene changes to a blue, cloud filled sky. A very
                large cloud moves quickly forward. Cut to the inside of the cloud, as Aang, standing
                on Appa's, bends the elements around the bison to create a cloud, to camouflage.
                Katara and Sokka look over Appa's saddle for a better look.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There it is. That's Roku's home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the island, as Appa lands. Cut to a shot of Team
                Avatar descending from Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> But, there's nothing here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph jumps from Appa's saddle, as her feet touch the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yes, there is. An entire village, hundreds of houses ... <charAction>A strong breeze
                moves a layer of ash along the ground, brushing past their feet.</charAction> all
            completely buried in ash.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to an overhead of Hari Bulkan. Cut to a hall, full of
                paintings of previous Fire Lords. Zuko stands before one of the portraits, as Azula
                passes by Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's never too early for a sitting with the court painter, Zuko. Make sure he gets
            your good side.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Wait, I need to ask you something. <charAction>Azula stops walking.</charAction>
            What do you remember about our great-grandfather's history?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>She sighs.</charAction> Oh, Zuko, it's so strange how your mind works.
                <charAction>Cut to an overhead shot of the hall, as Azula tells Zuko about Sozin's
                history.</charAction> Fire Lord Sozin began the war, of course. <charAction>Cut to
                Fire Lord Sozin's portrait, as it pans from the bottom to the top.</charAction> He
            spent his early years secretly preparing for it. He was as patient as he was clever. He
            famously waited for the comet, later renamed Sozin's Comet, and used its power to launch
            his full-scale invasion of the world. <charAction>Cut back to Zuko and
                Azula.</charAction> In the end, he died a very old and successful man.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">But how did he die?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Turning toward Zuko.</charAction> Didn't you pay
                any attention in school, Zuko? He died peacefully, in his
            sleep. <charAction>Cut to a shot of the full room, as Azula walks away.</charAction> He
            was ancient.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko stares, frustrated. Scene changes back to Roku's island. Team Avatar
                is sitting on the tip of a hardened wave of lava. Cut to Aang from the back, who is
                facing the ocean, and is meditating. Cut to him from the front, as his arrows glow,
                and he is shown sitting on a mountain top, surrounded by clouds, in the Spirit
                World. Fang, who is carrying Roku, flies near him, as he stands up, and Roku smiles
                at Aang. The scene cuts to Zuko in his room, lying on his back on his bed. He rolls
                over on his side and stares at the scroll. He picks it up and reads it to himself
                again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What does it mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Annoyed, he tosses the scroll aside, as it lands on a lantern. The light
                from the lantern shines through the parchment, and it reveals a secret message on
                the scroll. Zuko gasps and grabs the scroll from atop the lantern, and reads the
                secret message aloud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Reading.</charAction> The Fire Sages keep the secret history in the
            Dragonbone Catacombs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Zuko's eyes, as he finishes reading the secret
                message. Zuko quickly turns to leave. Cut to a dark temple. A Fire Sage walks
                through a courtyard, and stops over a large medallion fashioned in the shape of a
                flower in the middle of the courtyard. He crouches low, and delivers a blast of fire
                into the center of the medallion. It begins to open a hidden passage, under the
                courtyard of the temple. The Sage goes into the passage through the steps. Zuko
                hides and waits behind a pillar. When no one is around, Zuko goes to the secret
                passage, and bends a blast of fire into the medallion. The passage opens, and a
                spiral staircase is revealed along with a very large secret chamber. Zuko travels
                through the chamber and down a hall lined with bones of dragons, all lined up along
                the walls of the hall. He comes to an ornate door with a metal sculpture of Fire
                Lord Sozin on it. The chest of the sculpture has a Fire Nation emblem. Zuko places
                his left hand over the emblem, and bends a fire blast. The fire fills the door, and
                comes out from the statue's eyes, nose and mouth. Zuko enters the room, pulls his
                cloak from his head, and raises his lantern to look around the dark chamber, and
                sees that the room is filled with artifacts and various vessels. A large statue of a
                dragon sits in the middle of the room. Under the dragon's head, Zuko finds Fire Lord
                Sozin's history.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Reading aloud.</charAction> The final testimony of Fire Lord
            Sozin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko picks the scroll, the scene changes to Roku lending Aang a hand to
                climb on Fang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Come, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He climbs on Fang, who flies off.</charAction> Where're we
            going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">To visit my past. <charAction>He smiles at Aang, as Aang grins widely.</charAction>
            Our shared past.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to the room, where Zuko is reading from the
                scroll.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Narrating his history.</charAction> As I feel my own life dimming, I
            can't help but think of a time when everything was so much brighter.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a lush Fire Nation courtyard in a flashback. Two young
                firebenders are dueling. The young men, Prince Sozin and Roku, exchange fire
                blasts.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">I remember my friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While they duel, Sozin notices that Roku's feet are close to a tree root.
                Sozin smiles, and using this to his advantage, he steps up his attack to drive Roku
                back, causing Roku to trip over the root and fall back. As Roku falls, Sozin grabs
                Roku by the shirt to keep him from falling. While he holds him, he raises his hand
                as if to fire blast, but instead he lets Roku fall to the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Looks like I win again, Roku. <charAction>Extends a hand to help Roku to his
                feet.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Are you kidding? <charAction>Takes Sozin's hands and gets up.</charAction> The tree
            root did all the work. <charAction>After getting up, he pats Sozin on his
                shoulders.</charAction> Nice one, Sozin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You were friends with Fire Lord Sozin‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Back then, he was just Prince Sozin. <charAction>Cut to a
                close-up of Roku's face.</charAction> And he was my best friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Roku and Sozin leave the courtyard, a young Fire Nation lady goes by. As
                she walks past the friends, Roku stares at her and blushes, which Sozin
                notices.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Nudging Roku.</charAction> Say something to her.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku walks after the young lady. He raises his hand and attempts to greet
                the lady, who also slightly blushes, but is overcome by embarrassment. He sighs,
                puts his hands on his head, and falls down. Sozin sits down next to him and
                sprinkles blades of grass on Roku's face. Shot cuts to the older Roku and Aang,
                watching Roku's history.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Love is hard when you are young.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You don't have to tell me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Putting his hand over Aang's shoulder.</charAction> Don't worry, it gets
            better. <charAction>He turns back and walks, along with Aang.</charAction> Now, come
            with me. <charAction>Cut to a celebration on a courtyard.</charAction> We have a party
            to attend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait, whose party is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Cut to the young Roku and Prince Sozin.</charAction> Sozin and I shared
            many things, including a birthday.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku and Prince Sozin walk down from the stairs. As they walk down the
                stairs, the camera focuses on two young women in the crowd, one of whom is the lady
                whom Roku has a crush on, Ta Min. She looks at Roku, before looking down and
                blushes. Her friend leans over her shoulder and giggles. Roku notices the lady and
                blushes, while he continues down the stairs. Distracted, Roku falls down the stairs,
                but Sozin quickly grabs Roku by the wrist. Roku composes himself and blushes again
                from embarrassment, as Sozin laughs at his friend. The crowd suddenly grows quiet,
                as a group of Fire Sages enter the courtyard. They walk toward Prince Sozin and
                Roku, as Sozin hurries down the stairs to meet them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Did something happen to my father?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Sage">No, Prince Sozin. We are not here for you. <charAction>Shot cuts to the Fire Sage
                talking.</charAction> We're here to announce the identity of the next Avatar.
                <charAction>The crowd whispers, as the shot cut to Roku and Sozin, both in shock.
                Cut again to a close-up of the Sages. The Sages bow to the new Avatar.</charAction>
            It is our honor to serve you, Avatar Roku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Roku, standing with his jaw dropped, bewildered. The
                camera shows the crowd on the ground, all bowing. Sozin, who is still in shock
                himself, looks around at the crowd, and quickly turns to kneel before Roku. Scene
                changes to Zuko sitting in the chamber, reading Sozin's history.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Soon the day came when my friend Roku had to leave the Fire Nation and face his
            destiny as the Avatar. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Zuko's face, as he
                reads.</charAction> He needed to travel the world so he could master the other
            elements.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to a close-up of a young Roku from the side, sitting in his
                room, with a dejected look on his face, as Prince Sozin stands near the
                doorway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Hey, why aren't you packed yet, all-powerful Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku does not respond to his friend's question, and continues to stare
                down. Sozin looks down sympathetically. Suddenly, he smiles.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Sozin leaps in the room, attempting to demonstrate examples of all the
                bending disciplines.</charAction> Come on, show me how it's done using all four
            kinds of bending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I started packing, but then the Fire Sages told me I won't need any worldly
            possessions anymore.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Oh. <charAction>He sits down near Roku.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">It happened so fast. Everything's gonna be different now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the two friends from the side, as Sozin removes his Crown
                Prince headpiece and gives it to Roku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Here, hope you're at least allowed to have this. <charAction>Shot cuts to a close-up
                of the headpiece.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">But this is a royal artifact. <charAction>Cut to a shot of the friends from
                behind.</charAction> It's supposed to be worn by the Crown Prince.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">I want you to have it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Roku takes the headpiece, cut to a close-up of his top knot, as he
                slides the pin. Camera pans below to show Roku smiling, as he and Sozin get up, and
                bow to each other. Scene changes to Zuko reading from the scroll. </description>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Sokka, and Katara, both looking disturbed. Shot cuts
                to Aang standing up on the rock he has been meditating on, his eyes still closed.
                Aang moves to a squat and begins to groan, before smiling with relief. Cut back to
                the siblings, with Katara looking more disturbed than before.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Do they have bathrooms in the Spirit World?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Raises his forefinger.</charAction> As a matter of fact, they do
            not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Aang smiling, still peculiarly perched, before cutting again
                to Aang riding on Fang in the Spirit World. Shot cuts to an overhead shot of the two
                flying on the dragon, as Aang notices they are going to a familiar
                place.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Hey, we're almost at the Southern Air
            Temple!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">This was the first stop on my Avatar journey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to show the Patola Mountains with the Southern Air Temple in the
                distance. Fang flies through the mountain range.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">It was the place where I was trained to master airbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a line of young Air Nomad monks. The camera pans right to show
                Avatar Roku at the end of the line. Roku is airbending his long black hair at
                another young monk's face, who, irritated, bends it back at Roku. Roku responds by
                nudging the monk with his shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">And also where I met an old friend of yours: Monk Gyatso.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial shot of the airbenders on a grassy ledge. An older Air
                Nomad leads the students, and launches off the side of the ledge. The students line
                up by twos to follow their teacher. Cut to Gyatso and Roku soaring through the air
                on their gliders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Hey, Gyatso, you wanna see a new glider trick? <charAction>He flies up and loops
                twice.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">
         <charAction>Laughing.</charAction> Check this out! <charAction>He flips himself over
                and stands on top of his glider. Cut to Aang and Roku.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">He's air surfing! I can't believe I never thought of that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Gyatso, as he loses his balance on the glider, but as he falls,
                Roku catches him on the back of his glider. Roku is unable to control the glider,
                and the both go down toward the other young monks, who are now back on the grassy
                ledge. Cut to the other students looking up at the falling airbenders, as they panic
                and try to run. Cut to Roku and Gyatso, flying low, about to crash. They crash,
                leaving a large cloud of dust. Cut to the young monks knocked over, and scattered
                about. Roku's hair is in his face. Gyatso airbends it back while Roku lifts his
                head. They both grin widely, and Roku pats Gyatso on his shoulder. Cut to a close-up
                of Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling and surprised.</charAction> That's amazing! I can't believe you
            were friends with Monk Gyatso just like I was!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Camera pans back to show Roku.</charAction> Some friendships are so
            strong, <charAction>He closes his eyes.</charAction> they can even transcend
            lifetimes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Fang flies off, the scene changes to the Northern Water Tribe, where, in
                the distance, two individuals are standing on a plateau of ice. Cut to a close-up of
                an older Roku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">After my years mastering airbending, I traveled to the Northern Water
            Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Taqukaq, who bends a large water drill from the ocean waters behind
                him. It thrusts forward, knocking Roku, and a part of the plateau, into the
                water.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Waterbending was especially challenging for me. But in time, I mastered it as
            well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the water, as Roku emerges from it, and bends an enormous
                wave of water directly at his master standing on the glacier. The blast completely
                destroys the glacier, and carries his master all the way back to a Northern Water
                Tribe building. His master sits up, and shakes his head. Cut to Roku, standing on an
                ice float, as he smiles. Scene changes to Roku, standing shirtless, and wearing
                Earth Kingdom clothing from the waist. He moves his arms in quick motions across his
                body to bend a large piece of earth, riding up the side of a mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I moved on to the Earth Kingdom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Roku racing up the slope, as another earthbender catches up to him.
                Cut to a brief shot of the earthbender, before cutting back to Roku, as they compete
                for speed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">My earthbending master, Sud, was uncompromising, stubborn, and blunt ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two benders race into thick brush and trees, as they disappear from
                view. Cut to the top of the mountain overlooking a valley.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">... And a lifelong friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Sud comes to the finishing point, quickly brings his landmass to a halt.
                He thrusts his fists into the air, cheering for himself. The look on his face
                changes quickly to shock when he realizes that Roku not only beat him to the top,
                but he also had enough time to seat himself and pour them both tea. Cut back to Sud
                as he smiles at his pupil. Cut to a side shot of Roku and Sud. They both drink from
                their teacups. Scene changes to a close-up of Roku's head dress and slowly pans down
                to show his face in an extreme close-up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">It was bitter work ... <charAction>The camera pans back to Roku, as he moves his
                arms to bend the different elements.</charAction> but the results were worth it.
                <charAction>He starts by waterbending, before moving on to earthbending,
                firebending, and finally, airbending. The camera zooms out to an aerial view of Roku
                at the center of the four elements.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Zuko, still reading Sozin's history in the chamber. An
                extreme close-up shows his eyes quivering with each word he reads.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Twelve long years passed before I saw my friend again. When Roku returned, he was a
            fully realized Avatar, and I had changed as well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A wall of flames appears, as the scene changes to Sozin sitting in his
                throne room. Roku walks down a long red carpet toward Sozin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Sozin! Or should I say, Fire Lord!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Scene changes to Sozin from below him. Serious.</charAction>
            Customarily, my subjects bow before greeting me. <charAction>He walks down from his
                throne.</charAction> But you're the exception. <charAction>He smiles and hugs
                Roku.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the older Roku and Aang watching from behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">After all these years, he was still my best friend. <charAction>Scene changes to a
                wedding ceremony and celebration in a Fire Nation courtyard, with many guests
                attending. Cut to Roku, on whose right is Sozin, holding a scroll.</charAction> And
            a few months later, he was my best man.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>As Roku lifts the veil.</charAction> Roku, it's that girl who didn't
            even know you're alive!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Ta Min. I was persistent. <charAction>She stands up near Roku.</charAction> When
            love is real, it finds a way. <charAction>The attendees clap, as the newly-wed couple
                bow their heads. Cut to a shot of the couple from the side, as Aang and Roku
                watch.</charAction> And being the Avatar doesn't hurt your chances with the ladies,
            either.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">On wedding days, we look to the future with optimism and joy. <charAction>Fade to
                Sozin in deep thought.</charAction> I had my own vision for a brighter
            future.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Roku and Ta Min receiving and thanking guests. Sozin walks up behind
                the couple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Leaning toward Ta Min.</charAction> Excuse me. May I borrow him for a
            moment‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ta Min">It's not very traditional, but, okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Roku and Sozin on a balcony.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">What's on your mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Raises his fist slightly.</charAction> I've been thinking hard about the
            state of the world lately.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Putting his arm over Sozin's shoulder.</charAction> Sozin, it is my
            wedding! Have a cookie, dance with someone, lighten up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Smiling slightly.</charAction> I know, I know, but just hear me out.
                <charAction>Roku bows in agreement. Cut to a shadowed side-shot of the balcony as
                they walk.</charAction> Right from the start, I was destined to be Fire Lord. And
            although we didn't always know it, you were destined to be the Avatar. <charAction>Cut
                to a close-up side-shot of the two. Roku stops as Sozin continues on.</charAction>
            It's an amazing stroke of fate we know each other so well, isn't it? Together, we could
            do ... anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>The camera pans toward Roku. Now serious.</charAction> Yeah, we
            could.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot of the Fire Nation from the balcony.</charAction> Our
            nation is enjoying an unprecedented time of peace and wealth. Our people are happy, and
            we're so fortunate in so many ways.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Where are you going with this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">I've been thinking, we should share this prosperity with the rest of the world.
                <charAction>Cut to a shocked Roku with the camera closing in on him.</charAction> In
            our hands is the most successful empire in history. <charAction>Back to a close-up of
                Sozin.</charAction> It's time we expanded it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">No! The four nations are meant to be just that: four.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Cut to Sozin.</charAction> Roku, you haven't even stopped to consider
            the possibilities.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Cut to a close-up side-shot of Roku.</charAction> There are no
            possibilities. This is the last I want to hear <charAction>Closes his eyes.</charAction>
            about this. <charAction>He walks away from the balcony, with an angry expression on his
                face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>His spirit speaks to Aang.</charAction> That was my first real test as
            the Avatar. Unfortunately, it was many years before I learned <charAction>Cut to a
                extreme close-up of Sozin.</charAction> that Sozin <charAction>Sozin narrows his
                eyes. Fade to a back-shot of Fang flying with Roku.</charAction> had gone ahead with
            his plan, despite my warning.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Roku flying over a body of water on Fang, as he approaches
                land. As Roku flies over, he sees an Earth Nation dock, but as the camera pans up,
                he sees an Earth Nation fortress with plumes of smoke rising from inside, with the
                Fire Nation insignia strewn over the original Earth Kingdom symbol, covering it. The
                camera zooms in to an extreme close-up of the Fire Nation banner. Cut to Roku who
                widens his eyes in shock by his discovery. Scene changes to Roku, bursting through
                the doors of Fire Lord Sozin's throne room with steam coming out. Cut to an overhead
                shot of Roku's shadow in the doorway cast on the long red carpet.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> I've seen the colonies, Sozin. <charAction>Points at
                Sozin.</charAction> How dare you occupy Earth Kingdom territory!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">
         <charAction>Cut to Sozin, as Roku walks up to him.</charAction> How dare you, a
            citizen of the Fire Nation, address your Fire Lord this way. <charAction>Cut to a
                close-up of Sozin's face from the side.</charAction> Your loyalty is to our nation
            first. Anything less makes you a traitor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Don't do this, Sozin. Don't challenge me. It will only end badly. It's
            over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Roku turns back and starts to leave, Sozin, full of rage, jumps from his
                throne and delivers an immensely powerful fire stream. As the flames go out, Roku is
                nowhere to be seen. Sozin widens his eyes in suprise, expression becoming blank as
                he looks around. Suddenly, Roku bursts from the ground behind Sozin, revealing that
                he has burrowed into the ground with earthbending to defend from Sozin's attack.
                Before Sozin can turn back, Roku delivers a powerful air blast at the Fire Lord,
                which causes him to slam on the gates of the room. As Sozin falls down, Roku
                immediately earthbends a pillar of earth that lifts Sozin into the air and pins him
                by the back of his robes to the ceiling. Cut to a close-up of Avatar Roku, as he
                brings his hands together in front of his face, and enters the Avatar State. Cut to
                a shot of the entire throne room, as Roku breaks the pillars of the throne room. Cut
                to an aerial shot of the palace, as it is destroyed. Cut to Sozin, uncovering his
                face. Roku airbends an air spout, and raises himself to Sozin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I'm sparing you, Sozin. <charAction>Cut to a frontal shot of Roku.</charAction> I'm
            letting you go in the name of our past friendship. But I warn you. <charAction>Cut to a
                extreme close up of Roku.</charAction> Even a single step out of line will result in
            your permanent end.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sozin stares at Roku, his face still full of anger. Suddenly, his
                expression drops, and he hangs his head in defeat. Roku turns, and rides the cyclone
                quickly away from Sozin. Scene changes to an aerial shot of Roku's island at
                night.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Sozin and I didn't speak or see each other for twenty-five years after our battle.
                <charAction>Cut to Roku's house.</charAction> I spent most of my spare time here, at
            my home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of an elderly Roku and Ta Min sleeping, as a loud
                noise awakes Roku and he leaps out from the bed, and looks through the window. Cut
                to a shot of the window, as large fireballs falling from the sky, and crashing into
                the island. Roku and his wife flee the room, but as they do so, Roku's headpiece
                falls to the floor, and is left behind. Roku emerges from the house to find the air
                filled with smoke and ash. Coughing, Roku and his wife shield their faces. A worried
                Roku looks at the erupting volcano in the island.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Let's go! <charAction>He catches his wife's hand, and airbends smoke and ash in
                their way, creating a path, as both run through the path he
            created.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to the town, as the townspeople run through the streets to
                escape the waves of smoke and ash that now pour through the streets. Cut to Roku's
                home, as Fang flies up from behind the house. He narrowly escapes as an ash flow
                completely buries the house. Cut to a wide shot of Roku, with his face covered,
                leading his wife and many townspeople to safety. Ash continues to fall as we see a
                swell of lava ooze from the mouth of the volcano. Cut to a close-up of Roku still
                running. He looks to his wife, as shot cuts to her running. He lets go of her hand,
                and motions her to go on without him. With her arm still outstretched, she looks at
                him, and runs to safety. She continues to look back, desperately hoping Roku will
                grab her hand. Ta Min runs off with many of the townspeople. Roku turns to face the
                advancing smoke, and airbends a huge dome of protection around himself. Cut to the
                townspeople in boats, as they see the air dome. Cut to the worried faces of the
                people, including Ta Min. Scene changes to the volcano erupting in the island from
                the Fire Nation palace, as camera zooms back to show an elderly Fire Lord Sozin
                watching from his balcony.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Roku's island was a hundred miles away. But I could still feel it rumbling and see
            the black plume of smoke. I had never seen anything like this catastrophe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Sozin's face, before cutting to an aerial shot of the volcano. Large
                columns of black smoke billow from the summit, as lightning strikes above the
                volcano and the earth rumbles from the disaster. Cut to a close-up of a landslide
                quickly approaching the town, destroying it completely. Roku earthbends a gigantic
                wall, and rides the wall to meet the falling earth, and stop it. As he succeeds in
                stopping it, the volcano ejects a massive wave of lava. The flow breeches the wall
                of earth, causing Roku to flee to the bottom of the summit. He cuts into the earth
                using his earthbending, creating a channel to divert the lava into the surrounding
                ocean, away from the town. Cut to an aerial shot of the island, as the channel fills
                with lava, and empties into the ocean. Cut to Roku and Aang watching the destruction
                from a distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is amazing, Roku! You're battling a volcano, and you're winning.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Unfortunately, my success didn't last long, Aang. There was no way I could do it
            all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shot cuts to Roku looking up the top of the volcano. As the camera pans up
                and focuses on the mouth of the volcano, it violently expels another giant wave of
                lava. Roku runs toward the volcano, and leaps. Roku blows a powerful blast of air
                from his mouth at the lava, which cools and hardens, as Roku lands on it. Suddenly,
                a blast of poisonous gas spouts to his right, he turns and covers his face. He turns
                to the jet, airbending it away. Suddenly lava appears on his right, which he
                airbends, and quickly another jet of gases blasts to his left, and he quickly
                airbends it as well.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Battling the elements was hard enough. I had to do
            it while I could barely breathe. The poisonous, volcanic gases were
            overwhelming.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the sky directly over the eruption. Lightning
                crashes around the crater as Fang comes, flying. The summit emits another lava
                fountain. Fang pulls back, narrowly escaping the blast, and roars.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Airbends a jet of gases.</charAction> It's all right Fang!
                <charAction>Coughs.</charAction> Get out of here! I'm fine!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku turns his body from side to side, and enters the Avatar State. With a
                powerful blow from his fist, Roku earthbends a tremor through the volcano, breaking
                out the back side of the crater, which lessens the lava flow. As the lava flows
                down, the second volcano erupts, as Roku, no longer in the Avatar State, hopelessly
                drops his head. Cut to a view of Roku from behind, as Sozin, on a blue dragon,
                appears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Need a hand, old friend?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>A surprised Roku turns back.</charAction> Sozin?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">There's not a moment to waste.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an aerial view of the two volcanoes. Sozin and Roku ride on the Fire
                Lord's dragon's back to the second volcano. Cut to Roku bending the fire fountain
                down into the crater. Cut to Sozin balanced on the mouth of the vent, as he cools
                the lava by absorbing the heat, passing it through himself, and redirects out
                through his other hand. The scene pans out to show the silhouettes of the two
                friends, controlling the disaster. Cut to the townspeople in the boats, as they see
                the volcanoes erupting. Cut to a shot of Ta Min, with an anxious expression on her
                face. The scene cuts back to Roku and Sozin on the edge of the crater. Lightning
                blasts above Sozin, as the earth beneath him becomes unstable. He begins to fall
                back off the side of the volcano, but Roku quickly earthbends an earth shelf to
                catch Sozin. Stable again, Sozin looks to Roku for a moment. Suddenly, the earth
                violently shakes and another surge of ash and rock shoot from the crater, and the
                two turn to run.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Don't breathe the toxic gas.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As the two run, a jet of toxic gas shoots up directly next to Sozin. Roku
                quickly airbends it away to protect Sozin. Suddenly gas erupts directly into Roku's
                face, causing him to be disoriented.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Shaking, Cut to Roku's point of view. He lifts his hands to look at
                them, as they blur out of focus.</charAction> It's too much.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Overwhelmed by the poisons, Roku falls to his knees. He looks up toward
                Sozin, and holds out his hand for help.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Roku's point of view again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">Without you, all my plans are suddenly possible. <charAction>Cut to
                Roku.</charAction> I have a vision for the future, Roku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sozin's dragon appears. As Roku kneels, Sozin mounts the dragon and flies
                away. Cut to Roku, on the side of the volcano. He is surrounded by toxic gas, and
                behind him a surge of rock and ash flows swiftly toward him. Cut to a shot of the
                black clouds billowing from the island, as Sozin's dragon emerges from the plumes.
                The camera zooms to an extreme close-up of Sozin's eye. Shot cuts to Roku, from the
                back, still on his knees. He is coughing, and is unable to get to his feet. Fang
                appears from the right, and flies above him. Cut to a close-up of Roku from the
                side, as he looks up toward his dragon. Cut to an aerial view of the debris, rapidly
                approaching Avatar Roku. With the rock avalanche just moments away from swallowing
                Roku, Fang flies down, and wraps himself around Roku. The wave of ash and rubble
                cover the two completely, killing both of them. Fade to a bright light, as the
                camera pans to show an arched window frame. A baby's cries can be heard. The camera
                pans down to show a smiling born infant.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Who's ... wait, that's me, isn't it? <charAction>Cut to a long shot of three Air
                Nomads. A nun holds up the baby to the light while two people, presumably the
                infant's parents, stand in the shadows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Make sense of our past, Aang. <charAction>Cut to Roku and Aang.</charAction> And you
            will bring peace, and restore balance in the world. <charAction>He slowly
                disappears.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Roku? Roku!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang walks out of the flashback into whiteness as the scene changes to Zuko
                reading in the Dragonbone Catacombs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sozin">With Roku gone, and the great comet returning, the timing was perfect to change the
            world. <charAction>Cut to Sozin, standing on a balcony, from the behind, looking at his
                soldiers and the Fire Navy ships.</charAction> I knew the next Avatar would be born
            an Air Nomad. So I wiped out the Air Temples. <charAction>Scene changes to a burning
                temple. The camera slowly fades into an extreme close-up of Sozin's
                face.</charAction> But somehow, the new Avatar eluded me. <charAction>Scene changes
                to Fire Navy ships searching in the polar regions.</charAction> I wasted the
            remainder of my life searching in vain. <charAction>Cut to underside of the
                ship.</charAction> I know he's hiding out there somewhere. <charAction>Camera pans
                below to show the iceberg Aang was trapped in.</charAction> The Fire Nation's
            greatest threat ... the last airbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to a close-up of the scroll Zuko is reading.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">That can't be it! Where's the rest of it? <charAction>He searches the scroll to find
                more information.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko puts the scroll down and stands up, as the camera pans out. Scene
                changes to the Fire Nation prison, where Iroh is imprisoned. Cut to Zuko from the
                behind, slamming the door to the cell behind him as he enters. Cut to Iroh sitting
                with his head down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You sent this, didn't you? I found the secret
            history, which by the way should be renamed history most people already know! The note
            said that I needed to know about my great-grandfather's death, but he was still alive in
            the end.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Looking up at Zuko.</charAction> No. He wasn't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What are you talking about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You have more than one great-grandfather, Prince Zuko. Sozin was your father's
            grandfather. <charAction>Cut to a bewildered Zuko.</charAction> Your mother's
            grandfather was Avatar Roku.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Why are you telling me this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Because understanding the struggle between your two great-grandfathers can help you
            better understand the battle within yourself. <charAction>Zuko sits down, with his head
                facing down.</charAction> Evil and good are always at war inside you, Zuko. It is
            your nature, your legacy. But, there is a bright side. <charAction>Zuko looks
                up.</charAction> What happened generations ago can be resolved now, by you. Because
            of your legacy, you alone can cleanse the sins of our family and the Fire Nation. Born
            in you, along with all the strife, is the power to restore balance to the
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a bundle inside of a brick wall. Iroh removes a brick and reaches
                for the bundle. Cut to Iroh slowly unwrapping the bundle, revealing the once-lost
                headdress, while he walks toward Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">This is a royal artifact. It's supposed to be worn <charAction>Zuko
                stands.</charAction> by the Crown Prince.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko takes the headdress from Iroh's hand, and holds the artifact, as the
                shot cuts to Zuko from the behind, standing outside of Iroh's cell. Iroh stands
                quietly, looking at his nephew. Cut to a shot of the hardened lava wave the gang had
                been sitting on. Cut to a shot of Sokka, Katara, and Toph all facing Aang as the
                camera pans down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You mean, after all Roku and Sozin went through together, even after Roku showed him
            mercy, Sozin betrayed him like that‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Cut to Toph.</charAction> It's like these people are born bad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang from the side, with Sokka standing near him.</charAction>
            No, that's wrong. I don't think that was the point of what Roku showed me at
            all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shrugging.</charAction> Then what was the
            point?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to Katara, Toph and Sokka from the behind, as Aang
                speaks.</charAction> Roku was just as much Fire Nation as Sozin was, right? If
            anything, their story proves anyone's capable of great good and great evil.
                <charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of the hardened lava wave.</charAction> Everyone,
            even the Fire Lord and the Fire Nation have to be treated like they're worth giving a
            chance. <charAction>Shot cuts to a close-up of Aang's face.</charAction> And I also
            think it was about friendships.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Camera pans to Toph, and cuts to a close-up of her face.</charAction> Do
            you really think friendships can last more than one lifetime?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Catching Toph's hand.</charAction> I don't see why not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara catches Toph's other hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, scientifically speaking, there's no way to prove that ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Oh, Sokka, just hold hands.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka stops talking, and without moving, he thrusts out his hand to hold
                Katara's. Shot cuts to an aerial shot of Team Avatar, holding hands, and looking out
                toward the ocean. Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
