<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="8">Winter Solstice Part 2</title>
      <director>Giancarlo Volpe</director>
      <writer>Michael Dante DiMartino</writer>
      <date>2005-04-15</date>
      <location nation="earth">Senlin Village</location>
      <location nation="fire">Crescent Island</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The scene opens to a full moon in the sky. The camera pans down and shows
                Senlin Village during early morning hours. Cut to a view from among the houses,
                slowly zooming in on Aang who tries to get Appa to move, yanking on the reins,
                though the bison continually refuses and sits down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Strained voice.</charAction> Let's go, Appa! Come on, boy!
                <charAction>Appa roars in protest and sits down. Cut to a close side-view; Aang
                sadly addresses his pet.</charAction> Look I'm sorry, but Katara and Sokka aren't
            coming to the Fire Nation with us. <charAction>Frontal shot; looks down and away,
                sadly.</charAction> If they got hurt, I'd never forgive myself. <charAction>Cut back
                to the side-shot; sternly, emphasizing his command by straightening
                himself.</charAction> So get your big butt off the ground and let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He jerks at the reins, stretching them out, but is flung to the ground when
                the ropes pull him back as Appa did not move a muscle. Cut to a forlorn looking
                Aang, sitting spread-legged on the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Voice-over; Aang gasps in surprise and looks over his right shoulder and
                over his left, turning around in search for the origins of the voice.</charAction> I
            think his big butt is trying to tell ya something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a frontal shot of Appa as the camera swiftly pans to the right to
                reveal a collection of Senlin villagers, with Katara and Sokka standing in the
                front.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Desperately.</charAction> Please don't go Aang. The world can't afford
            to lose you to the Fire Nation. <charAction>Closer shot of Katara's pleading
                face.</charAction> Neither can I.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looks away sadly and recalls an image of Sozin's Comet.</charAction> But
            I have to talk to Avatar Roku to find out what my vision means! <charAction>Side-shot as
                he approaches his friends.</charAction> I need to get to the Fire Temple before the
            sun sets on the solstice. That's today!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends himself atop Appa's head. Close shot of him looking back with
                a sad expression on his face as he prepares to leave. As Appa stands up, the shot
                changes to a frontal view, and Katara and Sokka run to stand before the bison,
                preventing him from moving any further.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're not letting you go into the Fire Nation, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aang stares curiously.</charAction> At least, not without your friends.
            We got your back. <charAction>Momo soars up and perches atop Aang's shoulder, and Appa
                licks Sokka, who angrily looks at the bison.</charAction> Ew!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Senlin Village leader">It's a long journey to the Crescent Island. <charAction>Hands Aang a small
                bundle.</charAction> You'll have to fly fast to have any chance of making it before
            sundown. Good luck.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thank you for your-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Senlin Village leader">
         <charAction>Interrupts sharply, yelling. Points toward the ocean.</charAction>
            Go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa takes off with Aang, Momo, Katara, and Sokka. Later that morning, the
                Senlin Village leader exits a building, but he stops in his track upon finding Zuko
                standing in his path. In the background, Iroh is sitting on a komodo
                rhino.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>The Senlin Village leader gasps.</charAction> Having trouble sleeping?
                <charAction>Pushes the man back through the door, knocking him down. Frontal shot as
                he approaches him.</charAction> Seen the Avatar lately?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Day has come. Appa soars over the ocean. Aang, Katara, and Sokka all watch
                the ocean fearfully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come on boy, we've got a long way to go. Faster!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Sailing into Fire Nation waters ... Of all the
            foolish things you've done in your sixteen years, Prince Zuko, this is the most
            foolish!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I have no choice, Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Have you completely forgotten that the Fire Lord
                banished you>? <charAction>Fearfully.</charAction> What if
            you're caught?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Breaks away from telescope to talk to his uncle.</charAction> I'm
            chasing the Avatar! My father will understand why I am returning home!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You give him too much credit. My brother is not the understanding type!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Looks back into his telescope. Dark scope view reveals Appa
                mid-flight.</charAction> There they are. Helmsman! Full steam ahead!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looking back to Zuko's ship.</charAction> Aang. We've got
            trouble!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Panicked.</charAction> Yeah! And it's gaining, fast!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A Fire Nation catapult is raised to the deck of Zuko's ship. It is loaded
                with a steaming projectile.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Waving a fan at his face.</charAction> Uh, really Prince Zuko, couldn't
            you shoot them down with something more fragrant?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Lights the stinking ball with a fire punch.</charAction> On my mark!
            Fire!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A guard beside him slices the rope holding back the catapult. The flaming
                projectile races toward Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Fireball!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm on it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Aang, Katara, and Sokka all make faces and grasp their
                noses.</charAction> We have to get out of Zuko's range, before he shoots another hot
            stinker at us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Can't you make Appa go any faster?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah. But there's just one little problem.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up. Eyes widening.</charAction> A blockade.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Birds-eye view of a two-row line of Fire Nation ships stretching across the
                ocean as far as the eye can see. Brief glimpse of numerous Fire Nation catapults
                prepared to fire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Technically you are still in Earth Kingdom waters. Turn back now and they cannot
            arrest you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">If we fly north, we can go around the Fire Nation ships and avoid the blockade! It's
            the only way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">There's no time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is exactly why I didn't want you to come! It's too dangerous!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">And that's exactly why we're here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Boldly.</charAction> Let's run this blockade! <charAction>Both Katara
                and Sokka grin confidently.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa, yip-yip! <charAction>Appa roars readily, sailing forward even
                quicker.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">He's not turning around!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Please Prince Zuko! If the Fire Nation captures you, there is nothing I can do! Do
            not follow the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Lowers his head, closes his eyes, and clenches his hands into fists.
                Sorrowfully.</charAction> I'm sorry, Uncle. <charAction>Raises his head, opens his
                eyes, and thrusts his right hand forward commandingly.</charAction> Run the
            blockade!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Gazing through telescope.</charAction> The Avatar. <charAction>Lowers
                telescope lens to spot Zuko's ship.</charAction> And the banished prince.
                <charAction>Lowers telescope.</charAction> This must be my lucky day.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Commander Zhao. What are your orders?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Shoot the bison down, captain.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> But there's a Fire Navy ship out there, sir! One
            of our own! What if it's hit?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">So be it. <charAction>Captain backs up in shock. Zhao continues coolly.</charAction>
            It belongs to a traitor. <charAction>Command.</charAction> Ignite. Launch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The sky becomes littered with flaming fireballs fired from the blockade.
                View from Zuko's ship as the fireballs fill the sky. Close-up of a screaming Aang,
                Sokka, and Katara. Zoom out as Appa evades numerous fireballs, some exploding
                mid-air. Camera switch to forward view, close-up, as they fly through a blanket of
                fireballs. The team flies directly through one that exploded before them, Appa's fur
                darkened from the explosion. Katara, Sokka, and Momo all slap out embers on Appa's
                fur.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa, are you okay? <charAction>Appa roars a reply. They soar higher into the
                clouds.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>On the ocean surface, Zuko's ship is narrowly missing many falling
                fireballs. Sheets of ocean water crash over the ship, and crew members run for
                safety. A single fireball explodes on the aft side of the vessel.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Engineer">Prince Zuko! The engines are damaged! We need to stop and make repairs!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Spins away from the man, facing the blockade.</charAction> Do not stop
            this ship.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Launch!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Aang's view. Just over a cloud; fireballs burst through
                everywhere and smoke fills the screen. Aang, Katara, and Sokka scream and duck away,
                while Katara and Sokka grip Appa's saddle. Appa dodges many fireballs before two
                collide and explode in front of him. Sokka is thrown from the saddle and begins to
                plunge for the ocean, screaming anew.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cries out desperately.</charAction> Sokka! <charAction>Whips the reins
                down and begins a speedy descent in chase of Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa reaches Sokka just in time. Katara grabs his hand, pulling him back
                into saddle. Appa skims the ocean surface. A fish appears out of nowhere and slaps
                Sokka square in the face, knocking him into the saddle. Momo leaps up and grabs the
                fish as Appa continues his swift flight mere feet above the ocean. Fireballs crash
                into the water all around them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Ready ... <charAction>Holds hand up, issuing his command.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Appa's view, approaching the ships. Camera switch once to Zhao,
                moving to prepare the signal. Back to Aang, a look of obstinate determination
                overcomes him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Fire!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A single catapult launches a fire blast directly toward Appa. Close-up of
                Aang's eye as it snaps open, unafraid. Aang airbends forward off of Appa's head. He
                uses a powerful airbending kick, and the flaming boulder explodes in a large smoky
                blast. Aang falls back to Appa's head, Katara and Sokka grabbing him. Appa soars
                safely over the blockade, passing them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Ecstatic.</charAction> We made it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Katara and Sokka each grimacing in terror.</charAction> We got into the
            Fire Nation. <charAction>Meekly.</charAction> Great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Where do you think the Avatar is headed, sir?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I'm not sure. <charAction>Turns aside, gazes at Zuko's smoking ship.</charAction>
            But I bet a certain banished prince will know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switch to just overhead Zuko's ship. His small vessel approaches two
                ships in the blockade. These two ships sail opposite directions, in a moment they
                will close off Zuko's ship's path.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">We're on a collision course!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Confidently.</charAction> We can make it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">
         <charAction>Captain stands ahead of a squad of nine firebenders.</charAction> The
            boarding party is ready to apprehend Prince Zuko, sir.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Swiftly.</charAction> Wait! Cut the engines, and let them pass.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">Sir?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Each ship in the blockade halts, allowing Zuko's ship to glide by beneath
                their deck, untouched. Zhao stands high, sharing an interlocked gaze with the
                banished prince below. Zuko and Iroh look behind them in silence as they sail safely
                through. Iroh strokes his gray beard curiously.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts back to Appa, flying among blue skies. Sokka and Katara sit
                up in the saddle, while Aang sits on Appa's head.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to Sokka slumped in the back of the saddle. Katara is
                leaning her arms over the front of the saddle, and Aang is lounging against Appa's
                neck.</description>
      <description>The sky has changed to a darker, sunset-filled evening. Appa is visibly
                tired. Aang is sprawled over Appa's head with Momo equally sprawled over Aang's
                head. Katara and Sokka have each collapsed into the saddle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up. Momo is shown bouncing about in eager surprise.</charAction>
            There it is! <charAction>Sokka and Katara pop up in the saddle.</charAction> The island
            where Roku's dragon took me. <charAction>Full view of Crescent Island and its smoking
                volcano as Appa descends.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa is lying at the base of a stone bridge leading up to the island's
                mountain. The bridge ends at an elegant, multi-story Fire Temple. Lava is flowing
                beneath the bridge. The air is thick with steam. Aang stands by Appa's head, and
                Katara stands to Appa's side. Sokka is stretching further away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs against Appa's head.</charAction> You did it buddy. Nice flying.
                <charAction>Appa bellows in satisfaction, rolling to his side to wave his three legs
                into the air lazily. Appa's tongue lolls out.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiles sweetly and approaches Appa. Rubs his belly.</charAction> Aww,
            you must be tired.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Joyous. Katara's expresses dumbfounded interest.</charAction> No! I'm
            good. Refreshed and ready to fight some firebenders! <charAction>Continues to work out
                and flex his body.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Props hand off hip. Responds dryly.</charAction> I was talking to
            Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Instantly halts exercise.</charAction> Well ... I was talking to Momo.
                <charAction>Points to the lemur clinging to a dead tree's
            branch.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene cut to Katara, Sokka, Aang, and Momo walking along the stone bridge
                to approach a multi-story Fire Temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up, top-to-bottom view of the Fire Temple.</charAction> I don't
            see any guards.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Camera drops to show the group taking cover behind a lower wall below
                steps.</charAction> The Fire Nation must have abandoned the temple when Avatar Roku
            died.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's almost sundown. We better hurry! <charAction>The group leaps over the wall and
                charges for the front door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>The group tip-toes through an enormous chamber with fire-decor
                columns.</charAction> Wait. I think I heard something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">
         <charAction>Turning around, they see five men standing in the hallway dressed in red
                with tall hats.</charAction> We are the Fire Sages. Guardians of the temple of the
            Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Great! I am the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">We know. <charAction>Inhales briskly before punching a blast of fire their
                direction.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Deflects three balls of fire with his airbending. Close-up. Shouts over
                his shoulder.</charAction> I'll hold them off. Run!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang leaps forward and spins his leg across the ground, sending a low air
                blade that sweeps the Fire Sages' legs out from beneath them, and they all fall to
                the ground. Aang flees after his friends.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">If the Avatar contacts Roku, there's no telling how powerful the boy will become!
            Split up and find him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Hallway view; Aang skids in front of Katara and Sokka and continues
                running.</charAction> Follow me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Do you know where you're going? <charAction>The two follow
            Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rounds a corner and disappears from sight.</charAction> Nope!
                <charAction>A moment passes, Katara and Sokka stop when Aang skids into view again.
                Fearfully.</charAction> Wrong way! <charAction>Runs past them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Rounds the corner, frightening Sokka and Katara to chase after
                Aang.</charAction> Come back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The trio turns another corner and charges down the hallway. However, they
                reach a dead-end as Aang skids to an immediate halt. Turning around, they face Shyu,
                who raises a hand in peace.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">I don't want to fight you! I am a friend.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Firebenders aren't our friends! <charAction>Aang steps ahead of his friends,
                assuming an airbending posture.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Steps toward the Avatar, before dropping to his knees and pressing his
                palms to the floor in submission. This startles Aang, Katara, and
                Sokka.</charAction> I know why you're here, Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> You do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">Yes. <charAction>Rises from the floor to stand again.</charAction> You wish to speak
            to Avatar Roku. I can take you to him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Skeptically.</charAction> How?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Slides back a lamplight on the wall. Places palm on wall, focuses
                firebending into this location to open a secret passage.</charAction> This
            way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">
         <charAction>Echoes in the distance.</charAction> Find him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Briefly glances down the hall.</charAction> Time is running out!
            Quickly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Katara exchange a look with one another, asserting each other's
                belief to trust this firebender. The group enters the passage and descends the steps
                into the cave. Shyu enters behind them and closes the passageway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up. Tightens knuckles on ship's railing. Smoke billows behind his
                ship.</charAction> What's he up to, Uncle? Why didn't Commander Zhao arrest
            me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Because he wants to follow you. He knows you'll lead him to the prize you're both
            after: the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> If Zhao wants to follow a trail of smoke, then
            that's exactly what I'll let him do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Brief scene cut to show the sun nearly setting. Far overhead view of
                Shyu leading the group through caverns.</charAction> Avatar Roku once called this
            temple his home. He formed these secret passages out of the magma.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Did you know Avatar Roku?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">No. But my grandfather knew him. Many generations of Fire Sages guarded this Fire
            Temple long before me. We all have a strong spiritual connection to this place.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Is that how you knew I was coming?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">A few weeks ago, an amazing thing occurred. The statue of Avatar Roku; its eyes
            began to glow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's when we were at the Air Temple. Avatar Roku's eyes were glowing there,
            too!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">At that moment, we knew you had returned to the world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">If this is the Avatar's temple, why did the sages attack me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">Things have changed. In the past, the sages were loyal only to the Avatar. When Roku
            died, the sages eagerly awaited for the next Avatar to return. But he never
            came.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking down, guiltily.</charAction> They were waiting for me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Humorously mocking.</charAction> Hey don't feel bad. You're only a
            hundred years late! <charAction>Aang scowls heavily at Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">They lost hope the Avatar would ever return. When Fire Lord Sozin began the War, my
            grandfather and the other sages were forced to follow him. <charAction>Shakes head
                sadly.</charAction> I never wanted to serve the Fire Lord. When I learned you were
            coming, I knew I would have to betray the other sages.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thank you for helping me. <charAction>Close-up as Shyu smiles to
            Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Continues leading the group up a spiraling flight of
                stairs.</charAction> We'll follow these stairs to the sanctuary. <charAction>Time
                skip, Shyu continues talking as they near the top of the stairs.</charAction> Once
            you're inside, wait for the light to hit Avatar Roku's statue. Only then will you be
            able to speak with him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Slides back a secret tile and climbs into the outer sanctuary. Massive
                columns with dragon statues atop them line the room. An immense door is before them
                with a device holding five open-mouthed dragons.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Gasps.</charAction> No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Approaches door.</charAction> Shyu, what's wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">The sanctuary doors, they're closed!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Aang tugs at the door uselessly.</charAction> Can't you just open them
            with firebending? Like you opened that other door?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">No. Only a fully realized Avatar is powerful enough to open this door alone.
            Otherwise, the sages must open this door together, <charAction>Sokka shown in deep
                thought.</charAction> with five simultaneous fire blasts.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Ponderously states.</charAction> Five fire blasts, huh? <charAction>Zoom
                out to show a lamplight above him.</charAction> I think I can help you out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to Zuko's smoke-billowing ship. Close-up to show a small
                vessel holding Zuko being slid into the waters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle, keep heading north. Zhao will follow the smoke trail, while I use it as a
            cover.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh grunts in doubt, stroking his beard in deep thought. Zuko's boat
                settles on the ocean's surface and disappears in the smoke. Switch to a telescope
                view of nothing but smoke. Zhao lowers telescope, staring with
                determination.</description>
      <description>Switch to view of sanctuary door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Kneeling. Pours oil into a bag.</charAction> This is a little trick I
            picked up from my father. I seal the lamp oil inside an animal skin casing, Shyu lights
            the oil soaked twine and, <charAction>Picks up bag, holds it proudly before
                him.</charAction> ta-da! Fake firebending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Impressed.</charAction> You've really outdone yourself this time,
            Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">This might actually work.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Time skip. Sokka places his last bag into the dragon's
                mouth.</charAction> The sages will hear the explosion, so as soon as they go off,
            you rush in!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Hides behind a column with her brother. Holds Momo. Glances to the next
                column where Aang hides.</charAction> It's almost sunset. Are you ready?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Definitely.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shyu thrusts his finger forward, sending a small flare racing across the
                door to light all five bags at once. Shyu hurries to take cover. There is an intense
                explosion, producing a lot of smoke. Aang bursts forward and runs for the door. Aang
                strains to open the door, which has not budged.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> They're still locked!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Sadly sighs. Sokka rises from hiding behind his sister.</charAction> It
            didn't work. <charAction>Aang falls to his knees.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Time skip. Everyone stands in front of the door. Aang beats upon it
                furiously with consecutive airbending slices.</charAction> Why, won't, it,
            open?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Presses forward. Seizes Aang's arm.</charAction> Aang! Stop!
                <charAction>Relaxes, releasing his arm.</charAction> There's nothing else we can do
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Glumly.</charAction> I'm sorry I put you through all of this for
            nothing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Examining the explosion. Runs his finger across the black
                soot.</charAction> I don't get it. That firebending looked as strong as any
            firebending I've seen.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>A moment passes. Sudden excitement.</charAction> Sokka, you're a
            genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Wait. How is Sokka a genius? His plan didn't even
            work.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pleasantly.</charAction> Come on Aang. Let her dream.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're right. Sokka's plan didn't work. But it looks like it did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Dubiously.</charAction> Did the definition of genius change over the
            last hundred years? <charAction>Katara grasps her chin, slyly grinning toward
                Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Time skip. Fire Sages run toward Shyu in front of the door.</charAction>
            Come quickly! The Avatar has entered the sanctuary!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">How did he get in?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">I don't know. But look at the scorch marks! And down there! <charAction>Points to a
                shadow visible at the bottom of the door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">He's inside! Open the doors, immediately! Before he contacts Avatar Roku!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang slides into position behind a nearby column as the five sages firebend
                the doors locks open. As the door opens, a sooty Momo is revealed sitting on the
                floor. Momo sneezes, blowing the soot off himself.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">It's the Avatar's lemur. He must have crawled through the pipes! We've been
            tricked!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo springs into action, leaping atop the Great Fire Sage's head and
                clinging to his hat. Katara charged forward, pulling a nearby sage's tunic over his
                head to blind him. Sokka grabs the lower skirt of a sage's outfit, lifting it
                completely over his body to cover his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Grabs the last free sage and hauls him into his grip, pinning
                him.</charAction> Now, Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>A moment of silence.</charAction> Aang! Now's your chance!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Steps out from behind column. Grips Aang from behind, pinning Aang's
                arms behind him.</charAction> The Avatar's coming with me! <charAction>The captured
                sages use their captors' surprise to reclaim the upper hand, pinning their captors
                down. Momo flies off with the Great Fire Sage's hat.</charAction> Close the doors!
            Quickly!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Walking down steps, Aang glances over his shoulders to see Sokka and Katara
                being chained to a column. He breaks free, spinning behind Zuko to send him down the
                stairs with an airbending blast. Aang runs for Katara and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Chained. Sees him coming toward her. Turns head toward the closing
                door.</charAction> Go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang listens without hesitation, turning to charge for the door guarded by
                two sages. He leaps into the air to avoid the Great Fire Sage's fire punch. Aang
                bounces off his hands from each of the two sage's heads before sailing through the
                door just as it closes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pleased.</charAction> He made it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Everyone looks away as the door seals with a blinding flash of white light.
                Inside, Aang is kneeling and looks up to a tall statue of Avatar Roku. A beam of red
                sunlight enters the room and strikes a glistening red jewel held by the
                statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stands. Confused.</charAction> The light hits the statue and I talk to
            Roku. So why isn't anything happening?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He and four sages launch fire blasts into the door's locks. Nothing
                happens. Frustrated.</charAction> Why isn't it working? It's sealed shut!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">It must have been the light. Avatar Roku doesn't want us inside.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Exasperated. Standing in the middle of the room, facing the
                statue.</charAction> Why isn't anything happening? I don't know what I'm doing! All
            I know is airbending! Please Avatar Roku, talk to me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku's statue turns red as sunlight engulfs it. Its eyes glow white. View
                of Aang as smoke fills the room. When the white smoke dissipates Avatar Roku is
                standing before him, they are on a mountaintop and only clouds are visible
                below.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">It's good to see you Aang. What took you so long? <charAction>Aang respectfully
                places a fist into his palm, bowing his head to the Avatar before
            him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Firmly to Shyu, who is kneeling before him with his hands behind his
                back.</charAction> Why did you help the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Sadly and proudly.</charAction> Because it was once the sages' duty. It
            is still our duty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Claps. Interrupts interrogation. Approaches with six firebender
                guards.</charAction> What a moving and heartfelt performance. I'm certain the Fire
            Lord will understand, when you explain why you betrayed him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">
         <charAction>Places palms together. Bows head forward.</charAction> Commander
            Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">And Prince Zuko. It was a noble effort, but your little smokescreen didn't work.
                <charAction>Zuko scowls sharply. Firebenders step behind him, seizing his
                arms.</charAction> Two traitors in one day, the Fire Lord will be pleased.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Strains against his captor, snaps at Zhao.</charAction> You're too late,
            Zhao! The Avatar's inside and the doors are sealed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">No matter. <charAction>Grins confidently.</charAction> Sooner or later, he has to
            come out. <charAction>Katara and Sokka share a worried glance.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I have something very important to tell you, Aang. That is why, when you were in the
            Spirit World, I sent my dragon to find you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Interested, curious.</charAction> Is it about that vision? The one of
            the comet?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Yes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What does it mean?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">One hundred years ago, <charAction>Viewers see a visual of a comet in the dark
                sky.</charAction> Fire Lord Sozin used that comet to begin the War. He and his
            firebending army harnessed its incredible power, and dealt a deadly first strike against
            the other nations.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> So the comet made them stronger?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Yes. Stronger than you could even
            imagine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> But that happened a hundred years ago. What does
            the comet have to do with the War now?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Listen carefully. <charAction>Viewers see silhouette of Fire Lord Ozai standing amid
                flames, fists taut.</charAction> Sozin's Comet will return by the end of this
            summer, and Fire Lord Ozai will use its power to finish the War, once and for all.
                <charAction>Visual and audio of Ozai's silhouette roaring upward, fire streaming
                from his mouth.</charAction> If he succeeds, even the Avatar won't be able to
            restore balance to the world. Aang. You must defeat the Fire Lord, before the comet
            arrives.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Counters anxiously.</charAction> But I haven't even started learning
            waterbending! Not to mention earth and fire!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Mastering the elements takes years of discipline and practice. But if the world is
            to survive, you must do it by summer's end. <charAction>Close-up of a shocked
                Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Firebenders, including Zhao and his crew, circle around the door's
                perimeter, assuming a firebending form. A monk chant begins for the audience only.
                They wait patiently for the door to open.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">When those doors open, <charAction>Shouts.</charAction> unleash all your
            firepower!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> How's Aang gonna make it out of this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Troubled, questioning.</charAction> How are we gonna make it out of
            this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Terrified.</charAction> What if I can't master all the elements in time?
            What if I fail?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I know you can do it Aang. <charAction>Close-up of half his face.</charAction> For
            you have done it before. <charAction>Close-up of half of Aang's now-smiling
                face.</charAction> The solstice is ending. We must go our separate ways, for
            now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But I won't be able to come back to the temple. What if I have questions? How will I
            talk to you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I am a part of you. When you need to talk to me again, you will find a way.
                <charAction>Closes his eyes, providing Aang a vision of Fire Navy ships surrounding
                the island. Speaks to his mind without words.</charAction> A great danger awaits you
            at the temple. <charAction>Provides a vision of the awaiting firebenders on the other
                side of the door.</charAction> I can help you face the threat. But only if you are
            ready.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Eyes and arrows glow.</charAction> I'm ready.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene switches to the guard surrounding the door. The door glows bright
                white once again. Smoke streams come through into the room. The door unlocks itself,
                beginning to open. As it opens, a blinding white light forces all present to look
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Ready ... <charAction>Light fades, revealing a pair of glowing white eyes in the
                darkness.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sokka struggles against his chains. Katara is terrified.</charAction>
            No! Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Fire! <charAction>He and his guards cooperate in blasting fire onto the unseen
                target.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The wall of fire amasses, circling its new host as Avatar Roku, eyes aglow,
                is revealed behind the flames, untouched. Close-up of a shocked and horror-stricken
                Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>In awe.</charAction> Avatar Roku ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Avatar Roku draws the circling fire together in one motion. He sends it
                forward in one powerful wave that sears the room, blasting the offenders off their
                feet and melting the chains binding Katara, Sokka, Shyu, and Zuko with precision.
                View of outside the temple as the blast destroys the outer wall. Close-up of ghostly
                Avatar Roku, turning his glowing glare upon the offending sages. The sages panic,
                all turning to run from his wrath.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shyu">
         <charAction>Implores.</charAction> Avatar Roku is going to destroy the temple! We
            have to get out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Not without Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku kneels into a forward strike, melting the floor with a molten
                firebending trail. He steadily lifts his hand, causing the stream of lava below to
                erupt into maddened explosions. The lava soars through the temple, tearing it apart.
                Zhao and his firebenders are shown fleeing for the temple's exit.</description>
      <description>Katara and Sokka huddle together, arm-in-arm, behind a column. Sokka kneels
                over his sister, protecting her in a brotherly fashion. The destruction ceases
                momentarily as Roku lowers his hands, exhaling soundly. The solstice' beam of
                sunlight is shown leaving his statue; its eyes no longer glow. As this happens all
                smoke in the room draws in upon Avatar Roku, his form disappearing to leave behind a
                weary Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aang sighs weakly and drops to his knees. Sokka and Katara approach
                Aang's sides, supportively lifting him back to his feet.</charAction> We got your
            back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> Thanks. Where's Shyu?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">[ Walking away with Sokka, helping Aang.>] I don't
            know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Visual of the temple as it begins to lean, due to the destruction caused.
                Aang, Katara and Sokka stare in horror upon seeing the stairwell leading to the exit
                filled with lava. They quickly turn to the only exit; the hole in the wall Roku had
                created. There is no escaping, as they are on the top level of the
                temple.</description>
      <description>All three gasp in surprise as they notice Appa and Momo swiftly closing in.
                They run out of the temple, leaping into Appa's saddle. Scene of them flying away on
                Appa, gazing back at the destruction. Momo pops up wearing the Great Fire Sage's
                hat. Scene of Zhao watching the bison fly away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Turns angrily, snapping.</charAction> No Prince, no Avatar! Apparently,
            the only thing I do have is five traitors!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Great Fire Sage">
         <charAction>Interjects.</charAction> But Commander! Only Shyu helped the
            Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Save your stories for the Fire Lord. As far as
            I'm concerned, you are all guilty! <charAction>Orders.</charAction> Take them to the
            prison hold!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to show Zuko spying with his telescope toward Appa flying
                away. He lowers the telescope and sails off in his vessel.</description>
      <description>Night time falls. Appa flies through the clouds. Scene from behind, a
                mourning Aang with his head hung. Katara and Sokka stand and approach their friend,
                kneeling behind him to support him. Katara puts her hand around Aang's
                shoulders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
