<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title episode="27">Zuko Alone</title>
      <director>Lauren MacMullan</director>
      <writer>Elizabeth Welch Ehasz</writer>
      <date>2006-05-12</date>
      <location nation="earth">Plains Village</location>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins with Zuko by himself, riding his stolen ostrich horse
                through a fairly barren landscape. After walking for a bit, they arrive at a
                decrepit bridge over a ravine that breaks as they cross. After regaining control,
                they continue crossing. A little while later, Zuko smells food and spots a steak
                being cooked by a couple below the ridge he is walking on. He holds his stomach in
                hunger, and reaches for his dual dao swords, preparing himself to steal from them.
                However, after noticing that the woman is pregnant, he stops himself and continues
                on his way.</description>
      <description>Riding through grasslands covered in large broken Earth Kingdom rocks, Zuko
                holds his water pouch to his lips for a drink, only to finish it off thirstily.
                Exhausted from his travels, his sight becoming blurry and his eyes closing slowly as
                he struggles to maintain consciousness. He shakes himself awake, only to close his
                eyes again moments later. He has a flashback of a beautiful, middle-aged woman in a
                cloak turning and walking away in a dark hallway. He opens his eyes but keeps his
                head down.</description>
      <description>Under the hot sun, Zuko reaches a small, poor town where the buildings are
                mostly made of wood and seem to be poorly constructed. We come upon four men dressed
                in green, gambling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth Kingdom soldier">Come on, spidersnake eyes! <charAction>He rolls a pair of dice and they land with
                two fives, face-up.</charAction> Ha! Ha! Yeah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two of the other men turn around and punch him in the stomach once each. He
                grunts with each punch.</description>
      <description>Zuko rides through town and passes the soldiers. Their leader, Gow, glares
                at him and Zuko glares back. Zuko stops, gets off of his ostrich horse and turns to
                a merchant at a store.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Could I get some water, a bag of feed and something hot to eat? <charAction>Zuko
                holds out his hand. In it are two coins.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Store owner">Not enough here for a hot meal. I can get you two bags of feed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko looks down, disappointed. He notices that the four Earth Kingdom men
                are watching him.</description>
      <description>Two children hide behind the store counter, looking amused. One of them
                giggles and throws an egg. It hits a gambling soldier.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth Kingdom soldier">Ow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two boys run off as the Earth Kingdom soldier turn around, looking
                angry. They only see Zuko behind them, so they stand up indignantly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Hey! You throwing eggs at us, stranger?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">You see who did throw it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns to face them.</charAction> No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth Kingdom soldier">That your favorite word, no?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Egg had to come from somewhere.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns around.</charAction> Maybe a chicken flew over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Earth Kingdom soldier laughs, and Gow glares at him. At that moment,
                the store owner returns with Zuko's feed bags for the ostrich horse. Gow goes to the
                counter and grabs both bags before he can take them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Thanks for your contribution. The army appreciates your support. <charAction>He
                throws the bags to one of his fellow soldiers.</charAction> You better leave town.
            Penalty for stayin's a lot steeper than you can afford, stranger. Trust me.
                <charAction>He pats his hammer at his side menacingly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldiers turn and leave with the bags.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Store owner">Those soldiers are supposed to protect us from the Fire Nation. But they're just a
            bunch of thugs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko walks toward his ostrich horse. As he is about to re-mount, one of the
                little boys from earlier pops up from behind the animal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Thanks for not ratting me out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko ignores the boy, gets on his steed and starts riding away. Lee casts
                him an annoyed look before brightening. Lee comes up from behind and grabs the
                reins.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">I'll take you to my house and feed your ostrich horse for you. Come on, I owe you!
                <charAction>Lee leads the way, pulling along the animal.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A shot of Zuko holding his stomach in hunger fades to a pig farm, Zuko and
                Lee arrive on a dirt road at the farm among mountains in the countryside. A little
                wooden farmhouse with a roof that needs re-shingling. Several different types of
                hybrid pigs spotted in enclosures.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">No one can ever sneak up on us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No kidding.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Lee takes the ostrich horse away. Zuko casts his glance off to the side;
                the camera shifts to show a pig rooster, who crows at him. A man approaches Zuko. A
                woman peers out from behind the farmhouse.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">You a friend of Lee's?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Lee comes running out of the barn excitedly and grabs his father's
                arm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">This guy just stood up to the soldiers! By the end, he practically had them running
            away!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The woman from earlier comes forward to join her husband and son, wiping
                her hands on a rag.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">Does this guy have a name?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> I'm ... uh ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> He doesn't have to say who he is if he doesn't
            want to, Sela. <charAction>Cuts to shot of him standing with his family.</charAction>
            Anyone who can hold his own against those bully soldiers is welcome here. Those men
            should be ashamed to wear Earth Kingdom uniforms.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">The real soldiers are off fighting the War, <charAction>Cuts to shot of
                Lee.</charAction> like Lee's big brother Sensu. <charAction>Pause.</charAction>
            Supper's going to be ready soon. Would you like to stay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I can't. I should be moving on. <charAction>The wife frowns and casts a glance at
                her husband.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">Gansu could use some help on the barn. Why don't you two work for a while, and then
            we'll eat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko nods in agreement. The camera fades to Zuko and Gansu working on the
                roof of the barn. Lee is resting on a ladder, watching them re-shingle the roof.
                While Gansu is doing well and working steadily, Zuko has several twisted and broken
                nails in front of him, although it is evident he is trying hard to do a good
                job.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">You don't seem like you're from around here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shaking his head.</charAction> Mm-mm.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Where are you from then?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Lowers his hammer.</charAction> Far away.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Ohhh. Where are you going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">Lee, give it a rest. Stop asking the man personal questions, got it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">
         <charAction>Disappointed and rests his head on his arm. He sighs.</charAction> Yes.
                <charAction>Pause.</charAction> So how'd you get that scar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko is surprised at the question and swings down his hammer a little too
                hard. He strikes his thumb, now red, and groans in pain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">It's not nice to bother people about things they might not want to talk about. A
            man's past is his business.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gansu goes back to hammering and so does Zuko. The scene fades away to the
                sound of hammers hitting metal as Zuko starts reminiscing about the
                past.</description>
      <description>Fade to a shot of the water's surface. An unknown person places a fingertip
                in the water and holds their hand out to reveal bread crumbs. Cuts to shot of the
                Royal Gardens, two figures sitting by the edge of a large kidney-shaped pond. Cuts
                to shot of a younger Zuko and his mother, who are feeding some bread to four turtle
                ducks – a mother and her four babies.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Hey Mom, want to see how Azula feeds turtle ducks? <charAction>Zuko throws the rest
                of the loaf of bread into the water and hits one of the baby turtle ducks. Ursa is
                shocked.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Zuko! Why would you do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>After the baby turtle duck surfaces again, the mother turtle duck charges
                forth and bites Zuko's ankle hard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Ow! Ow ow! Ouch! <charAction>Ursa removes the turtle duck from Zuko and gently
                throws her back into the pond, where she swims off with her babies. Zuko is
                pouting.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Stupid turtle duck. Why she'd do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Zuko. That's what moms are like. <charAction>Puts her arm around Zuko.</charAction>
            If you mess with their babies,<charAction>She playfully bites behind Zuko's
                ear.</charAction>, they're gonna bite you back! <charAction>They
            laugh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A little while later, young Azula, Ty Lee and Mai are playing together in
                the royal yard by a man-made river and a rather large fountain. While Mai sits and
                watches under the shade of a tree, Azula does a complicated flip but messes up the
                ending and grunts. Ty Lee does the same flip, only she completes the ending
                perfectly and lands on her feet, arms proudly up in the air. Azula pushes her over
                and laughs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Ty Lee">Ugh! Azula!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko and Ursa walk by together nearby. Mai sees them, smiles, turns away
                and blushes. Azula notices her obvious crush, however, and turns to Ty Lee with a
                plot in mind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Whispering in Ty Lee's ear as her friend giggles.</charAction> Watch
            this! <charAction>Runs toward her mother and Zuko.</charAction> Mom! Can you make Zuko
            play with us? We need equal teams to play a game!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">I am not cart-wheeling.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">You won't have to. <charAction>Rolls her eyes.</charAction> Cart-wheeling's not a
            game, dum-dum.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">I don't care. I don't want to play with you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">We are brother and sister. It's important for us to spend time together! Don't you
            think so, Mom? <charAction>Shoots her mother an innocent smile.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">
         <charAction>Places her hands on Zuko's shoulder.</charAction> Yes, darling, I think
            it's a good idea to play with your sister. <charAction>Ruffles his hair.</charAction> Go
            on now, just for a little while. <charAction>Walks away, with Zuko glaring at his
                sister.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula reaches for an apple on the tree that Mai was under earlier. Mai, now
                standing in front of the fountain, is still while Azula places the apple on her
                head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> Here's the way it goes. <charAction>After
                placing apple on Mai's head, she runs back several feet.</charAction> Now what you
            do is, try to knock the apple off the other person's head, like this. <charAction>Azula
                shots a small jet of flame to the apple with her firebending and knowingly sets it
                on fire.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko is shocked and runs forward toward Mai, who screams as Zuko approaches
                her. He slams into her and the both of them fall into the fountain, with Zuko lying
                on top of Mai's stomach. Both seem very shocked and embarrassed. Azula starts
                laughing at them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Lays a hand on Ty Lee's shoulder.</charAction> See, I told you it would
            work!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Azula and Ty Lee observing Zuko and Mai in the fountain,
                their backs facing the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Ty Lee">Aww, they're so cute together!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko gets up angrily and leaves the fountain. Mai stands up as
                well.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Mai">You two are such ... ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At that moment, Ursa comes from the house toward the children, a scroll of
                paper in her hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">I was just coming to get you. Uncle Iroh sent us a letter from the war-front.
                <charAction>Zuko stomps past her, leaving small puddles behind him as he
                goes.</charAction> You're soaking wet?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">
         <charAction>Raises hands in frustration.</charAction> Girls are crazy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to the letter and what is occurring with Iroh. Rubble
                surround a large gap in the wall of Ba Sing Se with smoke emitting from everywhere.
                A tent is set up nearby, with a younger General Iroh writing at a
                desk.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> If the city is as magnificent as its wall, Ba
            Sing Se must be something to behold. I hope you all may see it someday, if we don't burn
            it to the ground first! <charAction>Laughs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch back to Ursa, Zuko and Azula. The children are laughing at the joke
                as well. Ursa continues down the letter.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Until then, enjoy these gifts.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two servants dressed in white come up, and Zuko runs to meet them. Ursa
                sits there and continues reading.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">For Zuko, a pearl dagger from the general who surrendered when we broke through the
            Outer Wall. Note the inscription and the superior craftsmanship.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko picks up the dagger admiringly, unsheathes it and reads the
                inscription.</charAction> Never give up without a fight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">And for Azula, a new friend. She wears the latest fashion for Earth Kingdom
            girls.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Ursa reads, Azula picks up her present. It is a doll wearing green. She
                picks it up by the head with disgust, making sounds and sticking out her
                tongue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">If Uncle doesn't make it back from war, then Dad will be next in line for Fire Lord,
            wouldn't he?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Azula, we don't speak that way. It would be awful if Uncle Iroh didn't return. And
            besides, Fire Lord Azulon is a picture of health.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">How would you like it if cousin Lu Ten wanted Dad to die?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">I still think our dad would make a much better Fire Lord than His Royal Tea-Loving
            Kookiness. <charAction>Sets the doll's head on fire.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Flashback ends. Night has fallen, and Zuko is sleeping on a pile of hay
                inside the barn. A door opens and Lee comes sneaking in. He takes the Dual Dao
                swords, but nearly stops when Zuko makes a sound in his sleep. Nevertheless, Lee
                walks out of the barn with the swords and closes the squeaky door. Zuko's eyes pop
                open as if he was only feigning sleep the whole time. Cut to a large sunflower
                garden, where Lee is practicing with the swords. He jumps around and chops off
                several sunflower heads. He starts stabbing a nearby dead tree trunk repeatedly, his
                tongue lolling out of his mouth and breathes heavily in effort as Zuko silently
                approaches behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You're holding them wrong.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Lee falls backward in surprise. The shot shows Zuko, arms crossed, standing
                a little further back in the patch of sunflowers. Lee gets back up, ashamed, and
                holds out the swords to Zuko. He takes them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Keep in mind, these are dual swords. Two halves of a single weapon. Don't think of
            them as separate, 'cause they're not. They're just two different parts of the same
            whole.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko swings around the swords carefully, demonstrating his skill. He cuts
                off some sunflower heads, turns around, and hands the swords back to Lee to try. Lee
                is a little more careful this time, and a little less awkward with the swords. He
                turns to Zuko once he is done his mini demonstration. Zuko smiles kindly; Lee smiles
                back and laughs. They begin walking away from the sunflower patch together, side by
                side under the full moon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">I think you'd really like my brother Sensu. He used to show me stuff like this all
            the time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to the morning at the pig farm. Zuko mounts his ostrich horse again,
                ready to leave the hospitable family. Gansu, Sela and Lee have all come to see Zuko
                off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">
         <charAction>Reaches up and offers Zuko a package.</charAction> Here. This ought to
            get you through a few meals.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko is just about to grab the package when he looks up and notices a cloud
                of dust in the distance. It is Gow and his cronies riding in on ostrich horses.
                Gansu steps forward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">What do you think they want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Trouble.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow and his crew ride toward the pig farm. The animals squeal, clearly
                irritated at their arrival. The Earth Kingdom soldiers stop right in front of
                Gansu's family and Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">What do you want, Gow?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Just thought someone ought to tell you that your son's battalion got captured.
                <charAction>To his fellow soldiers.</charAction> You boys hear what the Fire Nation
            did with their last group of Earth Kingdom prisoners?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth Kingdom soldier">Dressed 'em up in Fire Nation uniforms and put 'em on the front line unarmed, the
            way I heard it. <charAction>Spits on the ground.</charAction> Then they just
            watched.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You watch your mouth!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow rides forward a little more toward Gansu when Zuko goes in between
                them, interfering. Gow and Zuko glare at each other.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Why bother rooting around in the mud with these pigs?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow turns around his ostrich horse and all four soldiers ride away, kicking
                up a cloud of dust behind them. Cut to another one of Zuko's flashbacks in the
                palace grounds again and to the fountain seen earlier. Zuko and Azula are happily
                playing together while Ursa sits in front of the fountain when a messenger in white
                approaches her with a scroll. She opens and reads it before standing up and crying.
                She turns to young Zuko and Azula.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Iroh has lost his son. Your cousin Lu Ten did not survive the battle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko seems shocked and sad at the news, while Azula does not seem to react
                at all. Cut back to the present, where Zuko is still in front of the family
                protectively. Sela and Gansu are hugging behind him; Lee is standing close
                by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">What's going to happen to my brother?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gansu">I'm going to the front. I'm going to find Sensu and bring him back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sela and Gansu walk away from Zuko, with Sela crying desperately. Lee runs
                toward Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">When my dad goes ... will you stay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">No. I need to move on.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko reaches behind him and takes out a sheathed dagger. He bends down and
                gives it to Lee, who takes it with a faint smile.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Here. I want you to have this. Read the inscription.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">
         <charAction>Unsheathes the dagger.</charAction> Made in Earth Kingdom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">The other one.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Never give up without a fight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With that, Zuko rides away from Lee. Lee runs after him for a little bit,
                but stops shortly afterward. Cut to Zuko's memory again; this time he is in the
                Royal Palace playing with his dagger from Iroh (the one he just gave to Lee.) He
                fakes his death, dramatically falling to the floor with a groan. Azula sits
                cross-legged behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">You waste all your time playing with knives. You're not even good!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Put an apple on your head and we'll find out how good I am!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">By the way, Uncle's coming home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Does that mean ... we won the War?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">No, it means Uncle's a quitter and a loser.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">What are you talking about? Uncle's not a quitter!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">Oh yes he is! He found out his son died and he just fell apart! A real general would
            stay and burn Ba Sing Se to the ground, not lose the battle and come home
            crying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">How do you know what he should do? He's probably just sad his only kid is gone.
            Forever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At that moment, Ursa appears in the doorway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Your father has requested an audience with Fire Lord Azulon. Best clothes, hurry
            up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko runs past Ursa quickly to get ready, while Azula walks rather
                slowly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>In a bored tone.</charAction> Fire Lord Azulon ... can't you just call
            him 'Grandfather'? He's not exactly the powerful Fire Lord he used to be. Someone will
            probably end up taking his place soon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Young lady! Not another word!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula runs past her mother and leaves.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">What is wrong with that child?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to the Fire Lord's chamber, a large room with many
                columns and a wall of fire in front of the Fire Lord's throne. Ozai, Ursa, Zuko, and
                Azula are all sitting on the floor some distance back from Fire Lord Azulon, though
                Ozai's face remains obscured save for his mouth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">And how was it Great-Grandfather Sozin managed to win the Battle of Han
            Tui?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">
         <charAction>Confusedly.</charAction> Great-Grandfather won ... because ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">Because even though his army was outnumbered, he cleverly calculated his advantages.
            The enemy was downwind and there was a drought. Their defenses burned to a crisp in
            minutes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">Correct, my dear. Now, would you show Grandfather the new moves you demonstrated to
            me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula stands up and moves forward. She begins with some circular motions,
                warms herself up, and firebends. Ozai smiles. Azula does many fairly complicated
                moves with ease, and Zuko watches her in amazement. She finishes off her routine
                with a jump and a powerful fire blast toward the throne, before landing on her feet
                gracefully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">She's a true prodigy! Just like her grandfather for whom she's named.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Sits back down, and looks at Zuko out of the corner of her eye and
                whispers.</charAction> You'll never catch up ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">
         <charAction>Stands up angrily.</charAction> I'd like to demonstrate what I've been
            learning.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ozai frowns at this news. Zuko starts off well, doing the same circular
                motions as Azula earlier. He manages to produce a small fire blast, which does not
                impress Fire Lord Azulon. When he tries to create another one, he falls. He gets
                back up, panting heavily, and tries again, only to fall harder. Ursa gets up
                worriedly and approaches Zuko to comfort him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">I failed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">No. I loved watching you. That's who you are, Zuko. Someone who keeps fighting even
            though it's hard.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azulon">Prince Ozai, why are you wasting my time with this pomp? Just tell me what you want.
            Everyone else, go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ursa, Zuko and Azula start walking out of the throne room; however, Azula
                pulls Zuko off to the side just before they exit. The children hide in the curtains
                at the back of the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">What are you -?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">Shh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula and Zuko stop where the curtains open and peek back out at the throne
                room, exposing only their faces.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">Father, you must have realized as I have, that with Lu Ten gone, Iroh's bloodline
            has ended. After his son's death, my brother abandoned the siege at Ba Sing Se, and who
            knows when he will return home. But I am here, Father, and my children are
            alive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azulon">Say what it is you want!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ozai">Father, revoke Iroh's birthright. I am your humble servant, here to serve you and
            our nation. Use me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azulon">You dare suggest I betray Iroh? My first born? Directly after the demise of his only
            beloved son? I think Iroh has suffered enough! But you ... your punishment has scarcely
            begun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azulon's anger causes the flames around him to grow. Zuko, scared, runs
                away from behind the curtain as Azula watches, but she stays and continues watching
                with an evil smile on her face.</description>
      <description>The scene switches to Zuko laying in a large bed in a large ornate room. He
                suddenly looks up, alarmed. Azula is standing in his doorway, arms crossed. She
                looks amused.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Sing-songy.</charAction> Dad's going to kill you!
                <charAction>Seriously.</charAction> Really, he is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Ha-ha, Azula. Nice try.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">Fine, don't believe me. But I heard everything. Grandfather said Dad's punishment
            should fit his crime. <charAction>Imitates Azulon.</charAction> "You must know the pain
            of losing a first-born son. By sacrificing your own!"</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Liar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">I'm only telling you for your own good. I know! Maybe you could find a nice Earth
            Kingdom family to adopt you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Stop it! You're lying! Dad would never do that to me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ursa appears in the doorway of Zuko's room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Your father would never do what to you? What is going on here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">I don't know ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">It's time for a talk!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ursa drags Azula away from Zuko's bed, and Azula follows reluctantly. Zuko
                clasps the blanket tightly in his hands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">
         <charAction>Chanting in a low voice.</charAction> Azula always lies. Azula always
            lies.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the older Zuko, lying in green grass, holding his traveler's hat to
                his chest.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Azula always lies.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An ostrich horse can be heard. Zuko sits up and looks to see Sela riding
                toward him in a carriage. She is frantic and panicked.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">You have to help! It's Lee – the thugs from town came back as soon as Gansu left.
            When they ordered us to give them food, Lee pulled a knife on them! I don't even know
            where he got a knife! Then they took him away. <charAction>Begins to sob.</charAction>
            They told me if he's old enough to fight, he's old enough to join the army. I know we
            barely know you, but ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Stands up dramatically.</charAction> I'll get your son back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back in the Earth Kingdom town, it is sunset. Zuko is riding on his ostrich
                horse through a small archway that enters into the town. The people around scatter
                when they see him coming. Lee is tied up to a tower. He seems sad, but when he looks
                up to see Zuko. He quickly regains hope.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Hey! There he is! I told you he'd come!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Earth Kingdom soldiers approach him, as does their leader, Gow. Zuko
                dismounts and takes off his hat, placing it on the ostrich horse. They face each
                other, battle imminent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Let the kid go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">
         <charAction>Laughs loudly, but quickly regains composure.</charAction> Who do you
            think you are, telling us what to do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">It doesn't matter who I am. But I know who you are. You're not soldiers; you're
            bullies. Freeloaders, abusing your power. Mostly over women and kids. You don't want Lee
            in your army – you're sick cowards messing with a family who's already lost one son to
            the war.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">
         <charAction>To a fellow soldier.</charAction> Are you gonna let this stranger stand
            there and insult you like this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The soldier runs forward, spear in hand. He goes to attack Zuko, who pulls
                out his sword and punches the other man in the stomach with the hilt without fully
                unsheathing his sword. Zuko re-sheathes his sword while the man slides backward and
                runs away, panting heavily in fear.</description>
      <description>A second Earth Kingdom soldier groans and runs to attack Zuko with his
                spear this time. Zuko punches the spear upward to move it out of the way, grabs onto
                the man's forehead, and shoves him to the ground. The man gets up slowly and flees
                as well.</description>
      <description>A third Earth Kingdom soldier charges toward Zuko with his spear as well.
                Zuko stands there, waiting, until the spear is close enough and kicks the spear
                right in the middle, snapping it. The spearhead, along with half of the spear, goes
                flying in the other direction. The soldier gasps and runs away from Zuko like the
                two men before him. Lee laughs in satisfaction. A crowd has gathered; Sela's worried
                face is one of many.</description>
      <description>With the last of his cronies gone, Gow steps up to the plate to fight Zuko,
                dual hammers against dual swords. They draw their weapons, and Gow throws the first
                blow, a rock he has earthbent, and powerfully thrusts over to Zuko. Zuko deflects it
                readily with his swords. Gow strikes again, this time with three large rocks instead
                of one. He sends them over in rapid succession to Zuko, who deflects the first two
                easily. However, the third rock hits him in the stomach and he stumbles backward.
                This does not dismay him though, so he charges Gow. An old man in the crowd cheers
                him on.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old man">Give him a left! A left!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old woman">It's not a fistfight ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old man">He's got a left sword, don't he?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow does the same earthbending trick as earlier; he throws three large
                rocks at Zuko. Zuko responds the same as before, deflecting the first two but the
                third one hitting him square in the abdomen. However, this time, he falls over and
                somersaults backward, and manages to get up, although weakened and still stumbling
                around. Gow smiles.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old man">Look out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">Behind you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow earthbends again, but with increasingly larger rocks each time. He
                shoots four rocks at Zuko, who manages to destroy each, one by one. It continues
                this way, Gow no longer giving little recovery breaks to Zuko. Both are fighting at
                full force, although Zuko is so busy being defensive of the large flying rocks that
                he cannot become offensive to Gow. However, finally Gow creates a rockalanche and
                directs it at Zuko. The crowd gasps collectively. Zuko is sent flying and lands
                straight on his back, and has a sudden flashback.</description>
      <description>In the flashback, Zuko is sleeping in his room at night when a hand gently
                touches his shoulder. He awakens drowsily to see his mother dressed in a
                cloak.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">... Mom?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Zuko, please, my love, listen to me. Everything I've done, I've done to protect
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She pulls the barely conscious Zuko into a hug.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ursa">Remember this, Zuko. No matter how things may seem to change, never forget who you
            are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She turns away from him with a sad smile, pulls her hood up and disappears
                down the dark hallway; it is the flashback Zuko had at the very beginning of the
                episode.</description>
      <description>The flashback ends as suddenly as it begin, and we cut back to Zuko in the
                Earth Kingdom village, lying on the ground. Gow is approaching him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">
         <charAction>Whispers worriedly.</charAction> Get up ...!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gow raises his hammers to deliver the final blow when Zuko's eyes open. He
                reaches for his swords and gets up firebending, creating a hurricane of flame. Gow
                drops his hammers and is pushed over, and lands on his back. Zuko stands there,
                seething at Gow. Although unarmed, Gow stands up and raises his fists, determined to
                finish the fight. Zuko charges him, sending various fire blasts. Gow tries to
                deflect them with earthbending, but the blasts are too powerful and he is sent
                backward again. Rocks hit his head as he lands in with a cloud of
                dust.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gow">Who ... who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">My name is Zuko. Son of Ursa and Fire Lord Ozai. Prince of the Fire Nation, and heir
            to the throne.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old man">Liar! I heard of you! You're not a prince, you're an outcast! His own father burned
            and disowned him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko kneels down toward Gow, who shudders in fear. However, Zuko does
                nothing to harm him; he only takes Lee's dagger back. Zuko walks toward Lee to give
                it back, but Sela (who had been untying Lee) intervenes. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sela">Not a step closer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Zuko kneels down in front of Sela, with Lee peeking around his mother's
                back, offering the knife.</charAction> It's yours. You should have it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Lee">No! I hate you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko has another flashback. It is probably early morning and he is in his
                bed in his room. He wakes with a start.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Mom? <charAction>Zuko leaps out of bed and runs out of his room down the
                hallway.</charAction> Mom? Mom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko enters a pillared room, where Azula is admiring Zuko's dagger from
                behind a pillar. She re-sheathes it and steps out to face Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Where's Mom?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">No one knows. Oh, and last night, Grandpa passed away.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Not funny, Azula! You're sick. And I want my knife back, now. <charAction>Zuko tries
                to grab it, but misses as Azula quickly moves out of the way, and loudly
                grunts.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Azula">
         <charAction>Tauntingly.</charAction> Who's going to make me?
                <description>Mom?</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko dashes forward and grabs his knife from Azula, who was dangling in a
                tantalizing manner. He runs away to keep looking. Zuko reaches the garden where his
                father is standing still, staring into a pond.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Zuko">Where is she?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ozai does not acknowledge that he has heard Zuko. Zuko bows his
                head.</description>
      <description>The scene switches to the palace from the outside on the stairs, outside at
                night. Row upon row of people standing on the palace grounds, wearing red hooded
                cloaks and carrying long, red, rectangular flags. At the top of the steps to the
                palace, a Fire Sage leader dressed in red, with several other Fire Sages in white
                behind him. There is an elaborate coffin behind him as well. Zuko, Azula, and Ozai
                are standing to his right.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Sage">Azulon. Fire Lord to our nation for twenty-three years. You were our fearless leader
            in the Battle of Garsai. Our matchless conqueror of the Hu Xin Provinces. You were
            father of Iroh, father of Ozai, husband of Ilah, now passed. Grandfather of Lu Ten, now
            passed. Grandfather of Zuko, and Azula. We lay you to rest.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With those words, two attendants in white firebend Azulon's coffin, which
                was on a layer of wood so it burns easily. The Fire Sage holds up the fire
                crown.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Sage">As was your dying wish, you are now succeeded by your second son.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He places the fire crown in Ozai's top knot and steps away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Sage">Hail Fire Lord Ozai!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ozai stands up, and the group of mourners wearing red and holding flags all
                kneel down at once, as do the Fire Sages behind him and Zuko and Azula. Azula is
                smiling wickedly at this new development. Zuko looks over at her and the crowd with
                absolute fear in his eyes. The flashback ends.</description>
      <description>Zuko rides out of the Earth Kingdom village on his stolen ostrich horse.
                The villagers stand in lines on either side of him with various possible weapons in
                their hands: a hoe, a pitchfork, a rock for throwing. They watch him leave with
                anger and hatred in their eyes. As Zuko passes Lee, the boy looks the other way.
                Zuko ignores them, and rides off into the sunset, just as alone as when he
                arrived.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits</description>
   </section>
</root>
