<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>Escape from the Spirit World</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The shot opens to Aang on a hill sitting with his hands covering his ears.
                The camera pans in and Aang wakes up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What happened? Where am I?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> You are in the Spirit World.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looks up and smiles.</charAction> Princess Yue!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot changes to show the spirit Yue floating in front of the moon. The
                camera pans toward her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">Aang, your Avatar Spirit has been injured. If you don't act fast, you will lose your
            connection to your past lives ... <charAction>Shot changes to Aang looking
                concerned.</charAction> and the Avatar Cycle will end. <charAction>Shot changes to a
                side shot of Yue.</charAction> You must find your previous four past lives and
            reconnect with them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Camera pans to him.</charAction> How do I do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yue">
         <charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> You will find them here, in the Spirit World.
            But be careful ... Koh will try to steal your face. <charAction>Frontal shot of Aang,
                whose eyes widen in concern. He subsequently relaxes his face to show no
                emotion.</charAction> Be careful about what spirits you talk to. <charAction>Frontal
                shot of Yue.</charAction> Some will help you, but others work for Koh, and they will
            trick you. <charAction>Camera pans out as Yue fades away.</charAction> Good luck,
            Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to black.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shows a geyser of fire come out from the ground. When the geyser
                suddenly stops, the camera shows Aang standing behind it, and slowly pans
                in.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Roku, where are you? <charAction>A geyser goes off
                in the trees behind him. He looks around and slowly walks forward. Suddenly, a
                geyser goes off right in front of him.</charAction> Aaahh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Suddenly appears from inside the geyser. Bowing.</charAction> Hello
            Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sorry, Roku ... I tried to master the Avatar State ... but I failed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Mastering the Avatar State takes much spiritual discipline and patience.
                <charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> I learned this the hard way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera fades to white and shows an aerial shot of Crescent Island.
                Roku's blue dragon flies toward the volcano.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Where are we going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot changes to a closer shot of the volcano as Roku's dragon flies
                down to the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">To the Fire Sage's temple. One-hundred-fifty-four years ago ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to inside the temple. Aang and Roku are standing in the corner as
                spirits, while Kaja and a younger Roku sit on the floor meditating.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kaja">Concentrate on your breath ... Clear you mind of all thoughts ... <charAction>Split
                screen showing Roku on the bottom and Kaja on the top.</charAction> Enter the Avatar
            State ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A message appears on the bottom of the camera: "Fun Fact: Fire Sage Kaja is
                Fire Sage Shyu's Grandfather" before fading out. Frontal shot of Roku.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Roku">
         <charAction>Thinking.</charAction> Inhale ... and exhale ... I think my leg is
            falling asleep ... clearing mind ... I hope we're not eating komodo chicken for lunch
            again ... <charAction>Sweating and gritting his teeth.</charAction> Arrggh, concentrate!
                <charAction>The camera shakes as he tries to concentrate. He finally stands
                up.</charAction> I can't do it! I've been in retreat for five months and I'm no
            closer to mastering the Avatar State than when I arrived!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>Camera cuts to outside the temple.</charAction> But I was impatient, so
            I decided to use the winter solstice sun to help me ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to inside the temple. Roku meditates on the floor as a beam of light
                moves close to him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">I'm trying to enter the Avatar State using the spiritual energy from the
            Sun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shows a red crystal from which the beam of light emanates. Frontal
                shot of Roku as the circle of light falls on his face. Roku opens his eyes, showing
                he is in the Avatar State. The camera pans back to show the spirits Aang and Roku
                watching the scene.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You did it, Roku! You mastered the Avatar State!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">Well, not exactly ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks toward the camera, which pans back to show Kaja.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kaja">
         <charAction>Peeking from behind a door.</charAction> Roku, what did you
            do?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an outside-view of the temple. White light emanates from the windows
                before the roof explodes and a pillar of light beams up into the sky. Cut to Roku
                standing in a ball of air as he slowly lifts himself from the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>His spirit speaks to Aang.</charAction> I was stuck in the Avatar State.
                <charAction>Kaja protects himself from the winds.</charAction> I could see my body,
            but I couldn't control it. <charAction>The volcano on the island erupts.</charAction>
            Luckily, Fire Sage Kaja was wiser than I, and he knew how to break the Avatar State's
            hold on me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Kaja raises the red crystal and directs the beam at Roku's face. Pan in
                toward Roku as he exits the Avatar State.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Roku">What happened? <charAction>He collapses and the camera fades to black. Cut to Roku
                kneeling on the ground as Kaja stands next to him.</charAction> Cough!
            Cough!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kaja">Looks like we have a lot more training to do ... after you rebuild the
            temple.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Roku looks up and smiles sheepishly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Roku">
         <charAction>His spirit speaks to Aang.</charAction> I see my own impatience in you,
            Aang. Do not be too hard on yourself. You will master the
            Avatar State, as I finally did. <charAction>Camera fades to Roku riding away on his
                dragon.</charAction> Look for Avatar Kyoshi in the place where Hei Bai
            sleeps!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Camera fading to black.</charAction> ... what?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shows Hei Bai sitting among a bamboo forest and nibbling on a
                piece of bamboo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Off-camera; excited.</charAction> Hei Bai! <charAction>Hugging Hei
                Bai.</charAction> Roku told me I'd find you here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hei Bai">Rraaaawww!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stops hugging him.</charAction> I'm happy to see you too. I don't
            suppose you've seen Avatar Kyoshi around, have you? <charAction>Camera fades to black
                and cuts to Aang riding on Hei Bai. Pointing.</charAction> There she is!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Kyoshi standing in the bamboo forest as Aang stands near Hei Bai.
                She smiles at him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">It's nice to see you, Aang. Sorry about the whole "wrongfully accused of murder"
            thing back in Chin Village.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A box fades onto the bottom of the screen, reading "Fun Fact: Kyoshi lived
                for 230 years, making her the oldest Avatar in history", before fading
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">After Chin the Conqueror died, I helped the world live in balance. I accomplished a
            lot of good, but I also made some mistakes ... <charAction>Fade to white and cut to Ba
                Sing Se.</charAction> One of my greatest challenges was dealing with a peasant
            uprising in Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Royal Earthbender Guards defending the Royal Palace from the
                peasant mobs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Angry peasant">Down with the Earth King!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Ba Sing Se's Upper Ring.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> The peasants felt that the Earth King's role
            was outdated and that he did not represent their interests. So they stormed the Upper
            Ring. <charAction>Cut to outside the Earth Kingdom Royal Palace, where the peasants
                topple a statue.</charAction> The peasants destroyed priceless historical artifacts
            and buildings - anything that represented the "old governement
                <charAction>Sic.</charAction>." <charAction>Cut to inside to the throne
                room.</charAction> The Earth King summoned me to help him end the
            revolution.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up shot of the Earth King. A box fades on top of the screen
                with the words "Fun Fact: The 46th Earth King is the current Earth King's
                great-great-great-great grandfather", before fading away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth King">I don't care how you do it, but I want you to squash those unruly peasants!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">I won't do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth King">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> How dare you defy your King!
                <charAction>Pointing.</charAction> Guards, arrest Avatar Kyoshi!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Five of the Earth King's guards surround Kyoshi, who plants her feet on the
                floor and sends the guards flying away with her airbending. Cut to Kyoshi standing
                before the Earth King at his throne. He leans away from her in shock as she points
                one of her fans at him in a threatening manner.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">How dare you defy your Avatar! Are you ready to make a
            compromise?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth King">
         <charAction>Timidly.</charAction> Yes ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">I don't like this revolution either. But everyone in this Kingdom must have a voice
            if balance is to prevail over tyranny. So I propose this - you will listen to the
            peasants' grievances and I will protect you interests and Ba Sing Se's cultural
            heritage. Agreed?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Earth King">Agreed ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Kyoshi observing a line of earthbenders.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> I immediately set to work training an elite
            force of Earthbenders ... <charAction>Cut to her elite force scaling a
                wall.</charAction> They would be silent, precise ... <charAction>Cut to a closer
                shot of the wall, where a member of her elite force grabs onto it with a rock
                glove.</charAction> and feared by all. <charAction>Cut to her elite force standing
                in rows.</charAction> They became known as the Dai Li.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang as the flashback ends.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You trained the Dai Li? But they're the worst, most corrupt Earthbenders in the
            world!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">I thought I was doing the right thing by creating a group that protected cultural
            history. I had no idea what they would become. Aang, our actions always have an effect:
            sometimes positive, sometimes negative ... and sometimes not for many lifetimes.
                <charAction>Cut to her helping Aang onto Hei Bai.</charAction> Hurry! You must find
            the Waterbender Avatar who came before me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But I don't even know his name!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kyoshi">His name is Avatar Kuruk. <charAction>She fades away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to black.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shows Aang riding through the Spirit World on Hei
                Bai.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>They pass a faceless monkey spirit.</charAction> We're in the Realm of
            Koh, Hei Bai ... We better be careful. <charAction>Kuruk lands in front of them and Aang
                screams.</charAction> Aaahh! <charAction>Falls off Hei Bai and lands in some
                mud.</charAction> Koh took your face and replaced it with a bear's face!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Lifts his head to show that he is wearing a polar bear's skin
                hat.</charAction> Relax kid. I'm not going to hurt you. <charAction>Helps Aang stand
                up.</charAction> I'm Avatar Kuruk! Nice to finally meet you. Now tell me, have you
            seen a beautiful woman with long, brown hair around here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, who is she?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">She's my wife. <charAction>Closes his eyes. Fade to him as a young
                Avatar.</charAction> When I was a young Avatar ... <charAction>Camera pans out to
                show his younger self lifting a boulder with one hand while an earthbender stands
                beside him and lifts a boulder with two hands.</charAction> ... I traveled the
            world, challenging other benders to tests of strength ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Speaking inside the flashback and pointing at the camera.</charAction> I
            challenge you to an Agni Kai!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot changes to show him pointing at a Fire Nation
                civilian.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Nation civilian">Uh, I was just going to the store.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Eastern Air Temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> I loved impressing people with my bending
            prowess. Especially girls.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera pans down to show Kuruk creating an air funnel with lotus flowers
                inside to impress a group of Air Nomad ladies.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">Bet you girls have never seen a lotus tornado before!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Airbender girl #1">It's beautiful!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Airbender girl #2">I love you, Avatar Kuruk!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Kuruk riding a wave on a surf board.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> I was arrogant, proud, and boastful ... I never
            thought about settling down until I met the love of my life. <charAction>Cut to the
                Northern Water Tribe.</charAction> We met during the New Moon Celebration, when the
            sister tribes would come together as one. <charAction>Cut to Kuruk standing amid three
                women and looking past them.</charAction> It was love at first sight.
                <charAction>Cut to Ummi.</charAction> Her name was Ummi. She was from the Southern
            Tribe. And she was the most beautiful woman I'd ever seen. <charAction>Cut to Ummi and
                Kuruk sitting together in front of the full moon.</charAction> With Ummi in my life,
            I decided to change my irresponsible ways and settle down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Kuruk offering Ummi a betrothal necklace.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ummi">A betrothal necklace?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">Ummi, will you marry me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ummi">Yes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They kiss. Cut to the Spirit Oasis.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> We were to be married in the Spirit Oasis. But
            on the day of our wedding, tragedy struck.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Ummi glances down at the spirit pond and falls in.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">Ummi! No! <charAction>Swims into the spirit pond.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Ummi fell into the spirit pond, as if some
            unseen force pulled her in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Standing in the middle of the Spirit Oasis as Tui and La circle
                him.</charAction> She's gone ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> She didn't drown. She disappeared into the
            Spirit World ... Koh took her to punish me for my past mistakes. <charAction>Cut to Aang
                and Kuruk in the Spirit World.</charAction> Every year, on the anniversary of our
            wedding, I traveled <charAction>Sic.</charAction> to the Spirit World hoping to save my
            wife from Koh. But I failed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Glances to the side.</charAction> I'm sorry. I know how that feels.
                <charAction>His eyes widen.</charAction> Wait! I've seen her! <charAction>Cut to
                Aang's flashback of Koh using Ummi's face.</charAction> Koh still has her! When I
            was in Koh's lair, he showed me Ummi's face!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuruk">
         <charAction>Determined.</charAction> Thank you, Aang. My search is not over yet. I
            will keep hunting Koh until Ummi and I are reunited. <charAction>Runs away.</charAction>
            Hurry! Avatar Yangchen is waiting for you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to black.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The shot shows Aang and Hei Bai standing at the top of a
                mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Hello? Avatar Yangchen? Anyone here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>Fades in front of Aang.</charAction> It's an honor to meet you,
            Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's been such an amazing experience to meet my past lives.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">And what did you learn by meeting them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well ... I realized that no Avatar is perfect. They all struggled and made mistakes.
            Like me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">Very wise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But it made me wonder - why is the Avatar Spirit a human in every life? Wouldn't it
            be better if the Avatar was an all powerful spirit that never died?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">I don't think so. <charAction>Katara, Sokka, Toph, Iroh, and Zuko fade onto the
                camera.</charAction> The Avatar must be compassionate towards all people ... and the
            only way to do that is to live with them. <charAction>Fade to a sand sailer dragging
                Appa away.</charAction> The Avatar must experience sadness ... <charAction>Camera
                pans to show Aang with tears rolling down his face. Cut to Aang in the Avatar State
                in the crystal catacombs.</charAction> Anger ... <charAction>Cut to Aang and Katara
                penguin sledding.</charAction> Joy ... <charAction>Cut to Team Avatar reuniting with
                Appa.</charAction> and happiness. <charAction>Cut to Yangchen.</charAction> By
            feeling all these emotions, it helps you understand how precious human life is ... so
            you will do anything to protect it. If you were an all powerful spirit living on the top
            of some mountain, you wouldn't have much in common with an ordinary person. So the
            Avatar continues to take human rebirth. <charAction>Kuruk, Kyoshi, and Roku appear
                behind her.</charAction> And with each life, learns what it means to be
            human.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Now that I've reconnected with all of you, does that mean the Avatar Spirit is
            okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yangchen">
         <charAction>The three Avatar spirits behind Yangchen fade away.</charAction> Yes,
            but your physical body is still injured. You need time to heal. <charAction>Puts her
                hand on Aang's forehead tattoo and both of their Air Nomad tattoos
                glow.</charAction> And unfortunately, it seems your ability to enter the Avatar
            State has been disrupted. You won't be able to rely on your past lives to help you. You
            must rely on your friends. And when you wake up, you won't remember this journey to the
            Spirit World. It will be like a forgotten dream. <charAction>Fading away.</charAction>
            Until we meet again, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to the words "The End" with a black background.</description>
   </section>
</root>
