<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>Lake Laogai Episode</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to Team Avatar's place of stay in Ba Sing Se, where Sokka
                is drawing inaccurate pictures of Appa for missing posters. Katara and Aang
                enter.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> We found a printer to make our posters!
                <charAction>Reveals the poster and Aang smiles and points at
            it.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, I thought designing the lost Appa poster was my job. I've been working all day
            on my Appa! <charAction>Shows his crudely drawn picture of Appa with a proud smile. Cut
                to an exasperated Aang while Katara tries to hold back her
            laughter.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka, the arrow is on Appa's head.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> This is his head. <charAction>Points to the
                sketch.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Takes the picture from Sokka, looks confused.</charAction> Why are feet
            coming out of it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Snatches back the picture indignantly.</charAction> Those are his horns.
                <charAction>Hangs his head.</charAction> I haven't seen him in a while,
            okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> It looks just like him to me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Thank you, I worked really- <charAction>Suddenly remembering that she is
                blind.</charAction> Why do you feel the need to do that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Let's just stick with the professional version.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka angrily rips up his drawing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Come on, let's get busy! <charAction>Holds up
                some pamphlets.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang and Momo dropping dozens of posters all over Ba Sing Se. One
                poster falls in front of the camera, and the scene changes to tea shop where Zuko
                and Iroh are working. Iroh serves tea to two customers, who enjoy it. They approach
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">So, you're the genius behind this incredible brew. The whole city is buzzing about
            you! I hope Pao pays you well.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Good tea is its own reward.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">But it doesn't have to be the only reward. How would you
            like to have your own tea shop?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Pao looks around, concerned.</charAction> My own tea shop?
            This is a dream come true!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pao">
         <charAction>Quickly moving to stand between the group.</charAction> What's going on
            here? Are you trying to poach my tea-maker?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">Sorry Pao, but that's business for you, am I right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pao">Mushi, if you stay, I'll make you assistant manager. Wait, senior assistant
            manager!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">I'll provide you with a new apartment in the Upper Ring. <charAction>Cut to Zuko,
                who was busy putting empty tea cups on a tray, but now looks up and glances over his
                shoulder to follow Quon's offer more closely; voice-over.</charAction> The tea shop
            is yours to do whatever you want, <charAction>Cut back to frontal shot of
                Quon.</charAction> complete creative freedom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I even get to name the shop?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">Of course!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pao">Uh, senior executive assistant manager?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh hands him the pot of tea and bows to the customer, agreeing to the
                terms. Zuko walks by, as Pao walks away sadly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Did you hear, nephew? This man wants to give us our own tea shop in the Upper Ring
            of the city!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Quon">That's right, young man, your life is about to change for the better!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> I'll try to contain my joy.
                <charAction>Walks outside, slams door shut.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As he walks outside, he grabs a falling Appa poster. He climbs to the top
                of a house and notices several of them falling, searching the skies for any sign of
                the Avatar. He glances down again at the Appa poster. Camera zooms in as he looks up
                from the poster with a determined look on his face.</description>
      <description>Back at the house. Sokka and Katara are playing a game. Toph is just
                relaxing as Aang re-enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I just finished dropping all the leaflets. Has anyone come in with news about
            Appa?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's only been a day. Just be patient. <charAction>Aang sits,
                unenthused.</charAction> </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A knock at the door and Aang jumps up and runs to the door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow, you're right! Patience really pays off! <charAction>Opens the door, revealing
                the "original" Joo Dee has returned.</charAction> Joo Dee?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">Hello, Aang, and Katara, and Sokka, and Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>They approach as Joo Dee enters.</charAction> What happened to you? Did
            the Dai Li throw you in jail?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">What? Jail? Of course not. The Dai Li are the protectors of our cultural
            heritage.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">But you disappeared at the Earth King's party.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">Oh, I simply took a short vacation to Lake Laogai, out in the country. It was quite
            relaxing. <charAction>Sokka glares at her skeptically.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But then they replaced you with some other woman who also said her name was Joo
            Dee.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> I'm Joo Dee.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Why are you here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">Dropping fliers and putting up posters isn't permitted within the city. Not without
            proper clearance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We can't wait around to get permission for everything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">You are absolutely forbidden by the rules of the city to continue putting up
            posters.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angrily yelling; during this brief argument, Aang is shown as a chibi
                and his head turns scarlet red.</charAction> We don't care about the rules and we're
                not asking permission! <charAction>Camera cuts to Joo
                Dee's horrified face. She slowly backs out of the house as Aang continues to yell at
                her.</charAction> We're finding Appa on our own and you should just stay out of our
            way! <charAction>Slams the door as she exits.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">That might come back to bite us in the blubber.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Calming down.</charAction> I don't care! From now on, we do whatever it
            takes to find Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, let's break some rules! <charAction>Takes out a side of the house with
                earthbending.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo flies out the broken side of the house and they all exit. Two Dai Li
                agents watch overhead from a house roof across the street. </description>
      <description>The scene changes to the Royal Palace, where Long Feng meets with that
                particular Joo Dee. Two Dai Li agents stand guard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">I'm very disappointed in your work with the Avatar and his friends, Joo Dee. I had
            hoped that you would be able to control this situation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">I am so sorry, but they don't trust me anymore. <charAction>Starts getting
                upset.</charAction> I don't think I can keep working like this! <charAction>Begins
                to sob.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Joo Dee, the Earth King has invited you to Lake Laogai.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dee">
         <charAction>Camera zooms toward her eye as its iris dilates; in a monotone
                voice.</charAction> I am honored to accept his invitation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">
         <charAction>Nods.</charAction> Good. Now go await further orders. <charAction>Joo
                Dee nods and begins to exit. Long Feng gets up and moves to the
                fireplace.</charAction> If the Avatar keeps searching for his bison, it could upset
            the delicate balance we've worked so hard to achieve in this city. It could even cost us
            control of the Earth King.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dai Li agent">Should we take care of him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">No. It's much too dangerous for us to confront him directly. Let's see if we can
            still handle this quietly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At Iroh and Zuko's place of stay, which is about to change. Zuko enters
                Iroh's room. Iroh is packing his clothes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">So, I was thinking about names for my new tea shop. How about the Jasmine Dragon?
            It's dramatic, poetic, has a nice ring to it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Shows Iroh the flyer.</charAction> The Avatar is here in Ba Sing Se and
            he's lost his bison.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Grabs the flyer.</charAction> We have a chance for a new life here.
                <charAction>Cut to Zuko looking out a window.</charAction> If you start stirring up
            trouble, we could lose all the good things that are happening for us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns to Iroh.</charAction> Good things that are happening for
                you! Have you ever thought that I want more from life
            than a nice apartment and a job serving tea?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">There is nothing wrong with a life of peace and prosperity. I suggest you think
            about what it is that you want from your life and why.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I want my destiny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">What that means is up to you. <charAction>Zuko walks away. Continues brainstorming
                names for his new tea shop.</charAction> The Tea Weevil! No, that's stupid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Team Avatar, who are working to put up more
                posters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We'll split up to cover more area. Toph, I guess you should just come with
            me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Peevishly.</charAction> Why? Because you think I can't put up posters on
            my own?! <charAction>Angrily takes the paintbrush of glue from Sokka and throws glue on
                the wall. She slams a poster on it, but it is backward. Awkward pause.</charAction>
            It's upside-down, isn't it? I'll just go with Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all go their separate ways, with Toph following Sokka. Cut to an open
                square, where Katara is putting up a poster on a stone plinth near a flowing water
                stream. Suddenly, behind her, she hears a familiar voice call out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Katara?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet is seen emerging from an alleyway at the edge of the square. Katara
                wheels around with a startled gasp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Walks closer. Smiling confidently.</charAction> I think I can help you.
                <charAction>Katara's shocked blush transforms into a look of pure outrage. With a
                sweep of her arms, she bends up water from a lake directly at him while screaming in
                rage. Jet looks at the wave in fright.</charAction> Katara, I've changed!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The wave hits Jet, sending him back quite a distance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Bending up remaining water from the wave.</charAction> Tell it to some
            other girl, Jet! <charAction>Turns the water to ice, which sends Jet back to a
                wall.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Blocks the ice with his swords.</charAction> I don't want to fight you,
            I'm here to help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Throws his swords down, and reaches for something behind his back. Katara
                quickly fires more ice crystals, which pin him to the wall. The rest of the team
                approaches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Katara, what is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Jet's back. <charAction>Close-up of Jet's face. Cut to aerial view before switching
                to a closer view of the group.</charAction> We can't trust anything Jet
            says.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">But we don't even know why he's here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't care why he's here, whatever the reason is, it can't be good!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I'm here to help you find Appa! <charAction>Opens his hand and reveals he is holding
                a missing Appa poster.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turning from the leaflet back to Katara.</charAction> Katara, we have to
            give him a chance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I swear, I've changed! I was a troubled person and I let my anger get out of
            control, but I don't even have the gang now! I've put all that behind me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're lying!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Walks up to Jet and feels the wall he is pinned to.</charAction> He's
            not lying.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How can you tell?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I can feel his breathing and heartbeat. When people lie, there's a physical
            reaction. He's telling the truth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, we don't have any leads. If Jet says he can take us to Appa, we have to
            check it out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">All right. <charAction>Points and looks angrily at Jet.</charAction> But we're not
            letting you out of our sight.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She stabs her finger at Jet once more for emphasis, eyes narrowed. Cut to
                Jet entering a dimly lit warehouse, which sits empty except for a few sacks and a
                pile of canvas and rope.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">This is the place I heard about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There's nothing here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Preparing to waterbend in defense.</charAction> If this is a
            trap–</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I told you, I work nearby! Two guys were talking about some giant furry creature
            they had, I figured it must be Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">He was here! <charAction>She shows them a clump of Appa's fur.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> We missed him. <charAction>An old white haired man
                with a push-broom crosses behind the slumping Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old Sweepy">They took that big thing yesterday. <charAction>Aang straightens with a shocked
                look.</charAction> Shipped him out to some island. About time, I've been cleaning up
            fur, and various, uhhh ... leavings all day.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aang swiftly moves closer to the man.</charAction> What island? Where's
            Appa?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old Sweepy">Foreman said some rich royal type on Whaletail Island bought him up. Guess for a zoo
            or such. Though, could be the meat that'd be good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We've got to get to Whaletail Island! <charAction>Pauses.</charAction> Where's
            Whaletail Island? <charAction>Dejectedly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Looking at map.</charAction> Far, very far. <charAction>Puts the map on
                the ground as they all gather round.</charAction> Here it is. It's near the South
            Pole, almost all the way back home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, it will take us weeks just to get to the tip of the Earth Kingdom. And then
            we'll need to find a boat to get to the island.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't care. We have a chance to find Appa! We have to try!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old Sweepy">Must be nice to visit an island. I haven't had a vacation for years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Don't you have some more hair to clean up?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Old Sweepy">Shuffle on, I get you. No more need for Old Sweepy ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You're right Aang, right now our first concern has to be finding Appa. We can come
            back when we have him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">All right, let's get moving.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I'll come with you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We don't need your help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Why won't you trust me? <charAction>Walks after Sokka and
            Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Gee, I wonder.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>After Jet walks away.</charAction> Was this guy your boyfriend or
            something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What ... no! <charAction>She folds her arms and looks away
            defiantly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> I can tell you're lying ... <charAction>Katara runs
                away from her, embarrassed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back within the city</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We can take the train out to the wall but then we'll have to walk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't worry, on the way back we'll be flying!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">We're finally leaving Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Spreads her arms outward in
                celebration.</charAction> Worst ... city ... ever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Smellerbee and Longshot appear in the background and notice
                Jet.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Smellerbee">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Jet!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks at Jet angrily.</charAction> I thought you said you didn't have
            your "gang" anymore!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Turns to look at Smellerbee, confused.</charAction> I don't!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Smellerbee">
         <charAction>Runs up to Jet and hugs him.</charAction> We were so worried. How did
            you get away from the Dai Li? <charAction>Camera quickly zooms in to Katara's shocked
                face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> The Dai Li?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I don't know what she's talking about!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Smellerbee">He got arrested by the Dai Li a couple of weeks ago. We saw them drag him
            away!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Why would I be arrested? I've been living peacefully in the city!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Feeling the ground between Jet and Smellerbee.</charAction> This doesn't
            make any sense. They're both telling the truth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's impossible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No it's not! Toph can't tell who's lying because they both think they're telling the
            truth. Jet's been brainwashed!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">That's crazy! It can't be! <charAction>Glances to the sides.</charAction> Stay away
            from me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They all surround him. Cut to the moon in the night sky. Cut to a Dai Li
                agent walking the streets. Zuko, disguised as the Blue Spirit, runs
                by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Out of my way, skinny!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The agent prepares to use his rock glove, but pauses when the disguised man
                turns into an alley. The agent runs to the alley and sees a figure that appears to
                be him. He fires his rock gloves at the figure's chest and head, knocking off the
                stuffed figure's head and knocking it down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dai Li agent">Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>There is the whisper of a drawn blade behind him and Zuko, still disguised,
                captures him and places one of his swords to the agent's neck.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">If you don't want to end up like him, you'll do what I say.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back in an unknown building, Team Avatar, Longshot, and Smellerbee all
                surrounding a seated Jet.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The Dai Li must have sent Jet to mislead us, and that janitor was part of their
            plot, too!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I bet they have Appa here in the city. Maybe he's in the same place they took Jet!
            Where did they take you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Nowhere! I- I don't know what you're talking about!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We need to find a way to jog his real memories.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Teasingly.</charAction> Maybe Katara should kiss him. That should bring
            something back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe you should kiss him, Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, just an idea!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jealously.</charAction> A bad one.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Ooh, wait! I've got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka plucks a straw from his mattress, pokes it into Jet's mouth in
                trademark fashion and regards him thoughtfully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I don't think it's working. <charAction>Spits it out.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Try to think of something from your past that triggers your emotions.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Smellerbee">The Fire Nation! Remember what they did to your family!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Close your eyes. Picture it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet closes his eyes, while sweat beads start to form on his forehead. His
                eyes suddenly snap wide open and he sees images of himself at a younger age watching
                his town burning down and Mongke looking back at him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Sweating.</charAction> No! It's too painful!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe this will help. <charAction>Takes water and puts it around his ears, using
                healing to clear his mind.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet looks up from the floor and sees an image of Long Feng standing above a
                lake. Long Feng stares at Jet, and Jet sinks down under the lake into an underground
                room. He sees an image of a Dai Li agent shining a spinning light in his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">They took me to a headquarters under the water. Like a lake!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Wait! Remember what Joo Dee said? She said she went on vacation to Lake
            Laogai!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> That's it! Lake Laogai.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to an aerial shot of Lake Laogai. The camera pans down to show Team
                Avatar, Jet, Longshot, and Smellerbee standing at the edge of the
                lake.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So where's this secret headquarters?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Under the water, I think.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">There's a tunnel right there by the shore.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph points to the side and whistles as she walks to the edge of the shore.
                She uses her earthbending to bring up a slab of rock with an entrance. She moves the
                rock out the way with the same technique. They all look down at the tunnel and Momo
                flies away. Cut to them inside the secret headquarters. Jet checks to make sure the
                coast is clear and they walk down a long hallway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">It's all starting to come back to me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet walks past a room where a member of the Dai Li brainwashes a group of
                women.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Brainwasher">I'm Joo Dee. Welcome to Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dees">
         <charAction>Simultaneously</charAction>.] I'm Joo Dee. Welcome to Ba Sing
            Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Brainwasher">We're so lucky to have our walls to create order.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Joo Dees">[<charAction>Simultaneously.</charAction> We're so lucky to have our walls to create
            order.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">I think there might be a cell big enough to hold Appa up ahead. I think it's through
            here! <charAction>Opens a door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Appa chained up as a door opens in his cell and Appa wakes up. Cut
                to Zuko standing at the door, disguised as the Blue Spirit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Expecting someone else?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet opens the other door. An overhead shot reveals several Dai Li agents
                waiting on the ceiling. The door closes suddenly behind them. Lights turn on,
                revealing the agents.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Now that's something different.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">You have made yourselves enemies of the state. Take them into custody.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Dai Li agents jump off the ceiling and surround them. Two agents fire
                rock gloves, but Toph breaks them up and sends the two agents flying through the air
                with rock pillars. Jet runs toward the agents and breaks two other gloves fired by
                agents with his swords, and trips another. A full battle ensues. Aang deals with a
                pair of Dai Li agents. Sokka and Katara destroy two Dai Li gloves, but a second pair
                grabs them.</description>
      <description>Toph saves them by creating a rock wall and she raises ground up. Toph
                knocks away the four Dai Li agents that attack her, but a glove captures her and Jet
                swings by to free her. The agent fires his other rock glove, and Longshot fires an
                arrow, which destroys the glove. Jet jumps in front of Longshot to hold off more of
                their rock attacks. Long Feng escapes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Knocks away two agents with airbending.</charAction> Long Feng is
            escaping!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet and Aang chase him. They head into another part of the headquarters
                with many pipes of all sizes sticking out of the walls, with some of them pouring
                out water, but are sealed in by Long Feng.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">All right, Avatar, you've caused me enough problems. This is your last chance ... if
            you want your bison back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You do have Appa! Tell me where he is!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Agree to exit the city now, and I'll waive all charges against you and allow you to
            leave with your lost pet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Gets in a fighting position.</charAction> You're in no position to
            bargain.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Am I not?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Gets into a fighting position.</charAction> You're definitely
            not!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Jet, the Earth King has invited you to Lake Laogai.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Close-up of his eye, his iris dilates. In a monotonous
                voice.</charAction> I am honored to accept his invitation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet attacks Aang. Cut to Appa growling at the disguised Zuko. Appa tries to
                strike Zuko, but his chained feet hold him back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You're mine now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The door opens and Zuko gets into a fighting stance. Iroh
                enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">So, the Blue Spirit. I wonder who could be behind that mask ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sighs and takes off the mask.</charAction> What are you doing
            here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I was just about to ask you the same thing. What do you plan to do now that you've
            found the Avatar's bison? Keep him locked in our new apartment? Should I go put on a pot
            of tea for him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">First I have to get it out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Starts yelling.</charAction> And then what!? You never think these
            things through! <charAction>Points at him.</charAction> This is exactly what happened
            when you captured the Avatar at the North Pole! You had him, and then you had nowhere to
            go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I would have figured something out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No! If his friends hadn't found you, you would have frozen to death!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I know my own destiny, Uncle!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Is it your own destiny, or is it a destiny someone else has tried to force on
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Stop it, Uncle! I have to do this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm begging you, Prince Zuko! It's time for you to look inward and begin asking
            yourself the big questions. Who are you, and what do you
            want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko screams loudly, throwing down his swords and Blue Spirit mask. Cut to
                the brainwashed Jet continuing to swing at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Jet, it's me, Aang! <charAction>Runs back.</charAction> You don't have to do
            this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">I'm afraid he no longer has a choice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet resumes his attempts at attacking Aang, who dodges them and uses
                airbending to knock him back. Jet uses his hook swords to stop himself and he pants
                heavily.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Jet, I'm your friend! Look inside your heart!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Do your duty, Jet!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">He can't make you do this! <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Jet's face as he hangs
                his head, while panting and sweating.</charAction> You're a Freedom
            Fighter!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At these final words, Jet straightens in shock. Everything goes white and
                he has a rapid flashback of his past as a Freedom Fighter, seeing Longshot,
                Smellerbee, Pipsqueak and the Duke, and him with Katara. The Freedom Fighters cheer
                fades to him with Smellerbee and Longshot, before showing him sitting down with Iroh
                and Zuko. Fade to him giving the passengers food, and quickly to him being dragged
                away by the Dai Li. Fade more rapidly to Jet's brainwashing, and to Long Feng on
                Lake Laogai. Cut to his burning village, to Iroh, to him with Zuko, to him with
                Katara, to him watching his burning village crying. Cut to him in a Fire Nation
                camp, to him with Katara, and to him being brainwashed. Cut back to him crying while
                watching his village burn as Mongke watches. The flashback ends and Jet's irises
                return to normal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Do it! Do it now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Jet fires a sword at Long Feng, which misses. Long Feng counters with an
                uplifted rock which strikes Jet down. Aang runs toward Jet as Long Feng escapes
                through a pipe in the wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">
         <charAction>Escaping upward to a pipe.</charAction> Foolish boy. You've chosen your
            own demise. <charAction>Exits.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> I'm sorry ... Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> Don't be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The rest of the group arrives, all struck with sorrow and shock as they
                gather around Jet. Katara stares open-mouthed at Jet, her hands hovering near her
                mouth in shock. Snapping out of it, she withdraws water from her water skin, with
                which she covers her hands, and it begins to glow as she kneels down next to him.
                Cut to a shot from over her shoulder, with Jet glancing at her while she rubs her
                hands over his chest in an attempt to heal him. After rubbing his chest three times,
                the glow fades, the water stains Jet's clothing, and Katara looks back over her
                shoulder toward the rest of the group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This isn't good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Smellerbee">You guys go and find Appa. We'll take care of Jet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're not going to leave you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Longshot">There's no time. Just go. We'll take care of him. He's our leader.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They stare at Longshot in surprise.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Jet">Don't worry, Katara. I'll be fine. <charAction>Smiles a
            little.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara closes her eyes in painful sadness and opens them again as she
                rises. Team Avatar begins to exit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Whispering to Sokka.</charAction> He's lying ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Smellerbee crying. Longshot watches Team Avatar
                completely leave through a tunnel that is earthbent open before turning the other
                way to the other exit and standing guard, prepping an arrow. Smellerbee is seen
                kneeling next to Jet, rubbing her hands back and forth over him, with her right hand
                on his forehead.</description>
      <description>Team Avatar reaches Appa's hold, only to discover that it is
                empty.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa's gone! Long Feng beat us here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">If we keep moving, maybe we can catch up with them!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They find an exit back to the beach. As they make their escape, several Dai
                Li agents jump out from behind them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You think we can outrun them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't think it's gonna matter!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Another group of Dai Li agents, plus Long Feng, stand in front of them. All
                the agents box them in, lifting up the ground on both sides. Dai Li agents stand on
                all three walls. Momo flies to Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What is it, Momo?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo flies to the sky and chirps excitedly. Suddenly, Appa flies down.
                Cut to the overjoyed looks on Team Avatar's faces.</description>]
    </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa smashes through the rock walls, scattering the Dai Li agents. Aang and
                Toph use earthbending to knock other nearby agents off a cliff and into the lake.
                Appa confronts Long Feng.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">I can handle you by myself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Long Feng charges at Appa, but Appa grabs his leg and hurtles him skipping
                into the lake. Appa spits out Long Feng's shoe. The team cheers and they run toward
                Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah! Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily crying.</charAction> I missed you, buddy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa closes his eyes. A teary-eyed Katara somberly looks over Lake Laogai
                as they fly over it on Appa. Aang places his hand on her shoulder. The team all
                gathers in a group hug. Zuko and Iroh emerge from the Dai Li
                headquarters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">You did the right thing, nephew. <charAction>Zuko looks at his Blue Spirit mask as
                Iroh rests a hand on its shoulder.</charAction> Leave it behind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko walks to the edge and tosses the mask into the water, where it slowly
                sinks to the bottom of the lake. Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
