<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Southern Air Temple</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins with a beautiful sunrise that just peeks above some
                cliffs. The beams of the morning sun reflect on the water, bathing the whole scene
                in yellow light. The camera pans to the left, where the group has made camp on the
                shore. Appa is seen chewing on some grass while the smoke of the nearby campfire
                rises to the sky. Sokka is lying in a blue sleeping bag next to the fire. The camera
                zooms in on Aang and Katara atop Appa. Aang sits on the bison's head and is checking
                the knots that tie the reins to Appa's horns. Katara is sitting on the saddle,
                fiddling with their luggage.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Wait 'til you see it, Katara! The Air Temple is
            one of the most beautiful places in the world!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cautiously.</charAction> Aang, I know you're excited, <charAction>She
                turns around to face him.</charAction> but it's been a hundred years since you've
            been home.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling broadly.</charAction> That's why I'm so excited!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cautiously.</charAction> It's just that ... a lot can change in all that
            time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> I know, but I need to see it for myself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang jumps off Appa, landing softly due to his airbending. A side-view
                shows him as he walks over to a snoring Sokka, who is lying in his sleeping bag. The
                shot changes to a view from next to Sokka's head, looking up at the approaching
                airbender.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> Wake up, Sokka! Air Temple, here we come!
                <charAction>Sokka awakens, making groggy noises.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grunting sleepily.</charAction> Uggh! Sleep now. Temple later.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka turns around, showing his back to Aang and falls back asleep, snoring
                as soon as his eyes close. Close-up of Aang, whose big eyes blink in surprise. He
                looks discontent with Sokka's attitude, but he quickly smiles mischievously. Aang
                grabs a small, thin stick.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Sokka! Wake up! <charAction>Aang moves the stick
                up and down the sleeping bag, only touching Sokka with the tip of it.</charAction>
            There's a prickle snake in your sleeping bag!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He lazily opens one eye before yelling out in horror.</charAction> Ahh!
                <charAction>He quickly rises and hops around, still inside the sleeping
                bag.</charAction> Get it off! Get it off! <charAction>After two hops, Sokka slams
                flat to the ground.</charAction> Ahh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara giggles, as Sokka falls over. Close-up of Sokka's angry
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Great! You're awake! Let's go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene slowly fades to a harbor, where several Fire Nation ships are
                lined up next to each other. The camera pans to the left to reveal a smaller ship
                docked between all the others, identical mastodons. Its walkway is down and the
                small figures of two persons are seen leaving the ship. Cut to a closer shot of Zuko
                and Iroh, as they reach the bottom of the walkway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle, I want the repairs made as quickly as possible. I don't want to stay too long
            and risk losing his trail.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Disinterested.</charAction> You mean the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turns around sharply to face Iroh, as he slightly backs
                off.</charAction> Don't mention his name on these docks! <charAction>Makes some wide
                arm movements.</charAction> Once word gets out that he's alive, every firebender
            will be out looking for him, and I don't want anyone getting in the way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Iroh and Zuko turn, with shocked expressions on their face, toward the
                camera in the direction the sound came from.</charAction> Getting in the way of
            what, <charAction>Close-up of a man with big sideburns dressed in a Fire Nation
                uniform.</charAction> Prince Zuko?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man walks over to the duo with his hands held behind his back. Zuko
                awaits him with his arms crossed with contempt, while Iroh just stares at
                him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>With dislike in his voice.</charAction> Captain Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Smirks.</charAction> It's commander now. And <charAction>Bows slightly
                in Iroh's direction.</charAction> General Iroh. Great hero of our nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Bows back.</charAction> Retired general.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">The Fire Lord's brother and son are welcome guests anytime. What brings you to my
            harbor?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Our ship is being repaired.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Iroh gestures toward the ship, the camera moves back to show the
                severely damaged ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">That's quite a bit of damage.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Yes. <charAction>He holds up one finger, while Iroh stares disinterested in front of
                him.</charAction> You wouldn't believe what happened. <charAction>He glances at his
                uncle, and angrily commands him as he gestures at Zhao.</charAction> Uncle! Tell
            Commander Zhao what happened.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Iroh's eyes open wide in surprise, as he is addressed by
                Zuko.</charAction> Yes. I will do that. <charAction>He happily holds his hand up and
                relates enthusiastically.</charAction> It was incredible! <charAction>To Zuko, from
                the corner of his mouth in a confused tone.</charAction> What? Did we crash or
            something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Looks at his uncle uncomfortably.</charAction> Yes! Right into ... an
            Earth Kingdom ship!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>In disbelief.</charAction> Really? You must regale me with all of
                the<description> thrilling</description> details. <charAction>Smirks while he gets
                into Zuko's face.</charAction> Join me for a drink?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>He averts his gaze and begins to walk away.</charAction> Sorry, but we
            have to go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao smiles evilly at him as he starts to walk away, but after a few steps,
                Iroh place his hand on his shoulder to hold him back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Prince Zuko, show Commander Zhao your respect. <charAction>Removes his hand from
                Zuko's shoulder as he faces Zhao while Zuko just slants his eyes.</charAction> We
            would be honored to join you. Do you have any ginseng tea? It's my favorite.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh and Zhao walk off screen. Zuko grunts in anger upon hearing Iroh's tea
                comment. He growls angrily and firebends a small arc out of annoyance as he turns to
                walk after them.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to Appa, who is flying above the clouds in the Patola
                Mountain range. A closer shot reveals Aang and Katara sitting atop Appa's head, and
                Sokka is back in the saddle. Switch to a close-up of him clutching his stomach at it
                growls. Close-up of his face, with a look of dismay all over it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Hey, stomach? Be quiet, all right?
                I'm<description> trying</description> to find us some food.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka starts to go through the luggage and gets out a bag. He looks at it
                for a moment while it sways in the wind. With his tongue out of his mouth full
                anticipation, he sticks his hand in the bag and starts to go through it. He looks
                surprised for a moment, but quickly and with anticipation turns the bag upside down
                to pour the contents into his hand. Close-up of his gloved hand as only a few crumbs
                of blubbered seal jerky fall into it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Accusingly to the two in front of him.</charAction> Hey! Who ate all of
            my blubbered seal jerky?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Oh. That was food?
                <charAction>Happily.</charAction> I used it to start the campfire last night.
                <charAction>The hint of a smile can be heard.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You what?! <charAction>Looks up before slanting
                his eyes and groans. Longing.</charAction> No wonder the flames smelled so
            good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider shot, as Appa races past and ascends up to some
                mountains.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> The Patola Mountain range! We're almost
            there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Uneasily.</charAction> Aang, before we get to the temple, I want to talk
            to you about the airbenders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> What about 'em?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close-up of Katara.</charAction> Well, I just want you to be prepared
            for what you might see. The Fire Nation is ruthless. <charAction>Sadly.</charAction>
            They killed my mother, and they could have done the same to your people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Ponders over her words for a bit. Hopefully.</charAction> Just because
            no one has seen an airbender, doesn't mean the Fire Nation killed them all. They
            probably escaped!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Places one hand on Aang's shoulder.</charAction> I know it's hard to
            accept.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cheerfully, as Katara moves her hand back to her side.</charAction> You
            don't understand, Katara. The only way to get to an airbender temple is on a flying
            bison, and I doubt the Fire Nation has any flying bison! <charAction>Caresses Appa's
                head.</charAction> Right, Appa?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa grunts. The camera moves back to show that Appa flies past to begin a
                last ascent up the side of a mountain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>An overview shot follows Appa's flight up the mountain and through the
                clouds. Appa turns out of sight behind the flank of a mountain. The camera view
                shifts and Appa is seen emerging from behind that flank and turns further upward.
                Close-up of his passengers. Aang holds onto the reins tightly as Appa rapidly
                ascends while Katara, whose eyes are closed, and Sokka hold on tight to Appa's fur
                and saddle respectively. Aang looks back for a moment to his passengers. The camera
                switches to a further off view of Appa as he flies over the rocks and into the sky
                again. He flies over a last ridge that is covered with trees. The camera pans up to
                reveal a large temple as Appa floats toward it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> There it is. The Southern Air Temple.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, it's amazing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang is visibly excited as a close-up shows how his eyes widen upon the
                sight of the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Appa.</charAction> We're home, buddy! We're home. <charAction>His
                eyes squint a bit in happiness.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches back to the Earth Kingdom docks, where several Fire Navy
                ships are lined up. Something that looks like a railroad stretches out along the
                shipyard. The camera moves to the right to reveal a number of tents lined up in
                front of the ships. One of the bigger tents is being guarded by two Fire Nation
                soldiers. Switch to a shot of Zhao inside the tent, standing in front of a large map
                of the Avatar World that is hung up on the wall. He holds his hands behind his back.
                The camera slowly starts to move back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">... And by the year's end, the Earth Kingdom capital will be under our rule.
                <charAction>Shift to a bird view of the tent, revealing Zuko, sitting at a table,
                and Iroh, standing in the corner, looking at some weapons that are placed against
                the wall. Zhao turns around.</charAction> The Fire Lord will finally claim victory
            in this war.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up. Angrily.</charAction> If my father thinks the rest of the
            world will follow him willingly, then he is a fool!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Pulls up alongside Zuko and smirks.</charAction> Two years at sea have
            done little to temper your tongue. So, how is your search for the Avatar going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh knocks over a weapon display behind them. The weapons come crashing
                down with a lot of noise. The general cowers at the noise and the damage he wrecked.
                Zhao turns around looking annoyed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Eh.. My fault, entirely.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh places his hands in his sleeves and walks away backward out of the
                screen with a faint smile on his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Aggressively.</charAction> We haven't found him yet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Did you really expect to? The Avatar died a hundred years ago. <charAction>Close-up
                of Zuko, as he slants his eyes.</charAction> Along with the rest of the airbenders.
                <charAction>Close-up of Zhao, whose face contorts in an evil
                expression.</charAction> Unless you have found some evidence that the Avatar is
            alive?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Faces Zhao and responds very clearly.</charAction> No.
                <charAction>Stares back in front of him.</charAction> Nothing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>With an expression of disbelief on his face, as he rises from his
                chair.</charAction> Prince Zuko, the Avatar is the only one who can stop the Fire
            Nation from winning this war. <charAction>Leans in and faces Zuko.</charAction> If you
            have an ounce of loyalty left, you'll tell me what you found.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I haven't found <charAction>Looks up at Zhao and his tone becomes slightly more
                aggressive.</charAction> anything. <charAction>Close-up, as he continues on a softer
                tone, slightly mockingly.</charAction> It's like you said. The Avatar probably died
            a long time ago. <charAction>Gets up.</charAction> Come on, Uncle, we're going.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zuko approaches the door, the guards stop him from leaving by crossing
                their spears while a third soldier enters the room. The camera switches to Zhao's
                point of view. Zuko and the two soldiers blocking his path can be seen in the
                background. The camera pans to the right to reveal the soldier that entered walking
                up to Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">Commander Zhao, we interrogated the crew as you instructed. They confirmed Prince
            Zuko had the Avatar in custody, <charAction>Close-up of Zuko's head from
                behind.</charAction> but let him escape.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Smiling evilly.</charAction> Now remind me, <charAction>Close-up of
                Zuko's face, as Zhao walks up to him and leans over to talk into Zuko's ear. Zuko
                slants his eyes.</charAction> how, exactly, was your ship damaged?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades to a shot of the Southern Air Temple, as the camera slowly
                moves closer toward it. Cut to Appa, who has landed at the base of snow covered
                stairs. The camera quickly pans up to reveal three small figures making their way up
                the mountain trail. The lead figure is running. Close-up of Aang as he runs at the
                front, excitedly looking back at the two siblings. As the two emerge from behind a
                corner, Aang runs off the screen.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So where do I get something to eat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Closer shot of the two siblings. Sokka clutches his stomach with both
                hands. The bags under his eyes are darkened and he has a very annoyed look on his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritated.</charAction> You're lucky enough to be one of the first
            outsiders to ever visit an airbender temple, and all you can think about is
            food?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera switches to a broader view as the two siblings draw level with
                Aang, who is waiting for them at the next corner.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm just a simple guy, with simple needs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a front view of Aang, who points at something in front of him as
                Katara and Sokka approach.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> So that's where my friends and I would play
            airball, <charAction>The camera shifts to a shot of a stadium consisting of many tall
                poles.</charAction> and over there <charAction>The camera pans to the right to
                reveal the trio again.</charAction> is where the bison would sleep, and ...
                <charAction>Aang sighs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a front view of Aang, with Katara and Sokka in the background.
                Aang looks sad at the deserted remains of his home.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What's wrong?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>A bit saddened.</charAction> This place used to be full of monks and
            lemurs and bison. Now there's just a bunch of weeds. <charAction>His eyes squint with
                sadness. The shot changes to a back view of Aang as he stands on the ledge; his
                clothes flutter in the wind, a dead tree at each side of him. In a sad
                tone.</charAction> I can't believe how much things have changed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves back to show that Katara and Sokka give each other a look
                of sympathy. They quickly approach Aang. The camera switches back to a front view of
                Aang, who still looks sad as Katara and Sokka pull up beside him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cheerfully trying to distract Aang from his sadness.</charAction> So uh,
            this airball game. How do you play?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara smiles at her brother and Aang's face clears up. He smiles too, as
                he looks at Sokka from the corners of his eyes. Cut to a shot of Sokka, looking
                concentrated while standing on a pole and guarding the goal of the airball court.
                The camera quickly moves back to the other side of the court, where Aang also stands
                on one of the tall poles, suspending a hollow ball in the air with airbending. He
                lets the ball roll over his shoulders, tosses it from side to side and lazily tosses
                it up in the air. He looks and smiles innocently at Sokka with his hands behind his
                back. Switch to Sokka, who looks surprised at the upward movement of the ball before
                cutting back to Aang who opens one eye as the ball comes down again. The airbender
                jumps up and kicks the ball away with a powerful air swipe. It rapidly shoots across
                the poles, changing direction as it crashes into several poles, but steadily moving
                closer toward Sokka's goal. Switch to Sokka's point of view as the ball races
                quickly toward him. Change to a side-view of Sokka, who opens his mouth in shock. He
                grunts as the ball hits him right in the stomach. The force of impact sends Sokka
                and the ball flying backward, right through the rotating door of the goal behind
                him. The camera moves further back to reveal Sokka crashing into the snow behind the
                goal. Aang laughs as he jumps up in joy. Close-up of Aang as he holds a hand above
                his eyes to make out where Sokka landed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling broadly, he stretches out his arms above his head.</charAction>
            Aang, seven! <charAction>He forms a Zero with his hands and makes a circular movement
                with his whole body.</charAction> Sokka, zero!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Sokka lying in the dirt. A twig is lying on his head while
                he looks a bit miserable. Katara stands in the background looking at her
                brother.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Painfully.</charAction> Making him feel better is putting me in a world
            of hurt. <charAction>He erects himself, but before he gets up completely, his eyes widen
                when he sees something in front of him and he crawls to the front. The camera shifts
                to reveal an old Fire Nation helmet lying in the snow. It has been battered by the
                elements, and shows signs of cracks and burns. He looks up at his
                sister.</charAction> Katara, check this out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Fire Nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We should tell him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Aang! There's something you need to see.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aang runs to them from the airball court, still playing with the hollow
                ball. Cheerfully.</charAction> Okay!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Katara, as her determined look to tell Aang the truth shifts to
                one of insecurity. She glances at the helmet and back at the approaching Aang.
                Suddenly she shifts her weight and brings her arms up. With one swift movement she
                swings her arms back, manipulating the overhanging snow to fall down, obscuring the
                helmet and Sokka from sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily runs up.</charAction> What is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka brushes the snow off his head in the background and looks at his
                sister.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Innocently holds her hands behind her back.</charAction> Uh ... Just a
            new waterbending move I learned.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nice one! But enough practicing, <charAction>Excited as he turns around and start
                walking away.</charAction> we have a whole temple to see!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Brushes the last of the snow from his head and shoulders.</charAction>
            You know, you can't protect him forever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara sadly slants her eyes and walks after Aang. The scene switches to a
                full view of one of the temple's many towers and quickly pans down to reveal that
                the trio has made it to a courtyard with a fountain in the middle. The water is
                frozen. Sokka and Katara are standing at the entrance of the courtyard, while Aang
                runs up ahead excitedly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Arms crossed; stern.</charAction> Katara, firebenders were here. You
            can't pretend they weren't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara walks passed her brother. Camera view switches to a side-view. Sokka
                pulls up beside Katara as she is talking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I can for Aang's sake. If he finds out that the Fire Nation invaded his home, he'll
            be devastated.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Hey guys! <charAction>The two look up and see Aang
                standing in front of a statue of a monk, turning around and pointing toward
                it.</charAction> I want you to meet somebody!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Point of view switches to a shot from over the shoulder of the
                statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Who's that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Facing the statue again.</charAction> Monk Gyatso! The greatest
            airbender in the world. <charAction>Scene switches to a frontal view of the statue as
                Aang turns around again toward the siblings while gesturing at the
                statue.</charAction> He taught me everything I know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang bows to the statue of an elderly man with a mustache and a distinct
                round necklace sitting in lotus with his fists bumped to each other in front of him,
                while the camera zooms in on it. When the shot has zoomed in to a close-up of the
                statue's face, the scene changes to a flashback of Aang's past, the statue's face is
                replaced by the face of the real Gyatso. The scenery also become much brighter as it
                is a flashback of a sunny day at the Southern Air Temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">But the true secret, is in the gooey center.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves back a bit to reveal that Monk Gyatso is standing in front
                of an oven. With the use of a long wooden paddle, he retracts an orange, fruit pie
                out of the oven. With the use of his airbending, he creates a miniature tornado to
                spin out the fruity center of the pie.</description>
      <description>The camera moves back to reveal Aang sitting on the ledge of the balcony,
                resting his left hand on his knee while staring into nothing. A bison is grazing in
                the trees on the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Distant.</charAction> Hmm ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gyatso walk over to the ledge as well and places his newly baked cake next
                to three others that were already standing there.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">
         <charAction>With a calm, soothing and understanding voice.</charAction> My ancient
            cake-making technique isn't the only thing on your mind, is it, Aang?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Downcast.</charAction> This whole Avatar thing, m-maybe the monks made a
            mistake.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">The only mistake they made was telling you before you turned sixteen, but we can't
            concern ourselves with what was. We must act on what is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Gyatso extends his arm and while he does so, the camera moves back to
                reveal the beauty of the Southern Air Temple. The sky is filled with several sky
                bison with their calves who are feasting from the nearby trees. Sun beams bathe the
                scene in bright light.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> But Gyatso? How do I know if I'm ready for
            this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">
         <charAction>Cut back to a close shot of Gyatso with Aang sitting on the ledge in the
                background.</charAction> Your questions will be answered when you're old enough to
            enter the air temple sanctuary. Inside, you will meet someone who will guide you on your
            journey.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves slowly toward Aang whose face clears up. He uses his
                airbending to shift positions on the ledge, now facing his guardian and
                teacher.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited and curious.</charAction> Who is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">
         <charAction>Cut back to the close shot of Gyatso with Aang in the
                background.</charAction> When you are ready, he will reveal himself to you.
                <charAction>In the background, Aang, annoyed by this vague answer, grunts softly and
                looks up to the sky before cupping his face in his hands again. Monk Gyatso
                continues on a bright, happy tone.</charAction> Now, are you going to help me with
            these cakes, <charAction>Close-up of Aang as he smiles lovingly at Gyatso.</charAction>
            or not?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily stands up.</charAction> All right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a close-up of a purple fruit pie with Aang and Gyatso in
                the background. They take on an airbending stance, bringing their hand
                back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">One. <charAction>The camera switches to a side-view as the duo conjures a small air
                ball.</charAction> Two. Three!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They shift their weight to the front, launching their air balls. The balls
                send the four fruit pies flying high in the air, disappearing in the clouds. The
                scene of the flying cakes switches to a shot of four monks in lotus, meditating
                quietly between some trees. Suddenly, the cakes drop out of the sky and each of the
                monks is hit on the head by one of the colorful desserts. The monk at the far left
                of the line topples over upon impact. The moment the pies hit their heads, several
                flying lemurs appear and start to stuff their faces. One of the lemurs jumps up and
                down on the stomach of the toppled-over monk, while another grabs some cake right of
                the head of the monk on the far right. One of the lemurs jumps on the head on one of
                the monks. Cut back to Aang and Gyatso, who are laughing loudly at the scene. Aang
                is clutching his stomach, while Monk Gyatso is leaning on the railing of the
                balcony. They both move back from the railing when they are done laughing. The two
                monks bow at each other</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gyatso">
         <charAction>Full admiration and love.</charAction> Your aim has improved greatly,
                <charAction>Caressing Aang's head.</charAction> my young pupil.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The flashback fades back to reveal Aang in the present, bowing the same way
                before the statue as he had done for the real Gyatso. The camera switches to a
                frontal view of Aang as he erects himself with a sad look upon his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Understandingly places a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> You must
            miss him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Downcast.</charAction> Yeah. <charAction>He walks
            away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Curious.</charAction> Where are you going?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Switch to a shot from Katara's point of view. Aang is walking up some
                stairs that lead to a corridor behind the statue. He looks back while
                answering.</charAction> The air temple sanctuary. There's someone I'm ready to
            meet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang enters the hallway. Cut back to Katara; she looks questioningly at
                Sokka, who just shrugs. They both start walking after Aang. Switch to an overview
                shot of inside the corridor. The round symbol of intertwined air currents, the
                national symbol of the Air Nomads is largely embedded in the floor, surrounded by
                two square shapes that form some sort of sun together. The camera pans up to reveal
                that the trio has reached the entrance of the air temple sanctuary. The door
                supports a combination of metal colored pipes and three, blue, rolled up, pipes that
                are similar looking and arranges like the symbol for airbending. The large wooden
                door is framed by the branches of an old tree standing on the left of it and the
                hallway is illuminated by sunlight that falls through little, round
                windows.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But Aang, no one could have survived in there for a hundred years.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Camera changes to show the trio looking up at the door.
                Hopeful.</charAction> It's not impossible. <charAction>Opening his
                arms.</charAction> I survived in the iceberg for that long.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Touching her chin with a finger.</charAction> Good point.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close shot of Aang with Katara visible over his shoulder. He glances
                hopeful at her over his shoulder. Excited.</charAction> Katara, whoever's in there
            might help figure out this Avatar thing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Appears in screen from behind Aang's back. Katara and Aang look
                surprised at him. Eagerly.</charAction> And whoever's in there might have
                <charAction>Katara's look changes to one of annoyance. Close-up of Sokka's
                determined, anticipating face.</charAction> a medley of delicious <charAction>He
                rubs his hands together and practically starts to drool over the
                thought.</charAction> cured meats!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Full of anticipation and longing, Sokka charges at the door, but it will
                not budge and he simply smacks into it, head first. He quickly turns around and puts
                his back to it, trying to push the giant door open. When the door does not move, he
                sighs, slides down to the floor, disappointed, and rests against the
                door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I don't suppose you have a key?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shot from over Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> The key, Sokka, is
            airbending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Aang, as he takes a deep breath. He spreads his arms and
                thrusts them forward, sending an air current into both of the tubes on the door. The
                camera follows the path of the right air current as it travels through the pipe. The
                wind makes one of the blue curled tube turn around. When it does, the tube changes
                colors to purple and the wind blows out like a horn. The process is repeated for the
                other two blue tubes as well. When the three blue tubes have turned and become
                purple, the camera moves back to show that Aang has unlocked the door and it slowly
                starts to open. Switch to a shot from inside the sanctuary, as the door cracks open
                and light penetrates the dark room. The doors sway open and Aang is seen standing
                there with Katara and Sokka in the background. The scene switches to a shot from
                behind Katara and Sokka, as the door cracks open entirely.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut to a front view of Aang, as he brings his hand besides his
                mouth.</charAction> Hello? <charAction>Switch back to a shot from behind Sokka and
                Katara as Aang enters the sanctuary.</charAction> Anyone home?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Overview shot as Sokka and Katara walks behind Aang. Cut to a shot from
                close to the ground, as they enter further into the sanctuary and disappear in the
                darkness.</description>
      <description>The scene fades to Zuko, who is sitting in a chair in Zhao's tent, flanked
                by two Fire Nation soldiers while Zhao is pacing back and forth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">So a twelve-year-old boy bested you and your firebenders. <charAction>Wider shot of
                the tent as Zhao stops pacing. Iroh can be seen sitting in a corner.</charAction>
            You're more pathetic than I thought.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I underestimated him once, but it will not happen
            again!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Frontal view with Zuko in the background. Aggressively.</charAction> No,
            it will not. Because you won't have a second chance.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Commander Zhao, <charAction>Closer shot of
                Zuko.</charAction> I've been hunting the Avatar for two years and I -</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Cut to a shot from over Zuko's shoulder as Zhao angrily turns around,
                spreading flames in an arc.</charAction> And you failed! <charAction>He walks
                intimidatingly up to Zuko.</charAction> Capturing the Avatar is too important to
            leave in a teenager's hands. He's mine now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Zuko's face, as it contorts with anger and he jumps at Zhao.
                Cut to a side-view. Before Zuko can reach the commander, however, he is held back by
                the two guards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Keep them here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao walks away, leaving an angrily panting Zuko. Enraged, he kicks the
                table in front of Iroh, breaking it clean in two, sending the objects that were on
                it flying through the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Calmly with a hint of amusement in his voice.</charAction> More tea,
            please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the sanctuary. The camera pans to the right to show a frontal
                view of Aang, Katara, and Sokka who are venturing further down into the sanctuary.
                The only light comes from the open door behind them and illuminates the scene with
                bluish light. They stop, and Sokka holds a hand to his brow to look up ahead. Switch
                to an overview shot of the trio as they stand in the light that comes in through the
                door. Their shadows are cast over the floor. The camera moves back and pans more to
                the right to reveal a large amount of statues of people, lined up in a circular
                pattern. Switch to a side-view from among the statues as the trio walks through
                them, curiously looking around. Sokka halts before one of them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Disappointed.</charAction> Statues? That's it? Where's the
            meat?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a side-view of Aang and Katara, who also have stopped and are
                looking up at a statue.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Who are all these people?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Pensive.</charAction> I'm not sure. <charAction>Frontal view of
                Aang.</charAction> But it feels like I know them somehow. Look! <charAction>Camera
                shifts to a point behind Aang and Katara. Aang points at the statue of a man with
                airbending mastery tattoos in front of him.</charAction> That one's an
            airbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Camera pans to the right. Katara points at the statue of a male dressed
                in Water Tribe clothes next to the airbender.</charAction> And this one's a
            waterbender. <charAction>Looks to the right and back to the left.</charAction> They're
            lined up in a pattern: <charAction>Points at the respective statues.</charAction> air,
            water, earth and fire.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's the Avatar Cycle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Understanding.</charAction> Of course. They're Avatars. All these people
            are your past lives, Aang.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow! There are so many!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang starts to walk down the circular pattern. Switch to Katara, who is now
                standing next to Sokka who has his arms crossed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Skeptically.</charAction> Past lives? <charAction>Aang stops before a
                statue while Sokka and Katara are still visible in the background.</charAction>
            Katara, you really believe in that stuff?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's true. <charAction>The picture pans up the reveal Aang staring at the statue of
                an elderly man with a beard. In the background hundreds of statues can be seen
                spiraling up.</charAction> When the Avatar dies, he's reincarnated into the next
            nation in the cycle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a back view of Aang, who is looking at the elderly man while the
                camera moves in closer. Quick change to a frontal view of Aang, who stares with wide
                open eyes at the statue. The camera moves in closer to his face. Switch to the face
                of the statue. Its eyes gleam for a second. Cut back to a close-up of Aang, who is
                still mesmerized by the statue. Katara appears behind him, grabs his shoulders and
                shakes him a bit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang! Snap out of it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider view from over the shoulder of the statue. Aang is smiling
                at it while Katara looks worried at Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Dazed.</charAction> Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>She curiously follows his gaze and looks at the statue as
                well.</charAction> Who is that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's Avatar Roku, the Avatar before me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a back view of the duo, as Sokka walks up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You were a firebender? No wonder I didn't trust you when we first met.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks at the base of the statue.</charAction> There's no writing. How do
            you know his name?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm not sure. I just know it somehow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Growls irritably while crossing his arms.</charAction> You just couldn't
            get any weirder.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The trio startles and stares with big eyes in front of them when they hear
                something. They turn around. Switch to a scene of the blue light on the floor that
                comes in through the door. A long-eared shadow of another being that is approaching
                moves over it. The camera pans to the right toward the statues, but the trio cannot
                be seen. Overview shot from among the statues where Katara and Aang are hiding
                behind a statue on the left and Sokka, who is holding his club ready, hides behind a
                statue to the right. The shadow is creeping closer. Cut to a closer shot of the
                threesome. Katara has her teeth clutched in fright, while Aang looks in front of
                him. Sokka holds his hand to his mouth as he addresses them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> Firebender. Nobody make a sound.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Irritably.</charAction> You're making a sound!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang and Sokka">
         <charAction>Putting their finger before their mouths.</charAction> Shhhh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara looks scared in front of her again. Overview shot of the huddled
                trio as the shadow creeps closer. Close-up of Sokka, who raises his
                club.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> That firebender won't know what hit
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a broader view as Sokka stands up. The shadow has reached the bases
                of the statues and the camera pans up to reveal a small figure standing in the
                doorway; it chitters. The camera changes to a view from behind the figure. Sokka
                appears from behind the statue, his club to the ready, but lowers it as soon as he
                sees the animal. Aang and Katara peek form behind their statue as well. Frontal view
                of the erect flying lemur, as it sits down and lowers his ears, blinking at the
                appeared threesome. Close-up of Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Lemur!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Quickly pans to a drooling Sokka.</charAction> Dinner!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of the lemur, as the animal pricks his ears and slightly
                tilts his head. Cut back to a close-up of a friendly-looking Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Reassuring.</charAction> Don't listen to him. You're going to be my new
            pet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Aang glares angrily at Sokka, before the scene switches to a close-up of
                his drooling face. Challenging.</charAction> Not if I get him first!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka stretches his hand while he excitedly lunges himself at the animal
                from behind the statue. Aang runs up at the lemur as well. Point of view switches to
                that of the boys. The lemur arcs his back in fright, his ears, hair and tail
                standing upright as the snatching hands of the boys draw closer. Switch to a back
                view of the lemur. It startles, quickly turns around and makes a break for it. Sokka
                barely misses the animal and falls down. Aang nimbly avoids tripping as well by
                using Sokka's head as a stepping stone. Switch to an overview shot as Sokka quickly
                gets up and runs behind Aang and the lemur as they exit the sanctuary.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker=" Aang ">Wait! Come back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot from low in the hallway. The lemur bounces off the wall and
                chases out of the screen.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I want to eat you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Sokka come sliding around the corner and give chase. Sokka passes
                Aang and shoves him back. Cut to a side-view of Sokka running in the lead. Aang
                pulls up next to him again, so Sokka takes out his club and takes a swing at Aang's
                legs. Aang nimbly avoids the club and uses his airbending to run on the side of the
                wall, laughing loudly with amusement. Cut to a shot from Sokka's point of view as
                Aang runs up ahead. The airbender runs on the floor again. He quickly turns around
                and directs on airball at Sokka, which knocks his legs from underneath him. Sokka
                flips in the air before smacking face first on the ground, his hood falling over his
                head while he lands. Switch to a frontal view from a balcony as the lemur exits the
                corridor and sits on the ledge of the balcony, looking back at the approaching Aang.
                He pricks his ears again and takes flight with a scared look on his face. Cut to a
                shot from over Aang's shoulder as he is running down the hall. He briefly glances
                over to see if Sokka is still following. He too exits the hallway and without
                slowing down, he jumps over the ledge of the balcony, behind the lemur. Cut to a
                shot from underneath Aang. The airbender turns in the air and uses some of the rocks
                to break his freefall, jumping from one rock to the other. Cut back to Sokka, who
                too has reached the balcony, but stops there while looking over the
                rim.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey! No fair!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to a close-up of Aang, who's freefalling again. His mouth is wide
                open in a smile and his eyes are slightly squinted and watering, owing to the speed
                of his fall.</description>
      <description>Cut to the Fire Nation tent at the occupied Earth Kingdom harbor. Zhao is
                walking toward it. The scene changes from inside the tent, where two guards hold
                their spears in front of the exit. Zhao pushes the cloths aside that serve as tent
                doors and enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">My search party is ready. Once I'm out to sea, <charAction>Cut to a shot from over
                Zhao's head to reveal Iroh and Zuko sitting in two chairs in front of him in the
                middle of the tent.</charAction> my guards will escort you back to your ship and
                <charAction>Close-up of Zuko, who angrily looks down.</charAction> you'll be free to
            go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Why? Are you worried I'm going to try and stop
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zhao, who starts to laugh out loud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Amused.</charAction> You? Stop me? Impossible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily gets up. Enraged.</charAction> Don't underestimate me, Zhao! I
            will capture the Avatar before you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Gets up as well; sternly.</charAction> Prince Zuko, that's
            enough.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Confidently.</charAction> You can't compete with me. I have hundreds of
            war ships under my command and you? You're just a banished prince. No home, no allies.
            Your own father doesn't even want you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You're wrong! Once I deliver the Avatar to my
            father, he will welcome me home with honor, and restore my rightful place on the
            throne!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Close-up of Zhao, as the camera pans to the right to slowly reveal his
                whole face.</charAction> If your father really wanted you home, he would have let
            you return by now, Avatar or no Avatar. But in his eyes you are a failure and a disgrace
            to the Fire Nation.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Cut to Zuko.</charAction> That's not true.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">You have the scar to prove it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>With a cry of frustration, Zuko jolts up out of his chair and into Zhao's
                face. Side-view as the two stare at each other in anger.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Furiously.</charAction> Maybe you'd like one to match!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Slightly mockingly.</charAction> Is that a challenge?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">An Agni Kai. At sunset.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Very well. <charAction>Zhao erects himself.</charAction> It's a shame your father
            won't be here to watch me humiliate you. <charAction>Turns around.</charAction> I guess
            your uncle will do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao walks away. Front view of Zuko, with Iroh in the
                background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Camera pans slowly to the right to a full close-up of Zuko.
                Worried.</charAction> Prince Zuko, have you forgotten what happened last time you
            dueled a master?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Darkly.</charAction> I will never forget.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a scenery shot of the Southern Air Temple. Switch to somewhere
                inside the temple where the lemur lands on the ground. The animal erects his ears as
                Aang touches down on the ground behind him as well and launches forward. The lemur
                jumps out of the way. The camera pans to the right to follow the animal's escape as
                he runs through some ripped drapes, which once formed a tent.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Follows the lemur.</charAction> Hey! Come back! <charAction>Cut to a
                shot from inside the tent, as Aang pushes the decaying curtain of drapes out of the
                way. Happily looks around.</charAction> Come on out, little lemur! That hungry guy
            won't bother you anymore.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang walks up to another curtain of drapes. Cut to a frontal view from the
                other side of the curtain as Aang parts them. He looks in the room, but suddenly
                takes a sharp breath in shock. Switch to several skeletons dressed in Fire Nation
                uniforms lying scattered over the floor. The camera slowly pans up to a skeleton
                lying in the snow, surrounded by many more skeletons of Fire Nation
                soldiers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Firebenders? They were here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang enters the room and looks around with a sad expression on his face.
                The scene switches to a closer shot of the skeleton in the snow and slowly zooms in
                on it. The skeleton is adorned with a round necklace that supports the symbol of
                airbending. Close-up of Aang, as he stares at the skeletons. Cut back to a close-up
                of the skeleton dressed in yellow monk robes. The camera focuses on the round,
                wooden necklace. Cut back to Aang, whose eyes are trembling with sadness and hold
                back tears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Devastated.</charAction> Gyatso.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The view changes to one from beside the skeleton; its fingers are clearly
                visible in the front as Aang drops to his knees in the background and lets out a
                mournful sigh. Cut to Sokka, who pulls the drapes aside and looks
                around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Hey, Aang! You find my dinner yet? <charAction>Cut
                to a side-view of Aang sitting on his knees, his head cupped in his hands. Sokka
                walks toward him. Reassuring.</charAction> Aang, I wasn't really going to eat the
            lemur, okay? <charAction>He approaches Aang with a smile on his face, but shakes his
                head and does a double take.</charAction> Oh, man. <charAction>Switch to a shot of
                the skeleton of the monk, which slowly moves back to reveal that Sokka places a hand
                on Aang's shoulder.</charAction> Come on, Aang. Everything will be all right. Let's
            get out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, Aang's arrow tattoos begin to glow a bluish white. Cut to a
                frontal view of Aang, as he lifts his head, his eyes glowing in the same color. The
                camera pans up; Sokka retracts his hands and gasps for air in fright. Switch to an
                overview shot of inside the sanctuary where Katara is walking down the circular
                pattern of statues. She stops before and looks at the statue of Avatar Roku. Cut to
                a close-up of the statue's face. The camera's point of view switches to behind
                Roku's shoulder. Katara suddenly looks surprised as a bluish, white light
                illuminates her face; it seems to come from the statue. Cut back to a close-up of
                the statue. Its eyes are gleaming bright. The bright light spreads to the other
                statues and one by one, their eyes start to gleam. The camera pans up to reveal how
                the light travels from statue to statue and makes its way up to the top of the
                sanctuary. The camera's point of view switches again to behind Roku's shoulder to
                show Katara, who is still staring at Roku in shock.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worried.</charAction> Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara turns around and sprints away.</description>
      <description>Switch to another temple hidden somewhere in the mountains. Inside the
                temple is a man, dressed in the typical green of the Earth Kingdom, sitting in front
                of a painting of past earth Avatars. Their eyes also begin to gleam brightly. Cut to
                a frontal view of the man's frightened expression. The light is so strong that it
                casts long shadows on his face. Switch to somewhere on one of the poles, where two
                Water Tribe civilians are looking at the water temple's roof that glows bright with
                bluish, white light. Cut to a far-off view of the Fire Temple; its roof glows with a
                reddish light. Cut to a view from inside the temple, where a Fire Sage is leaning
                out of the room from which the light emanates.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Sage">Send word to the Fire Lord immediately! The Avatar has returned!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The expression on the recipient Fire Sage's face turns to fright. Cut back
                to the decaying building Aang is in at the Southern Air Temple. Switch to a close
                shot of Aang's feet, where a whirlwind begins to form. The wind kicks away a bone.
                The camera slowly pans up. The wind kicks up and forms a sphere around Aang; his
                eyes and tattoos still glowing brightly. Aang's clothes flutter heavily in the
                wind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Aang! Come on! Snap out of it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka holds up his arm to protect himself against the raging winds.
                Suddenly, the air sphere around Aang expands and sends Sokka flying
                backward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aaaaahh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overview of the dilapidated building. The roof explodes by the
                force of the hurricane and debris is catapulted high into the air. Switch back to
                inside the rubble of the building where Sokka spins through the air and smacks
                against the wall. The air sphere has expanded to a raging tornado with Aang in its
                center. Sokka peeks at Aang from behind a rock. Switch to an overview shot as Katara
                walks up to Sokka, holding her arm protectively before her face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shouting above the raging winds. Close-up of the two siblings. Katara
                looks worried at her brother.</charAction> What happened?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> He found out firebenders killed Gyatso!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh no! It's his Avatar Spirit! <charAction>Raises her hand to protect herself
                against the winds and the flying debris.</charAction> He must have triggered it! I'm
            going to try and calm him down! <charAction>Closes an eye against the wind and starts to
                make her way toward Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holds on to the rock in an attempt to keep from being blown away.
                Alarmed.</charAction> Well, do it! Before he blows us off the mountain!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a side-view as Katara fights the storm to get to Aang. Cut to a shot
                from over her shoulder. The sphere of wind that engulfs slowly starts to rise in the
                air. Katara is pushed back by the strong wind currents that fill the remains of the
                building as the sphere ascends higher and higher.</description>
      <description>Cut to an overview shot of a Fire Nation arena at the occupied Earth
                Kingdom harbor at sunset. Switch to a view of the inside. The camera pans to the
                left to reveal some two figure standing at the right and 5 figures standing at the
                left of the arena. Close-up of Zhao, as he is squatting down; He is bare-chested and
                barefoot and wears a cape over his shoulders. Zuko and Iroh can be seen in the
                background. Switch to a close-up of Zuko, squatting the same way and dressed in the
                same attire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Remember your firebending basics, <charAction>Close-up of Iroh's upper
                body.</charAction> Prince Zuko. They are your greatest weapons.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Close-up of Zuko's determined face.</charAction> I refuse to let him
            win.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko stands up and turns around. The cape drops from his shoulder. Switch
                to Zhao on the other side of the arena who also rises and turns around; his garment
                swivels down as well.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Confident whisper.</charAction> This will be over quickly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a Fire Nation soldier standing on higher grounds. He sees that the
                duo has readied themselves for battle, so he rings a large gong. Cut back to a
                side-view of Zuko and Zhao standing in the middle of the arena, both taking on a
                firebending stance. Close-up of Zuko, who has his hands stretched out in front of
                him, glaring at Zhao. Switch to Zhao, who stands the same as Zuko. The screen
                splits; the upper pane is a close-up of Zhao's eyes and slowly slides to the left,
                the lower is a close-up of Zuko's eyes and slowly slides to the right.</description>
      <description>Cut to a view from behind Zuko, as he starts to lower his arms, leaving a
                trail of fire behind. Camera moves to a frontal view of Zuko, as he directs a strong
                fire blast at Zhao. Zhao moves to the left, out of the way of the blast before
                moving back to the right to avoid another blast. Switch to a shot of Zhao's left
                foot with Zuko in the background; the camera pans to the right. The prince shoots
                two more strong blast at Zhao. Frontal view of Zhao, as he crosses his arms in front
                of him and takes the blasts head on. He moves one arm up and the other down,
                dissipating the flames. He smirks at Zuko, who is seen panting heavily with his arm
                still stretched out from his last attack. He angrily grinds his teeth and performs a
                roundhouse kick, spraying flames toward the camera. The shot switches to a side-view
                of Zhao, who creates his own flames to push away Zuko's blazing attack. He performs
                his trick again. Close-up of Zuko, who squints his eyes and directs another powerful
                flame kick in Zhao's direction. Close-up of a smirking Zhao, who holds his own fire
                ready. He launches forward. Shot of his feet, showing his strong stance as he swings
                his arms over the ground, severing Zuko's next attack. The camera switches from
                Zhao, who seems unfazed by Zuko's attacks to Zuko, who is panting heavily with
                fatigue. Cut to Iroh, who is holding his fist up while rooting for his
                nephew.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Basics, Zuko! <charAction>Close-up of Zuko's determined face.</charAction> Break his
            root!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Side-view of Zhao, who ferociously attacks Zuko with a strong fire blast.
                Zuko is thrown back a bit by the force of the attack while he diverts the flames to
                both of his sides. Zhao takes a step forward. Closer shot as he directs another
                powerful blast at the prince, using both his arms this time. Zuko is thrown back
                again, but still diverts the fire away from him. Zhao takes another step forward and
                fires again with the same result on Zuko's side. Shot of Zhao, who firmly plants his
                foot down; cut to a shot where he holds his both wrists together and fires another
                strong blast. Zuko is thrown back upon impact and slides back several meters over
                the ground. He lifts his head while grunting in pain. His expression turns to one of
                shock as he looks up and sees that Zhao has jumped up and is soaring through the
                skies toward him. With a loud scream, he lands at Zuko's feet, erects himself and
                thrusts his fist forward to deliver the final blow.</description>
      <description>Cut to Zuko's eyes, which open wide in fright as the fire reflects in them.
                At the last possible second, a frontal shot of Zuko shows him rolling out of the way
                and swirling his feet around. The view switches to a side-view of Zuko as he, while
                getting up in this swirl, swipes Zhao's legs from underneath him. This same move is
                shown two more times, from a closer side-view and from a close-up angled shot of
                Zuko's perspective, before cutting to a shot of Zuko's feet as he firmly plants them
                on the ground. Close-up as he smiles confidently. Switch to a shot from over the
                ground as Zukosteps forward, sliding fire at Zhao's feet, who steps back. Zhao is
                caught off balance and wobbles backward. Zuko keeps repeating his move, directing
                his attacks at Zhao's feet in an attempt to throw him off balance. Switch to Zhao,
                who falls back in distress and subsequently to Iroh, who smiles approvingly. Cut to
                Zuko, who directs a powerful kick at his adversary. Zhao barely pushes it out of the
                way while staggering back ever further. Zuko kicks again and this time he succeeds
                in knocking the commander over. Zhao falls down and rolls over the ground, where he
                ends up on his back. Zuko runs up at him and threatens him with an outstretched arm,
                ready to deliver the final blow. Zhao brings his head up and looks at Zuko. Close-up
                of Zuko's eyes and back to a shot of Zhao's face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Challenging.</charAction> Do it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko grunts and thrusts his fist forward, emitting another fire blast.
                Smoke appears on screen and Zuko erects himself. Cut to a blackened spot on the
                ground, next to Zhao's face. The camera moves back to a broader view.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">That's it? Your father raised a coward.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Anger clearly audible in his voice.</charAction> Next time you get in my
            way, I promise, I won't hold back.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko turns his back to Zhao and starts to walk away. Close-up of Zuko's
                face as he walks; Zhao can be seen erecting himself in the background, his back
                facing Zuko. He suddenly turns around and aims a powerful kick at Zuko, spreading
                his flames. Before Zuko notices anything, however, Iroh intervenes and grabs Zhao's
                foot, dissipating the fire. Iroh tosses Zhao back who slides away on his back. Zuko
                wants to charge Zhao in anger, but Iroh stops him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No, Prince Zuko. Do not taint your victory. <charAction>Turns to face Zhao.
                Condescending.</charAction> So this is how the great Commander Zhao acts in defeat?
                <charAction>Close-up of Zhao lying on the floor.</charAction> Disgraceful.
                <charAction>Cut back to a closer shot of Zuko and Iroh.</charAction> Even in exile,
            my nephew is more honorable than you. <charAction>Zuko looks at Iroh upon hearing those
                last words. Switch to a shot from over Zhao's shoulders.</charAction> Thanks again
            for the tea. It was delicious.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh and Zuko turn and walk toward the gate of the arena. Zhao partially
                erects himself, with his left arm resting on his left knee, and grunts as he watches
                them go. Overview shot of Iroh and Zuko exiting the arena and a close-up of the
                duo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Softly.</charAction> Did you really mean that, Uncle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Smiling slyly, while glancing at his nephew.</charAction> Of course. I
            told you ginseng tea is my favorite.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko slightly smiles, before the shot switches to an overview of the harbor
                as the duo walks toward their ship.</description>
      <description>Cut to Aang, who is still suspended in the air in his sphere. Strong winds
                are rampaging through the rubble of the destroyed building. Katara and Sokka are
                holding on for dear life on some stones, trying not to get blown away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>In the background, Sokka is hunched over his rock, clenching his teeth
                together. Katara shouts calmly with a sad expression on her face. The camera slowly
                moves in on her.</charAction> Aang! I know you're upset and I know how hard it is to
            lose the people you love. I went through the same thing when I lost my mom.
                <charAction>Diverts her eyes. Shot switches to a frontal view of Aang, his tattoos
                glowing and wind swirling around him; his clothes flutter in the storm. Sokka runs
                over to his sister in the background.</charAction> Monk Gyatso and the other
            airbenders may be gone, <charAction>Close-up of her as she looks up at him.</charAction>
            but you still have a family. Sokka and I! <charAction>Sokka opens his eyes and glances
                at his sister.</charAction> We're your family now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Aang's emotionless face, as he begins to descend. The angle
                changes to a view from behind Sokka and Katara as they watch him lower himself back
                to the ground; the winds start to die down and the air sphere that surrounded Aang
                disappears. Close-up of his feet, as he touches the ground. Frontal view of the
                young Avatar, his eyes and tattoos are still glowing bluish white. Katara and Sokka
                pull up next to him, one on each side.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Gently.</charAction> Katara and I aren't going to let anything happen to
            you. Promise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Katara taking Aang's hand. The moment she does, the glowing
                fades away. Cut to a close-up of his face as his arrow and eyes also stop glowing.
                He slants his eyes with a saddened expression, before he collapses from exhaustion
                in Katara's arms.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sad and tired.</charAction> I'm sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's okay. It wasn't your fault.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> But you were right. And if the firebenders found
            this temple, that means they found the other ones, too. <charAction>Close-up of his sad
                face, as he closes his eyes.</charAction> I really am the last airbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara hugs Aang tightly. The camera moves back and Sokka places a hand on
                Aang's shoulder. Switch to a shot of the statues inside the sanctuary. The camera
                pans down to reveal Aang standing in front of Roku's statue again. Shot from over
                Roku's shoulder as Katara pulls up next to Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Everything's packed. You ready to go?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Closer shot of Aang and Katara's faces. Softly.</charAction> How is Roku
            supposed to help me if I can't talk to him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe you'll find a way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They glance at each other when they hear something behind them. They turn
                around and see the flying lemur standing on its back legs in the middle of the
                doorway. Cut to a back view of the animal as it jumps to the right, toward where
                Sokka is standing. The animal reaches his feet and drops the load he was carrying: a
                variety of fruits. The lemur quickly dashes away as Sokka sits down and starts to
                stuff his face with the fruit, taking large bites of two different pieces of fruit.
                Cut to a shot of Aang and Katara, who smile at Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Looks like you made a new friend Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Pushing the food in his mouth with his two hands. Looks up with an
                exhilarated look upon his face. With a full mouth.</charAction> Can't talk! Must
            eat! <charAction>Takes another big bite.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The flying lemur climbs onto Aang and hides behind his head, his tail
                curled around Aang's neck</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at the lemur from the corners of his eye.</charAction> Hey,
            little guy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a panoramic view of the Southern Air Temple from a distance. The
                camera pans down to reveal Aang standing next to Appa with Momo perched on his
                arm.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To the winged-lemur.</charAction> You, me and Appa; <charAction>Frontal
                view as the camera closes in on them.</charAction> we're all that's left of this
            place. <charAction>Looks at the lemur.</charAction> We have to stick together. Katara,
            Sokka, <charAction>Switches to a shot of the duo fiddling with their luggage. They turn
                back to look at Aang as he calls them. Sokka is still eating a peach.</charAction>
            say hello to the newest member of our family.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Aang approaches the duo.</charAction> What are you going to name
            him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka is about to take another bite of the peach he is eating. Cut to a
                shot of Aang, who looks surprised when the lemur suddenly leaps off his arm and
                returns, holding the peach. The animal starts to nibble from it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Momo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wider shot. Sokka still stands there, mouth open and hand in front
                of his mouth, ready to take a bite, however, he has no peach anymore. The others
                start to laugh upon seeing Sokka's expression. Cut to a panoramic view of the
                Southern Air Temple at dusk; the camera slowly pans to the right. Cut to Aang, who
                is sadly staring back at it, leaning on the luggage that is tied at the back on
                Appa's saddle. Momo chitters quietly as they fly further away from the temple. Dark
                clouds slowly move in front of the temple, obscuring their view.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
