<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Bending Battle</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The short opens with the shot focusing on Aang, Katara, and Toph's hands,
                which are stretched outward. Aang is airbending a very small tornado, Katara is
                bending a small amount of water, and Toph has a small pyramid; each of these are
                contained on their benders' respective palms.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang, Katara, and Toph">Aang, Katara, and Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Simultaneously.</charAction> One, two, three, bend!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka slowly stretches his hand, which is in a "U" shape, forward. Camera
                zooms out, and cuts to Sokka's fingers twitching.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's that supposed to be, Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Sokka.</charAction> This is boomerang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka raises his arm up, hand still in same shape. He waves his hand,
                imitating his boomerang, and hits Aang on his forehead, who starts rubbing
                it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Ow, my arrow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Raising a small portion of earth and using it as an arm
                rest.</charAction> I don't think boomerang is an element. <charAction>She removes a
                large ball of snot from her nose.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Aang and Sokka, with the latter listening to Toph's statement
                with his ears, which have grown big.</charAction> Even if it was, nothing beats
            air!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He bends a gust of air at Sokka, messing his hair and clothing. Camera pans
                right to Katara, whose hair and clothing have also become messed due to Aang's gust
                of air.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Yeah, nothing except for water. <charAction>Cut to
                Katara's water skin as she flicks its lid out. Cut to Katara's face.</charAction>
            Everyone knows that water is the best element in the world!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara uses the water from her pounch to lift Sokka, who is looking at
                himself with a mirror, and thrust him into the air, where she freezes him into a
                block of ice. She subsequently breaks the ice into several smaller blocks with some
                difficulty, causing the pieces to fall down. Finally, Katara joins the pieces again,
                thus "joining" Sokka back as well. Sokka uses his own strength to break out of the
                ice. She and Aang begin to bicker.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Guys, come on, <charAction>Both look toward Toph, who is standing with her arms
                rested on two vertical earth columns.</charAction> I think air and water are both
            wonderful elements. <charAction>Katara's and Aang's expressions immediately change to
                proud ones. Cut to Toph's confidently smiling face as she points her hand toward a
                direction.</charAction> But earth beats the pants off both of those sissy elements
            combined!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara and Aang">Katara and Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Very angry. Simultaneously.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>She pushes Aang, causing him to go flying behind, and she
                yells.</charAction> You think earth is better?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Toph.</charAction> Can waterbending do this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She stomps the ground with one leg, as the camera pans right to show Sokka,
                who is walking away to avoid being used to show a bending art's greatness. He is
                pushed above by two diagonal earth columns, and is sent flying to a vertical
                surface. He is used as a ball in a pinball-styled game as Toph creates many
                projections to change his direction. As he moves from one projection to another, he
                literally becomes ball-shaped, and finally falls inside a sleeping Appa's head on
                top of the vertical surface. Appa suddenly stands up with his six legs stretched
                out. Appa spits Sokka from his mouth, causing Sokka to go flying. He is stopped by
                Aang, who airbends him to ensure a safe landing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>As he lands slowly.</charAction> Thanks, Aang, for catching me. You
            know, I'm sick and tired of being used as everyone's personal <charAction>His voice
                changes to a nasal one as Aang grabs his nose.</charAction> dummy ...
                <charAction>Camera zooms out to show Aang airbending a lot of air into Sokka's
                mouth, causing Sokka to inflate. Sokka is unable to open his mouth, making him
                unable to talk properly as he rises into the sky above.</charAction> Aang! What are
            you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to an aerial shot of Aang, Katara and Toph standing on the ground
                with Sokka flying above.</charAction> I'm showing these two why air is the best
            element!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka reaches Appa, who is sleeping and blowing huge amounts of air from
                his mouth for each breath. Sokka helplessly waves his hands and lets go of the air
                Aang airbent into his mouth when he impales himself on Appa's right horn. He is sent
                flying due to the force of the air coming out from his mouth and spins in many
                circles before falling into a pond with a splash. Cut to Toph and Katara looking
                disappointed as Aang grins widely and laughs behind them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Coming out of the pond, catching a fish. Angrily.</charAction> All
            right, enough! No more bending!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka suddenly hears a voice and looks surprised. Cut to Iroh and Zuko
                standing near Appa on an elevated platform in a distance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You guys call that bending?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a closer shot of Zuko and Iroh, with the latter grinning very
                widely. Cut back to Katara and Toph, the former having two hearts as eyes as soon as
                she sees Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Blushing.</charAction> Tiny Zuko! You look so cute!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He is shocked for a moment, but soon becomes very angry, steam blasting
                out from his nose. He reverts to his appearance in the original series, instead of
                the super deformed version.</charAction> I am neither cute nor tiny!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Steam comes out from Zuko's mouth as he becomes smaller and reaches the
                size of all other characters, but he is still in his normal appearance. Iroh pokes
                him with his finger, and he realizes something and changes back to his super
                deformed version.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You are pretty cute, my tiny nephew.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angry.</charAction> I'll show you tiny!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He jumps up and seemingly goes behind, and delivers a very powerful fire
                stream. Katara, Aang, and Toph stand ready to stop the attack which goes toward
                Sokka, burning the fish he took from the pond when he fell in it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Zuko and Iroh from below.</charAction> Everyone knows fire is the
            best!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Toph, Katara, Sokka, and Aang from behind Zuko.</charAction> You
            want a bending battle?! <charAction>Cut to Toph.</charAction> You got it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She performs a movement with her hands as pebbles levitate into the air.
                She raises a giant portion of the earth above and delivers an earth fissure to the
                side, raising a mountain-shaped and sized portion. She raises many mountains,
                creating a chain of them. Cut to the mountains from outer space, which show that
                they create a picture of Toph herself. She pulls a heart-shaped giant portion of the
                earth down, creating a heart near her face. Cut to Toph showing the photograph of
                this, with Katara and Aang visibly angry and jealous. Upon seeing its photograph,
                Appa gives her an "8.2" mark, Momo, a "7.6" mark, and Iroh enthusiastically
                applauds.</description>
            <description>Cut to a confident looking Aang as he makes a small ball of air in his
                hand. Camera zooms out as he makes a large dome of air and jumps high into the air
                by using the dome as a trampoline. He gets a cape and, while rising above, eats a
                part of a cloud. He reaches outer space and, after shivering for a moment, makes a
                ball around himself and descends down very fast, leaving a trail as he does. Aang
                lands down on the ground with a confident expression, and grins. Appa gives him an
                "8" mark, Momo, a "6" mark, with Iroh waving his finger in an unimpressed
                manner.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing above.</charAction> Come on, heh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera zooms out to show that he has left a trail in the shape of his
                arrow. Momo flips his board to make his "6" mark a "9" mark, and Appa, mimicking
                Momo, flips his board make his "8" an "8". Iroh gives him a thumbs-up. Appa, Momo,
                and Iroh turn their heads to a side as they see a volcano erupting and a lava wave
                coming out of it rapidly. Zuko emerges from it and bends the lava into a
                dragon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing on the dragon made of lava.</charAction> Step back! I'll bring
            in the heat!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He grins cockily, but is surprised when he sees a larger wave of water with
                Katara on top of it, bending it herself, and approaching his dragon made of lava.
                Cut to Katara as she grins widely. Camera zooms out to show the wave engulfing Zuko
                and his lava dragon, causing the lava to shrink and dry up, forming a dragon made of
                stone. Zuko spits out some water from the wave that got into his mouth. Iroh walks
                near Zuko, facing the others.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing a finger above.</charAction> Now I hope that you can see that
            each element has its own strengths and weaknesses. <charAction>Sokka eats his fish. Iroh
                suddenly becomes very tall and raises his voice.</charAction> But fire is the
            best!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He and Zuko quickly run away, creating a white cloud of smoke. Fade to
                credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
