<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Jet Episode</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens in a forest. Momo is chasing a bug through the trees. In
                his pursuit he lands on the ground to see a neatly stacked pile of lychee nuts. When
                he runs toward it, Momo is pulled into the air by a cage trap, joining two other
                caged animals. Camera changes focus to find the rest of Team Avatar
                camping.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Where's Momo? <charAction>Camera zooms in to close-up shot of Aang, Katara, and
                Sokka, the siblings sitting next to each other with bored faces, and Aang standing
                with his back to the camera. Momo screeches and the gang looks
            around.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera fades to find Aang as he spots the three animals in their cage traps
                hanging by rope on tree limbs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hang on, Momo! <charAction>Aang uses his airbending to fly to the top of the tree,
                jumping from trunk-to-trunk to get higher. He finds the traps' mechanisms, undoes
                them, and carefully lowers Momo to the ground where Katara and Sokka are waiting.
                They open the trap together and the lemur runs out with one of the lychee nuts in
                his mouth. Katara and Sokka look on as Momo gets on his hind legs and eats it as
                though nothing has happened. Sokka grunts in frustration and facepalms. When Aang
                lands, he looks up to see the other two animals seemingly crying out to him for
                help.</charAction> All right, you too. <charAction>Jumps up to
            them.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This is gonna take forever. <charAction>Throws his boomerang to simply cut the
                animals free.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Inching his way upside-down to the traps on the tree branch. They fall
                before he can reach them.</charAction> That works.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The hog monkeys run up the tree and out of the camera's view and Aang jumps
                back down, dirt flying from the ground as he lands. Everyone gathers around two of
                the traps and Sokka kneels down to examine them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>These are Fire Nation traps, <charAction>Camera zooms to upward shot of the gang
                looking at the trap.</charAction> you can tell from the metalwork. We better pack up
            camp, and get moving.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They gather their things and begin to pack them onto Appa's
                saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Uh uh. No flying this time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> What? Why wouldn't we fly?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes the sleeping bag from Aang's hands.</charAction> Think about it:
            Somehow Prince Zuko and the Fire Nation keep finding us. It's because they spot Appa,
            he's just too noticeable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What? Appa's not too noticeable!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points dramatically at Appa; condescendingly.</charAction> He's a
            gigantic fluffy monster with an arrow on his head! It's kinda hard to miss him!
                <charAction>The bison yawns and the camera flashes to Aang sitting comfortably on
                the animal's head.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Appa.</charAction> Sokka's just jealous 'cause he doesn't have an
            arrow.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera closes in on Sokka and Katara next to each other.</charAction> I
            know you all wanna fly, but my instincts tell me we should play it safe this time and
            walk.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Leans forward at her brother and smiles.</charAction> Who made you the
            boss?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points his finger at his chest; to Katara.</charAction> I'm not the
            boss, I'm the leader.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> You're the leader? But your voice still
            cracks!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice cracks.</charAction> I'm the oldest, and I'm a warrior, so
                <charAction>Deepens voice.</charAction> I'm the leader!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up shot of Katara's face.</charAction> If anyone's the leader,
            it's Aang. I mean he is the Avatar. <charAction>Pan back to
                Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Are you kidding, he's just a goofy kid!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While hanging upside-down from Appa's right horn with feet sticking out
                in the air.</charAction> He's right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why do boys always think someone has to be the leader? I bet you wouldn't be so
            bossy if you kissed a girl.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up on Sokka; defensively.</charAction> I've kissed a girl, you
            just haven't met her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Back to Sokka.</charAction> Who? Gran-Gran? I've met Gran-Gran.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Throws arms into the air.</charAction> No! Besides Gran-Gran. Look, my
            instincts tell me we have a better chance of slipping through on foot, and a leader has
            to trust his instincts.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Okay, we'll try it your way, oh wise
            leader.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang steps over, now wearing a backpack. Momo is sitting on the
                top.</charAction> Who knows? Walking might be fun. <charAction>Cut to the forest at
                a later time. Between trees the group trudges along, with Sokka in front, followed
                by Aang and Momo, Katara, and Appa.</charAction> Walking stinks! How do people go
            anywhere without a flying bison?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Well I don't know, Aang. Why don't you ask
            Sokka's instincts? They seem to know everything.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Ha, ha, very funny.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Complaining.</charAction> I'm tired of carrying this pack.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You know who you should ask to carry it for a while? Sokka's instincts.
                <charAction>Sokka's eyes turn to her in irritation.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's a great idea. Hey, Sokka's instincts, would you mind-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, okay, I get it. Look guys, I'm tired too. But the important thing is that
            we're safe from the <charAction>Walks through a bush and sees something in front of
                him.</charAction> Fire ... Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka sees a Fire Nation campsite with a lot of soldiers; most of them are
                seated or crouched near the fire with bowls in hand and a couple of them sit close
                to the tents, which have the Fire Nation emblem on the doorflap. One of these
                soldiers has a patch over his left eye. They all notice the group and get
                up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Run! <charAction>They turn to run but a firebender blocks them off by setting the
                plants behind them on fire.</charAction> We're cut off!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, your shirt! <charAction>Sokka yells; Katara clears a fire on Sokka's shirt
                with waterbending.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>If you let us pass, we promise not to hurt you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> Bluffing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Eye-patch soldier">Eye-patch soldier</speaker>
        <speech>You promise not to hurt us? <charAction>He's somehow knocked
            out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Nice work, Sokka! How'd you do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, instinct?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points up a tree.</charAction> Look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In a tree, a man with hook swords, Jet, jumps and takes down two soldiers.
                He runs forward and takes down two more using his hook swords.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Down you go. <charAction>Katara looks amazed, Aang shocked, and Sokka
                confused.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Another soldier charges at Jet, but he is defeated.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation soldier">Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>They're in the trees!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A young boy lands on top of the soldier and turns his helmet around to
                blind him, before riding him around while laughing. Another boy launches arrows at
                the soldiers while more boys come out of the trees. Aang and Katara are shown
                fighting the soldiers. Sokka holds up his boomerang and yells as one approaches him,
                but stops when Jet takes him down first.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, he was mine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Gotta be quicker next time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks dismayed and the camera cuts to show a huge boy fall out of the
                trees and easily take down two soldiers as Jet skillfully takes down one more,
                causing this soldier's weapon to hit another soldier, who was going to battle Sokka,
                in the head, making that soldier also fall down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet disarms another soldier and runs up to Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Hey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hi.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They look around to see a now empty camp</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amazed.</charAction> You just took out a whole army almost
            single-handed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Disdainfully.</charAction> Army? There were only like, twenty
            guys.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>My name is Jet, and these are my Freedom Fighters, Sneers, Longshot, Smellerbee, The
            Duke, and Pipsqueak.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughing; looking at The Duke.</charAction> Ha, ha, Pipsqueak, that's a
            funny name. <charAction>The Duke sniffs his nose, as the camera pans upward to
                Pipsqueak.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looming over Aang in a threatening manner; in a low, growling tone of
                voice.</charAction> You think my name is funny?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side-shot; Aang looks taken aback for a second before replying in an
                upbeat tone.</charAction> It's hilarious!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Facial shot of Pipsqueak, still looming forward with a frown on his face.
                He suddenly starts laughing. The camera moves back, showing Aang and The Duke
                following suit. Pipsqueak pats the Avatar on the back in a friendly manner, though
                the hit was hard enough to knock Aang flat on the ground. The Duke stops laughing
                and looks down at Aang sprawled on the ground before his feet, face flat in the
                dirt, though when Aang raises his head and continues laughing, so does The
                Duke.</description>
            <description>The scene fades to the Fire Nation camp, and the camera cuts to show the
                Freedom Fighters raiding the empty camp.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Jet.</charAction> Umm, thanks for saving us Jet. We're lucky
            you were there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I should be thanking you. We were waiting to ambush those soldiers all morning, we
            just needed the right distraction, and then you guys stumbled in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eyeing Sokka.</charAction> We were relying on instincts.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You'll get yourself killed doing that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks at them disdainfully as The Duke and Pipsqueak look through the
                barrels.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>Hey Jet, these barrels are filled of blasting jelly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>That's a great score.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>And these boxes are filled with jelly candy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Also good, let's not get those mixed up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>We'll take this stuff back to the hideout.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You guys have a hideout?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You wanna see it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Very excitedly.</charAction> Yes, we wanna see it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet smiles at her and the camera fades to show them standing on the forest
                floor.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>We're here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Where? There's nothing here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Hold this. <charAction>Gives a rope to Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Skeptically.</charAction> Why? What's this do? <charAction>Screams as he
                is pulled up into the branches.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Aang? <charAction>Offers Aang another rope.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll get up on my own. <charAction>Leaps up into the trees with
                airbending.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Grab hold of me, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara blushes as she takes his hand and they rise up through the tree
                together in a romantic setting. They come to a landing on a wooden platform in the
                trees. Once up there, Aang is seen zip lining through the trees.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While passing through with Momo.</charAction> Nice place you
            got!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's beautiful up here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>It's beautiful ... and more importantly the Fire Nation can't find us.
                <charAction>Smellerbee lands near the two.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>They would love to find you. Wouldn't they, Jet?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>It's not gonna happen, Smellerbee.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>As Aang zips by again.</charAction> Why does the Fire Nation want to
            find you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I guess you could say I've been causing them a little trouble. See, they took over a
            nearby Earth Kingdom town a few years back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>We've been ambushin' their troops, cutting off their supply lines, and doing
            anything we can to mess with 'em. <charAction>Sokka is now seen comically hopping around
                trying to get past Pipsqueak.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>One day, we'll drive the Fire Nation out of here for good and free that
            town.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That's so brave. <charAction>Sokka manages to get by
            Pipsqueak.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, nothing's braver than a guy in a tree
            house.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Don't pay any attention to my brother.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>No problem. He probably had a rough day.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So, you all live here? <charAction>Sokka who is being ignored comically sinks back
                behind them.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>That's right. Longshot over there? <charAction>The screen cuts to Longshot and The
                Duke walking not making a sound.</charAction> His town got burned down by the Fire
            Nation. And we found The Duke trying to steal our food. I don't think he ever really had
            a home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What about you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Katara and Jet come to a halt as the rest pass.</charAction> The Fire
            Nation killed my parents. I was only eight years old. That day changed me
            forever.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka and I lost our mother to the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I'm so sorry, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The screen fades from the two of them alone on the suspension bridge to the
                blue sky above the canopy. A cloud of cawing birds is disturbed as Appa raises his
                head with a roar. In the hideout, ropes with lanterns hang between branches.
                Sentries keep watch on several upper platforms while the group sits at a banquet
                table. While the group eats, Jet stands on the table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Today, we struck another blow against the Fire Nation swine. <charAction>Everyone
                cheers. Katara and Aang smile while Sokka cops an attitude and a scowling
                face.</charAction> I got a special joy from the look on one soldier's face, when The
            Duke dropped down on his helmet and rode him like a wild hog monkey. <charAction>The
                Duke, without his helmet, climbs up the table. He marches on the table with his arms
                in the air.</charAction> Now, the Fire Nation thinks they don't have to worry about
            a couple of kids hiding in the trees. <charAction>He prepares to take a drink from his
                wooden cup.</charAction> Maybe they're right. <charAction>A very loud and long boo
                is heard; with an angry face.</charAction> Or maybe ... they're
                dead wrong. <charAction>A loud and long cheer is
                heard.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey Jet, nice speech.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks. By the way, I was really impressed with you and Aang. That was some great
            bending I saw out there today.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, he's great. He's the Avatar. <charAction>Blushes.</charAction> I could use
            some more training.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Avatar huh? Very nice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks Jet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>So I might know a way that you and Aang can help in our struggle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Unfortunately, we have to leave tonight. <charAction>Sokka starts walking
                away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, you're kidding me! I needed you on an important mission tomorrow.
                <charAction>Sokka turns around.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What mission?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to the top of the forest the next day. Jet and Sokka are
                in branches of the same tree. Jet cups his hands and makes a birdcall; several trees
                down Pipsqueak and Smellerbee step into view from their branches. They reply with
                another birdcall. Sokka jams his jawbone knife into the trunk of the
                tree</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Shh ... It amplifies vibrations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Impressed.</charAction> Good trick.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sokka puts his ear to the handle of his knife.</charAction> Nothing yet.
                <charAction>Whispers.</charAction> Wait! Yes, someone's approaching.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> How many?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I think there's just one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Does a another birdcall.</charAction> Good work, Sokka. Ready your
            weapon. <charAction>Sokka takes his knife out of the tree. His eyes spot an old
                man.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> Wait, false alarm ... He's just an old
            man.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet ignores Sokka and prepares to attack the old man, leaping to the ground
                in front of the traveler. Sokka watches with horror.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing in our woods, you leech?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Old Fire Nation civilian">Old Fire Nation civilian</speaker>
        <speech>Please sir, I'm just a traveler.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet takes a step, and with one swipe, sends the man's cane flying from his
                hand. The old man backs away, but when he tries to flee the way he came, he runs
                face first into Pipsqueak's chest. The force of the impact knocks him to the ground;
                Pipsqueak looms over him. He tries to crawl away, but Pipsqueak's foot on his
                backside effectively pins him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Do you like destroying towns? Do you like destroying families? Do you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Old Fire Nation civilian">Old Fire Nation civilian</speaker>
        <speech>Oh ... Please let me go ... have mercy ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Does the Fire Nation let people go? Does the Fire Nation have mercy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet is about to kick the man, but his foot is snagged by Sokka's club
                before it can be delivered. Sokka releases him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, he's just an old man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>He's Fire Nation! Search him! <charAction>Pipsqueak holds the prisoner and
                Smellerbee steps up to search the poor man.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But he's not hurting anyone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Have you forgotten that the Fire Nation killed your mother? Remember why you
            fight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>We've got his stuff, Jet. <charAction>She holds up the old man's bag. The old man is
                thrown back on the ground.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This doesn't feel right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>It's what has to be done, now let's get outta here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet pushes past Sokka. Pipsqueak and Smellerbee follow. Sokka looks at the
                old man still on his hands and knees in pity.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka slowly turns and runs to catch up with the others. At the hideout,
                Aang and Momo are playing with the ziplines again. He leaps near
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka! Look what the Duke gave me! <charAction>Aang is wearing a bag and pulls a
                small pellet from it. With a sly grin, he tosses it next to Momo, where it explodes
                with a pop. Momo puffs up like a startled cat. He hisses and lunges for the bag.
                Momo sits on Aang's shoulder and tosses several pellets at his feet. Aang dances
                about wildly.</charAction> Ow! Quit it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka is oblivious of it all. He's sitting with his back to the trunk and
                staring at the ground, glaring. Katara walks up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, Sokka. Is Jet back?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah he's back. But we're leaving.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But I made him this hat. <charAction>She shows a cap made out of stitched leaves
                with a flower on top.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Your boyfriend Jet's a thug.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What? No, he's not.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He's messed up Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>He's not messed up, he's just got a different way of life, a really fun way of
            life.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He beat and robbed a harmless old man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I wanna hear Jet's side of the story. <charAction>The scene changes to Jet in a
                room.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, you told them what happened, but you didn't mention that the guy was Fire
            Nation?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet is sitting on a hammock-bed, the others stand. Sokka stands grumpily as
                far away as he can get. Aang is wearing the hat Katara made; he looks ridiculous and
                goofy.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, he conveniently left that part out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Fine! But even if he was Fire Nation, he was a harmless civilian!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>He was an assassin, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet pulls out a knife and thrusts it into a nearby stump. It is a sinister
                looking curved blade. There are four spikes evenly spaced along the grip, with
                enough space for fingers to go between them. There is a ring on the butt of the
                knife.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>See? There's a compartment for poison in the knife. <charAction>He pulls on the ring
                and removes a small glass tube filled with red liquid.</charAction>. He was sent to
            eliminate me; you helped save my life, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I knew there was an explanation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I didn't see any knife!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>That's because he was concealing it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>See, Sokka? I'm sure you just didn't notice the knife.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There was no knife! I'm going back to the hut and packing my things.
                <charAction>Sokka stomps away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Tell me you guys aren't leaving yet. I really need your help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What can we do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>The Fire Nation is planning on burning down our forest. If you both use waterbending
            to fill the reservoir, we could fight the fires. But if you leave now, they'll destroy
            the whole valley.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara look at each other. Fade to them entering their hut. Sokka
                is tying up a mat on the floor.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We can't leave now with the Fire Nation about to burn down a forest!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry Katara. Jet's very smooth, but we can't trust him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You know what I think? You're jealous that he's a better warrior and a better
            leader!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, I'm not jealous of Jet. It's just that my instinct—</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well my instincts tell me we need to stay here a little
            longer and help Jet. Come on Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They leave the hut. Fade to the night sky above the canopy. A full moon
                shines on Appa, who is on his back and snoring extremely loud as he sleeps. Inside
                the Trio's hut, Sokka sleeps propped up against his still-packed gear while the
                others sleep in their sleeping bags.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Let's go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka wakes up. He pulls the door flap aside enough to see some of Jet's
                followers descending on the rope lines. Sokka grabs a rope line down to a lower
                branch. On the ground below him, Jet's Freedom Fighters are quietly pushing the
                loaded wagon as Jet leads them out of the camp. Sokka stealthily follows. In the
                dark valley. Upstream, and up toward the wall of the valley there is an old falls,
                and beyond that a man-made dam. A bare cliff off to the reservoir's left provides
                the view. Jet and his boys emerge from the forest. He goes to the edge and looks
                down on the dam below. The reservoir behind it is low. He turns back to the
                wagon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Now listen, you are not to blow the dam until I give the signal. If the reservoir
            isn't full, the Fire Nation troops could survive. <charAction>The Duke jumps off the
                wagon.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>But what about the people in the town, won't they get wiped out too? <charAction>Jet
                places a hand on The Duke's shoulder.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Look Duke, that's the price of ridding this area of the Fire Nation. <charAction>To
                Longshot.</charAction> Now don't blow the dam until I give the signal—got it?
                <charAction>Longshot nods.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka watches incredulously from the bushes. He frowns, and hears rustling
                just before Pipsqueak drags him out by his wolf-tail. Smellerbee's knife is
                instantly at his throat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sneering.</charAction> Where do you think you're going,
            ponytail?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet, standing near the edge of the cliff. As he watches, Pipsqueak and
                Smellerbee drag Sokka between them. Pipsqueak still has a handful of Sokka's
                wolf-tail.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, I'm glad you decided to join us. <charAction>Pipsqueak and Smellerbee send
                Sokka to his knees. He rubs his shoulder.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I heard your plan to destroy the Earth Kingdom town.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Our plan is to rid the valley of the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There are people living there, Jet; mothers and fathers and children.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>We can't win without making some sacrifices. <charAction>Sokka points an accusing
                finger at Jet.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You lied to Aang and Katara about the forest fire!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Because they don't understand the demands of war. Not like you and I do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I do understand. I understand that there's nothing you won't do to get what you
            want.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I was hoping you'd have an open mind, but I can see you've made your
            choice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pipsqueak and Smellerbee grab for Sokka. Before he can even react, Jet has
                his wrist pinned with the hooks of his shuang gou. Sokka's other hand is forced
                behind his back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I can't let you warn Katara and Aang. <charAction>Jet releases Sokka's hand; it is
                immediately forced behind his back.</charAction> Take him for a walk, a long
            walk.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You can't do this!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Cheer up, Sokka. We're gonna win a great victory against the Fire Nation
            today.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The screen pans to the riverside upriver from the dam. The collected water
                behind it is much less than the larger cavity of the reservoir. The river leading to
                down to it is a thread compared to its 'rainy season' gully. Jet, Katara, and Aang
                are seen walking upriver along its west bank.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, I'm sorry about how Sokka's been acting.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>No worries, he already apologized.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Really? <charAction>Aang and Katara stop and look at one another.</charAction> Sokka
            apologized?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I was surprised too. I got the sense that maybe you talked to him or
            something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I did.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I guess something you said got through to him. Anyhow, he went out on a scouting
            mission with Pipsqueak and Smellerbee.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm glad he cooled off. He's so stubborn sometimes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They are now walking in the gully, beside the 'river'. Aang pauses after
                noticing something strange, and is launched into the air by a blast from the geyser
                he was standing on.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>All right, we're here. Underground water's trying to escape through these vents. I
            need you guys to help it along.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I've never used bending on water I can't see. I don't know ... <charAction>Jet
                stands behind her and places his hands on her shoulders.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Katara. You can do this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Airbends himself back on the ground.</charAction> What about
            me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I know the Avatar can do this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara stand on one of the many geysers in the gully. While Jet
                looks on, they bend the water up. After a few minutes, a stream of water emerges
                from the hole. They pull it to their height and send it toward the river where it
                continues to flow like a waterfall. The water quickly joins the river.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Yes! Good job! This river empties into the reservoir--a few more geysers and it'll
            be full.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Look, there's another steam vent. <charAction>Aang and Katara walk off in its
                direction.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Okay. You two keep it up, I'll go check on things at the reservoir. <charAction>He
                turns and walks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>When we're done we'll meet you over there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Actually ... probably better if you meet me back at the hideout when you're done.
                <charAction>Jet resumes walking away Aang and Katara bend the next geyser into
                another fountain.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Later.</charAction> I bet that's enough, and I'm not just saying that to
            be lazy. <charAction>Around them, over a dozen geysers flow into the
            river.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Let's catch up with Jet at the reservoir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I thought we agreed to meet Jet back at the hideout.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, we finished early. I'm sure he'll be happy to see us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The screen changes to a path in the forest. Pipsqueak and Smellerbee follow
                Sokka, who has his hands tied behind his back. Smellerbee gives Sokka a shove; Sokka
                stumbles but remains on his feet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, move along!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>How can you stand by and do nothing while Jet wipes out a whole town?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>Hey listen Sokka, Jet's a great leader. We follow what he says, and things always
            turn out okay. <charAction>Sokka notices a couple of snare leaf-piles nearby identical
                to the one that enticed Momo, right down to the pile of nuts.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>If that's how Jet leads, then he's got a lot to learn. <charAction>Sokka sprints off
                in the direction of the snares. Smellerbee makes a grab for him, but
                misses.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! <charAction>They give chase. Sokka leaps over the leaf piles. Pipsqueak and
                Smellerbee don't, and end up snared and hanging many feet up in the
                air.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>While you two are up there, you might want to practice your knot work.
                <charAction>He holds up his now-worthless bindings, turns, and walks
                away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>Hey Smellerbee, you gonna eat your lychee nuts? <charAction>Smellerbee hits him in
                the head with a lychee nut and it lands in the pile he's holding.</charAction> Ooh.
                <charAction>He picks one up and licks his lips.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Aang are standing on the edge of the cliff. At the base of the
                dam, four of Jet's people are unloading barrels from the wagon and arranging
                them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What are they doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, those are the red barrels he got from the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why would they need blasting jelly? <charAction>Zooms on Aang, who is
                horrified.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Because Jet's gonna blow up the dam.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What? No, that would destroy the town. Jet wouldn't do that. <charAction>Aang opens
                his glider.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I've gotta stop him. <charAction>He takes off.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Less convinced.</charAction> Jet wouldn't do that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Before Aang can reach the edge, Jet crosses his path from behind and
                snatches the glider. Aang is left wobbling precariously on the edge, and uses
                airbending to get himself back on stable footing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Yes I would.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, why?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, you would too if you just stopped to think. Think about what the Fire Nation
            did to your mother, we can't let them do that to anyone else, ever again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>This isn't the answer!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I want you to understand me Katara. I thought your brother would understand,
            but—</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Where's Sokka? <charAction>Tears fall from her eyes. Jet reaches out and touches her
                face.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She lowers her head, and with a shout, sends Jet flying with the water from
                her waterskin. She draws it back into the skin when she's done.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I need to get to the dam.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang's closed glider is on the ground. As he reaches for it, one of Jet's
                hook swords pins it. Jet has the two swords hook to hook; with a yank he pulls
                Aang's glider to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You're not going anywhere without your glider.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet swings the swords at Aang. Aang somersaults backward to avoid the extra
                reach. Aang finishes his retreat in a nearby tree.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not gonna fight you, Jet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Taunting.</charAction> You'll have to if you want your glider
            back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang retreats back into the forest, as Jet hooks the branch and pulls
                himself up. Katara follows on the ground. Jet attacks; Aang defends himself with
                balls of air, which Jet ducks. Jet attacks head on, but Aang blocks with his arms
                and sends his opponent flying into a tree trunk with an air kick. Jet combines his
                swords again and advances. Aang avoids the flail-like move and sends another air
                blast. Jet stoops down and lets the air flow over and past him before
                lunging.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They continue the chase through the many levels of the forest. Jet catches
                up to Aang and sends them both freefalling, attacking as they go. They both end up
                on a branch. Jet continues his attack. Aang avoids it all. Jet charges again, but
                Aang hits him with a jetstream of air. Jet falls. He recovers, but loses the glider
                in the process. Before Aang can get to the ground Jet kicks him into a trunk. He
                lands with a thud next to his glider.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A small tributary flows past him. Aang is slow to get up. Before Jet can
                take more than a step however, he his hit by a large water strike. Katara is there;
                she uses water from the river to throw Jet against the trunk of the tree. Over and
                over she attacks; Jet is unable to cut the water and its force plasters him against
                the trunk. She freezes Jet from toe to neck.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why, Jet? I can't believe I trusted you. You lied to me, you're sick and I trusted
            you! <charAction>A birdcall is heard. Katara and Aang are startled, and look to the
                valley beyond where it's coming from. Jet gives an answering birdcall.</charAction>
            What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You're too late.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Horrified.</charAction> No!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang opens his glider and runs for the nearby cliff. His glider's wings are
                damaged to the point that he has no lift, and slams back into the ground near the
                edge. Katara runs over to help him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In pain from the fall.</charAction> Sokka's still out there, he's our
            only chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, Sokka. I'm sorry I ever doubted you, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot stands on a branch, his bow pulled. He has a flaming arrow on the
                string. He takes aim and fires. It arcs down to the base of the dam. Katara watches
                in horror.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispers.</charAction> No ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The center of the dam explodes in a cloud of smoke and fire. Katara and
                Aang watch a massive wall of water go to the town. Inside the town the streets are
                empty except for the occasional barrels and the Cabbage Merchant's cabbage cart. The
                water rushes through the open gate, as a cresting wave dwarfs it. The wall and gate
                are swallowed as the wave strikes the town. The flotsam carried away includes a
                smiling doll in a purple dress.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka didn't make it in time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>All those people ... <charAction>She turns in rage back to Jet.</charAction> Jet,
            you monster!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>This was a victory, Katara. Remember that. The Fire Nation is gone and this valley
            will be safe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It will be safe, without you. <charAction>In shock, Jet looks up to see Sokka, Appa,
                and Momo rise from below the level of the cliff.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I warned the villagers of your plan, just in time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>What?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts to an illustrated set of flashback stills each being panned
                through.</charAction> At first they didn't believe me. The Fire Nation soldiers
            assumed I was a spy. But one man vouched for me, the old man you attacked. He urged them
            to trust me, and we got everyone out in time. <charAction>The flashback ends and the
                townsfolk are seen on high ground above the river, on the bank opposite the town. A
                little girl, who was seen in the flashback, runs down to the water's edge as the
                doll floats by. She retrieves it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Little girl">Little girl</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> Misses Pretty! <charAction>She hugs her
                doll.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, you fool! We could've freed this valley!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Who would be free? Everyone would be dead.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You traitor!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, Jet. You became the traitor when you stopped protecting innocent
            people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Katara. Please, help me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Goodbye Jet. <charAction>Sokka gives Appa's reigns a flick.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yip yip. <charAction>Jet is left behind, still frozen to the
            tree.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sky they fly in is empty, save a few wispy clouds.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We thought you were going to the dam. How come you went to the town
            instead?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Let me guess, your instincts told you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugs his right shoulder.</charAction> Hey, sometimes they're
            right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang:">Aang:</speaker>
        <speech>Um ... Sokka? You know we're going the wrong way, right? <charAction>Sokka is
                surprised, but quickly recovers.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And sometimes they're wrong. <charAction>With a grin, he pulls Appa's reigns. They
                fly off screen before reappearing, going in the opposite
            direction.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
