<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Nightmares and Daydreams</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Some koala sheep are sleeping, as Katara, Sokka, Aang, Toph, and Appa come
                out of the bushes. Sokka looks at a map, while everyone else looks around. Momo
                jumps over on Aang's shoulder, as Aang scratches his head.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Somewhat excitedly.</charAction> This is it! The official rendezvous
            point for the invasion force.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans to the left, showing a vast area of the
                place.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>How did you pick this place?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Before we split up, my dad and I found this island on the map. It's uninhabited, and
            the harbors surrounded by the cliffs seemed like the perfect secluded place.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Nice choice, Sokka. And we're here four days ahead of schedule.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Anxiously.</charAction> Wait! Four days? The invasion's in
                four days?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Yawns.</charAction> Whatever. That's like four days from now. Let's just
            calm down and-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka falls asleep and begins snoring.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka's got the right idea, Aang. We're here. We're ready. The best thing we can do
            now is get plenty of rest. <charAction>Lies down.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Half-heartedly.</charAction> I guess.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <p>
                <description>Everyone else falls asleep. Aang lies down and, as he closes his eyes,
                    the camera zooms in on his face.</description>
            </p>
            <p>
                <description>Scene briefly fades to black before changing to a large Fire Nation
                    insignia, which is revealed to be a door when the camera zooms back. The door
                    busts open, revealing a boy with large hair, a headband, and a yellow jump suit,
                    with his face turned the other side. He enters the room with a series of
                    dramatic gestures. It is revealed that this boy is Aang in strange attire. Aang
                    quickly jumps on to a rock tower. Cut to wider shot of Aang standing on the rock
                    tower, surrounded by floating broken pillars.</description>
            </p>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He makes some fast and dramatic ninja-like moves as he
                speaks.</charAction> Your days of tyranny are over, Fire Lord! I'm bringing you
            down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to close-up of the Fire Lord, who is about to take a bite of a bundle
                of grapes with his eyes closed. Hearing Aang's words, he stops and opens his eyes to
                look down at his adversary. The camera pans out quickly to reveal he is actually a
                giant when compared to Aang and surrounded by a pit of fire.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>Really? <charAction>Brings his face close to Aang.</charAction> How do you plan on
            doing that when you're not even wearing pants?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang's scared face, as he looks down to see that Ozai was telling
                the truth, and screams.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh no!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang quickly covers himself with a white Air Nomad shield pulled out of
                thin air. The camera zooms out to a larger shot of Aang shaking with embarrassment.
                Suddenly, giant eyes begin to appear all around him. The eye's close and disappear.
                Cut to shot of the giant Fire Lord laughing, as Aang slowly backs out the door. The
                Fire Lord raises his arms to the ceiling, while surrounded by flames, laughing
                heartily. Aang wakes up and starts touching his pants. Momo is seen awake as
                well.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It was just a dream, Momo. I still have my pants. <charAction>Stands
                up.</charAction> Well, I better keep training.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang walks over to a bush and starts kicking it. Momo gets bored of
                watching him, and soon falls back asleep. Scene changes to the Fire Nation Palace,
                where Zuko is getting dressed and ready, with help from his servants.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #1">Servant #1</speaker>
        <speech>Fresh fruit, Prince Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko puts out his hand and shakes his head respectfully.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #2">Servant #2</speaker>
        <speech>May I wash your feet, sir?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko respectfully puts his hand out and shakes his head
                again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #1">Servant #1</speaker>
        <speech>Head massage?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko shakes his head again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #2">Servant #2</speaker>
        <speech>Hot towel?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko looks at the towels for a moment and takes one. He is seen wiping his
                forehead before walking out of the room. The two servants bow behind him. Zuko walks
                out the palace gates, with Fire Nation citizens waiting for him. One woman becomes
                overly excited at seeing Zuko, and is taken away by the palace guards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #1">Servant #1</speaker>
        <speech>Prince Zuko, is something wrong? You didn't take the palanquin.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm just going to Mai's house. It's not far.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant #1">Servant #1</speaker>
        <speech>It's not a prince's place to walk anywhere, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <p>
                <description>Zuko looks to the distance, walks over, and gets into the palanquin.
                    The servants pick it up and walk over to Mai's house. Zuko looks out of the
                    palanquin's curtains and sees Mai, who is standing by the doors to her house,
                    who waves and walks away.</description>
            </p>
            <p>
                <description>The scene changes back to Aang, who is still training. He is now
                    banging his fists against a tree, which wakes up Sokka, Toph, and Katara. Katara
                    looks at Sokka, who just shrugs. She decides to go talk to Aang about
                    this.</description>
            </p>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey. How long have you been up?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>A couple hours. I got a lot more skills to refine if I'm gonna fight Ozai.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang stops, panting.</charAction> You know, there is such a thing as
            over-training.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang hits the tree one last time, which sends a vibration throughout his
                body and makes him fall down, with all of the leaves off the tree collapsing on him.
                Katara just gazes down at him, and Sokka, holding his map, and Toph, who is facing
                the other direction, look out from behind her. Aang comes out from under the leaves
                and walks around Katara in a fighting stance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You don't get it, do you? My form is bad, I'm sloppy, and I still don't know any
            firebending. Not even the basics.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang's left eye twitches a little bit after saying this. Katara brings
                Aang's hand down, with a forced smile on her face. Sokka is seen, lying down, still
                looking at the map.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's okay, Aang. The eclipse will block off firebending anyway. You don't need to
            know it. <charAction>Looking at Aang.</charAction> Plus, it's a stupid element.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, well I still have to work on everything else. I better spend the whole day
            training.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang bows quickly toward Sokka, followed by Katara, and rides off on an air
                scooter. Sokka moves the map up in front of his face to hide behind it. The view
                changes to the blue sky, which changes to a starry night. Aang is walking back from
                his training, now exhausted. Everyone else is asleep. Aang rubs his eyes and yawns
                before collapsing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wide shot of the group on the cliffside with the camera slowly zooming
                out.</charAction> Good night, Katara. Good night, Sokka. Good night, Toph. Good
            night, Appa. Good night, Momo. Good night, Appa and Mo-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>
            <charAction>With chibi face in a speech bubble that appears above her;
                angrily.</charAction>
            <description>Go to sleep already!</description>
            <charAction>Clenches her teeth.</charAction>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang, who flinched upon hearing Toph, but goes back into his normal
                position and closes his eyes. The camera pans up.</description>
            <p>
                <description>The scene fades briefly to black again, before cutting to shot of Aang
                    busting through the same large Fire Nation door from his previous dream. This
                    time, he is wearing boats, white pants, a high collared yellow tunic that covers
                    his mouth, white sleeves with blue arrows on them, and has his chest wrapped in
                    a chain. He has sideburns, his hair is long and stands up straight, wears his
                    headband, and has two small metal rings in the top of his right ear. As he
                    stands in the opening where the doors once were, he snaps his fingers and smoke
                    starts to pour into the entrance. Aang slides in and jumps over some small
                    pillars to face Ozai, who is still a giant.</description>
            </p>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot as he points outward.</charAction> Your days of tyranny are
            over, Fire Lord. <charAction>Scowls.</charAction> I'm bringing you down!
                <charAction>Looks down momentarily; confidently.</charAction> And this time, I
            brought pants.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera shows a view of some chains wrapping around Aang's clothing,
                including his pants. The shot turns to Ozai.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>So it seems, but are you prepared for your ... mathematics test?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A giant abacus lands behind Aang. Camera turns to show Aang's worried
                face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Math test? Oh no! I forgot all about the math test!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ozai is heard laughing in the background as Aang is screaming while being
                pulled backward and crushed by some beads on the abacus. He suddenly wakes
                up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I've gotta be ready.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang gets up and walks away. He is seen pacing around some sleeping koala
                sheep. Katara comes over to talk to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, it's the middle of the night. You need to go back to sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But I forgot my pants and my math test.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara sighs and grabs Aang's shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, sleep. Please. For me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <p>
                <description>Aang looks at her, rubbing his eyes. He bows his head, and the two walk
                    back. A koala sheep makes a sound. The scene changes to the Royal Palace, where
                    Zuko and Mai are relaxing on a couch.</description>
            </p>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Tell me, if you could have anything you want right now, what would it be?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Hm ... A big fancy fruit tart, with rose petals on top.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You know, being a prince and all, I might just be able to
            make that happen.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> That would be impressive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To the servants.</charAction> Do you think you could find a fresh fruit
            tart for the lady, with rose petals on top?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>Excellent choice, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>I guess there's some nice perks that come with being royalty. <charAction>Pushing
                him Zuko to lay down with her.</charAction> Though there's annoying stuff, too. Like
            that all-day war meeting coming up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting up, followed by Mai.</charAction> War meeting? What are you
            talking about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Azula mentioned something. I-I assumed you were going, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I guess I wasn't invited.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two look away from each other. The scene changes back to the Black
                Cliffs, where Aang is still sleeping.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>Wake up, Aang. Wake up, sleepy head! <charAction>Cut to an out of focus swaying shot
                of the Fire Lord standing over Aang.</charAction> Rise and shine! You overslept.
                <charAction>The Fire Lord bends in close and then even closer.</charAction> You
            missed the invasion.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ozai begins to laugh, and is seen riding a giant, flying hippo cow, which
                breathes out fire at Aang, making him move from his spot. He watches as Ozai flies
                away, still laughing. Aang quickly wakes up, and goes to wake up
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, get up! I needa know what day it is!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What? Who's talking?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka grabs his sword and jumps up, but hits his head on a nearby rock and
                falls down. Toph and Katara are seen waking up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Relax! It's still two days before the invasion!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang begins pulling on Sokka's legs, trying to get him up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, you've gotta get up drill your rock-climbing exercises.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>In one of my dreams, you were running from Fire Nation soldiers, trying to climb
            this cliff, <charAction>Camera turns to show an annoyed look on Sokka's
                face.</charAction> but you were too slow and they got you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka stands up quickly and steps in front of Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But that was just a dream. I'm a great climber!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While pointing at the cliff nearby.</charAction> Then climb that cliff!
            Climb it fast!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera turns to show the size of the cliff. When it sets back on Sokka, he
                looks at Aang, pointing to the cliff. Aang nods fast, and Sokka reluctantly begins
                to climb it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Stupid Avatar! Stupid cliff! Stupid dream! I can climb fast!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang is seen looking up at Sokka with an anxious smile, before frowning at
                seeing how slowly he was going. Toph tries to get a drink of water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning around to her.</charAction> Don't drink that!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka is seen behind Aang falling off the cliff after hearing Aang. Toph
                spits out the water onto Katara, who waterbends it off her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Why? Is it poisoned?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>In my dream, we were right in the middle of the invasion, and you had to stop to use
            the bathroom! <charAction>He puts his hands between his legs and squeezes them
                together.</charAction> We died because of your tiny bladder. <charAction>He turns to
                Katara.</charAction> And you need to start wearing your hair up. In my dream, your
            hair got caught in a train, and-.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Putting a hand on the side of his face.</charAction> Aang! I know you're
            just trying to help, but you really need to get a grip.
            You're unraveling.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He takes a deep breath before finally speaking.</charAction> You're
            right. I'm losing my mind.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka is still climbing the cliff, and almost reaches the top, but is seen
                sliding down. Cut to the sun in the sky. Cut to Aang's face, his eye twitching, as
                he paces around, stressed. Cut to his hands rotating between putting his thumb and
                finger together before alternating to the opposites on the other hand.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It's like every time I think about how stressed I am, I just end up more stressed.
            I'm like a big growing snowball of nerves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As he paces, Katara sits, concerned, petting Momo and watching Aang, while
                Sokka hammers away at a piece of armor for Appa. Toph lies resting against a
                sleeping Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to look at Aang.</charAction> Of course you are. That's 'cause
            you gotta fight the Fire Lord, the baddest man on the planet. And you better win or
            we're all done for.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Sokka, annoyed.</charAction> Sokka! You're not
            helping!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing.</charAction> What? It's true. That's the deal. He knows
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara pushes down Sokka to sit, before looking over at Aang, who is
                nervously shaking. She walks over to him and touches his shoulders.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You know what, I've got just the thing! Get ready to be de-stressified!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to Aang and Katara in a mountain doing some yoga. Steaming
                water in the middle of the room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>These yoga stretches can really work wonders if you do them in extreme heat. Reach
                up. <charAction>Katara puts her hands above her head
                together, Aang follows along.</charAction> Reach for the sun. <charAction>They wave
                their hands and upper bodies side to side.</charAction> Feel your chi paths
            clearing. <charAction>Both bend over so their heads touch the ground, grabbing their
                legs.</charAction> Now close your eyes. How are you feeling?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of Aang sweating.</charAction> I feel ... really warm.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Good, good. Go on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Like there's this warm feeling all around me. This heat. <charAction>Becoming
                frantic again.</charAction> Like I'm in the Fire Lord's palace and he's shooting a
            bunch of fireballs at me! And the whole world is being engulfed in flames!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>An orange flame is seen circling around, covering the view, before
                disappearing. Aang gets out of his position and lands on his back,
                panting.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe your stress is the kind you need to talk
            out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes to Sokka, in his Wang Fire outfit, and Aang lying on a koala
                sheep.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In his Wang Fire voice.</charAction> Why don't you get right down to
            business and tell me what's been bothering you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You know what's bothering me. I have to fight the Fire
            Lord in a few days.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He nods upon hearing Aang's explanation.</charAction> Tell me more about
            this "Fire Lord". Why are you so afraid of him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You said it yourself! He's the baddest man on the planet! I'm supposed to defeat him
            and save the world!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nodding in agreement.</charAction> Life does feel that way sometimes,
            doesn't it? Like we're all trying to save the world from evil.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay! But what can I do to feel better?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While handing Aang a koala sheep.</charAction> Want to try screaming
            into this pillow?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang does so. Once his face is out of the wool, the koala sheep makes a
                noise at him. After Sokka scratches his head, he does a thumbs-up while nodding.
                Aang shakes his head so Sokka nods faster, but Aang shakes his head faster. Scene
                changes to Azula at the royal spa, getting her hair done. Zuko comes in and walks up
                to her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Hello, Zuzu. If you've come for a royal hair-combing, I'm afraid you'll have to
            wait.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>So I guess there's a big war meeting coming up, huh? And apparently I'm not welcome
            there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean? Of course you're welcome there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, yeah?! I guess that's why no one bothered to tell me about it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, Zuko. Don't be so dramatic. I'm certain Dad wants you there. You probably just
            weren't invited because it's so obvious you're supposed to be
            there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Well, were you invited?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Of course! I'm the princess.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>And I'm the prince!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Exactly, so stop acting like a paranoid child! Just go to the meeting.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Forget it! I'm not going!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko turns around and walks away. The scene changes to Aang lying down on
                some pillars.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>All right! What you need is a good old-fashioned back pounding to relieve your
            stress.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking up at her.</charAction> Pound away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph begins stomping fiercely, causing the pillars to move up and down in
                various order.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The pillars causing him pain.</charAction> Ow! Toph ... I ... think ...
            this ... is ... bruising ... me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph stops, and Aang begins sliding to the left, off the
                pillars.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry. I forgot you had baby skin. <charAction>Aang grabs onto the edge of the
                pillars and gets up.</charAction> Well, there's one other thing we can try.
                <charAction>She stomps the ground, sending a distant boar-q-pine to her. She catches
                it and holds it out to Aang with a wide grin.</charAction> Acupuncture!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The boar-q-pine's quills stick out, and Aang runs away. Scene changes back
                to the Fire Nation Palace, where Zuko is looking out a window. Mai comes up to
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko, it's just a dumb meeting. Who cares?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I don't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Well, good. You shouldn't. I mean, why would you even
                want to go? Just think about how things went the last
            meeting you went to.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> I know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>You know what will make you feel better? <charAction>Zuko turns his head
                slightly.</charAction> Ordering some servants around. I might be hungry for a whole
                tray of fruit tarts. And maybe a little palanquin ride
            around town. Double time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She turns Zuko's face to look at her, but he quickly looks away, making Mai
                let go of him. Scene changes back to the Black Cliffs. Aang is sitting up, holding
                his knees.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks for everything, guys.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So, do you feel less stressed? Ready for a good night's sleep?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He turns his head away.</charAction> Uh, I kinda think I sorta might
            slightly feel a little better. <charAction>He looks back at his friends.</charAction>
            Maybe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Then our work here is done.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka, Katara, and Toph stretch and yawn before lying down. Aang slowly
                lies down, and closes his eyes, leading to another dream. It begins with a
                thunderstorm, with Aang riding on Appa through it. They fly by a giant Momo, who
                tries hitting them down, and grabs them in his hand. It changes to an image of the
                Fire Nation Royal Palace, and Aang emerges in the water, and is pushed forward into
                the palace. He looks in all directions, waiting for something to happen. Toph is
                seen rotating around. Her bangs move to reveal that her eyes are blank. She falls
                down under the floor in front of Aang, who becomes scared. Sokka tries running away,
                but some wet earth closes around him. Katara is seen surrounded by fire. Aang tries
                to go save her, but his feet are frozen to the ground. Ice crawls up his body, and
                he reaches out, but he's completely frozen. The ground that he was on becomes
                completely ice. Ozai, as a fire monster, begins laughing and melts the ice, which
                makes Aang fall down. He is released from his form and falls into some water, where
                he sinks to the bottom and looks through the floor, seeing Zuko as if he was
                standing above. The comet is seen passing by behind Zuko. Aang is seen still holding
                his breath. The comet is shown rushing down. Momo is seen telling someone to be
                quiet. Aang is standing on grass and seeing bushes and mountains when the comet
                strikes the ground, and everything is scorched and on fire. He quickly wakes up,
                screaming and waking everyone else up. Appa becomes scared, and Momo slides off him.
                Everyone rushes over to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What happened, Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns away on hands and knees.</charAction> It's the nightmares. They
            just get worse and worse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Looks like it's time for another ... <charAction>He turns around and puts his Wang
                Fire disguise on and voice.</charAction> therapy session.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Momentarily looking back.</charAction> No. That won't help. Nothing
            helps. There's only one thing I can do! I'm going to stay awake straight through to the
            invasion!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang starts shaking upon this, and everyone behind him is shocked, except
                for Toph, who just smiles. Sokka's Wang Fire disguise falls off him. The scene
                changes to the next day, where Katara is doing some exercises on the edge of the
                cliff. Aang is pacing nervously behind her, which makes her stop.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Invasion. All aboard for the invasion.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching.</charAction> You don't look so good. You sure you can't
            just lie down for a little nap?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I told you, I can't go back to sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, staying up all night can't be good for you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking toward the cliff edge. Katara turns and moves a bit to
                follow.</charAction> Actually, staying up all night has given me some time to think.
            And I've realized some big things, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What big things?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I see everything so clearly now. What really matters. Why I'm really doing this.
                <charAction>He turns around to look at Katara.</charAction> I'm doing it to save the
            world. But more than that. I'm doing it for the people I love. <charAction>Side shot of
                Aang and Katara near each other.</charAction> I'm doing it for you, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, what are you saying?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm saying, I love you! <charAction>He kisses her. After he pulls back, she embraces
                and kisses him back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>After kissing for a while she pulls back, whispering
                slightly.</charAction> What are we doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What our hearts have been telling us to do for a long, long time. Baby,
                <charAction>He moves Katara down to the side.</charAction> you're my forever girl.
                <charAction>Aang puckers up his lips for another kiss.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang! <charAction>Aang realizes he was just daydreaming, and realizes he is not
                holding Katara anymore.</charAction> I was just saying you should take a
            nap.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He quickly turns around to face Katara.</charAction> Oh, I guess I kinda
            drifted off into a daydream.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What was your dream about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He pauses to think for a moment.</charAction> Uh, living
            underwater?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Initially confused, she smiles back.</charAction> Sounds neat!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang nervously laughs. Katara walks away, and he lets out a sigh of relief.
                The scene changes back to Mai's house. Zuko is lying down on the arm of the couch,
                while Mai is making tea. Just as she is about to give him a cup, someone calls for
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>Prince Zuko, <charAction>He bows before the prince.</charAction> everyone's waiting
            for you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Mai and Zuko walk over to the servant to see what he's talking
                about.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>The high admirals, the high generals, the war ministers, and the princess have all
            arrived. You're the only person missing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>So, my dad wants me at the meeting?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>The Fire Lord said he would not start until you arrived, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko smiles, and looks at Mai, who is also smiling. The scene changes back
                to the Black Cliffs, where Aang is hiding behind a bush in his Fire Nation uniform.
                He jumps out and rolls behind a rock, before stepping up from behind the
                rock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Put 'em up, Fire Lord!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang jumps out from behind the rock and starts shooting air blasts at the
                noodle picture of Fire Lord Ozai tied to a tree. One of the shots goes too far and
                hits Sokka, who is working on a golden arrow.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! I'm tryin' build Appa some armor here so he doesn't have to go into the
            invasion naked. He's your bison.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing in front of the "Ozai" tree in a fighting stance.</charAction>
            Ozai's defense is impeccable. I'll have to try a different approach.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang jumps up and shoots more air blasts, but they all miss. Aang lands on
                his feet and looks at the picture. Only a leaf falls. Aang runs up in front of the
                picture.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You think you're untouchable, don't you, Mr. Fire Lord?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Momo">Momo</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> Boy, you are really starting to lose it,
            kid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang quickly becomes surprised upon hearing the voice, and quickly turns
                around to face Momo.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Momo, did you hear something? <charAction>Turns back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Momo">Momo</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> No, but I said something. <charAction>Aang
                becomes shocked and gets close to Momo.</charAction> You, my friend, are just a few
            plums short of a fruit pie. <charAction>Aang stares at Momo in disbelief, his jaw wide
                open. He quickly stands up, shakes his head, and covers his eyes. He peeks through
                them, at which point Momo begins chittering normally again. Aang walks up to him and
                pets him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's more like it. I'm so tired that for a second there, I imagined you were
            talking to me. <charAction>Momo tilts his head in confusion. Everyone is seen walking
                forward and watching Aang.</charAction> Oh, Momo, let me explain. <charAction>Aang
                begins chattering like Momo. Katara and Sokka share a look of confusion, as Toph
                merely stands there with a slightly annoyed look. Momo chitters back, in which Aang
                laughs before chittering again. Katara interrupts him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang? We're all starting to get a little worried about you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You've been awake too long.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>And you're acting downright weird.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Appa">Appa</speaker>
        <speech>You've got to take care of yourself. You can't go on like this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Look, I appreciate what you guys are saying, but the
            stress and the nightmares. They were just too much. Staying awake is the best way for me
            to deal with it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Momo">Momo</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing and pointing at Appa.</charAction> Yeah! Leave the kid
            alone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Appa">Appa</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing back.</charAction> Hey, who asked
                you? <charAction>The two begin to
            fight.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You guys, come on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Appa">Appa</speaker>
        <speech>No! I am sick of this guy always mouthing me and telling me what to do!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Momo">Momo</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, you don't like it? Well, let's go right now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang runs over to Sokka for help, not realizing that his friends don't see
                anything.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, what do we do?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> About what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing.</charAction> About that!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks in the direction Aang was pointing. Momo is seen in a purple
                samurai outfit with the fur between his ears tied in a topknot. Appa is seen with
                orange and dark red armor and a helmet, with three swords. Momo takes out his one
                sword, and the two charge at each other. Momo parries Appa's three swords with his
                single one. Some koala sheep start cheering on the two.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Koala sheep">Koala sheep</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a group of koala sheep.</charAction> Appa! Appa! Appa!
                <charAction>Cut to another group.</charAction> Momo! Momo! Momo!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa takes out another sword, and twists in a twister toward Momo, who
                blocks the attacks. Aang walks forward and tries stopping them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, guys. We're all on the same side.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Guru Pathik appears on a cloud with six arms, holding two cups of onion and
                banana juice, and playing a veena.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pathik">Pathik</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Singing.</charAction> Chakras, chakras, everybody loves chakras.
            Chakras, chakras, chakras sandwich tastes good. Yum!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo and Appa continue fighting. Momo keeps trying to strike Appa, but Appa
                keeps jumping away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Koala sheep">Koala sheep</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to some koala sheep.</charAction> Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang begins sweating. Rocks, in a snake like formation, begin to slide in
                and around Aang, before sliding away. The koala sheep continue cheering on Momo and
                Appa. The tree with Ozai's noodle picture begins dancing. A ring of rocks surrounds
                Aang, as do the koala sheep. Three lines of rocks are seen on each side of Aang, as
                Momo and Appa continue to fight.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I just need to jump in a cold waterfall!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He screams and runs away from the scene. The scene changes to the Royal
                Palace, where Mai is waiting for Zuko after the meeting, who is
                exiting.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>So, how did it go? <charAction>They walk on together.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>When I got to the meeting, everyone welcomed me. My father had saved me a seat. He
            wanted me next to him. I was literally at his right
            hand.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko, that's wonderful! You must be happy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two stop at a picture of Ozai. Zuko gazes at it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>During the meeting, I was the perfect prince. The son my father wanted.
                <charAction>Looks down, eyes closed.</charAction> But I wasn't me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene changes back to the Black Cliffs. It is nighttime, and Aang is tired.
                A mist of fog surrounds koala sheep wool. Aang looks at it and begins touching
                it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, look. Another hallucination. An imaginary bed made out of clouds.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pan right to see Katara, Toph, and Sokka standing nearby, with a flock of
                sheared koala sheep.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! It's real! We spent hours working on it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We made it for you. A good night's sleep will probably take the crazy away. We
            hope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Look! You guys keep telling me that I need to sleep, but I can't! The invasion's
            tomorrow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Concerned.</charAction> Aang ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, Katara! There's still so much I haven't learned. I don't need sleep. What I need
            is practice. Quick, hit me! <charAction>He begins to wobble.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not going to hit you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You want me to do it? <charAction>Sokka nudges her back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Aang, placing a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> Listen to
            me. You've been training for this since the day we met. <charAction>Moves behind him,
                talking over his shoulder.</charAction> I've seen your progress. You're smart,
            brave, and strong enough.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You really think so? <charAction>Katara nods.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We all do. You can do this. You're ready.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You're the man, Twinkle Toes!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks, guys. <charAction>He nods, yawns, and rubs his eyes. Katara aids him to the
                bed, where he lies down.</charAction> You know what? I think I am ready.
                <charAction>The other three watch as he falls asleep quickly. He falls into another
                dream, meeting with Ozai again.</charAction> Your days of tyranny are over, Fire
            Lord!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>Really? You're gonna take me out? You're not even wearing pants!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles smugly.</charAction> No, Fire Lord Ozai.
                <description>You're</description> not wearing any pants.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ozai looks down and sees Aang is right. He quickly pulls over a shield with
                the Fire Nation emblem on it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ozai">Ozai</speaker>
        <speech>No! My royal parts are showing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The view goes outside, where it is seen that the palace is up on a rock in
                the sky. The scene fades back to the Black Cliffs with Ozai screaming to Aang, who
                is seen smiling upon his success in the dream. Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
