<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Drill</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens where several Fire Nation tanks rumble across the
                terrain, a large metal mechanism following close behind. The camera zooms out to a
                shot of the Fire Nation drill slowly moving its way toward the Outer Wall of Ba Sing
                Se. Several sections of the drill extend forward, releasing steam as spikes are
                driven into the ground. The drill's command module ascends where inside are Princess
                Azula, her friends, Mai and Ty Lee, War Minister Qin and several operators of the
                drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Qin">Qin</speaker>
        <speech>This drill is a feat of scientific ingenuity and raw destructive power. Once it
            tunnels through the wall, our troops will storm their city. The Earth Kingdom will
            finally fall, and you can claim Ba Sing Se in the name of your father. Nothing can stop
            us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking through the telescope.</charAction> Hmmm, what about those
            muscle-y guys down there?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She peers through a periscope at several Earth Kingdom troops using
                earthbending to create large trenches, Fire Nation forces following them in hot
                pursuit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Qin">Qin</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Strikes the periscope roughly alarming Ty Lee.</charAction> Please. The
            drill's metal shell is impervious to any earthbending attack.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I'm sure it is, War Minister Qin, but just to be on the safe side ...
                <charAction>Sharply while looking at the two girls.</charAction> Mai and Ty Lee,
            take the earthbenders out!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Swinging a knife around her finger; relieved.</charAction> Finally,
            something to do. <charAction>Rises and walks out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Katara, Sokka and Toph are escorting Than and
                his family to the city. Aang appears, flying in on his glider with Momo behind him.
                He lands, Momo perched on his shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Aang, what are you doing here? I thought you
            were looking for Appa.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I was, but something stopped me. Something big.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to the base of the Outer Wall where Aang and Toph use
                earthbending to transport everyone up the wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Now what's so big that Appa has to wait?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera zooms out to drill.</charAction> That.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The group arrives at the top of the Outer Wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Despairingly.</charAction> We made it to Ba Sing Se and we're still not
            safe. No one is! <charAction>Huddles with family members.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender guard">Earthbender guard</speaker>
        <speech>What are you people doing here? Civilians aren't allowed on the wall!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm the Avatar. Take me to whoever is in charge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a portion of the Outer Wall where a roof rises
                overhead, supported by tall arches. An Earth Kingdom general sits behind a
                desk.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> It is an honor to welcome you to the Outer Wall,
            young Avatar, but your help is not needed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Not needed?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction>
            Not needed. I have the situation under control. I assure you
            the Fire Nation cannot penetrate this wall. Many have tried to break through it, but
            none have succeeded.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What about the Dragon of the West? He got in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly taken aback.</charAction> Well ... uh, technically yes, but he
            was quickly expunged. <charAction>Confidently.</charAction> Nevertheless, that is why
            the city is named Ba Sing Se. It's the "impenetrable city". They don't call it Na Sing
            Se. <charAction>Laughs, but subsequently turns serious.</charAction> That means
            "penetrable city."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, thanks for the tour, but we still got the drill problem.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech>Not for long. To stop it, I've sent an elite platoon of earthbenders called the
            Terra Team.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's a good group name. Very catchy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to where the Terra Team is launching their assault on the
                Fire Nation drill. They manage to overthrow one tank and get closer to the
                drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Terra Team leader">Terra Team leader</speaker>
        <speech>Ready ... attack!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The earthbenders wedge large earth spikes into the metal shell of the drill
                to halt it. However, the drill's segments separate, reducing the columns to
                crumbles. The Terra Team narrowly manages to conjure earth shields to defend
                themselves against an assault of flying daggers hurled by Mai. She and Ty Lee are
                seen sliding down the shell of the drill. The scene cuts to the side of the drill
                where Ty Lee lands gracefully onto the ground. She effortlessly manages to defeat
                the earthbenders through an acrobatic display, utilizing chi blocking.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Upon witnessing the defeat of the Terra Team.</charAction> We're doomed!
                <charAction>Flails arms in panic.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slaps him across the face.</charAction> Get a hold of yourself,
            man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rubbing cheek.</charAction> You're right. I'm sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe you'd like the Avatar's help now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Meekly stands before the Avatar. Humbly.</charAction> Yes,
            please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Aang and the rest are overlooking the wall at
                the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The question is, how are we going to stop that thing? <charAction>All turn their
                heads to Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why are you all looking at me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're the idea guy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Complaining.</charAction> So I'm the only one who can ever come up with
            a plan? That's a lot of pressure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>And also the complaining guy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That part I don't mind.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where a ticket woman is inspecting Zuko and Iroh's
                tickets.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket woman">Ticket woman</speaker>
        <speech>So, Mr. Lee and Mr. ummm ... Mushy, is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>It's pronounced Mushi.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket woman">Ticket woman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> You telling me how to do my job?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches the ticket booth.</charAction> Uh, no, no. But may I just say
            you're like a flower in bloom. Your beauty is intoxicating.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket woman">Ticket woman</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Flirtatiously.</charAction> You're pretty easy on the eyes yourself,
            handsome. Raorr! Welcome to Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Stamps their
            tickets.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Disgusted.</charAction> I'm going to forget I saw that.
                <charAction>Grabs ticket and walks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera changes to view of Jet, overlooking Zuko, now under the adopted
                alias, Lee.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I think Lee would make a good Freedom Fighter. He's just trying to find his way in
            the world, like us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>You don't know anything about him, Jet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I know he didn't get that scar from a waterbender.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Besides, I thought we were going straight now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>We are, and the new Freedom Fighters could use a guy like Lee. What do you think,
            Longshot?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot looks over at him silently with a meaningful look on his face and
                blinks his eyes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I can respect that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, back at the Outer Wall, Katara attempts to heal a member of the
                Terra Team.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech>What's wrong with him? He doesn't look injured.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>His chi is blocked. <charAction>Stops healing.</charAction> Who did this to
            you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Terra Team member">Terra Team member</speaker>
        <speech>Two girls ambushed us. One of them hit me with a bunch of quick jabs and suddenly I
            couldn't earthbend anymore and I could barely move. Then she cartwheeled away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eyes widen in realization.</charAction> Ty Lee. She doesn't look
            dangerous, but she knows the human body and its weak points. It's like she takes you
            down from the inside.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh! Ooh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Yes?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What you just said! That's how we're going to take down the drill! The same way Ty
            Lee took down all those big earthbenders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>By hitting its pressure points!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking out over the wall with a determined look.</charAction> We'll
            take it down from the inside.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to the Fire Nation drill. The camera pans to where Aang,
                Katara, Sokka and Toph are crouching together in one of the abandoned trenches of
                the Terra Team.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gesturing toward the drill.</charAction> Once I whip up some cover,
            you're not going to be able to see. So, stay close to me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She steps outside the trench and with a powerful stomp of her foot, sending
                a mass of flying debris clouding toward the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Run!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The group races into the dust cloud behind Toph. The scene cuts to the
                command module where Ty Lee is peering at the cloud through the
                periscope.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, look at that dust cloud. <charAction>Periscope view shows front of drill and
                billowing cloud.</charAction> It's so ... poofy. <charAction>Cut back to Ty Lee who
                looks away from the periscope with a spaced-out expression.</charAction>
            Poof.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Qin">Qin</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, Princess. I'm sure it's nothing. <charAction>Azula casts a doubtful
                look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to outside where the group is standing in the midst of
                the dust beside the drill. Toph earthbends a hole into the ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone into the hole!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She and the others jump into the hole and the ground above them closes
                shut. The camera pans to underground where it is pitch black.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's so dark down here, I can't see a thing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh no, what a nightmare!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They make their way to the surface underneath the drill, where Sokka spots
                an opening.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang leaps up to the bar hanging from the opening and, dangling upside-down
                from his legs, hoists himself and Katara into the drill. He realizes Toph is not
                following them. Sokka sticks his head out of the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, come on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>No way am I going in that metal monster. I can't bend in there. I'll try to slow it
            down out here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, good luck! <charAction>He and Aang disappear into the
            drill.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph earthbends a wedge of rock into the drill, however, it is proving to
                be a difficult task as it pushes her back. The scene changes to inside the drill
                where Sokka is leading the others through a tunnel of valves and
                pipes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I need a plan of this machine. Some schematics that show what the inside looks like.
            Then we can find its weak points.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Where are we going to get something like that? <charAction>Sokka unexpectedly cuts
                off a steam valve with his machete.</charAction> What are you doing? Someone's going
            to hear us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's the point. I figure a machine this big needs engineers to run it. And when
            something breaks ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>They come to fix it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara smile at each other. Moments later, an engineer wearing a
                mask is seen walking down the misty hallway to the site of the damage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Appears behind him.</charAction> Hi.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She freezes the mist, covering the engineer in a thin layer of ice. Sokka
                runs up to the frozen engineer and takes his schematics.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This'll work. Thanks!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The trio runs off, leaving the helpless engineer who drops his spear
                unintentionally. The scene changes to where Sokka and the others are studying the
                plans.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It looks like the drill is made up of two main structures. There's the inner
            mechanism where we are now and the outer shell. The inner part and the outer part are
            connected by these braces. If we cut through them, the entire thing will
            collapse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Katara nod in agreement. The scene changes to the train station
                where Zuko, Iroh and the three Freedom Fighters are awaiting their train. The camera
                focuses on Zuko and Iroh, who sit in the waiting area. Jet approaches and sits next
                to Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>So, you guys got plans once you're inside the city?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tea seller">Tea seller</speaker>
        <speech>Get your hot tea here! Finest tea in Ba Sing Se!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waves hand.</charAction> Ooh! Jasmine please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The tea seller pours tea into a leaf cup for Iroh. Iroh sips the tea, but
                soon grimaces at its repulsive taste.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Blaugh! Ugh, coldest tea in Ba Sing Se is more like it! What a disgrace!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, can I talk to you for a second?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He motions for Zuko to follow him. Zuko sighs and reluctantly rises. The
                two walk several feet away from Iroh's spot.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You and I have a much better chance of making it in the city if we stick together.
            You want to join the Freedom Fighters?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks, but I don't think you want me in your gang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, we made a great team looting that captain's food. Think of all the good we
            could do for these refugees.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking away.</charAction> I said no.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Have it your way.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He catches sight of Iroh, who is sipping his now steaming hot tea, causing
                his eyes to widen in shock and realization. Zuko, approaching Iroh, glances over his
                shoulder at Jet, who narrows his eyes and walks away. Angrily, he knocks the tea cup
                out of Iroh's hand.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Hey!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gritting in a whisper.</charAction> What are you doing firebending your
            tea? For a wise, old man, that was a pretty stupid move!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mourning.</charAction> I know you're not supposed to cry over spilled
            tea, but ... <charAction>Sniffs. The cup is shown overturned in a puddle.</charAction>
            it's just so sad!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to the interior of the drill where Sokka is leading the
                others through a door onto a massive steal beam.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, it looks a lot thicker in person than it does in the plans. We're going to have
            to work pretty hard to cut through that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Crosses her arms.</charAction> What's this "we" stuff? Aang and I are
            going to have to do all the work.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns and gestures to self.</charAction> Look, I'm the plan guy. You two
                <charAction>Makes rapid chop-chop gestures.</charAction> are the cut stuff up with
            waterbending guys. <charAction>Strikes a heroic pose.</charAction> Together, we're Team
            Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Aang shoot each other awkward looks. The scene cuts to one where
                the two are positioned on either side of one brace. Using waterbending, they slice
                through the metal sharply. The shot changes to when the brace is sliced halfway
                through. Both Katara and Aang are bent over and gasping in exhaustion.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pumping arms in the air.</charAction> C'mon team. Don't quit now.
                <charAction>Katara grinds her teeth as she seethes with rage.</charAction> We're
            ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Explodes with frustration.</charAction> Grrr!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara shoots a menacing glare while pulling out her water whip and
                threatening to strike him with it. Cut to Sokka, who stands wide-eyed, arms still in
                air.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I mean, <charAction>Recovers and points reassuringly.</charAction> you're almost
            there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two resume work slicing the brace. With every lash of the water whip,
                the cut through the brace enlarges and Sokka grows more and more eager. At last, a
                cut is made clean through the brace, however, to their disappointment, the brace
                budges mere inches from its position.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Panting in exhaustion.</charAction> At this rate, we won't do enough
            damage before the drill reaches the wall.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know how many more of those I have in me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The drill suddenly creaks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Do you hear that? We took it down! We better get out of here fast!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The trio run for the door, only to halt upon hearing an announcement being
                made through overhead speaking tubes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Qin">Qin</speaker>
        <speech>Congratulations, crew. The drill has made contact with the wall of Ba Sing Se.
                <charAction>Cuts to him standing in the command module.</charAction> Start the
            countdown to victory!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cheers erupt from the crew. The camera cuts to Azula, a threatening look of
                determination on her face. Aang, Katara and Sokka look at each other in shock and
                dismay. The camera cuts to a scene of the drill hammering through the wall, sending
                loose boulders in every direction. The scene changes to one of a stream of a
                saturated rock and water solution traveling through tubes and making its way through
                the back entrance of the drill. Cuts to Sokka, who is desperately attempting to move
                the brace.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pushing against brace.</charAction> C'mon brace ... budge!
                <charAction>Makes several more attempts to move it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>This is bad, really bad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We're putting everything we've got into busting these braces, but it's taking too
            long!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Struck with realization.</charAction> Maybe we don't need to cut all the
            way through. Toph has been teaching me that you shouldn't give one hundred percent of
            your energy into any one strike. <charAction>Rises.</charAction> Sokka, take a fighting
            stance. You've got to be quick and accurate. Hit a series of points and break your
            opponent's stance. <charAction>Strikes Sokka several times.</charAction> And when he's
            reeling back, you deliver the final blow. <charAction>Hits him softly on the
                head.</charAction> His own weight becomes his downfall, literally.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Aang is speaking, Sokka kneels over.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So we just need to weaken the braces, instead of cutting all the way
            through.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Then I'll go to the top of this thing and deliver the final blow.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rising.</charAction> And boom! It all comes crashing down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone inside that wall. The whole world is counting on us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The whole world minus the Fire Nation that is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka grins, while the other two simply stare at each other exasperated.
                The scene cuts to Toph under the drill, putting all her strength into keeping the
                rock column stable as she is slowly pushed back by the force of the
                drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Straining as the drill continues to push her back.</charAction> C'mon,
            Twinkle Toes, hurry up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Aang and Katara are making rapid progress,
                slicing through several braces halfway to weaken them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's enough! We need to get to the next one!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to outside the drill, where earthbenders are sending
                boulders down at the drill from the wall. The scene changes to the command module
                where the War Minister receives shocking news from engineers communicating through
                speaking tubes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Engineer">Engineer</speaker>
        <speech>War Minister, an engineer was ambushed! His schematics were stolen!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Qin is clearly surprised while Azula narrows her eyes in
                suspicion.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Second Engineer">Second Engineer</speaker>
        <speech>War Minister, a brace on the starboard side has been cut clean through! It's
            sabotage, sir!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sharply.</charAction> Let's go, ladies!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where the trio continues to slice through the
                braces.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Good work, Team Avatar! Now Aang just needs to ... <charAction>Glances up in
                horror.</charAction> duck!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He ducks just in time to evade the blue fire blast sent his way by Azula,
                who runs out and stands on another brace followed by her friends.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Barely misses another fire blast.</charAction> Whoa!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, Azula, you were right! It is the Avatar!
                <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Ty Lee; she smiles flirtatiously at
                Sokka.</charAction> ... and friends.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles and waves.</charAction> Hey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara approaches her brother and drags him away, clearly annoyed. Ty Lee
                swings herself forward toward Aang who quickly airbends her away. The trio escape
                the scene and race through the drill's hallways. They come to an
                intersection.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Guys, get out of here. I know what I need to do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Wait. <charAction>Throws him her water skin.</charAction> You need this water more
            than I do!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang catches the water skin and starts running again. Azula and her team
                reach the intersection.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Follow them! The Avatar's mine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Mai and Ty Lee begin chasing Katara and Sokka while Azula chases after
                Aang. Meanwhile, the two siblings have arrived at the end of the hallway where there
                is a closed hatch.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reads a sign nearby, while Sokka struggles to open the
                hatch.</charAction> Slurry pipeline? What does that mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Having successfully opened hatch which leads to a canal channeling
                slurry.</charAction> It's rock and water mixed together. It means our way
            out!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two begin descending into the pipe when Mai and Ty Lee arrive. They
                manage to escape into the canal just as a flurry of daggers is sent their way. The
                camera cuts to a shot of them floating through the slurry. Mai and Ty Lee run over
                and peer into the pipeline.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holds her hands over the slurry.</charAction> Ugh, disgusting!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech>C'mon! You heard Azula. We have to follow them!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>She can shoot all the lightning she wants at me. I am not going in that wall sludge
            juice. <charAction>Shivers in disgust.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ty Lee shrugs and leaps through the pipeline into the slurry. Mai shudders
                with a final expression of disgust and closes the hatch. The scene cuts to where
                Aang races past several engineers through the drill. The camera cuts to the rear of
                the drill where a flood of slurry is continually being released. Katara and Sokka
                slide through the slurry onto the ground with Ty Lee following them in hot pursuit.
                Katara uses waterbending to stop the flow of slurry and plug up the back entrance of
                the drill, thus trapping Ty Lee.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hatefully and tauntingly.</charAction> Why don't you try blocking my chi
            now, circus freak?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, keep that up. The pressure will build up in the drill. Then when Aang
            delivers the final blow, it'll be ready to pop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Aang and Momo have made their way to the top of
                the drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Halting.</charAction> This looks like a good spot, Momo.
                <charAction>Looks up to find boulders being hurtled down the wall, nearly crushing
                him. Yelling.</charAction> General Sung, tell your soldiers to stop shooting rocks
            down here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="General Sung">General Sung</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frantically.</charAction> Soldiers, whatever you do, don't stop shooting
            rocks down there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The soldiers nod and launch another round of rocks toward the drill. Aang
                leaps out of the way of the oncoming boulders and begins slicing at the hull of the
                metal using water from Katara's water skin. The scene changes to where Katara
                continues to hold Ty Lee captive in the slurry.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Good technique, little sister! Keep it up! Don't forget to breathe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> You know, I'm just about sick and tired of you
            telling me what to do all day! You're like a chattering hog-monkey!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Screaming.</charAction> Just bend the slurry, woman!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Frustrated, Katara bends a wave of slurry into her brother with her free
                hand, knocking him down into the foul muck.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Katara.</charAction> You guys need some help?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, help me plug up this drain.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two cooperate with each other to bend the slurry, sending Ty Lee
                farther into the drill and causing the pipes to begin to expand under the pressure.
                The scene cuts to where Aang continues to slice the metal of the
                drill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exhausted.</charAction> What I'd give to be a metalbender.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo suddenly shrieks and Aang deflects a blue fire blast just in
                time.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Assuming a fighting stance.</charAction> Momo, get out of here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula appears before the Avatar and a battle ensues between the two. Azula
                shoots fire blasts at Aang, who manages to block them using airbending. She
                continues the fire attacks only to have each one of her strikes deterred by water
                whips. She eventually manages to vaporize the water, sending Aang back. The two
                narrowly dodge the several boulders that are hurtled toward them at that moment.
                Aang uses earthbending and airbending to send rocks at Azula, who manages to avoid
                them all. Azula sends another powerful firebending assault that slams Aang into the
                Outer Wall of Ba Sing Se, leaving him unconscious.</description>
            <description>The camera view briefly changes to where the front of the drill is seen
                having completely dug its way through the Outer Wall. Camera changes to Azula as she
                walks over to him with fire in her right hand, preparing to deal a deadly final
                strike, but Aang awakens and sends her skidding back using an earthbending gauntlet.
                A flood of slurry is released as the drill bores deeper into the wall, coating the
                two. Azula slides toward a helpless Aang, attempting to halt herself by windmilling
                only to collide with him. The force of the collision sends both sliding off opposite
                sides of the drill. Azula is able to stop her descent by grinding her feet into the
                drill's side while Momo drags Aang up to the top with the help of Aang's
                airbending.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks, Momo. I owe you one. <charAction>Runs over to the wedge he sliced in the
                drill.</charAction> Now all I need ... <charAction>A boulder falls before
                him.</charAction> Actually, that is what I need for once.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He uses airbending to position the boulder over the X mark in the drill.
                Using earthbending, he cuts the rock several times, creating a wedge that fits
                inside the middle of the hole. He begins sprinting toward the wall, scales up its
                side by riding an air scooter and, once he arrives at his highest point, rockets at
                lightning speed toward the bottom. As he propels himself downward, Azula catches
                sight of him and fires at him. She misses by mere seconds and is sent back
                forcefully as Aang leaps and slams down on the wedge, creating a large ripple
                effect. The impact of the blow causes the sliced braces inside the drill to collapse
                and the pipes to burst, releasing a torrent of slurry. Slurry begins to seep from
                the drill. The scene cuts to Katara and Toph, who remain in their bending
                stances.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Woohoo!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Here it comes!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She earthbends Katara, Sokka, and herself onto a rock pillar to avoid the
                flood of slurry. Slurry gushes from the rear of the drill, and Ty Lee slams into the
                wall of the rock pillar as she is forcefully pushed forward by the flood. The drill
                begins to release steam and its segments begin to collapse. On the other side of the
                wall, the drill is seen coming to a halt.</description>
            <description>The camera zooms out on the destroyed drill. The scene cuts to Aang covered
                in slurry, Momo licking him as he wipes it away near his face, a huge smile spread
                across his face. Cut to War Minister Qin, who stares at the slurry from inside the
                command module, completely shocked. Cuts to General Sung atop the Outer Wall,
                covered in the muck. Cuts to Ty Lee as she attempts to clear away the mess. Cut to
                shot of Azula, skidding down the drill also covered in slurry. She lands by Ty Lee,
                causing the acrobat to be covered in slurry once again. A hatch opens, revealing
                Mai, who is completely clean.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Dryly.</charAction> We lost.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to the train station.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Train conductor">Train conductor</speaker>
        <speech>Last call for Ba Sing Se!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene shifts to Jet, who is storming toward the train, Longshot and
                Smellerbee following close behind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Jet, relax. So the old guy had some hot tea. Big deal.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>He heated it himself! <charAction>Darkly.</charAction> Those guys are
                firebenders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh and Zuko board the train, Jet and his groups eying them. Iroh and Zuko
                seat themselves next to Than and his family. Iroh notices Hope.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>What a handsome baby. <charAction>Strokes the infant.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera closes up on Hope, who is sleeping. Scene cuts to outside where two
                earthbenders begin moving the train out of the station. Scene changes to Team Avatar
                standing at the top of the wall, overlooking the sunset.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I just want to say, good effort out there today, Team Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unamused.</charAction> Enough with the Team Avatar stuff. No matter how
            many times you say it, it's not going to catch on.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>How about ... <charAction>Pulls out boomerang.</charAction> the Boomeraang Squad!
            See it's good because it's got "Aang" in it.
            Boomeraang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grins.</charAction> I kind of like that one.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Begins walking away.</charAction> Let's talk about this on our way into
            the city.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The Aang Gang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The Fearsome Foursome?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Also walking away.</charAction> You're crazy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why? We're fearsome!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He runs after them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
