<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Boiling Rock Part 2</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to morning at the Boiling Rock, where an overhead shot of
                the volcano is seen. Cut to view from some point in the boiling water, where the
                stronghold lies ahead. Cut to view of the warden walking forward, toward the
                camera.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bodyguard">Bodyguard</speaker>
        <speech>Line 'em up for the warden!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an overhead shot of the perimeter on which they are standing, the
                warden's back facing the camera. Eight prisoners are seen filing in line, one next
                to the other, including Hakoda. Cut to the end of the line of prisoners where the
                last of them line up, the camera zooming out to show Hakoda, who stands at the very
                end of the line on the right side. Cut to Sokka, who walks forward and lifts his
                guard mask.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Dad ... <charAction>Exiting a stairway and passing through a lineup of guards,
                surprising them a bit.</charAction> Excuse me, coming through. The warden wants me
            over there. <charAction>Points in the warden's direction.</charAction> Sorry!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to overhead shot of the perimeter, the prisoners lined up toward the
                right and the guards to the left of the screen. Sokka is seen inching his way behind
                several guards, taller than him. The warden approaches the new
                prisoners.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking past the line of prisoners starting from the left.</charAction>
            Welcome to the Boiling Rock. I'm sure you've all heard the horrible rumors about our
            little island. Well, I just want to tell you that they don't have to be true, as long as
            you do everything I say. <charAction>He stops in front of Hakoda who looks downward;
                looks closer at Hakoda.</charAction> Look me in the eye when I'm talking to
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Averting his gaze slightly off to the side; firmly.</charAction>
            No.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Oh? You'd rather look at my shoes? <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Then take a
            look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He raises his left leg and drags Hakoda by his handcuffs down onto the
                floor. Cut to a side-view of Hakoda kneeling over, his face expressing anger. Cut to
                Sokka standing behind two guards as he gasps in horror. Cut to shot from below
                Hakoda, where the warden stands over him, keeping his foot firmly pressed on the
                warrior's handcuffs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>I know exactly who you are, Hakoda of the Water Tribe. So strong-willed.
                <charAction>Cut to the warden's face.</charAction> But don't worry, we'll get rid of
            that in time. Now look me in the eye!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hakoda reluctantly lifts his head to look the warden in the eye and glares
                hatefully at him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmer.</charAction> See, isn't that better? <charAction>To the other
                prisoners.</charAction> You will all do as I say or pay the price. You will
            all-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He begins to walk forward only for Hakoda to lift his left handcuff
                slightly, tripping the warden and causing him to fall flat on the ground. Sokka
                stifles a chuckle, as the two guards he was standing behind rush to aid the
                warden.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bogyguard #2">Bogyguard #2</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Standing over him.</charAction> Are you okay, sir?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises and snaps angrily.</charAction> I'm fine! Get these prisoners out
            of my sight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He storms away impatiently. The two guards look at each other. Cut to
                wide-view of the perimeter where the prisoners file one behind the other and are led
                down a stairwell into what is presumed to be the prison hold. Sokka runs away
                off-screen. Cut to inside the prison, followed by an overhead shot of inside
                Hakoda's cell, where he sits on his mattress, his face buried in his arms. A sliver
                of light appears as the doorway to the cell is opened. Hakoda raises his head to see
                who has entered. Cut to side-view of the entire cell, revealing that Sokka has
                walked in, still dressed as a guard.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches his father.</charAction> Thank goodness you're okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises to his feet and extends his right arm out, clenched in a fist, not
                realizing the guard is his son in disguise; Sokka backs up a bit.</charAction> If
            you take one step closer, you'll see just how "okay" I am.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lifting up his helmet mask.</charAction> Dad, it's me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Softens up and grows teary-eyed.</charAction> Sokka, <charAction>The two
                embrace; Sokka drops his helmet to the floor.</charAction> my son.
                <charAction>Amused.</charAction> You know Sokka, you should be more careful with
            that guard outfit on. I almost punched you in the gut.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rubs the back of his neck sheepishly.</charAction> Yeah, I ran into that
            problem earlier.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a dimly-lit corridor. Cut to view of a door as it slides open,
                revealing Chit Sang sitting inside an interrogation room, cuffed to a wooden chair.
                The warden walks on-screen into the room. Cut to an overhead shot of the
                interrogation room as he approaches the prisoner.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Are you comfortable, Chit Sang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Snaps.</charAction> If you're trying to get me to talk, forget it!
                <charAction>The warden appears behind him.</charAction> I'm not a squealer!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts to close-up of his face; casually.</charAction> Chit Sang, I only
            asked if you were comfortable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brightly.</charAction> Well, yeah, actually I am pretty
            comfortable.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden, in a fit of anger, kicks the chair to the ground. Chit Sang
                falls forward off screen. Cuts to shot of him lying on the floor, still bound to the
                chair, his face pressed against the ground. The warden walks up to Chit
                Sang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Are you still comfortable?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>No.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>I know you and your cronies are not smart enough to come up with that little escape
            plan. So you're gonna tell me ... <charAction>Leans in closer to Chit Sang.</charAction>
            who is?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden exits the room. Cut to view of the room, as the two guards hoist
                the chair upward and set it on the ground. The guard on Chit Sang's left walks over
                to the doorway and slides the door to the cell closed. Cut to shot of the prison
                courtyard. Cut to shot of outside Hakoda's cell where Sokka can be seen looking
                through the open slit in the cell door, averting his eyes in different
                directions.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Hakoda.</charAction> So where's Bato? <charAction>Cut to inside the
                prison cell; Sokka turns away from the door.</charAction> Where's everyone else from
            the invasion?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>The others are being held at a prison near the Fire Nation palace. They singled me
            out as their leader and sent me here. <charAction>Sokka comes by his father and sits
                down.</charAction> But before I left, I met some young women who said they knew you.
            The ... Oshinama Fighters?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles.</charAction> You mean the Kyoshi Warriors?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>That's right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Their leader Suki is here and she's gonna escape with us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lays a hand on Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> Good. We'll need all the
            help we can get.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And you know Prince Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>The son of the Fire Lord? I don't know him, but I know of him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, he's here too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Crosses his arms angrily.</charAction> Sounds like a major
            problem.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, he's on our side now. <charAction>Cut to Hakoda, who gives his son a
                suspicious look.</charAction> I know. I had the same reaction. After all he's done,
            it was hard to trust him. But he's really proven himself, and I never would've found you
            without his help. <charAction>Hakoda nods his head at Sokka, indicating that he
                understands.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>So, do you have a plan?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Downcast.</charAction> We had one, but some of the other prisoners got
            involved and ruined it. <charAction>Leans forward and rests his face in his
                arms.</charAction> I dunno if there's another way off this island.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles and pats a hand on Sokka's back.</charAction> Sokka, there's no
            prison in the world that can hold two Water Tribe geniuses.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Then we'd better find two.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hakoda laughs. Sokka chuckles nervously. Cut to a ground level shot of
                inside the prison hold. Sokka approaches a cell door and averts his gaze alertly. He
                lifts his helmet mask and peers into the slit of a cell doorway.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a hushed voice.</charAction> Zuko, are you there?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>A view of Zuko's eyes appears in the slit from inside the
                cell.</charAction> I'm here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I just got done talking to my dad. We came up with an escape plan together.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera; startles Sokka.</charAction> What are you doing
            here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka turns around, pulling down his helmet mask. The camera shifts to
                reveal two guards standing on the stairwell behind him. Cut to shot from in between
                the two guards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing to the cell and trying to act gruff.</charAction> I was just
            telling this dirty lowlife what I think of him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Well, you'll have to do that later. He's coming with us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puzzled.</charAction> Why?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> Because we have orders straight from the warden,
            that's why!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Could I just get ten more seconds to rough him up a bit? <charAction>Punches his
                palm with his fist.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female guard">Female guard</speaker>
        <speech>Fine, ten seconds.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two guards fold their arms. Sokka enters the cell and begins to "rough
                up" Zuko. The female guard leans against the wall, crosses her arms and shakes her
                head in mock disapproval.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera from inside the cell.</charAction> Take that ... and this!
                <charAction>Punching noises come from the cell.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> Newbie.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to shot of a bundled-up mattress being held up, several blows being
                landed to it. Cut to shot of the cell where Sokka is seen punching the mattress
                which Zuko holds up, the two faking the entire scenario. Zuko shouts a few times in
                mock pain.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a hushed voice while still punching the mattress.</charAction> We
            have a new plan, but it's gonna need a big distraction. <charAction>Cuts to shot of Zuko
                who peers from behind the blanket; off camera.</charAction> Be in the yard in one
            hour.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A sliver of light appears as the cell door is opened. Sokka suddenly grabs
                Zuko and begins to wrestle him to look convincing as the two guards
                enter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Separates the two.</charAction> All right, that's enough.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko is escorted out of the cell by the guards while Sokka remains behind.
                Cut to an overhead shot of a hallway, the camera shifting downward to show Zuko
                being dragged.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> What are you doing? Where are you taking me?
                <charAction>He is thrown into a chair in an interrogation room.</charAction> I
            didn't do anything wrong!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, <charAction>Zuko looks to the source of the voice.</charAction> Zuko.
                <charAction>Emerges from the corner of the room; annoyed.</charAction> We all know
            that's a lie.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> Mai!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to shot of the entire cell, Zuko still sitting on the floor with Mai
                standing over him. The cell door is open, with at least one guard patrolling it from
                outside. Cut to view of prison hold before switching to an upside-down shot of the
                warden sliding open another cell door and entering the room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>How is he?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to right-side up shot of the two guards holding Chit Sang upside-down
                in the chair. Chit Sang's face is red and strained.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bodyguard #2">Bodyguard #2</speaker>
        <speech>I think he's ready to talk.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They toss chair the chair forward toward the warden back to a normal
                position. Chit Sang inhales deeply a few times, his face slowly returning to normal
                color, sweat dripping down his face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches him from behind.</charAction> Have you had enough time to
            think about what I asked?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Yes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eager.</charAction> And?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>You're right. There was another person involved in the escape plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Places his hand on Chit Sang's shoulder.</charAction> Who?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>It's a guy who's disguised like a prison guard. Only he's not a prison guard. He's
            the mastermind. He came up with the plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden smiles slyly, pats Chit Sang on the head, and exits. The camera
                focuses on Chit Sang, who maintains a cold-hard expression. The scene changes to the
                prison cell where Zuko sits in the chair slumped over and Mai stands over
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>How did you know I was here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Because I know you so well.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>But, how-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>The warden's my uncle, you idiot. <charAction>Zuko facepalms and sighs; Mai shows
                him a letter.</charAction> The truth is, I guess I don't know you. All I get is a
            letter? You could have least looked me in the eye when you ripped out my heart.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I didn't mean to -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>You didn't mean to? <charAction>Reading the letter.</charAction> "Dear Mai, I'm
            sorry you that you have to find out this way, but I'm leaving."</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Stop! This isn't about you. This is about the Fire Nation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Thanks Zuko, that makes me feel all better.
                <charAction>Throws the letter at him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Mai, I never wanted to hurt you. But I have to
            do this to save my country.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Save it? You're betraying your country!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>That's not how I see it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Mai who looks away from him sulkily and folds her arms. Cut to
                Suki's cell, where she is practicing her fighting moves. Sokka enters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, what's going on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Places his hand on her shoulder.</charAction> I don't have much time. If
            I'm seen with you the guards might think something's up. <charAction>Walks over to the
                door and peers outside.</charAction> I just talked to my dad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>That's great.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, and we're escaping today, on the gondola.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>My dad and I came up with the plan together. We're gonna commandeer the gondola
                <charAction>Puts both hands on her shoulders.</charAction> and we're gonna take a
            hostage with us so they won't cut the lines.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes his hands off her shoulders.</charAction> We'll never make it onto
            the gondola. There's too many guards.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>My dad already thought of that. He said we'll need a distraction. That's why we're
            gonna start a prison riot.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, let's say by some miracle this all works and we make it on the gondola. The
            warden will still just cut the lines, even if we have a captive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Not if the warden is the captive. <charAction>Nearby noise occurs. Moves to look
                outside.</charAction> I have to go. <charAction>Suki hugs him.</charAction> I'll
            find you before we start the riot. <charAction>Cut to outside the cell, where he slides
                out of the cell.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, you, the warden wants to see you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know, I didn't ask.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe I could schedule another time with him? How's tomorrow? <charAction>Walks
                off-screen.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard">Male guard</speaker>
        <speech>He wants to see you ... now. <charAction>Sokka is escorted by two
                guards.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene moves to the yard with a line-up of guards, the warden, and Chit Sang
                present.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Put him in the line-up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They throw Sokka in the line-up with a bunch of other guards, now with no
                helmet like the rest of them. He tries hiding behind a lowly guard, but the guard
                pushes him away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>One of you is an impostor who thought he could fool me. <charAction>Chit Sang steps
                forward.</charAction> But now, that person is going to be in a lot of trouble. Who
            is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka's teeth start chattering, clearly nervous among the other calm
                guards. The camera stays on Sokka, who closes his eyes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> That's him, warden. He's the impostor!
                <charAction>The camera shifts to Chit Sang, who is pointing at the bully
                guard.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the warden, who smiles evilly and walks away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs Chit Sang by the shirt.</charAction> I am not! <charAction>Chit
                Sang just raises his hands nonchalantly in defense.</charAction> He's lying!
                <charAction>Another guard grabs him.</charAction> He's a liar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guard is taken away. Chit Sang turns and smiles slyly at Sokka, who
                looks on and breathes a sigh of relief.</description>
            <description>Cut to a window. The camera pans down to the bully guard in an
                interrogation room surrounded by two guards. The warden stands in front of and away
                Chit Sang, holding his hands behind his back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>I'm telling you ... it wasn't me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Save your breath! I know you were working together. <charAction>Turns around and
                moves in closer to the guard.</charAction> You threw Chit Sang in the very cooler
            they used to escape. It was all part of your plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech>That was just a coincidence!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The door opens, someone enters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bodyguard #2">Bodyguard #2</speaker>
        <speech>Sir, there's someone to see you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Who told you to interrupt me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden turns angrily toward the door, but looks shocked and bows upon
                seeing who it is. Cut to show Azula standing at the door with Ty Lee behind her. All
                of the guards bow to her as well.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>I did.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut closer to Azula.</charAction> Princess Azula. <charAction>Azula and
                Ty Lee walk in.</charAction> Ah ... It is an honor to welcome you to the Fire
            Nation's most exemplary prison. <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> I didn't realize you
            were coming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks in and notices the guard sitting in the chair.</charAction> Who is
            this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to the bully guard, who looks away.</charAction> He's a guard who
            was involved in a recent and feeble escape attempt.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bully guard">Bully guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Desperately.</charAction> It wasn't me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Quiet, you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Crossing her arms.</charAction> You're wasting your time. That's not one
            of them. <charAction>Turns and starts to leave.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The warden turns and looking surprised, and confused, looks from Azula to
                the guard before looking back to Azula again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>How do you know?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles sinisterly; quietly.</charAction> Because I'm a people person.
                <charAction>Exits.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In the hall, Sokka approaches a guard in charge of the cell
                doors.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, I just got orders. Let the prisoners out into the yard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Door guard">Door guard</speaker>
        <speech>But we're in the middle of a lockdown.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, okay, I'll just go tell the warden you said that. <charAction>Walks off-screen;
                the guard raises his mask and looks at him speechless.</charAction> I'm sure he'll
            be glad to hear about you undermining his authority. <charAction>Guard grows more
                nervous. Walks back on-screen, lifting his helmet mask.</charAction> What's your
            name again?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Door guard">Door guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Starts to sweat; horrified.</charAction> Wait! Don't tell the warden.
            I'm just a little confused.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, I'm confused too, but the warden's in a bad mood, and ... irrational, so if you
            ask me, it's best not to question it, and just do what he says. <charAction>Places his
                arm around the guard's shoulder.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Door guard">Door guard</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah ... you're right. We're letting them out!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guard opens all the doors by pulling the levers. The prisoners head for
                the yard. The prisoners mingle in the yard, where Sokka, Suki, and Hakoda
                meet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This is it! We have to start a riot.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Okay. But how do we do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles smugly.</charAction> I'll show you. <charAction>Shoves a
                prisoner.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tough prisoner">Tough prisoner</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! What'd you do that for? That hurt my feelings.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Aren't you mad at me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tough prisoner">Tough prisoner</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, well, normally I would be, but I've been learning to control my anger.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This isn't working.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly, Chit Sang appears behind Sokka and puts his hand on Sokka's
                shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey you! You're lucky I didn't rat you out, <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> but my
            generosity comes with a price. I know you're planning another escape attempt, and I want
            in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets an idea.</charAction> Actually, we're trying to escape right now,
            but we need a riot. <charAction>Points to him.</charAction> You wouldn't happen to know
            how to start one, would you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>A prison riot? Please. <charAction>Grabs a prisoner and lifts him in the air,
                bouncing him up and down.</charAction> Hey! <charAction>All the prisoners look at
                him.</charAction> Riot!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The riot begins. Several blasts of fire go off.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks shocked for a moment.</charAction> Impressive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tough prisoner">Tough prisoner</speaker>
        <speech>Forget about controlling my anger ... <charAction>Raises his arms.</charAction>
            let's riot! <charAction>He is taken down by another prisoner. The riot is in full swing.
                Cut the floor of the yard as chaos and dust ensues everywhere. Cut to a prisoner
                sitting on another prisoner's shoulders, attempting to choke him. Cut to the bottom
                of a tower as various guards look down at the scene.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>Who let these prisoners into the yard? <charAction>Cut to the warden on a
                balcony.</charAction> This is supposed to be a lockdown!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The door guard, who was in charge of the control room, raises his visor and
                looks at the warden, horrified. He puts his back against the wall and sneaks away by
                quickly tip-toeing and ducks to a corner. The camera cuts back to Zuko and
                Mai.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard #2">Male guard #2</speaker>
        <speech>Ma'am, there's a riot going on! I'm here to protect you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>I don't need any protection.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gives a slight chuckle; proudly.</charAction> Believe me, she
            doesn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male guard #2">Male guard #2</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry, but I'm under direct orders from your uncle to make sure nothing happens.
                <charAction>Zuko gives a serious look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko blasts fire at the guard and starts to run toward the door. The guard
                jumps in front of Mai to shield her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Get off of me! <charAction>She throws the guard away from her and chases
                Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Exiting, Zuko closes and locks the door, trapping Mai and the guard in the
                room. He looks at Mai through the slit in the door with regret, while she stares
                back in anger, before running off to join his friends. Back in the yard, he reaches
                everyone else and slams down another guard as the riot continues.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko! Good, we're all here. Now all we need to do is grab the warden, and get to the
            gondolas!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>And how do we do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not sure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Groans.</charAction> I thought you thought this through!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I thought you told me it's okay not to think everything through!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe not everything, but this is kind of important! <charAction>Rubs his
                forehead.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, uh, fellas. I think your girlfriend's taking care of it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka peeks out and looks amazed as he sees Suki hop up on the heads of the
                rioters before jumping and flipping onto the tower. She easily defeats the first
                guard with a few quick jabs. Two more guards arrive. She ducks a fire blast and
                sweeps the first one, promptly dodges the second one's fire blast, and continues to
                climb the tower. She makes it up to the top and defeats the final guard with a
                sliding kick. She soon grabs the warden, threatening him with her fist in front of
                his face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech>You wouldn't dare.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Ties his hands together and uses his headband as a gag.</charAction>
            Sorry, warden. You're my prisoner now. <charAction>Slams the warden against the wall;
                the rest of the escapees arrive.</charAction> We've got the warden! Now let's get
            out of here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone else is out of breath.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>That's some girl.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Proudly.</charAction> Tell me about it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the roof as they all make the run to the gondola.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>We're almost there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They are stopped by guards who launch two fire blasts at them. Zuko shoves
                Sokka out of the way and blocks the two fire blasts. More guards appear to
                help.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Back off! We've got the warden! <charAction>The guards see the warden on Chit Sang's
                shoulder, bound and gagged, and clear the way.</charAction> Let's go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They continue along their path, cautiously watching the guards so they do
                not try any sudden moves. They arrive at the gondola. Suki opens the
                door.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone in!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko starts the gondola and kicks the handle a few times attempting to
                break it. He sees the guards rushing toward him and kicks the handle again and
                breaks it. He jumps toward the gondola while dodging guards fire blasts. Sokka grabs
                Zuko's hand and helps him into the gondola.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm making it so they can't stop us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Way to think ahead.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>We're on our way!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! Who's that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula and Ty Lee stand at the bottom of the gondola station. All the guards
                bow down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>That's a problem. It's my sister and her friend.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Looking up at the retreating gondola, Azula suddenly snatches a pair of
                handcuffs from a guard's belt and runs forward. Behind her, Ty Lee jumps up and onto
                the cable, running along it toward the gondola. After elevating herself to the line
                with a fire blast, Azula uses the cuffs to attach herself to the cable and propel
                herself forwaard. The occupants of the gondola watch as they approach, Suki looking
                very grim.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> This is a rematch I've been waiting
            for.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Me too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka, Suki, and Zuko climb to the top of the gondola to meet Azula and Ty
                Lee. Ty Lee flips into the air and lands in front of Suki, who growls and assumes a
                battle-ready position. Azula pulls herself up onto the roof and faces Zuko and
                Sokka. An overhead shot shows them all standing atop the gondola before closing in
                on Azula again. The Fire Nation princess assumes a battle stance and performs a
                slicing kick, sending blue fire at her opponents, but Zuko blocks it. Ty Lee and
                Suki trade blows, the latter blocking the former's attempts to use chi blocking each
                time. Ty Lee is forced to the edge but jumps into the gondola and comes out the
                other side, continuing her attacks. Zuko continues to wipe out Azula's fire blasts.
                Sokka draws her back to the edge with his sword. Zuko goes in for a finish, but
                Azula dodges Zuko's blast and stays on the gondola. She counters with a blast that
                goes wide, almost striking Suki and Ty Lee, who barely manage to dodge it.
                Meanwhile, the warden attempts to free himself while the other prisoners are
                distracted. A male guard watches from a telescope.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard">Gondola guard</speaker>
        <speech>There's the warden! I see him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden">Warden</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frees himself and runs to look out of the gondola.</charAction> Cut the
            line! <charAction>Chit Sang notices and grabs the warden.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard">Gondola guard</speaker>
        <speech>He wants us to cut the line.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard #2">Gondola guard #2</speaker>
        <speech>But if we cut the line, there's no way he'll survive!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard">Gondola guard</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puts down his telescope.</charAction> He knows that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guards stop the gondola by jamming the mechanism with metal bars; the
                wheel screeches angrily as it grinds to a halt. The gondola rocks back and forth
                from the sudden stop, disrupting the combatants from their respective duels. Losing
                his balance, Sokka slides to the edge of the gondola, but Zuko pulls him in at the
                last moment. Ty Lee jumps up to the top of the wire to see what is
                happening.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech>They're about to cut the line!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The guards work to cut the line. Azula notices another gondola approaching
                on the other wire, heading inbound.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smirks.</charAction> Then it's time to leave. <charAction>Blasts herself
                up.</charAction> Goodbye, Zuko. <charAction>Reaches the other
            gondola.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ty Lee backflips to the other gondola. When she reaches it, she looks back
                at Sokka, Suki, and Zuko with concern, in contrast to Azula's sadistic smile. The
                other three jump back into the gondola.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>They're cutting the line! The gondola's about to go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>I hope this thing floats.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pan down to the Boiling Lake. The line is almost entirely severed by now,
                but before the guards can finish the job, they are suddenly yanked away from it and
                pinned to the wall by stilettos.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard #3">Gondola guard #3</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera cuts to show Mai standing near the line.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>Saving the jerk who dumped me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Other guards try to attack Mai, but she dodges all their fire blasts and
                retaliates with her knives, pinning them all down by their wristguards. Mai rears up
                in front of a female guard, who stops in fear, and deploys four knives that send the
                two guards behind her flying, dislodging one of the bars jamming the wheel
                mechanism. She pulls out her three-pronged sai and pins down the last guard.
                Releasing the block on the line, she allows the gondola to continue in motion.
                Everyone looks back to see what happened.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Who's that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Mai continues to fight off guards and turns her head to see the
                others.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> It's Mai!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What is she doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ty Lee shrugs and makes a small sound as they watch her continue to fight
                off guards, all of whom are helpless against her. The gondola makes it to the top of
                the hill. Everyone leaves. Chit Sang holds the warden and throws him back in when
                Hakoda points at it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry, warden. Your record is officially<description> broken</description>.
                <charAction>The warden struggles against his bindings.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the others escaping over the rim of the volcano.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Well, we made it out. Now what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka turns and notices Zuko standing still.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko, what are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>My sister was on that island.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, and she's probably right behind us, so let's not stop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What I mean is she must have come here somehow. <charAction>Walks up to a large hill
                by the sea.</charAction> There! <charAction>Pan down to a large
                airship.</charAction> That's our way out of here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the prison. Mai is detained by two guards, while Azula glares at
                her. Ty Lee stands in the middle, looking terrified and concerned at the
                two.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Leave us alone. <charAction>The guards give the Fire Nation salute and exit. Mai
                raises her head a little, looking defiant.</charAction> I never expected this from
            you. <charAction>Cut to a side view of Mai, followed by a frontal shot of Ty Lee, who
                looks from one to the other, tears in her eyes, and back to Azula.</charAction> The
            thing I don't understand is "Why?". Why would you do it? You know the
            consequences.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech>I guess you just don't know people as well as you think you do. You miscalculated. I
            love Zuko more than I fear you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Her intrigued expression contorts into one of absolute
                rage.</charAction> No, you miscalculated! You should have feared me more!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula angles her fingers to create lightning, and Mai readies one of her
                stilettos, her eyes narrowed. Before Azula can complete her attack, however, she is
                struck twice by Ty Lee, who chi blocks her. Cuts to Mai, blade still in hand and
                looking very surprised, and to Azula, who dumbfoundedly falls to the ground,
                paralyzed. Ty Lee seems surprised at her own actions.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs to a shocked Mai, shaking her from her stupor.</charAction> Come
            on! Let's get out of here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Mai and Ty Lee are quickly surrounded by guards and captured before they
                can escape.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Still on the ground; angrily.</charAction> You're both fools!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula is helped up by two guards. Mai and Ty Lee are both restrained,
                looking defiantly at the princess.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Gondola guard #4">Gondola guard #4</speaker>
        <speech>What shall we do with them, princess?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Put them somewhere I'll never have to see their faces again, and let them
            rot!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Nightfall, Western Air Temple. The ship is returned. Zuko and Sokka exit,
                standing in front of Toph, Aang, and Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing in this thing? What happened to the war balloon?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>It kind of got destroyed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sounds like a crazy fishing trip.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Did you at least get some good meat?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I did. The best meat of all. The meat of friendship and fatherhood.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suki, Hakoda, and Chit Sang exit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Chit Sang">Chit Sang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waving.</charAction> I'm new. What's up, everybody?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tearing up; overjoyed.</charAction> Dad? <charAction>Runs to
                him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Hi, Katara. <charAction>They embrace.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How are you here? What is going on? Where did you go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We kind of went to a Fire Nation prison.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hakoda pulls Sokka into the embrace. The camera pans away from the
                scene.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously? You guys didn't find any meat?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
