<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Western Air Temple</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode begins with an aerial shot of Appa, still in his armor, and the
                rest of the gang, now including Haru, The Duke, and Teo, searching for the Western
                Air Temple on foot. Cut to Toph leading with Haru and Sokka behind. Cut to Aang,
                Momo on his head, walking next to Appa. Cut to Teo and The Duke. Cut to Katara,
                Sokka next to her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>This is humiliating.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking up at her.</charAction> You mean getting thoroughly spanked by
            the Fire Nation or having to walk all the way to the Western Air Temple?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at him momentarily before answering.</charAction> Both.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He pets Appa, smiling slightly.</charAction> Sorry guys, but Appa gets
            tired carrying all these people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the whole team, Toph leading the way.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Teo">Teo</speaker>
        <speech>I wonder how the rest of the troops are.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> They're probably on their way to a prison.
            Seems like my dad just got out and now he's going back in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to view of The Duke walking next to Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>I miss Pipsqueak.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I miss not having blisters on my feet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Brief view of the team from behind before we see Toph's foot stamp down.
                Cut to Toph looking up, smiling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, we're here! I can feel it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a wide panning shot of the surrounding area. A cliff edge in front
                of the gang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Uhhh ... I think your feet need their eyes checked.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang with Sokka behind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No, she's right. We are here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks around before shrugging. Cut to the front of the gang as the
                camera pans down, revealing the temple, hidden under the cliff.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Wow ... it's amazing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At another part of the temple, Zuko descends down a rope and swings back
                and forth twice before jumping down. When he lands on the ground, he has a flashback
                to three years ago, just after his banishment. Cut to a frontal shot of the cliff
                similar to the one Toph and the group were on earlier. Camera pans down to show the
                various natural structures through the mist of the temple.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>What a stunning view.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Zuko with covering over his fresh scar. Iroh stands behind
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The only view I'm interested in seeing is the Avatar in chains.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You know, the Avatar hasn't been seen for one hundred years. The chances of finding
            him here are very slim. <charAction>Cut to a shot of Zuko's bandaged
            side.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> First we'll check each of the air temples, then
            we'll scour the world, searching even the most remote locations until we find
            him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Prince Zuko, it's only been a week since your banishment. You should take some time
            to heal and rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>What else would I expect to hear from the laziest man in the Fire Nation?
                <charAction>Iroh sighs.</charAction> The only way to regain my honor is to find the
            Avatar, so I will.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh walks away as the flashback ends, fading to Zuko who looks
                disappointed in himself. Zuko notices Appa flying nearby and hides quickly. He
                subsequently runs off. Cut back to Team Avatar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Teo">Teo</speaker>
        <speech>It's so different from the Northern Air Temple. I wonder if there are any secret
            rooms.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Running off to explore.</charAction> Let's go check it out!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Teo and The Duke follow Haru. Aang tries to, but is cut off by
                Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You guys go. I think we need to talk about some things.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Teo">Teo</speaker>
        <speech>I'll race you, Duke.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>I told you, it's The Duke!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The three head off. Cut to Katara and Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Why can't I go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We need to decide what we're gonna do now, and since you're the Avatar, maybe you
            should be a part of this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting down.</charAction> Fair enough. So, what's the new
            plan?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, if you ask me, the new plan is the old plan! You just need to master all four
            elements and confront the Fire Lord before the comet comes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh, yeah. That's great, no problem. I'll
            just do that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, no one said it's going to be easy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, it's not even gonna be possible! Where am I supposed to get a firebending
            teacher?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We could look for Jeong Jeong!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shooting her idea down.</charAction> Yeah ... right. <charAction>He lays
                down on the bench without a care.</charAction> Like we'll ever run into Jeong Jeong
            again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curiously.</charAction> Who's ... oh, <charAction>She folds her arms
                irritably.</charAction> never mind. If it's important I'll find out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh well, guess we can't come up with anybody. Why don't we just take a nice tour
            around the temple? <charAction>He and Momo fly off.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What's up with him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There's gotta be someone who can teach him firebending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara and Toph look down dejectedly as the camera slowly pans up and fades
                to a smiling Zuko in a forested area with his tent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Hello ... <charAction>Raises an arm in greeting.</charAction> Zuko here, but I guess
                <charAction>Rubs his hand against the back of his head nervously.</charAction> you
            probably already know me, sort of. Uhhh ... so, the thing is I have a lot of firebending
            experience, and I'm <charAction>Places an arm on his chest with pride.</charAction>
            considered to be pretty good at it. <charAction>He continues smiling.</charAction> Well,
            you've seen me, you know, when I was attacking you. <charAction>His eyes
                widen.</charAction> Uhhh ... yeah, I guess <charAction>Places his fingers against
                his forehead in embarrassment.</charAction> I should apologize for that. But anyway,
                <charAction>Waves an arm to the side dismissively.</charAction> I'm good now.
                <charAction>Clenches both fists and places one on his chest while the other arm is
                raised.</charAction> I mean, I thought I was good before, but I realize I was bad,
                <charAction>He gets visibly uncomfortable and drops his arms into a
                slouch.</charAction> but anyway, I think it's time I joined your group and taught
                <charAction>Straightens up with a sincere expression on his face.</charAction> the
            Avatar firebending. <charAction>A badgerfrog croaks at him. Angrily.</charAction> Well,
            what's your answer? <charAction>The badgerfrog hops on his head before hopping
                away.</charAction> Yeah ... that's what I'd say, too. How am I supposed to convince
            these people that I'm on their side? What would Uncle do? <charAction>Imitating
                Iroh.</charAction> Zuko, you have to look within yourself to save yourself from your
            other self. Only then will your true self, reveal itself. <charAction>Normal
                voice.</charAction> Even when I'm talking for him I can't figure out what he means.
            What would Azula do? <charAction>Imitating Azula.</charAction> Listen, Avatar, I can
            join your group, or I can do something unspeakably horrible to you and your friends.
            Your choice. <charAction>Normal voice. Stops and sits down.</charAction> I guess I'm
            just not that good at impersonations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A badgerfrog jumps in front of him as he sits and croaks. Meanwhile, Aang
                is flying on his glider. Sokka, Katara, and Toph follow him on Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, can we talk about you learning firebending now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What? The wind is too loud in my ears! Check out this loop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang proceeds to do a loop.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, I think we should be making some plans about our future!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, we can do that while I show you the giant Pai Sho table! Oh, you're gonna love
            the all-day echo chamber!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a close up of Toph as she turns serious.</charAction> I think
            that'll have to wait.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph points behind herself, and the camera zooms out to show Team Avatar
                looking at her quizzically. Appa moves out of the way to reveal a shadow, and as the
                camera pans up, it is revealed to belong to Zuko. Cut to a close-up of the team as
                they look at him with shocked expressions, which subsequently turn into
                anger.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a close up of Zuko's face.</charAction> Hello ...
                <charAction>Raises his arm up in greeting and waves.</charAction> Zuko
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The gang prepares to attack.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, I heard you guys flying around down there, so, I just thought I'd wait for you
            here. <charAction>Appa growls at him and licks him twice. Cut to a surprised Momo and
                Aang as he lowers his staff slightly.</charAction> I know you must be surprised to
            see me here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Not really, since you've followed us all over the world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Right. Well, uhhh ... anyway ... what I wanted to tell you about is that I've
            changed, and I, uhhh, I'm good now, and well I think I should join your group, oh, and I
            can teach firebending to you. <charAction>The gang expresses shock.</charAction> See, I,
            uhhh ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You want to what now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You can't possibly think that any of us would trust you, can you? I mean, how stupid
            do you think we are?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, all you've ever done is hunt us down and try to capture Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I've done some good things! I mean, I could have stolen your bison in Ba Sing Se,
            but I set him free. That's something! <charAction>Appa licks him again, much to his
                surprise.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Appa <charAction>The siblings turn toward her.</charAction> does seem to like
            him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He probably just covered himself in honey or something so that Appa would lick him.
            I'm not buying it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I can understand why you wouldn't trust me, and I know I've made some mistakes in
            the past.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Like when you attacked our village?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Or when you stole my mother's necklace and used it to track us down and capture
            us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Look, I admit I've some awful things. I was wrong to try to capture you, and I'm
            sorry that I attacked the Water Tribe. And I never should have sent that Fire Nation
            assassin after you. <charAction>Toph and Sokka's eyes widen with shock.</charAction> I'm
            going to try and stop-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pulls out his boomerang; angrily.</charAction> Wait, you sent Combustion
            Man after us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Well, that's not his name, but-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Ohhh, sorry. I didn't mean to insult your
            friend!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> He's not my friend!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>That guy locked me and Katara in jail and tried to blow us all up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Why aren't you saying anything? You once said you
            thought we could be friends. You know I have good in me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description> Aang turns to look at his friends, and Sokka shakes his head at
                Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>There's no way we can trust you after everything you've done. We'll never let you
            join us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You need to get out of here. Now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm trying to explain that I'm not that person anymore!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Either you leave, or we attack.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>If you won't accept me as a friend, then maybe you'll take me as a prisoner.
                <charAction>Zuko kneels down, bends his head, and raises his arms in
                surrender.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, we won't! <charAction>Blasts water at him.</charAction> Get out of here, and
            don't come back! And if we ever see you again, well, we'd better not see you
            again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko walks away. Cut back to Zuko's campsite.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uggh! I can't believe how stupid I am! I mean, what was I thinking? Telling them I
            sent an assassin after them? Why didn't I just say Azula did that? They would have
            believed that! Stupid! <charAction>A badgerfrog croaks at him.</charAction>
            Uggh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the air temple.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why would he try to fool us like that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Obviously he wants to lead us into some kind of trap.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>This is just like when we were in prison together at Ba Sing Se. He starts talking
            about his mother and making it seem like he's an actual human being with
            feelings.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He wants you to trust and feel sorry for him so you let your guard down, then he
            strikes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>The thing is, it worked. I did feel sorry for him. I felt like he was really
            confused and hurt, but obviously, when the time came, he made his choice, and we paid
            the price. We can't trust him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I kind of have a confession to make. Remember when you two were sick and I got
            captured by Zhao?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And you made us suck on frozen frogs? How could I forget? I had a wart on the flap
            that hangs down from the back of my throat for a month!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, I looked at it, and I told you, there was nothing there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I could feel it! It's my throatal flap!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Anyway, when Zhao had me chained up, it was Zuko who came in and got me out. He
            risked his life to save me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No way! I'm sure he only did it so he could capture you himself!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, face it Aang, you're nothing but a big prize to him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're probably right.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>And what was all that crazy stuff about setting Appa free? What a liar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, he wasn't lying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh, hooray! In a lifetime of evil, at least
            he didn't add animal cruelty to the list.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'm just saying that, considering his messed-up family and how he was raised, he
            could have turned out a lot worse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> You're right, Toph! Let's go find him and
            give him a medal. The "not as much of a jerk as you could have been" award!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>All I know is that while he was talking to us, he was sincere. Maybe you're all just
            letting your hurt feelings keep you from thinking clearly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Easy for you to say! You weren't there when he had us attacked by pirates!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Or when he burned down Kyoshi Island!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Or when he tried to capture me at the Fire Temple!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Why would you even try to defend him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Because Katara, you're all ignoring one crucial
            fact: <charAction>Pokes Aang in the chest.</charAction> Aang needs a firebending
            teacher! We can't think of a single person in the world to do the job! Now one shows up
            on a silver platter, and you won't even think about it? <charAction>Stamps her feet on
                the ground to a point where the ground shakes slightly.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm<description> not </description>having Zuko as my teacher!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're darn right you're not, buddy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I guess that settles that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Ergh! I'm beginning to wonder who's really the blind one around here!
                <charAction>Walks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Nightfall. Zuko's campsite. Zuko is asleep when he hears
                something.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Who's there? Stay back! <charAction>Whips fire.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It's me! <charAction>Throws up an earth shield, but steps back into Zuko's fire
                blast.</charAction> Ow! You burned my feet!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry, it was a mistake! <charAction>Comes toward her, but she begins to crawl
                away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Get away from me! <charAction>As Toph crawls away, she grabs the earth under her and
                throws it backward at Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Let me help you! <charAction>Dodges another rock.</charAction> I'm sorry!
                <charAction>Tries to grab her.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Get off me, get off me! <charAction>Brings up some earth which sends Zuko flying
                back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I didn't know it was you! Uggh, come back! <charAction>Toph leaves.</charAction>
            Uggh! Why am I so bad at being good?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The next morning, Western Air Temple. Katara is serving everyone
                breakfast.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Handing a bowl to The Duke.</charAction> Has anyone seen Toph?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I haven't seen her since she stormed off yesterday.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe she's just exploring the air temple. There are some pretty fun spots to
            practice earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I think we should go look for her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting.</charAction> Let her have fun with her rocks. I'm in no rush to
            have her yelling at us again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>We can go check for her!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Teo">Teo</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Has a bandage around his forehead.</charAction> Yeah! I want to ride
            that tunnel down to the Hall of Statues again. It will work a lot better now that I
            fixed my brakes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Haru, The Duke, and Teo exit.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A large rumble occurs. Toph falls down the pile of rock that she created
                from a wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching, with Sokka and Aang. Worried.</charAction> Toph! What
            happened?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>My feet got burned!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Oh no, what happened?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I just told you, my feet got burned!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I meant, how.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I kind of went to see Zuko last night. <charAction>Everyone is
                shocked.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Uhhh ...!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I thought he could be helpful to us. <charAction>Katara begins to try and heal her
                feet.</charAction> And if I talked to him, maybe we could work something
            out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So he attacked you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Well, he did, and he didn't. It was sort of an accident.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But he did firebend at you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Yes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>See? You trusted Zuko, and you got burned. Literally!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's gonna take a while for your feet to get better. <charAction>Stops
                healing.</charAction> I wish I could have worked on them sooner.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, me too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko's clearly too dangerous to be left alone. We're gonna have to go after
            him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I hate to go looking for a fight, but you're right. After what he did to Toph, I
            don't think we have a choice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He's crafty, but we'll find a way to capture him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe just invite him back here. <charAction>Aang and Sokka go to pick her
                up.</charAction> He's already offered himself up as a prisoner once.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, get him to come back and say he'll be our prisoner, then we'll jump him and
            really make him our prisoner. He'll never suspect it! <charAction>Aang and Sokka carry
                Toph away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Following. Sarcastically.</charAction> You are a master of surprise,
            Sokka ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Toph's feet as they are dipped into a fountain.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Ahhh, that's the stuff. Now I know how the rest of you guys feel. Not being able to
            see with your feet stinks. <charAction>Katara sits next to her putting a hand on her
                shoulder.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, Combustion Man eyes the gang from a higher elevation. He sets
                his sights on Aang. As he prepares to fire, however, Zuko jumps in and knocks him
                off-balance, causing his shot to be wild. Team Avatar make to run away before
                hearing Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Stop! <charAction>Team Avatar turns their head up to the sound.</charAction> I don't
            want you hunting the Avatar anymore! <charAction>Cut to a quick close up of Aang looking
                up with shock as he is helping Sokka carry Toph. Cut back to Zuko as he stands in
                front of Combustion Man, arms spread out to block him.</charAction> The mission is
            off. I'm ordering you to stop.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Combustion Man shoves him away and attacks again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>If you keep attacking, I won't pay you! <charAction>Attempts to firebend at him, but
                Combustion Man grabs him.</charAction> All right, I'll pay you double to
            stop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko kicks Combustion Man as he fires, causing him to miss again. He
                subsequently takes aim at Zuko. Zuko creates a firewall to stop the attack but is
                pushed off the ledge. Cut to a shot of Team Avatar looking over the edge of the
                fountain shocked. Cut to a shot from behind Combustion Man as he faces a small
                crater in the floor and the smoke that is dissipating. Cut to a shot of the edge of
                the ledge and strafe right, revealing climbing a vine hanging underneath it and Zuko
                survived by grabbing the plant's root. Cut to Combustion Man as he turns back. Cut
                to a close up of Aang as he stands up from behind the fountain pool and runs to the
                side. Cut to a shot of Aang doing a spinning back kick, airbending and kicking up
                the dust around him, and leaping straight up just as a blast from Combustion Man
                explodes beneath him. The camera turns up to Aang spinning in mid air, airbending a
                tornado and kicking it at Combustion Man. Combustion Man leaps over the tornado and
                fires another blast as he descends. Aang lands and quickly back flips away from the
                blast, landing next to Katara and Sokka. Cut to a shot of Combustion Man falling
                before switching to a shot of his metal, clawed hand as it catches on a small ledge
                and breaks it, slowing his fall. He lands on a new ledge and rolls, firing a blast
                just as he stops. Cut to a shot of Katara and Aang shielding themselves as the blast
                hits the fountain water. The camera follows Katara as she runs forward and bends the
                water from the pool. Cut to a far shot from the side as Katara bends a huge wave up
                between them and Combustion Man. Cut to a shot in front of the camera as she
                descends from jumping, bringing her arms down and crossing them and giving a battle
                cry. The wave matches her arm movements and icicles in both directions. Cut to a
                shot of Combustion Man as the icicles speed toward him. He brings his metal arm over
                his face and lifts his metal leg to shield him from the attack. The icicles break
                against him. Combustion Man flings his arms down to shake off the ice shards and
                steps forward, an angry frown on his face. Cut to his perspective as he scans the
                area. The group is nowhere to be seen. Aang fires a tornado, which the assassin
                jumps over and fires again. Aang narrowly avoids the blast by jumping back.
                Combustion man falls and lands on a ledge as he fires and misses again. Katara bends
                water from the fountain and turns it into ice spikes, but Combustion Man appears
                unaffected. The assassin looks up and realizes they have disappeared but continues
                firing. Cut to shot of the team hiding behind a wall, out of sight.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>He's going to blast this whole place right off the cliff side!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara looks out from behind the wall only to see another incoming
                blast.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can't step out to waterbend at him without being blown up and I can't get a good
            enough angle on him from down here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pausing for a moment to think before having an idea.</charAction> I know
            how to get an angle on him! <charAction>Takes out his boomerang. After another blast, he
                sneaks his head out, but has to hide from another shot. He projects Combustion Man's
                angle with his boomerang.</charAction> All right buddy, don't fail me now!
                <charAction>Throws his boomerang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The boomerang hits the assassin in the head where his third eye tattoo is,
                causing him to hit the ground, before it returns back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, boomerang! <charAction>Jumps up and grabs it, but Combustion Man gets up,
                albeit clearly shaken.</charAction> Awww, boomerang ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As the team runs back to their hiding spot, Combustion Man gears up again,
                but is dizzy and cannot aim properly. His next shot fails to escape, causing an
                explosion around him resulting in the building he stands on getting destroyed. Cut
                to his metal arm as it flies away from the explosion, followed by the falling
                building. The gang looks on, shocked. Haru, Teo, and The Duke all appear from behind
                a pillar also shocked.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko climbs a plant root, having survived the ordeal. Later, Zuko again
                approaches the gang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe I'm saying this, but ... thanks, Zuko.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, what about me? I did the boomerang thing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Listen, I know I didn't explain myself very well yesterday, I've been through a lot
            in the last few years, and it's been hard. But I'm realizing that I had to go through
            all those things to learn the truth. I thought I had lost my honor, and that somehow my
            father could return it to me. But I know now that no one can give you your honor. It's
            something you earn for yourself, by choosing to do what's right. All I want to do now is
            play my part in ending this war, and I know my destiny is to help you restore balance to
            the world. <charAction>To Toph.</charAction> I'm sorry for what I did to you.
                <charAction>Bows to her.</charAction> It was an accident. Fire can be dangerous and
            wild, so as a firebender, I need to be more careful and control my bending, so I don't
            hurt people unintentionally.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks at Zuko shocked, hearing these words, and thinks for a
                moment.</charAction> I think you are supposed to be my firebending teacher. When I
            first tried to learn firebending, I burned Katara, and after that, I never wanted to
            firebend again. But now I know you understand how easy it is to hurt the people you
            love. I'd like you to teach me. <charAction>Bows before Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bows.</charAction> Thank you. I'm so happy you've accepted me into your
            group.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Not so fast. I still have to ask my friends if it's okay with them. <charAction>To
                Toph.</charAction> Toph, you're the one that Zuko burned. What do you
            think?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Go ahead and let him join. <charAction>Pounds her fist into her palm
                jokingly.</charAction> It'll give me plenty of time to get back at him for burning
            my feet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to Sokka.</charAction> Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugging.</charAction> Hey, all I want is to defeat the Fire Lord. If
            you think this is the way to do it, then, I'm all for it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Katara.</charAction> Katara?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Glares at Zuko for a moment and Zuko starts to sweat;
                reluctantly.</charAction> I'll go along with whatever you think is right.
                <charAction>Aang smiles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly approaching the group.</charAction> I won't let you down! I
            promise!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang, Katara, and Sokka exit, the latter carrying Toph. Later, Sokka shows
                Zuko to his room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So, here you go, home sweet home, I guess, you know, for now. Unpack? Lunch, soon?
            Uhhh ... welcome aboard? <charAction>Zuko glances back and smiles at him.</charAction>
            Yeah. <charAction>Walks out of the room and meets Aang in the hallway; to
                Aang.</charAction> Okay, this is really, really weird.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two exit. Cut to Zuko as he pulls out a painting of Iroh. He
                subsequently has another flashback to three years ago.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>If I have to, I will spend every day of the rest of my life hunting the Avatar. I
            know it's my destiny to capture him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Placing a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> You know Prince Zuko,
            destiny is a funny thing. You never know how things are going to work out. But if you
            keep an open mind, and an open heart, I promise you will find your own destiny
            someday.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to Zuko in the present, smiling at the memory. Zuko suddenly notices a
                clearly disgruntled Katara at the door.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You might have everyone else here buying your ... transformation, but you and I both
            know you've struggled with doing the right thing in the past. <charAction>Approaches
                him; threateningly.</charAction> So let me tell you something, right now. You make
            one step backward, <charAction>Close-up of Zuko.</charAction> one slip-up, give me one
            reason to think you might hurt Aang, and you won't have to worry about your destiny
            anymore. <charAction>Close-up of Katara's angry face.</charAction> Because I'll make
            sure your destiny ends ... right then and there. Permanently.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She walks away and slams the door shut. Zuko slumps his
                shoulders.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
