<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Library</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode begins with a view of the mountains. The camera pans down to
                show a back shot of Aang sitting in cross legged in a prairie on the ground looking
                over a vast open savanna landscape. The landscape is mostly barren save for small
                shoots of grass which bend in the breeze. A range of mountains can be seen in the
                distance. The ground in front of Aang is littered with holes.</description>
            <description>Cut to a shot of the group from the front of Appa, Sokka, Toph, Katara, and
                Momo standing behind Aang. The Avatar is holding a thin wooden flute in both
                hands.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What's out here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Shot changes to show Appa, Sokka, Toph, Katara, and Momo standing behind
                Aang, who holds a flute.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puts her hand on the ground.</charAction> A lot, actually. There's
            hundreds of little ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns around and silences Toph.</charAction> Shh! I know you can see
            underground, but don't ruin the surprise. Just watch. <charAction>Blows a note on the
                flute. A groundhog-type creature pops out of a hole in the ground and mimics the
                note.</charAction> Yeah! <charAction>Plays another note and another groundhog mimics
                it.</charAction> I'm putting an orchestra together.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Makes hand motions while looking on with annoyance.</charAction>
            Orchestra, huh? Well, la-di-da.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Three groundhogs pop out of the ground and sing descending notes. Momo
                jumps into a hole and comes out the middle one, trying to catch the groundhogs. The
                shot shows all of the holes in the ground. Aang plays four notes and Momo tries to
                catch the groundhogs that pop up. Katara giggles as she watches the amusing sight.
                Aang plays another note as Sokka runs up to Aang and plugs the flute with his
                finger, causing nothing to play. As Aang's cheeks swell with air, the Avatar looks
                at Sokka with a sad expression.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> This is great and all, but don't we have more
            important things to worry about? We should be making plans.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>We did make plans. We're all picking mini-vacations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There's no time for vacations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm learning the elements as fast as I can. I practice hard every day with Toph and
            Katara. I've been training my arrow off!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks next to Aang.</charAction> Yeah, what's wrong with having a little
            fun in our down time?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Even if you do master all of the elements, then what? It's not like we have a map of
            the Fire Nation. <charAction>Gestures to the side, sarcastically.</charAction> Should we
            just head west until we reach the Fire Lord's house? <charAction>Knocking on an
                imaginary door.</charAction> Knock, knock. Hello, Fire Lord? Anybody home? I don't
            think so. We need some intelligence if we're going to win this war.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang plays a note on the flute and a groundhog pops up underneath Sokka and
                sings the note.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Giggles.</charAction> All right, we'll finish our vacations and
                <charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> then we'll look for Sokka's intelligence.
                <charAction>Aang laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opening a map and shows it to Katara.</charAction> Your turn, Katara.
            Where would you like to go on your mini-vacation?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing at the map.</charAction> How about the Misty Palms Oasis? That
            sounds refreshing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, yeah, I've been there. It's a pristine natural ice spring. And I usually don't
            use the word "pristine". <charAction>Cut to the symbol on the map.</charAction> It's one
            of nature's wonders.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The close-up of the map's illustration fades to the Misty Palm Oasis, which
                has a small ice spring in the center. Cut to a shot of Aang, Katara, Sokka, and Toph
                stare at the oasis in disappointment.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Must've changed ownership since I was here. <charAction>Laughs
                sheepishly.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They walk through the entrance and the hanging sign falls down. Fade to
                Team Avatar walking past the small ice spring. They walk into the bar and pass five
                sandbenders hanging around outside. One sandbender spits at Sokka's feet. Sokka
                looks at the man angrily. The man utters a raspy groan, slurps, and chuckles. Katara
                grabs Sokka and pulls him into the bar, which is filled with weary
                travelers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To the bartender.</charAction> One mango, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The bartender uses two swords to slice a bowl from a large chunk of ice. He
                cuts down some mangos from the overhanging fruit and dices them up. He chops up a
                piece of fruit and pours a jug of milk into the bowl, still using the swords. He
                throws a decorative umbrella and straw into the bowl and serves it to Zei, who gives
                the bartender a coin.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I don't see anything wrong with having one of those fruity beverages while we plan
            our strategy. <charAction>Runs up to the bartender.</charAction> Excuse me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zei bumps into Aang and spills his drink onto the airbender.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No worries, I clean up easy. <charAction>Airbends the drink off of his
                clothes.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gasps.</charAction> You're a living relic.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugs.</charAction> Thanks, I try.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>An Air Nomad, right in front of me. <charAction>Shot changes to show Katara holding
                an icy bowl.</charAction> Professor Zei, head of anthropology at Ba Sing Se
            University. <charAction>Grabs Aang's arm and points at his arrow tattoo. Camera pans to
                Aang's face.</charAction> Tell me, which of the air temples do you hail
            from?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The Southern Temple.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Measures Aang's head with a pair of calipers and speaking
                excitedly.</charAction> Oh, splendid! Now tell me- what was the primary agricultural
            product of your people?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Uh, are fruit pies an agricultural
            product?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, truly fascinating. That is one for the journal. <charAction>While Sokka speaks,
                Zei writes in his journal.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So Professor, you're obviously a well-traveled guy. Do you have a more current map?
            Ours seems to be a little dated.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Certainly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka unrolls a map on a table and examines. Toph sips her drink and props
                her legs on another chair.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What, no Fire Nation? <charAction>Straightening his back.</charAction> Doesn't
            anybody have a good map of that place?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Examines the map while the camera pans across it.</charAction> You've
            made a lot of trips into the desert.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>All in vain, I'm afraid. I've found lost civilizations all over the Earth Kingdom,
                <charAction>Raises his fist slightly.</charAction> but I haven't managed to find the
            crown jewel: Wan Shi Tong's Library. <charAction>Cut to a shot of Toph laying down. Her
                feet are closest to the camera, showing her dirt-stained
            soles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In disbelief.</charAction> You spent years walking through the desert to
            find some guy's library?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>This library is more valuable than gold, little lady. It is said to contain a vast
            collection of knowledge, and knowledge is priceless.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Hmm, sounds like good times.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, it is. According to legend, it was built by the great Knowledge Spirit, Wan Shi
            Tong, with the help of his "foxy" knowledge seekers.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Intrigued.</charAction> Oh, so this spirit has attractive assistants,
            huh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puts her hand on the side of Sokka's face to stop him from
                talking.</charAction> I think he means they look like actual foxes, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>You're both right. <charAction>Katara and Sokka turn to him in surprise. Cut to
                Zei.</charAction> Handsome little creatures. <charAction>Takes out a drawing of the
                library and places it on the table.</charAction> Wan Shi Tong and his knowledge
            seekers collected books from all over the world, and put them on display for mankind to
            read, so that we might better ourselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>If this place has books from all over the world, <charAction>Aang walks over to look
                at the maps while he sips his drink.</charAction> do you think they've got info on
            the Fire Nation? A map, maybe?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>I wouldn't know. But if such a thing exists, it's in Wan Shi Tong's
            Library.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Then it's settled. Aang, I do believe it's my turn. I'd like to spend my vacation
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of Sokka as he points his finger into the air
                dramatically. The background changes to a rushing one.</charAction> at the library!
                <charAction>Sokka's voice echoes. Zoom back to a group shot, with Sokka still having
                his finger raised in the air.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waving her hand to gain the others attention.</charAction> Uh, hey, what
            about me? When do I get to pick?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You gotta work here a little longer before you qualify for vacation time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hmph! <charAction>Slams her drink on the table and folds her arms. Cut to a shot of
                Zei.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Of course, there's the matter of finding it. I've made several trips into the Si
            Wong Desert and almost died each time. <charAction>In a depressed voice.</charAction>
            I'm afraid that desert's impossible to cross.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Professor, would you like to see our sky bison?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>A sky bison?! You actually have one?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Appa retreating from four sandbenders, as he growls.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs toward the sandbenders.</charAction> Sandbenders, shoo, away from
            the bison!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sandbenders run away and get into two sand-sailers. They drive the
                sailers by creating a small tornado of sand near the sail. Cut to a ground view of
                Appa flying across the sky. Cut to Appa's saddle and pan from Katara and Toph
                leaning against the sides to Sokka who grabs a telescope and looks over the side.
                The shot changes to Momo, Zei, and Aang on Appa's head. Zei leans over Appa's
                head.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Tell me, sky bison, are you the last of your breed? <charAction>Appa growls and Zei
                responds enthusiastically.</charAction> Delightful! I only wish I spoke his tongue.
                <charAction>Scratches Appa's head.</charAction> Oh, the stories this beast could
            tell. <charAction>Momo crawls up to Zei's side and starts chittering.</charAction>
            Shush, chatty monkey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Examines the picture of the library.</charAction> Wow, shouldn't be too
            hard to find a place like this out here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa flies away from the camera. Cut back to the saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Groans in frustration.</charAction> Does this place even exist?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Some say it doesn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eyes widen in surprise before narrowing.</charAction> Shouldn't you have
            mentioned that before? <charAction>Collapses on the saddle, putting her feet over the
                side.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an aerial view of Appa flying. Cut to Zei, who writes in his journal
                and pans to Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing over the side of the saddle with excitement.</charAction> There
            it is! <charAction>Everybody on Appa looks to where Toph is pointing, but they can only
                see sand dunes. Aang, Katara, and Sokka glare at Toph in annoyance for tricking
                them. Cut back to the shot of Toph.</charAction> That's what it will sound like when
            one of you spots it. <charAction>Waves her hand in front of her face with a blank grin
                to remind them of the fact that she is blind. She quickly goes back to clutching the
                saddle.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Appa flying and shows a closer shot of Aang driving Appa while Momo
                sleeps on Aang's head. Sokka and Katara search for the library on Appa's
                saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It shouldn't be this hard to spot a giant, ornate building from the air.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks through his telescope and spots a tower. Pointing.</charAction>
            Down there, what's that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo wakes up. Cut to the tower and Appa flies down next to
                it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holding the illustrations.</charAction> Forget it. It's obviously not
            what we're looking for. <charAction>Side shot.</charAction> The building in this drawing
            is enormous.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They see a sparkle in the distance and a fox holding a scroll with its
                mouth walking over a dune.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Zei.</charAction> What kind of animal is that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The fox runs up the tower. Shot changes to a window at the top of the tower
                through which the fox enters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>I think that was one of the Knowledge Seekers. <charAction>Frontal
                shot.</charAction> Oh, we must be close to the library!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at the illustration Katara is holding.</charAction> No, this is
            the library- look! <charAction>Camera pans down from the tower to the
                illustration.</charAction> It's completely buried.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a zoom out shot of the spire from far away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Further shot of the top of library. The camera pans up from the sand to the
                top of the library.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shouting dramatically.</charAction> The library is buried?!
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of the group standing in front of the spire. Zei runs
                forward. Depressed.</charAction> My life's ambition is now full of sand.
                <charAction>Collapses. Smiling, he lifts his head and reveals a small shovel in
                hand. Excitedly.</charAction> Well, time to start excavating. <charAction>He
                attempts to unearth the library using the tiny shovel. Cut to a close-up of the
                spire's surface as Toph places her palm against it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut a small part of the library which Toph puts her hand
                on.</charAction> Actually, that won't be necessary. The inside seems to be
            completely intact. <charAction>Aerial shot.</charAction> And it's huge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That fox thingy went in through a window. I say we climb up there and give it a
            look.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I say you guys go ahead without me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You got something against libraries?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I've held books before. And I gotta tell you, they don't exactly do it for
            me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> Oh, right. Sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Let me know if they have something you can listen to.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the window at the top of the tower. A boomerang with a rope tied to
                it is thrown into the window. At the bottom of the tower, Sokka starts scaling the
                rope and the camera pans to Aang, Appa, and Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Appa.</charAction> Don't worry, buddy. I'm not making you go
            underground ever again. You can stay out here with Toph. <charAction>Walks off
                camera.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa makes a low, rumbling growl.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> What's up?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to overhead shot Katara, Sokka, Aang, and Zei scaling the rope inside
                the library. The shot changes to a closer view as Zei, Aang, Sokka, and Katara climb
                down and Momo flies down. The shot changes to show the library's ceiling
                dome.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, it's breathtaking! <charAction>Shot changes to show Zei, Aang, and Sokka climb
                down the rope with owl arches in the background.</charAction> The spirit spared no
            expense in designing this place. <charAction>Pointing.</charAction> Look at those
            beautiful buttresses! <charAction>Cut to an above shot of Sokka, Aang, and Zei, who are
                hanging from the rope. Sokka and Aang giggle at the word.</charAction> What's
            funny?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Nothing. We just like architecture.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut back to a smiling Zei.</charAction> As do I.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They slide off the rope onto a bridge and Momo lands on Aang's
                shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>My word! <charAction>Examines an owl mosaic above two pillars.</charAction> The
            exquisite mosaic handiwork of this tile-rendered avian symbol ... <charAction>Sokka,
                Katara, and Aang look at Zei quizzically.</charAction> Eh, nice owl.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They hear rustling noises. Sokka and Katara run behind a pillar. Aang grabs
                Zei and they hide behind another pillar. Wan Shi Tong, an owl spirit, walks over the
                bridge and examines the rope. Aang cranes his head around the pillar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns his head around.</charAction> I know you're back there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang gasps and hides again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiles and walks from behind the pillar and up to Wan Shi
                Tong.</charAction> Hello, I'm Professor Zei, head of anthropology at Ba Sing Se
            University.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>You should leave the way you came. <charAction>Looks to the side.</charAction>
            Unless you want to become a stuffed head of anthropology.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans to three stuffed animal heads on a pillar. Frontal shot of
                Zei, as he moans and clutches his neck. Katara, Sokka, and Aang walk out from behind
                their pillars and up to Wan Shi Tong.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Are you the spirit who brought this library to the physical world?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>Indeed, I am Wan Shi Tong, "He Who Knows Ten Thousand Things." And you are obviously
            humans, which, by the way, are no longer permitted in my study.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What do you have against humans?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>Hm! Humans only bother learning things to get the edge on other humans.
                <charAction>Cut to Zhao, studying scrolls in the library. Voice-over.</charAction>
            Like that firebender who came to this place a few years ago, looking to destroy his
            enemy. <charAction>Scene changes to the present.</charAction> So ... <charAction>Leans
                toward a sweating Sokka.</charAction> who are you trying to destroy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to his reflection in Wan Shi Tong's eye.</charAction> What?
            No-no-no-no destroying. We're not into that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Blinks.</charAction> Then why have you come here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Um ... knowledge for knowledge's sake?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shot changes to him leaning toward Sokka.</charAction> If you're going
            to lie to an all-knowing spirit being, you should at least put some effort into
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not lying, I'm here with the Avatar, <charAction>Grabs Aang and puts him into
                the shot.</charAction> and he's the bridge between our worlds. He'll vouch for me.
                <charAction>Nudges Aang.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Ow. <charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> Uh, yeah, I'll vouch. We will not abuse
            the knowledge in your library, good spirit. <charAction>Side shot.</charAction> You have
            my word. <charAction>They bow to Wan Shi Tong.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>Hmm, very well. I'll let you peruse my vast collection <charAction>Shot changes to
                Zei, Aang, Katara, and Sokka looking hopefully.</charAction> on one condition.
                <charAction>They look at the spirit a little worriedly. Further overhead
                shot.</charAction> To prove your worth as scholars, you have to contribute some
            worthwhile knowledge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks up to Wan Shi Tong holding a book and kneels down.</charAction>
            Please accept this tome as a donation to your library.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> First edition, very nice. <charAction>Grabs
                the book with his wing.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera pans up to show her holding the waterbending scroll.</charAction>
            I have an authentic waterbending scroll.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> Ooh, these illustrations are quite stylish.
                <charAction>Grabs the scroll.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to him.</charAction> Uh ... oh, I know! <charAction>Grabs his wanted
                poster out of his shirt and shows it to Wan Shi Tong.</charAction> Hah!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>I suppose that counts. <charAction>Takes the poster.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Side shot of him walking forward.</charAction> Oh, great spirit,
                <charAction>Frontal shot of him holding a piece of string.</charAction> check this
            out. <charAction>Ties the string into a butterfly knot and shows it to Wan Shi
                Tong.</charAction> Ta-da! <charAction>Aang, Katara, and Zei look at Sokka with
                uncertainty. Shot of Wan Shi Tong just looking at him in silence.</charAction> It's
            a special knot. That counts as knowledge!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> You're not very bright, are you?
                <charAction>Sokka grunts as Wan Shi Tong takes the knot.</charAction> Enjoy the
            library. <charAction>Jumps off the bridge and flies down to lower levels of the
                library.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Team Avatar and Zei walk toward the library.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Narrows his eyes.</charAction> Bright enough to fool you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to an overhead view of the desert outside the library, where Appa and
                Toph rest in the shade. The shot changes to a closer view of Appa and
                Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Appa.</charAction> So ... you like ... flying? <charAction>Appa purrs
                deeply and scratches his ear.</charAction> Of course, I'm more comfortable on the
            ground where I can see. Well, I don't see the way you do. I feel the vibrations in the
            ground with my feet. <charAction>Closer shot of the two. Toph picks up a handful of sand
                and lets it fall.</charAction> But this sand is so loose and shifty, it makes
            everything look fuzzy. <charAction>Appa makes a rumbling groan with a further
                shot.</charAction> Not that there's anything wrong with fuzzy. <charAction>Appa
                grunts.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a large room full of books and the camera pans down to show the
                Knowledge Seeker, Team Avatar, and Zei at a bookshelf. In a closer shot, the
                Knowledge Seeker deposits its scroll on a shelf and the camera pans to the right to
                Team Avatar and Zei. Closer shot of Aang, as he flips a page on his book. He finds
                an illustration of a person talking to a lion turtle with two more lion turtles in
                the background.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holds the illustration up to show Sokka and Katara.</charAction> Hey,
            look at these weird lion turtle things.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pulls a book off the bookshelf with the symbols 子白 on the
                cover.</charAction> Eh, I've seen weirder.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks up to Aang, carrying a book.</charAction> Aang, did you know in a
            past life, you were left-handed?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I always knew I was special.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Sokka and Zei. While Zei takes books off of bookshelves and adds
                them to his stack, Sokka takes a scroll from a shelf, reads it, and puts it in his
                purse. Back shot of Sokka walking up to a podium. He sees the burnt piece of
                parchment framed on the podium with the characters 培治龍年七月九日烈火國最黑暗的一天.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reading from the parchment.</charAction> "The darkest day in Fire Nation
            history." It's got a date at the top, but it doesn't say anything else. <charAction>He
                looks around, making sure no one is watching, before prying open the frame with his
                sword and taking the parchment.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks in with Katara and Zei.</charAction> Sokka, where are you
            going?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Running down a section of a library.</charAction> I want to know what
            happened to the Fire Nation on their darkest day. This could be promising.
                <charAction>Aang, Katara, and Zei follow him.</charAction> The information on the
            Fire Nation should be right up here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at a room full of ashes.</charAction> Firebenders.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>They destroyed everything having to do with the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's so unfair! Just when I think I'm one step ahead of the Fire Nation, it turns
            out they beat us here a long time ago. <charAction>Collapses on his knees.</charAction>
            I need to know what happened on the darkest day. <charAction>Hears whimpering and looks
                at the entrance to see the Knowledge Seeker standing on its hind legs.</charAction>
            Hello, little weird fox guy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Knowledge Seeker gets on its four legs and points outside the
                room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>Seems it's trying to assist you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Um, sure, I guess I'll follow you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They follow the Knowledge Seeker to a large round door with a texture
                lining the bottom sides of the wall. The Knowledge Seeker enters a small door in the
                texture. The large door opens showing the Knowledge Seeker standing behind it. Team
                Avatar and Zei walk toward the center of the room. The Knowledge Seeker pushes a
                lever beside the calendar wheel and the domed ceiling changes from day to
                night.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech>This room is a true marvel, a mechanical wonder. It's a planetarium that shows the
            heavens moving.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The domed ceiling changes back into day.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Uh, this is beautiful, but how is it helpful?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe these dials represent dates and times. Sokka, try entering that date from that
            parchment you took.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mock whispering.</charAction> Shh, Katara, not in front of the fox, he's
            with the owl.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Knowledge Seeker whimpers. Sokka glances at the parchment and changes
                four of the calendar wheels. He pushes the lever and the domed ceiling changes from
                day to night.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, I got to hand it to you, Sokka. You picked the best mini-vacation for
            sure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The ceiling changes from night to day and the planetarium suddenly grows
                dark.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, wait. What happened to the sun?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Narrows his eyes.</charAction> Great, you must have broken it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks next to Aang.</charAction> It's not broken. <charAction>Shot
                changes to show the sun piece of the planetarium covered by the moon
                piece.</charAction> The sun is behind the moon. It's a solar eclipse! It's literally
            the darkest day in Fire Nation history. Now I get it. <charAction>Grabs Aang's shoulders
                and shakes him.</charAction> Something awful happened on that day. I don't know
            what, but I do know why. Firebenders lose their bending during a solar eclipse.
                <charAction>Pushes Aang back.</charAction> Sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That makes sense. I mean, think what the lunar eclipse at the North Pole did to the
            waterbenders. This is huge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Knowledge Seeker gets on its hind legs and begs.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To the Knowledge Seeker.</charAction> Fine, you earned it.
                <charAction>Tosses the fox a snack from his bag. To Aang and Katara.</charAction>
            We've gotta get this information to the Earth King at Ba Sing Se. We'll wait for the
            next eclipse, then we'll invade the Fire Nation when they're totally helpless. The Fire
            Lord is going down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enters the shot from behind Sokka.</charAction> Mortals are so
            predictable, and such terrible liars. <charAction>Sokka gulps. Shot changes to show Wan
                Shi Tong talking to them from the entrance.</charAction> You betrayed my trust. From
            the beginning, you intended to misuse this knowledge for evil purposes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You don't understand. If anyone's evil, it's the Fire Nation. You saw what they did
            to your library. They're destructive and dangerous. We need this information.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>You think you're the first person to believe their war was justified? Countless
            others before you have come here seeking weapons or weaknesses or battle
            strategies.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We had no choice. Please, we're just desperate to protect the people we
            love.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>And now I'm going to protect what I love. <charAction>Flaps his wings and the
                library starts shaking.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>I'm taking my knowledge back. No one will ever abuse it again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sand pours from the ceiling.</charAction> He's sinking the building.
            We've gotta get out of here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>I'm afraid I can't allow that. You already know too much. <charAction>Pecks at them,
                but misses.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Wan Shi Tong pursues them as they run out the planetarium. The camera pans
                up to the surface. Appa snarls as the library starts sinking and the ground starts
                shaking.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I already told you, I don't wanna snuggle. <charAction>Appa stands up and hurries
                away from the library. Toph looks at the sinking library.</charAction> Library
            sinking. <charAction>Running up to the library.</charAction> Library sinking!
                <charAction>Punches both fists into the library to stop it from sinking. Her feet
                slip in the sand, so she pauses to solidify it.</charAction> Hi-yah!
                <charAction>Struggles to stop it from sinking again.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans down to an aerial view of Team Avatar and Zei running
                through the library. They round a corner, and Wan Shi Tong continues pursuing
                them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops running and turns back toward Wan Shi Tong.</charAction> Great
            Knowledge Spirit, I beg you, do not destroy your vast collection of priceless
            tomes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang uses air suction to move Zei out of Wan Shi Tong's attack. Aang fires
                an air blast at Wan Shi Tong, sending the spirit falling off the side of the
                bridge.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs back to Katara, Zei, and Sokka.</charAction> We've gotta get back
            to the surface!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, let's go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But we still don't know when the next eclipse is gonna to happen.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Don't be stupid! We'll find out later!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, we won't. If we leave this place, we'll never get the information. Aang, come
            with me to the planetarium, <charAction>Aang runs up to him.</charAction> I need cover.
            Katara, take Momo and get out of here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But ...!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Wan Shi Tong breaks in between the two groups and pursues Katara and
                Zei.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hurry, Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka and Aang run away. Zei evades Wan Shi Tong by diving into a smaller
                aisle of books. He grabs a book, looking at the cover excitedly. Katara runs and Wan
                Shi Tong swoops down. Cut to the surface with Toph holding up the library. Appa
                grunts nervously.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What is it now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to three sand-sailers. The camera pans across a sandbender's face and
                cuts to a side shot of the sailer. The sandbenders direct a sand blast at
                Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Struggling.</charAction> Who's there?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sand-sailers circle Appa and a sandbender jumps out. Cut to inside the
                library, where Sokka and Aang run across a bridge and reach the entrance to the
                planetarium.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Why are we doing this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Because if this calendar can tell us about eclipses in the past, then maybe it can
            project when the next one will be.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You can't possibly check every single date.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Adjusting the calendar wheel.</charAction> I don't have to. We just need
            to check every date before Sozin's Comet arrives. Because after that- well, try not to
            think about that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka finishes adjusting the wheels and Aang pushes the lever. The camera
                fades from the moon traveling across the ceiling to Sokka adjusting the wheel
                calendar, before switching to the ceiling changing from night to day. The camera
                fades to Aang looking at the night sky to the moon traveling across the ceiling, to
                the calendar wheel, to Sokka adjusting the wheel, to the sun and moon traveling
                close to each other, to Sokka trying again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pushing the lever.</charAction> Come on, eclipse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the moon and sun traveling across the ceiling until the moon
                overlaps with the sun.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's it! The solar eclipse! It's just a few months away. <charAction>Takes out a
                piece of paper and writes down the date.</charAction> Got it. Now, let's get to Ba
            Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They run out of the planetarium. Cut to Appa surrounded by sandbenders
                yielding weighted ropes. They throw the ropes over Appa and solidify the sand near
                their feet to bring Appa down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Don't make me put this down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph lets go of the library and earthbends a slice of sand at the
                sandbenders, but misses. She grabs the library again. Cut to a tied up Appa as the
                sand-sailers drag him away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>No! Stop sinking! <charAction>Fires three more slices of sand.</charAction> No!
                <charAction>Grabs the library.</charAction> I'm sorry, Appa. <charAction>Closes her
                eyes as the camera pans to show the sand-sailers dragging Appa
            away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Katara running away from Wan Shi Tong. She stops beside a bookshelf,
                holding Momo. Wan Shi Tong walks on the other side of the bookshelf and spots Momo's
                tail.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>At least I'll have one specimen to add to my collection.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Wan Shi Tong tries to grab Momo with his beak, but Katara runs away with
                Momo. She reaches the bridge with the rope and turns back to face Wan Shi
                Tong.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Wan Shi Tong">Wan Shi Tong</speaker>
        <speech>Your waterbending won't do you much good here. <charAction>Raises his head and
                unfolds his wings to attack.</charAction> I've studied Northern water style,
            Southern water style, even Foggy Swamp style.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a view of the ceiling. Aang flies his glider holding Sokka, who
                jumps off holding a book, yelling. Sokka slams the book onto Wan Shi Tong's head,
                knocking him out.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's called Sokka style. <charAction>Swings his fist to the side as he says
                this.</charAction> Learn it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Pan up to a shot of the hole in the ceiling where the rope is dangling.
                Light from the outside is pouring down. Cut to a shot from the side of Sokka,
                Katara, and Momo, and the defeated spirit lying unconscious on the bridge. More
                streams of sand pour in from above. Sokka and Katara climb over Wan Shi Tong and up
                the rope. Aang glides past them. Cut to a close shot of Sokka climbing the rope. He
                stops and looks back down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! Professor, let's go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zei">Zei</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting among a pile of books holding a scroll that surrounds him. The
                sand is building up and beginning to cover some of the stacks. Zei is reading a
                scroll. The camera slowly zooms in.</charAction> I'm not leaving. I can't.
                <charAction>Drops the parchment to his lap and raises his right fist.</charAction>
            I've spent too long trying to find this place. <charAction>Places his hand on his chest
                and looks up.</charAction> There's not another collection of knowledge like this on
            earth. <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Zei with his eyes closed. He opens his eyes
                while smiling and speaks wistfully.</charAction> I could spend an eternity in
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a shot of Sokka and Katara looking at the professor. Katara looks
                up at Sokka.</charAction> Just go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Wan Shi Tong screeches and shakes the rope, making Sokka and Katara fall
                off. Aang catches them and they fly up while Wan Shi Tong pursues them. Cut to
                outside the library, where Aang, Sokka, and Katara land. Toph lets go of the
                library, falling back. Aerial shot showing the ground where the library used to
                be.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We got it. There's a solar eclipse coming. <charAction>Jumps and hugs his
                sister.</charAction> The Fire Nation's in trouble now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up and walks toward Toph.</charAction> Where's Appa?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph shakes her head. Aang gasps and a tear falls down his cheek. The
                camera pans up from the crater to the sun. Fade to white, followed by the
                credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
