<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Boy in the Iceberg</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Water. Earth. Fire. Air. My grandmother used to tell me stories about the old days:
            a time of peace when the Avatar kept balance between the Water Tribes, Earth Kingdom,
            Fire Nation and Air Nomads. But that all changed when the Fire Nation attacked. Only the
            Avatar mastered all four elements; only he could stop the ruthless firebenders. But when
            the world needed him most, he vanished. A hundred years have passed, and the Fire Nation
            is nearing victory in the war. Two years ago, my father and the men of my tribe
            journeyed to the Earth Kingdom to help fight against the Fire Nation, leaving me and my
            brother to look after our tribe. Some people believe that the Avatar was never reborn
            into the Air Nomads and that the cycle is broken, but I haven't lost hope. I still
            believe that, somehow, the Avatar will return to save the world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As the title card fades, the scene opens onto a shot of an icy sea before
                panning slowly to the left, revealing more towering icebergs drifting in the water
                as the shot rotates, moving over a large snow-covered area where the untouched
                blanket of snow is broken by two tracks of footsteps. The shot fades to another shot
                of the sea and of icebergs in blue water contrasted by the paleness of the sky
                beyond. As the shot once again pans to the left and rotates likewise, a small canoe
                comes into view, its motion through the water indicated by the wake left behind it.
                The shot zooms slightly on the canoe before cutting down to it, providing a side
                angle of the canoe and of the walls of ice rising on either side of the vessel.
                Sokka, a teenage boy, and his younger sister, Katara, a teenage girl, are sitting in
                the boat; Sokka holds a spear at the ready, while Katara simply stares into the
                water on the other side of the boat. The shot cuts to an overhead view, revealing
                that a fish is swimming close to the surface right in front of Sokka, who is focused
                on it, following its every movement. Cut to a frontal view of him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's not getting away from me this time. <charAction>Close-up of Sokka as he grins
                confidently over his shoulder in the direction of Katara.</charAction> Watch and
            learn, Katara. This is how you catch a fish.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot pans quickly from Sokka to Katara, who seems indifferent to his
                claim and turns back to her side of the boat again. Her expression changes to
                surprise; as the shot jumps behind her, looking down into the water over her
                shoulder, another fish quickly swims by her, close to where she sits. She shoots a
                quick glance toward her brother, removing the glove from her left hand. She
                stretches her arm out in the direction of the fish, taking a deep breath. Her look
                is a mixture of concentration and apprehension as she starts making a wavy motion
                with her wrist, moving her hand up and down.</description>
            <description>The shot widens out; Sokka, still focused wholly on the fish in front of
                him, is completely unaware of what is happening behind his back. As Katara continues
                to move her hand, the water in front of Katara, just in front of the shot, starts to
                ripple. Suddenly, a bubble of water rises up from the ocean containing the newly
                trapped fish.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily surprised.</charAction> Sokka, look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of Sokka; whispering.</charAction> Sshh! Katara, you're going
            to scare it away. <charAction>A look of bliss adorns his face. He licks his lips and
                wiggles his fingers, not taking his eyes off the fish.</charAction> Mmmm ... I can
            already smell it cookin'.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Behind Sokka, Katara is still making circular movements with both her arms,
                suspending the bubble of water that holds the fish in the air and moving back and
                forth. The camera cuts to her face, contorted slightly by the focus it takes to
                control the water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Struggling with the water that passes right in front of
                her.</charAction> But, Sokka! I caught one!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The bubble containing her fish slowly drifts around her to hang over Sokka,
                who is still oblivious. As the bubble hovers over his head, Sokka raises his spear
                to strike the fish he was following. He bursts the bubble of water with the blunt
                end of his weapon, causing Katara to lose control of the water; it rains down on
                Sokka, soaking him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exclaims indignantly.</charAction> Hey!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Sokka lets out a gasp of discomfort, the fish tumbles through the air
                and Katara follows its arc with her eyes as it flies over her head and splashes back
                into the sea. Sokka rounds on his sister, placing his spear perpendicular to the rim
                of the boat as he yells irately. The shot cuts to a close-up of him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why is it that every time you play with magic water, I get soaked?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka clenches his fists and a few drops of water fall from his soaked
                gloves.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to her face; she sighs lightly before answering in slight
                annoyance.</charAction> It's not "magic", it's waterbending! And it's ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cutting her off.</charAction> Yeah, yeah, "an ancient art unique to our
            culture", blah, blah, blah. Look, I'm just saying <charAction>Grabbing his warrior's
                wolf knot with his left hand as he turns away from her, wringing the water out of
                it. Meanwhile, Katara has crossed her arms.</charAction> that if I had weird powers,
            I'd keep my weirdness to myself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to her face as she raises an eyebrow skeptically, arms still
                crossed.</charAction> You're calling me weird? I'm not the one who makes muscles at
            myself every time I see my reflection in the water!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Near the end of her response, Katara smiles smugly at her brother; as the
                shot cuts to him, he is flexing at his reflection in the water and grinning
                confidently. His happy look vanishes upon hearing his sister's remark and he turns
                around slowly, meaning to face her. Before he can say anything, however, the canoe
                suddenly shudders. As they both try to keep from falling over, Sokka whirls around
                toward his end of the canoe, a frantic look on his face.</description>
            <description>The camera cuts to a far view of the canoe, which pans up as the boat moves
                away from it. The boat is caught in a rapid current, which is pulling it swiftly
                toward a jumble of large icebergs which block the end of the narrow passage formed
                by the towering walls of ice. Sokka paddles the boat in an attempt to stay clear of
                any floating chunks of ice. He manages to gain just enough speed to keep the boat
                from being crushed by two icebergs which slam together behind the boat. A series of
                shots follows: the canoe moving through the water as Sokka rows furiously; a
                close-up of Sokka's head; and a frontal shot of the canoe as it is nearly pinned by
                a number of smaller chunks of ice. Cut to Katara's face, both her face and voice
                full of panic as she yells commands to Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Watch out! Go left! Go left!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot shows an overview of the ice floes moving closer together in front
                of the boat, narrowing their path. The boat manages to stay clear of some of the
                icebergs, but it veers to the right with the current and becomes pinned by three
                large chunks of ice. As the canoe is completely crushed by the ice, Katara and Sokka
                throw themselves from the canoe and onto one of the floes; Katara nearly slides off
                the other side into the water, but comes to a halt at the floe's very edge. As she
                raises her head, looking around, the shot zooms out to reveal the siblings are
                floating on one floe among dozens.</description>
            <description>Katara, shuffling on her hands and knees, moves away from the rim toward
                the middle of the floe, sitting next to her brother. His spear is embedded
                point-first in the ice just behind him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>A touch of bitterness in her voice.</charAction> You call that
                <description>left?</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You don't like my steering? Well, maybe you should've <charAction>He waves his
                hands, mockingly imitating waterbending.</charAction> waterbended us out of the
            ice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot cuts to a wide shot of the two on their floe; among the large
                icebergs and tiny floes surrounding them stands a massive, towering shard of ice,
                its craggy peak rising high above the siblings. Katara gets on her feet again,
                facing Sokka so that the pointed iceberg is behind her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Indignantly.</charAction> So it's my fault?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> I knew I should've left you home! <charAction>Cut
                to a close-up of the siblings; Katara is staring down at her brother in anger while
                he rants calmly.</charAction> Leave it to a girl to screw things up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a close-up of Katara's face as it contorts with fury. The shot cuts
                to a side view as Katara points accusingly at her brother, who makes no movement as
                she screams her disgust at him, the floe bobbing lightly up and down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You are the most sexist, <charAction>She brings her hands up to her head and swings
                them back down and behind her in her rage; the movement creates a small wave of
                water behind her.</charAction> immature, <charAction>Hands raised back to her
                head.</charAction> nut brained ... <charAction>Swings her arms back down again,
                creating a slightly larger wave; she raises her hands back to her head during a
                brief loss for words.</charAction> I'm embarrassed <charAction>Throwing a hand
                upward, a short jet of water shoots upward as well.</charAction> to be related to
            you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She swings both her hands back forcefully once again and her unconscious
                waterbending hurls a wave directly into the towering iceberg behind her; with a
                loud, splitting crack, a hooklike fissure arcs up its surface and out its side,
                leaving a spray of ice where it ends. Sokka, who wears a somewhat disinterested
                expression, glances briefly in his sister's direction and sees the iceberg; after a
                short moment, he does a double-take, his expression morphing into one of terror. The
                shot cuts to show Katara's outburst from behind Sokka; as she continues with her
                verbal outburst and arm movements, little chunks of ice from the iceberg splash into
                the water, unheard and unnoticed by Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Ever since mom died, <charAction>Points to herself.</charAction>
            <description>I've been doing all the work around camp while you've</description> been
            off playing soldier!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She emphasizes the last words with a strong swing of her hand, waterbending
                and deepening the crack in the iceberg. Sokka's terror deepens.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing to the iceberg behind her, his voice subdued by
                fright.</charAction> Uh ... Katara ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of a rage-fueled Katara as she continues her outburst, a finger
                pointed in Sokka's face.</charAction> I even wash all the clothes! Have you ever
            smelled your dirty socks? Let me tell you, <description>not
            pleasant!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As she yells out that last word, she unconsciously waterbends once again,
                causing two new splits in the chunk of ice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a screeching voice, his eyes open wide in fear.</charAction> Katara,
            settle down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No that's it! I'm <description>done helping you! From now on, you're on your
                own!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Her last movement is her most agitated and it creates a huge wave which,
                when it impacts the iceberg, sends a number of fissures to snake their way up the
                iceberg; one of them reaches the top of the iceberg, splitting it completely in
                half. Petrified, Sokka gasps for air, and it is only now that Katara turns to look
                behind her. She gasps and the shot cuts to the iceberg; the two halves begin to fall
                away from each other and the siblings can be seen through the widening space between
                them. The shot jumps to the siblings' backs as the two halves collapse into the
                water; a wave larger than any Katara cast at it radiates outward toward them and
                they are thrown to the ice as it pushes their floe backward.</description>
            <description>As the waves subside, the shot cuts to a head-on close-up of the siblings,
                their heads slightly over the edge of the ice. Sokka, holding a protective arm over
                Katara, turns his head toward her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, you've gone from "weird" to "freakish", <charAction>He releases
                her.</charAction> Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Astonished.</charAction> You mean <description>I </description>did
            that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically, glancing at her and smirking.</charAction> Yep.
                <charAction>Nudging her with his elbow.</charAction> Congratulations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Several small bubbles appear on the surface of the water directly in front
                of them and a small spot of water begins to glow with a bright bluish hue. An
                overhead shot shows the spread of the brilliant glow and the bubbles within. Cut to
                the head-on close-up as the two siblings scramble back in renewed terror from the
                edge, just as a large, roughly spherical iceberg breaks the surface of the
                water.</description>
            <description>The shot jumps behind Katara and Sokka as an iceberg rises above the
                surface, revealing its massive form to be the source of the glow. The crashing waves
                generated by the iceberg's rising push the floe backward as the berg itself rocks to
                one side, before coming to rest with its rounded dome exposed above the water.
                Mesmerized by the iceberg, Katara strays closer and stares at the iceberg; behind
                her, Sokka halfheartedly stretches out his hand, as if to hold her back. A few cuts
                ensue: the iceberg from behind Sokka and Katara; Katara's face as she stares at the
                object; and a shot of the iceberg itself, revealing a human shape within below a
                larger, indistinguishable mass. The human figure, perched in lotus, has glowing
                arrows on its head and hands. Close-up of Katara as she raises an eyebrow in
                confusion. The shot cuts to a closer view of the figure in the ice, its features
                accentuated by reflected light, revealing it to be a boy. Suddenly, the boy opens
                his eyes, the same brilliant light emanating from them, eliciting shocked gasps from
                both of the siblings.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He's alive! We have to help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Before Sokka can grab it, Katara grabs Sokka's club out of its sheath on
                his back and pulls her hood over her head, heading in the direction of the strange
                boy sealed in the iceberg. Sokka again reaches out his hand in an attempt to hold
                Katara back, though she is already running across the ice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, get back here! <charAction>He grabs his spear from the ice and runs after
                Katara, who is already at the ice's edge.</charAction> We don't know what that thing
            is!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara hops across the short distance between her floe and the iceberg on
                five tiny chinks of ice; Sokka, close behind her, does the same. Reaching the
                iceberg first, Katara repeatedly strikes the iceberg with Sokka's club. On her fifth
                strike, the club breaks through the surface and a great gust of wind, which escapes
                from within the iceberg, throws her and her brother back from the side of the dome.
                Fissures quickly snake their way over the whole iceberg and, in a massive outward
                explosion, the entire orb of ice destroys itself. A beam of light bursts from the
                core of the iceberg and rockets into the sky. The camera shows the iceberg from the
                shallow sea bottom as it emits ripples of light. The scene switches to a group of
                tiger seals, who erect themselves to growl at the distant beam of
                light.</description>
            <description>Cut to a Fire Nation ship, where a boy in a Fire Nation military uniform
                stands on the deck, gazing at the light. His ponytail flutters in the
                wind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Finally! <charAction>He turns around to face another person in uniform, who sits at
                a small table.</charAction> Uncle, do you realize what this means?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He is playing some sort of card game. He answers calmly while looking
                over the tile he's holding toward his nephew.</charAction> I won't get to finish my
            game?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning around again to face the light.</charAction> It means my search
            is about to come to an end.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh sighs uninterestedly and places his tile on the table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gestures at the light while facing his uncle again.</charAction> That
            light came from an incredibly powerful source! <charAction>The light dwindles and
                disappears.</charAction> It has to be him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With continuing disinterest and an air of skepticism.</charAction> Or
            it's just the celestial lights. We've been down this road before, Prince Zuko.
                <charAction>He looks at the tile in his hand, depicting the symbol of
                airbending.</charAction> I don't want you to get too excited over nothing.
                <charAction>He places it on a tile carrying the symbol of firebending and gestures
                toward the open place at the other side of the table while continuing in a relaxed
                voice.</charAction> Please, sit. Why don't you enjoy a cup of calming Jasmine
            tea?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Furiously, still facing Iroh.</charAction> I don't need any calming tea!
            I need to capture the Avatar! Helmsman, head a course for the light!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko points in the direction of where the light once was. Iroh calmly
                continues with his game, placing another tile bearing the airbending symbol on the
                previous one. As he does, a gust of wind washes over him, shaking his
                tiles.</description>
            <description>Cut to the iceberg, where the gale has begun to settle. Sokka had
                protectively clutched Katara, but he now releases her as he looks around. Light
                still encircles the remains of the former mountain of ice, now reduced to a
                hollowed-out crater. Sokka looks at his sister and they both get to their feet,
                Katara holding onto her brother. He points his spear at the crater, ready to defend
                them, though lowers it in shock as a figure emerges slowly from the depression in
                the iceberg.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brandishing his spear in defense once again.</charAction> Stop!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Now standing atop the crater, the figure slowly erects himself and looks
                down at them, and the two siblings stare back in wonder and fear.</description>
            <description>The circles of light finally dissipate as the boy stops glowing. The figure
                is revealed to be nothing more than a young boy, who gives a moan of exhaustion and
                suddenly faints. Katara gasps and runs forward to catch him before he hits the
                ground. Sokka follows behind and begins to poke at the boy's head with the blunt end
                of his spear.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waves the spear away. Annoyed.</charAction> Stop it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara places the boy gently against the base of the crater. Close-up of
                the boy as he slowly opens his gray eyes. He gasps in awe as he beholds the Southern
                Water Tribe girl, who stares at him, in wonder, with deep blue eyes. Her hair
                loopies sway in the wind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a weak voice.</charAction> I need to ask you something ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Please ... come closer.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curiously.</charAction> What is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a clear, happy, hopeful tone.</charAction> Will you go penguin
            sledding with me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> Uh, sure ... I-I guess.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera moves back again to show the threesome at the base of the
                iceberg. The boy elegantly rises to his feet in one swift motion, surprising the
                other two. Katara looks at him in awe while Sokka backs away in shock, aiming his
                spear at him again. Katara glances at him in disbelief.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking around and rubbing his head, while Katara scrambles on her
                feet.</charAction> What's going on here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aggressively.</charAction> You tell us! <charAction>Points at the top of
                the crater.</charAction> How did you get in the ice? And why aren't you frozen?
                <charAction>He pokes the boy in his side with his spear.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lazily pushes the spear away.</charAction> I'm not sure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A low, gruff noise suddenly fills the air, coming from within the crater of
                the iceberg. Quickly, the boy scrambles up the ridge of ice and happily jumps on the
                head of a large, furry creature that has the same arrow-shaped marking on his
                forehead as the boy.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exclaims happily.</charAction> Appa! Are you all right? <charAction>He
                hangs down the side of the beast to look at its eyes, which are still
                closed.</charAction> Wake up, buddy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He opens an eyelid that immediately closes again once it is released. He
                jumps down to the front of the bison and tries to lift its enormous head. Sokka and
                Katara appear around the corner as Appa finally starts to react to Aang, opening his
                mouth and licking Aang with his giant tongue. Sokka's jaw drops upon seeing the
                beast.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughing cheerfully.</charAction> Ha, ha! You're okay!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang hugs the bison's nose. The camera moves back to reveal that the
                creature stands up on his six legs and stretches itself. When the picture moves
                closer again, Aang is petting the bison's nose.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What is that thing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>This is Appa, my flying bison.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Right, and this is Katara, my flying sister.
                <charAction>Katara shoots him an odd look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang looks questioningly at Sokka for a moment, but his attention is
                diverted back toward his bison when Appa starts to inhale deeply. Realizing what is
                about to happen, Aang ducks before Appa sneezes, sending a large blast of green snot
                flying directly onto Sokka, who becomes completely covered in it. He squeals in
                disgust and begins to frantically try clean it off, rubbing his face in the snow
                under the amused gaze of his sister.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> Don't worry, it'll wash out. <charAction>Green
                snot is hanging from Sokka's face to his glove, dripping down as he retracts his
                hand. Katara covers her mouth in disgust.</charAction> So do you guys live around
            here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing his spear accusingly again at Aang who is surprised to see the
                thing.</charAction>
            <description>Don't </description>answer that! Did you see that crazy bolt of light?! He
            was probably trying to signal the Fire Navy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pushes Sokka's spear away again and addresses him
                sarcastically.</charAction> Oh yeah, I'm sure he's a spy for the Fire Navy. You can
            tell by that evil look in his eye. <charAction>Aang shoots the two an earnest
                grin.</charAction> The paranoid one is my brother, Sokka. You never told us your
            name.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm A ... a-a-a-Achoo! <charAction>The boy sneezes, creating an air blast that sends
                him soaring into the air. He lands on the ground, unharmed.</charAction> I'm Aang.
                <charAction>He sniffles a bit.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Total disbelief.</charAction> You just sneezed ... <charAction>Points to
                the sky.</charAction> and flew ten feet in the air!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>He looks questioningly toward the sky.</charAction> Really? It felt
            higher than that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gasps for air in comprehension.</charAction> You're an
            airbender!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sure am!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Giant light beams, flying bison, airbenders ... <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
            I think I got midnight sun madness. I'm going home to where stuff makes sense.
                <charAction>He realizes, however, that he is stranded in the middle of the ocean
                with no way home.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, if you guys are stuck, Appa and I can give you a lift. <charAction>Aang
                airbends himself onto Appa.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We'd love a ride! Thanks! <charAction>Katara runs to the side of the
                bison.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh no! I'm not getting on that fluffy snot monster!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>While climbing on top of Appa with the help of Aang.</charAction> Are
            you hoping some other kind of monster will come along and give you a ride home? You
            know, before you freeze to death?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka opens his mouth in defiance and point at Katara, ready to retaliate,
                but he cannot think of anything. He sighs and bows his head in consent and
                defeat.</description>
            <description>The camera switches to a shot where both siblings are sitting on Appa's
                saddle. Sokka has his arms crossed in front of him with a sulking expression on his
                face while Katara is full of excitement and anticipation.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, first time flyers, hold on tight! Appa, yip-yip!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang whips the reins and Appa growls in response. He moves his tail up and
                down and takes a huge jump into the air. He soars through the air for merely a few
                seconds, making it appear as though he would fly, before belly-flopping into the
                water with a splash. The bison begins trudging through the water slowly. Katara
                crawls to the front of the saddle while Aang tries to get Appa flying, whipping the
                reins again.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Come on, Appa. Yip-yip!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Wow, that was truly amazing ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Katara shoots her brother an angry glance.</charAction> Appa's just a
            little tired. A little rest and he'll be soaring through the sky. You'll see.
                <charAction>Katara smiles at Aang, who returns this gesture. When she wants to move
                back, she realizes that he is still smiling at her.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Uncomfortably.</charAction> Why are you smiling at me like
            that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I was smiling? <charAction>Flattered, Katara smiles back.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka throws his head back and sticks his tongue out in disgust while
                groaning loudly. Katara glares at him while Appa continues to make his way through
                the icy sea, flapping his tail in the water.</description>
            <description>The picture tilts up and fades away to reveal Zuko standing on the helm of
                his ship, staring into the distance. The young man is approached by his
                uncle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I'm going to bed now. <charAction>Yawns and stretches.</charAction> Yep, a man needs
            his rest. <charAction>After a short pause, he abandons his try at a veiled suggestion
                and delivers his request more clearly, his tone tired.</charAction> Prince Zuko, you
            need some sleep. Even if you're right, and the Avatar is alive, you won't find him. Your
            father, grandfather and great-grandfather all tried and failed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Because their honor didn't hinge on the Avatar's capture. Mine does. This coward's
            hundred years in hiding are over.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene fades to Appa who is still swimming in the water. Aang now lies
                lazily on his back, his arms tucked under his head. Katara crawls to the front of
                the saddle again to have a better look at the boy. She leans on the front of the
                saddle and rests her head on her arm.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey. What'cha thinkin' about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I guess I was wondering, your being an airbender and all, if you had any idea what
            happened to the Avatar?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, no. I didn't know him. I mean, I knew people that knew him, but I didn't. Sorry.
                <charAction>He smiles weakly at Katara.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Okay. Just curious. <charAction>She slants her eyes in disappointment for a second
                before smiling again at Aang.</charAction> Good night.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sleep tight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang uncomfortably turns around and a look of guilt crosses his face. The
                camera switches to another wide shot of Appa swimming through the vast sea,
                reflecting the brilliant sunlight.</description>
            <description>The scene switches to a dream of Aang's, colored in various shades of gray.
                Aang is sleeping on Appa's saddle while clouds build around and ahead of him.
                Lightning splits the sky and the rumble of the following thunder awakens him. He
                shoots up and looks around. In the next shot it is raining and Aang is sitting on
                Appa's head again, holding the reigns and screaming at the top of his lungs in
                terror while they go down. Appa and Aang splash into the waters of the ocean. Appa
                resurfaces again, growls, but is quickly subdued anew by another wave. Both Aang and
                Appa sink unconscious into the water. As Aang releases the reigns and drifts off,
                his eyes and tattoos suddenly start to glow brightly. He slams his fists together,
                creating a bluish-white sphere that encases Appa and himself. As the air sphere
                slowly solidifies into an icy globe, a voice permeates the dream.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang? Aang! Wake up. <charAction>Aang shoots up, throwing the covers of his body and
                gasping for air. Katara perches beside him and stands up as she sees that Aang is
                awake.</charAction> It's okay, we're in the village now! Come on, get ready.
                <charAction>She points to the door of the tent.</charAction> Everyone's waiting to
            meet you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang happily gets out of bed and starts to dress himself while Katara takes
                a step toward the door. Before she exits, however, she glances back at Aang and
                gasps, staring in wonder at the blue, arrow-shaped tattoos that trace his arms and
                legs and reach up his back and to his head. Before Aang is able to get up, Katara
                pulls him along by his arm to meet the rest of the village.</description>
            <description>Aang is dragged out the tent toward a small congregation of villagers. He
                passes Sokka, who is sitting at the side of the tent, sharpening his
                boomerang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, this is the entire village. <charAction>Points to the line of villagers in
                front of them.</charAction> Entire village, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang bows respectfully toward the villagers, but they cower away in fear,
                bringing a surprised look to Katara and Aang's faces. Sokka just watches from a
                distance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Uncomfortably.</charAction> Uh, why are they all looking at me like
            that? Did Appa sneeze on me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang checks his clothing while an elderly woman steps forward out of the
                line of villagers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kanna">Kanna</speaker>
        <speech>Well, no one has seen an airbender in a hundred years. We thought they were extinct,
            until my granddaughter and grandson found you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked disbelief.</charAction> Extinct?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gesturing.</charAction> Aang, this is my grandmother.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kanna">Kanna</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Flatly, with a dull look on her face.</charAction> Call me
            Gran-Gran.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka walks toward Aang and abruptly snatches his staff out of his hands
                and starts to examine it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> What is this, a weapon? You can't stab anything
            with this!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang uses a small air current to get his staff back.</charAction> It's
            not for stabbing! It's for airbending. <charAction>He opens his staff into a glider,
                making Sokka gasp in fright and cover his head with his hands.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Village girl">Village girl</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excited.</charAction> Magic trick! Do it again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Not magic, airbending. <charAction>He moves his glider around him, visually
                demonstrating what he is talking about.</charAction> It lets me control the air
            currents around my glider and fly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mockingly states his disbelief.</charAction> Ya know, last time I
            checked, humans <description>can't fly!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Accepting Sokka's challenge, smiling.</charAction> Check again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang grabs hold of his glider and pushes himself off the ground, leaving
                Katara and Sokka to cover their faces against the sudden wind. The village stares in
                awe as Aang makes some loops and turns in the sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Village girl">Village girl</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In admiration.</charAction> He's flying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang makes another loops and speeds up to soar past the gazing
                villagers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Village girl">Village girl</speaker>
        <speech>It's amazing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang's shadow passes over Katara, who is smiling broadly at him. Aang,
                intending to further impress the villagers, flies sideways and closes his eyes while
                grinning broadly. He promptly flies head-on into the village's watchtower, causing
                his head to be stuck in its side. Katara covers her mouth as she watches Aang
                struggle to extricate his head from the icy watchtower. Succeeding, he tumbles
                downward onto a pile of snow at the base of the tower that crumbled from the
                building. Katara immediately rushes to his side while Sokka stares in shock at the
                damage inflicted on his watchtower.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> My watchtower!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang lies covered in snow at the base of the partially collapsed tower.
                Katara and some other girls of the tribe run toward Aang, smiling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Offering her hand to pull him out of the snow.</charAction> That was
                <description>amazing!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka runs toward his watchtower and starts to pat it in the hope that he
                can save it from collapsing any further. While Aang spins his staff around to
                retract its wings, Sokka is being knocked down by a large pack of snow that falls
                down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Great. You're an airbender, Katara's a
            waterbender. Together you can just waste time all day long. <charAction>He wedges
                himself free from underneath the weight of the snow and stalks
            off.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised and with admiration.</charAction> You're a
            waterbender?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Well, sort of. Not yet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kanna">Kanna</speaker>
        <speech>All right, no more playing. Come on, Katara, you have chores.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Kanna leads Katara away from Aang. The surrounding villagers part to let
                the duo pass.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> I told you, he's the real thing Gran-Gran! I
            finally found a bender to teach me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kanna">Kanna</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Katara, try not to put all your hopes in this
            boy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But he's special! I can tell! <charAction>Clenches her fist and closes her eyes in
                hope.</charAction> I sense he's filled with much wisdom.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara opens her eyes again and glances back toward Aang, who is surrounded
                by a bunch of kids. He smiles while his tongue is stuck to his staff.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Muffled.</charAction> See? Now my tongue is stuck to my staff!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Much to Aang's discomfort, one of the smaller village boys starts to yank
                his staff, pulling Aang along with every movement. The village kids laugh and
                applaud Aang as his tongue remains stuck to his staff.</description>
            <description>The scene shifts to Zuko's ship where Zuko is facing two soldiers dressed
                in the uniforms of a firebending Fire Nation soldier. Iroh is sitting on a small
                chair next to them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sternly.</charAction> Again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko opens the fight by spreading his arms in the direction of the two
                firebenders, showering them with flames. His adversaries block Zuko's attack with
                ease. Zuko shifts his weight to duck under a retaliation blast of the firebender to
                his left. The firebender to his right jumps forward to aim a blast at Zuko's feet.
                The prince propels himself out of the way. He twists around in mid-air and directs
                another fire blast with his hand to the firebender that retaliated first, and
                another with his foot to the firebender that aimed for his feet. Both soldiers jump
                out of the way of Zuko's flames. Zuko lands and stretches his fists out toward his
                adversaries, ready to face another attack.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs while he gets up.</charAction> No! <charAction>Zuko lowers his
                arms and looks at his uncle.</charAction> Power in firebending comes from the breath
                <charAction>Iroh moves his both hand up in front of him to emphasize the breathing
                motion.</charAction>, not the muscles. <charAction>He stretches his left arm out as
                if he was sending a fire blast.</charAction> The breath becomes energy in the body.
            The energy extends past your limbs and becomes: fire! <charAction>Iroh directs a fire
                blast at his nephew that evaporates just before it would scorch him.</charAction>
            Get it right this time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With suppressed anger, he walks toward his uncle and addresses
                him.</charAction> Enough! I've been drilling this sequence all day. Teach me the
            next set! I'm more than ready!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>No, you are impatient. <charAction>He sits down again on his chair.</charAction> You
            have yet to master your basics. <charAction>He yells his order.</charAction> Drill it
            again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko clenches his teeth in anger. He turns around and suddenly directs a
                power fire kick toward one of the soldiers. The firebender attempts to stop the fire
                blast, but he is unable to and is thrown on his back by its power.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The suppressed anger is very apparent in his voice.</charAction> The
            sages tell us that the Avatar is the last airbender. <charAction>Close-up of Iroh, who
                does not look pleased with the attitude of his nephew.</charAction> He must be over
            a hundred years old by now. He's had a century to master the four elements! I'll need
            more than basic firebending to defeat him. <charAction>Starts to yell at his
                uncle.</charAction> You will teach me the advanced set!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Concedes reluctantly. On a dire tone.</charAction> Very well,
                <charAction>His expression changes completely to one of delight as he picks
                something up from the ground.</charAction> but first, I must finish my roast duck.
                <charAction>He quickly munches down the roast duck, much to the dismay of
                Zuko.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene shifts back to the Southern Water Tribe, where it pans down to
                reveal Sokka pacing to and fro, his arms behind his back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With a stern expression.</charAction> Now men, it's important that you
            show no fear when you face a firebender. <charAction>He brings out his club and holds it
                proudly.</charAction> In the Water Tribe, we fight to the last man standing! For
            without courage, how can we call ourselves men? <charAction>He clutches his fist to
                emphasize the word "men" as he stares down the people in front of
            him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera shifts positions to reveal that Sokka is talking to six
                uninterested little boys.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Southern Water Tribe boy">Southern Water Tribe boy</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waving his hand in the air.</charAction> I gotta pee!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Listen! Until your fathers return from the War,
            they're counting on you to be the men of this tribe, and that means no potty breaks!
                <charAction>He makes some wide arm gestures to emphasize his words
                again.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Southern Water Tribe boy">Southern Water Tribe boy</speaker>
        <speech>But I really gotta go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs.</charAction> Okay, who else has to go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Every child immediately raises his hand. Sokka is surprised for a second,
                before facepalming in frustration.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs up to Sokka as the children leave. In a worried tone.</charAction>
            Have you seen Aang? Gran-Gran said he disappeared over <description>an
                hour</description> ago.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang appears from an outhouse igloo, pulling his pants up a bit
                higher.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> Wow! Everything freezes in there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He points toward the bathroom with a smile on his face. Sokka's "soldiers"
                halt beside Aang and laugh with him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Uh! <charAction>Angrily points at
                Aang.</charAction> Katara, get him out of here! This lesson is for warriors
            only!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka is about to walk away when he hears the sound of playing
                children.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Village boy">Village boy</speaker>
        <speech>Whee!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He turns around, and the picture follows his gaze to reveal the village
                children sliding down Appa's tail like a slide. The end of the tail is propped
                upward, so the children are propelled into the air. They fly over Sokka's spear, now
                serving as a mark that they need to cross before landing in a soft pile of snow.
                Katara laughs as a boy lands head-first in the snow, but Sokka rushes
                forward.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Yelling angrily.</charAction> Stop! Stop it right now! <charAction>The
                laughter of the children is stifled immediately and Appa turns his head to look at
                Sokka, who accusingly directs his anger to Aang.</charAction> What's wrong with
            you?! We don't have time for fun and games with <description>the War</description> going
            on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka takes back his spear and casts an annoyed glance at the laughing
                children who run past him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slides down from Appa's head.</charAction> What war? What are you
            talking about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Raises one eyebrow in disbelief.</charAction> You're kidding,
            right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang looks questioningly at Sokka, but the expression on his face changes
                to enthusiasm when he catches sight of an otter-penguin.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Exclaims enthusiastically.</charAction> Penguin!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The animal is startled by Aang's outburst and quickly waddles off. Aang
                gives chase, racing past Katara and Sokka, enhancing his speed with his airbending.
                He leaves a deep trail in the snow as he dashes after the penguin.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He's kidding, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The siblings glance at each other, not sure what they need to think of
                Aang's reaction.</description>
            <description>The scene fades away to show the otter-penguin habitat, where hundreds of
                otter-penguins are walking or sliding down icebergs. Katara approaches the penguins
                in search for Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Chasing the penguins while laughing.</charAction> Hey, come on little
            guy. Wanna go sledding? <charAction>He jumps at a penguin, but the animal evades his
                attempt and Aang belly flops into the snow. He turns on his back and quickly erects
                himself with his airbending as Katara comes up beside him.</charAction> Heh heh. I
            have a way with animals.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang stretches his arms wide and imitates the sound and movements of the
                animals around them, making Katara laugh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> Hehehe, Aang, I'll help you catch a penguin if you
            teach me waterbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Having grabbed the tail of a penguin, he holds on as it pulls him
                through the snow for a short way before letting go and looking up at
                Katara.</charAction> You got a deal! Just one little problem ... <charAction>He
                airbends himself into a sitting position.</charAction> I'm an airbender, not a
            waterbender. Isn't there someone in your tribe who can teach you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sadly.</charAction> No. You're looking at the only waterbender in the
            whole South Pole.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>This isn't right. A waterbender needs to master water. <charAction>He thinks for a
                moment.</charAction> What about the North Pole? There's another Water Tribe up
            there, right? Maybe they have waterbenders who could teach you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe, but we haven't had contact with our sister tribe in a long time. It's not
            exactly "turn right at the second glacier". It's on the other side of <description>the
                world</description>.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But you forget, I have a flying bison. <charAction>He happily points at
                himself.</charAction> Appa and I can personally fly you to the North Pole. Katara,
            we're going to find you a master!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unsure.</charAction> That's ... I mean, I don't know. I've never left
            home before.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, you think about it, but in the meantime, can you teach me catch one of these
            penguins?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mockingly imitating a teacher.</charAction> Okay, listen closely my
            young pupil. <charAction>Inclines her head toward Aang.</charAction> Catching penguins
            is an ancient and sacred art. <charAction>She conjures a fish out of her
                sleeve.</charAction> Observe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She tosses Aang the fish. As he catches it with an uncomprehending look on
                his face, the penguins immediately begin crowding him. He laughs as the penguins
                swarm over him, pulling him down amidst their ranks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hi hi hi! Ha, ha, ha!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches to a protruding iceberg that Aang and Katara use as a
                slide, each sitting atop a penguin. They soar through the air for a moment before
                landing on the slope and continuing their journey downward. They race down and Aang
                uses another iceberg as a ramp to propel him into the air and to soar over and past
                Katara. She in turn uses the next jump to land next to Aang again. The two laugh and
                shout out as they gleefully ride over snowy bumps.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> I haven't done this since I was a kid!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You still are a kid!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two ride through a tunnel of ice. Katara is in the lead and tries to
                hold Aang back by constantly changing her direction when he wants to pass her. Aang
                solves this problem by increasing his speed with airbending, enabling him to race
                over the ceiling past Katara. The tunnel levels out on an open plain of ice where
                the two get off their rides. The plain itself is dominated by a large metal ship,
                elevated and held in place by a large protrusion of ice with the bow pointing toward
                the sky. Curious, Aang gazes at it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In awe.</charAction> Whoa! What is
            <description>that?</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>On a slightly dark tone.</charAction> A Fire Navy ship. And a very bad
            memory for my people. <charAction>Aang begins to approach the wreckage.</charAction>
            Aang, stop! We're not allowed to go near it! The ship could be booby-trapped!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>If you want to be a bender, you have to let go of fear.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara ponders over that remark for a moment and walks toward Aang with a
                scared look upon her face. The two venture closer toward the ship. Aang helps Katara
                to climb some of the blocks of ice that lay beside the ship and they crawl through a
                hole in the hull of the ship. The two walk through the silent rooms of the
                shipwreck. Some white hamsters roam the otherwise deserted ship. Aang enters a room
                stocked with weapons in various places.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Her voice echoes through the room.</charAction> This ship has haunted my
            tribe since Gran-Gran was a little girl. <charAction>The camera shifts through the room,
                revealing all the weapons more closely.</charAction> It was part of the Fire
            Nation's first attacks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, back up. I have friends all over the world, even in the Fire Nation.
                <charAction>Aang picks up a Guan Dao to inspect it.</charAction> I've never seen any
            war.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, how long were you in that iceberg?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Uncertain.</charAction> I don't know. A few days, maybe?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I think it was more like a hundred<description> years!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In full disbelief and slightly accusing.</charAction> What?! That's
            impossible! Do I look like a hundred-twelve-year-old man to you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Think about it. The War is a century old. You don't know about it because, somehow,
            you were in there the whole time! <charAction>Aang's expression changes to one of
                comprehension.</charAction> It's the only explanation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang backs away and slumps to floor in shock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>A hundred years! <charAction>Saddened by his new discovery.</charAction> I can't
            believe it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Squats beside him.</charAction> I'm sorry, Aang. Maybe somehow there's a
            bright side to all this ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> I did get to meet you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling warmly at him while offering her hand.</charAction> Come on,
            let's get out of here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara smiles and pulls him to his feet and the two exit the
                room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, let's head back, this place is creepy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang ventures down yet another room with Katara on his trail. There, he
                trips over a thin rope; as he stumbles, metal bars slide downward over the entrance,
                barring it and trapping them inside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Huh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They both run toward the bars and peek through them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What's that you said about booby traps?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The gears and engines of the shipwreck suddenly power up, beginning to
                function. In shock, Katara and Aang follow the movements of the machines until
                suddenly, a flare is fired and explodes high in the sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Uh oh ... <charAction>Aang notices a hole in the roof of the ship and takes a
                surprised Katara into his arms.</charAction> Hold on tight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aaah!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang enhances the power of his jump with his airbending to jump several
                feet into the air through the hole.</description>
            <description>The scene switches to Prince Zuko, who is peering through a telescope. He
                follows every movement the duo makes as Aang, still holding Katara, jumps down the
                side of the ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The last airbender! <charAction>Aang and Katara reach the ground again and Aang sets
                Katara down. They start to walk away.</charAction> Quite agile for his old age.
                <charAction>He turns and angrily yells to a soldier behind him.</charAction> Wake my
            uncle! Tell him I found the Avatar. <charAction>Zuko peeks through his telescope again
                to see that Katara and Aang are running now. Zuko follows the direction they are
                running in with his telescope and discovers that they must be headed for the village
                he spots.</charAction> As well as his hiding place ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Close-up of Zuko's right eye as he squints it to look in the direction of
                the Southern Water Tribe.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
