<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Blind Bandit</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans across a wide-view over Gaoling. Town citizens move through
                the streets. The team stands inside a shop. The camera zooms in on them, gathered
                around a green bag. Sokka is looking at the bag while pondering. Katara and Momo on
                her shoulder look at him. Aang sits down, looking the other way and wearing his
                conical hat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pensively.</charAction> It's pricey ... but I really do like
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Then you should get it, you deserve something nice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I do, don't I? <charAction>Katara looks at him with a bored expression.</charAction>
            But no, it's too expensive. I shouldn't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In the background, a town citizen tries to talk to a passer-by, showing him
                a flyer.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>All right, then don't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara walks away in boredom. Aang gets up and follows her. Sokka pauses
                for a moment and goes along, too, his eyes still on the bag as he moves out of view.
                The town citizen with the flyers walks away into the same direction. Sokka quickly
                comes back into view.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enthusiastically.</charAction> You know what? I'm gonna get it.
                <charAction>Smiles in a pleased way.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang, Katara, and Momo wait down the street. The town citizen turns toward
                them, showing them the flyer.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Flyer distribution man">Flyer distribution man</speaker>
        <speech>Psst, psst! Hey, you kids love earthbending? You like ... throwing rocks? Then check
            out Master Yu's Earthbending Academy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The flyer distribution man hands over a flyer with a broad smile. The shot
                switches to a close-up of the flyer as Aang, Katara, and Momo look at it. Aang turns
                it around.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Look! There's a coupon on the back! The first lesson is free.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms out, showing Aang, Katara, and Momo looking at the
                flyer.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Who knows? This Master Yu could be the earthbending teacher you've been looking
            for.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka joins them, holding the green bag. He looks wondering at the flyer.
                Scene cuts to Yu's academy. The camera shows a short view of the entrance. Aang
                looks perplexed, wearing an Earth Kingdom outfit and a green hat. He puts his finger
                into his ear, wiggles it and sniffs his finger. Turning to his right, he sees that
                all the younger children with whom he is standing in line with sport a serious
                expression and he promptly straightens his back. Their teacher, Master Yu, moves
                toward his two opposing rows of pupils. The row opposite of Aang has rocks placed in
                front of them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech>Take your stances! <charAction>His students take their fighting stances, except for
                Aang.</charAction> Now, strike as if you're punching through your opponent's
            head!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yu demonstrates the movement he means. The pupils lift their rocks. A
                close-up shows Aang's startled expression. The camera shifts to a close-up of the
                student that stands across Aang as he fires his rock at him. Aang gets hit by the
                rock in the gut and smashes into a vase in the shape of a tea pot by the impact of
                the blow.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches Aang.</charAction> So, are you ready to commit to more
            lessons? If you pay for the whole year in advance, I'll bump you up to the next
            belt!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang stares at him, covered in sand and shards. Only his eyes, nose and
                right hand are visible. The sand shifts and covers his face completely. Moments
                later, Aang walks out of the academy with the other students and returns to Katara
                and Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Ehhh, he's not the one. <charAction>Beats his right ear, causing sand to fall out of
                his left ear.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Leaves the Earthbending Academy, accompanied by another
                student.</charAction> I think The Boulder's going to win back the belt at Earth
            Rumble VI.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student #2">Male student #2</speaker>
        <speech>He's going to have to fight his way through the best earthbenders in the world to
            get a shot at the champ.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang overhears their conversation and runs after them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Excuse me, but where is this earthbending tournament, exactly?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> It's on the island of Noneya ... "Noneya"
            business!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The students laugh and walk away as he looks on disappointed. Sokka walks
                up to Aang laughing while Katara glares at them while walking up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs and wipes tears of laughter away.</charAction> Oh, I got to
            remember that one!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Consolingly to Aang.</charAction> I'll take care of this. <charAction>To
                the students.</charAction> Hey, strong guys! Wait up! <charAction>Runs after the
                students around a corner.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at his bag, holding it out.</charAction> What was I thinking?
                <charAction>Angrily to Aang.</charAction> I don't need a new bag! Why did you let me
            buy this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He puts the bag down and crosses his arms in front of his chest. Momo hops
                off his shoulder, into the bag. He turns around inside of it and settles down,
                closing his eyes. Katara comes running back.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You ready to find an earthbending teacher? Because we're going to Earth Rumble
            VI!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks surprised.</charAction> How'd you get them to tell you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Oh ... a girl has her ways. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A scene shows the two students frozen together at the head, encased in ice
                in an alley. Nightfall. The camera shows the entrance to location of Earth Rumble
                VI: a lighted tunnel in a rock face. People enter the tunnel. The camera shows the
                hall where the competition will be held. A large rectangular arena is located in the
                middle. The arena has stairs running down to a lower, oval shaped area. Seats for
                the spectators start at the same level as the arena. Team Avatar walks into an empty
                row of seats.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, front row seats! I wonder why no one else is sitting here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They sit down but quickly jump back up as a huge rock smashes into the
                seats next to them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I guess that's why.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In the center of the ring, the event's host raises an earthen platform. He
                brings it back to the level of the rest of the arena.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Raises his left arm.</charAction> Welcome to Earth Rumble VI! I am your
            host, Xin Fu!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sighs and looks the other way.</charAction> This is just going to be a
            bunch of guys chucking rocks at each other, isn't it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> That's what I paid for.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>The rules are simple. Just knock the other guy out of the ring, and you win!
                <charAction>Leaps up to a podium above the ring. A bell rings.</charAction> Round
            one: The Boulder vs. The Big Bad Hippo! <charAction>While Xin Fu speaks, The Boulder
                raises his arms and turns around to the cheering of the audience. The Hippo
                roars.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing at The Hippo.</charAction> Listen up, Hippo. You may be big,
            but you ain't bad! <charAction>Grinning insanely.</charAction> The Boulder's gonna win
            this in a landslide!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Hippo">The Hippo</speaker>
        <speech>Hippo ... mad!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Hippo raises his arms in anger and stomps one foot. Momo lowers himself
                more inside Sokka's bag out of fear. The Boulder fires three rocks. They crash into
                The Hippo, but he does not move. He catches one piece of rock with his mouth, chews
                on it and spits it out. The Hippo jumps up and down, causing the surface of the
                arena to tilt. The Boulder hereby loses his balance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>Unbelievable, ladies and gentlemen! The Hippo is rocking the boat!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Boulder reaches the edge, but saves himself by bending out part of the
                ring into a small platform. He grabs it and throws it at his opponent, hitting him
                on the back. As The Hippo turns around to look at him, The Boulder bends up The
                Hippo's part of the ring, and throws him out on it. The Hippo crashes in the lower
                area of around the arena. The fight ends thus in his favor.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>The Boulder wins!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at The Boulder.</charAction> How about The Boulder? He's got
            some good moves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugs.</charAction> I don't know. Bumi said I need a teacher who
            listens to the earth. He's just listening to his big muscles. What do you think,
            Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka cheers loudly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>Next match ... The Boulder versus <charAction>Cut to to a close-up of Fire Nation
                Man happily waving a Fire Nation flag; voice-over.</charAction> Fire Nation
            Man!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Far off side-shot as the crowd boos at the Fire Nation Man who is making
                his way over to the arena, still waving his flag, on a makeshift earthen bridge,
                which crumbles away behind him. Cut to a close-up of Sokka, who loudly boos the
                fighter as well, while giving him a thumbs down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation Man">Fire Nation Man</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With a pseudo-Russian accent.</charAction> Please, to rise for Fire
            Nation national anthem! <charAction>Put his left hand over his heart; begins to
                sing.</charAction> Fire Lord, my flame burns <charAction>Drops to his right knee and
                stretches out his left arm.</charAction> for thee!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The crowd boos at him again while bombarding him with pieces of rock, much
                to his surprise. Cut to Sokka with a stone cocked back in his hand, ready to
                throw.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Yelling.</charAction> Go back to the Fire Nation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka throws his rock. Cut to a close-up of the Fire Nation Man, who is hit
                against the head by a rock. He starts to become angry, though the emotion quickly
                changes to wonder and he is sunk chest-deep into the ground; he drops his flag in
                the process. Cut to a shot from over his shoulder to reveal The Boulder as the
                culprit, who subsequently raises himself high into the air on an earth pillar. Cut
                to a close-up of the Fire Nation Man, who looks petrified.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation Man">Fire Nation Man</speaker>
        <speech>No, no, please!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a close-up of The Boulder grinning broadly. He leaps in the air, his
                face serious. Cut to a side-shot; The Boulder is plummeting straight down, his feet
                held back behind his back as to direct his knees to the ground. Switch to a further
                off shot as he slams the surface of the ring, by which he creates a pillar under
                Fire Nation Man that catapults him out of the ground. Frog-view shot of the Fire
                Nation Man as he sails screaming through the air. Cut to a frontal shot of the place
                where Team Avatar is sitting. The Fire Nation Man smacks upside down and face first
                against the large boulder that was embedded into the stand next to team Avatar.
                Sokka gets up and waves both hands in the air in celebration of the Fire Nation
                Man's defeat, while shouting in the fighter's direction.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah! Wooo! <charAction>Points at Fire Nation Man.</charAction> The Boulder knows
            how to put the hurt in the dirt! <charAction>Close-up of Sokka as he continues to cheer
                and make taunting faces.</charAction> Yeah! Woohoo!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the arena where a man riding a badgermole is going over the surface
                to make it smooth again, letting the animal bend all the rubble away. A turning,
                frog-view shot reveals the ceiling and a female assistant holding up a sign to
                announce the next round as a bell is struck. A montage shows The Boulder defeating
                several more fighters: The Gopher gets slammed between two rocks, The Gecko jumps
                up, but gets hit in the stomach by a broad earthen pillar, Headhunter gets hit with
                an earthen coin. Between his victories, The Boulder entertains the cheering crowd by
                wobbling his chest. As The Boulder relishes from his fans' praise, there is a faded
                scene with the crowd cheering with Sokka soon appearing in front. Far off shot of
                Xin Fu standing on his platform.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>Now, the moment <charAction>The light slowly dims to put him in the
                spotlight.</charAction> you've all been waiting for. The Boulder versus
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of a person with black hair mostly obscured by a green
                prize belt; voice-over.</charAction> your champion ... the Blind Bandit!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As Xin Fu was speaking, the girl raises her championship belt above her
                head, under loud cheering of the crowd. Cut to a further off frontal shot, showing
                the girl to actually be a short child, barely reaching to the waists of the female
                assistants standing next to her. As the spotlight dies down, the girl offers her
                championship belt to the assistant on her right, while the other one removes her
                cape, and they both walk off. The camera shifts to Aang and Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>She can't really be blind. <charAction>Turn her head and squints her eyes
                skeptically.</charAction> It's just part of her <charAction>Cut to a close-up of the
                Bandit's milky-green eyes; pans right.</charAction> character, right?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> I think she is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera moves back to include Sokka in the shot; deadpanned.</charAction>
            I think she is ... <charAction>Shouting, gesturing downward with both
                hands.</charAction> going down!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka's movement causing Aang to flinch back and Momo to coo and hide in
                the bag Sokka bought earlier on the market. Cut to a shot of the Blind Bandit that
                nearly instantly moves back to a view from on the arena's floor level. The Boulder
                confidently puts his foot in the middle of the screen, cracking the floor in the
                process and throwing up some dust. Cut to a frog-point frontal view of the
                fighter.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>The Boulder feels conflicted about fighting a young blind girl.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points at The Boulder. Mockingly.</charAction> Sounds to me like you're
                <charAction>Goes into a mockingly scared position.</charAction> scared,
            Boulder!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>After a pause where he looks stunned.</charAction> The Boulder's over
            his conflicted feelings, <charAction>Narrows his eyes.</charAction> and now he's ready
            to bury you screen <charAction>Expands instantly and the Boulder makes a dramatic,
                crushing gesture.</charAction> in a rock-alanche!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Whenever you're ready, The Pebble! <charAction>Throws her head back and
                laughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to a close-up of Aang, before switching to a flashback from "The
                Swamp" where he saw the girl in white and the flying boar. He remembers her laugh,
                which is the same as that of the Bandit. The flashback shows a closer shot of the
                girl in the fancy dress. The camera closes in and turns around the girl to reveal
                her face as the Bandit's. The flashback ends in a flash of white to reveal Aang's
                stunned face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>It's on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to a shot from behind The Boulder who faces the Bandit, before
                shifting to a tilting down shot of The Boulder's head. Despite his bravado, he is
                sweating profusely. Switch to a frontal shot of the Bandit. The camera whirls around
                her head and ends with a close up shot of her ear. Cut to The Boulder, who yells and
                takes a step forward. As his heel hits the ground, the frame freezes and goes to
                black and white. Shock waves in white move out from his heel where it has struck the
                floor of the arena. Cut to an overhead shot of The Boulder showing the shock wave
                emanating away from his heel in concentric circles. Cut again to the Bandit standing
                perfectly still. The shock waves reach her and travel up her body.</description>
            <description>Return to a frontal shot of the Bandit in full color. She moves forward,
                opening her arms as soon as she registers the shock wave indicating the movement of
                her opponent. Cut to a shot of her feet as she moves forward to finish the set up
                for her attack. The Boulder moves forward at a slow frame rate. He is bellowing a
                slurred battle cry. Cut to a wider shot of The Boulder as his foot strikes the
                ground again, the screen flashes black and white again as another shock wave is
                shown moving out from him. Cut back to a frontal shot of the Bandit who has begun to
                swing her right foot in an arc toward the ground in font of her. As she strikes the
                ground, the view cuts to a wide shot from behind and above on her right. The frame
                rate speeds up to normal. Her strike creates a shock wave in the arena floor that
                churns up the ground in the direction of the Boulder in a straight
                line.</description>
            <description>A quick shot of Aang staring incredulously at the camera, his face turning
                to follow the Bandit's shock wave. Cut back to a frontal shot of The Boulder whose
                foot meets the shock wave just as he puts it back on the ground. The shock wave
                makes him drop down onto the ground in a perfect split. Cut briefly to Momo and
                Sokka. Momo squeaks and Sokka's look of adulation and excitement turns to a look of
                pain. Cut to a close shot from above The Boulder. He looks up into the camera with a
                look of excruciating pain on his face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Painfully.</charAction> Ooooooh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to the Bandit who makes a chopping motion with her right hand.
                Three stalagmites erupt from the ground near The Boulder and eject him from the
                ring. He slams into the wall beneath the stands and slides down into the crevice
                between the arena and the stands.</description>
            <description>Shift to a close-up of the Bandit's face, which softens into a crafty and
                satisfied smile as Xin Fu speaks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>Your winner, and still the champion, <charAction>Cut to a wider shot of the Bandit,
                who raises her right fist in victory.</charAction> the Blind Bandit!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How did she do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>She waited ... and listened.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a wide shot of the announcer's tower as Xin Fu jumps down and lands
                next to Toph on the arena floor. He holds a green bag in his left
                hand.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>To make things a little more interesting, I'm offering up this sack of gold pieces
            to anyone who can defeat <charAction>He motions toward the champion.</charAction> the
            Blind Bandit! <charAction>He motions toward Toph once again. Silence.</charAction> What?
            No one dares to face her?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I will!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Xin Fu looks disappointed for a moment before the camera cuts to Aang
                entering the ring. The crowd murmurs its approval. Shift to a long, wide shot of
                Aang as he closes the distance between himself and the Bandit. Xin Fu jumps out of
                the screen. Cut to Sokka and Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Go Aang! Avenge The Boulder!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Do people really want to see two little girls fighting
            out here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Audience">Audience</speaker>
        <speech>Oooh.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Aang puts his hands up in a conciliatory gesture.</charAction> I don't
            really want to fight you. I want to talk to you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Sokka and Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Boo! No <charAction>Katara turns to her brother with a look of
                disapproval.</charAction> talking!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slaps Sokka.</charAction> Don't boo at him!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Aang's feet; he takes a step. Cut back to the Bandit, who smiles as
                soon as his foot hits the ground. She stomps the ground with the side of her left
                foot. A shock wave travels across the ground and causes a large rock to grow out of
                the ground underneath Aang, who is launched into the air. He lands softly on the
                ground behind her. She turns around with an upset expression on her
                face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Somebody's a little light on his feet! What's your fighting name: <charAction>Cut to
                Aang.</charAction> the Fancy Dancer? <charAction>Aang grins sheepishly before Toph
                launches another pillar, which lifts him up.</charAction> Where'd you go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Please, wait!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>There you are!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She launches a rock at him. He stops it with airbending and the blast
                knocks Toph out of the ring. Quick shots of Xin Fu, The Boulder who is recovering
                from his match with the Blind Bandit, and the Water Tribe siblings as they confirm
                their collective shock. Cut back to Aang, who looks around in surprise as the crowd
                cheers. Cut to a shot of the Bandit walking away from the base of the arena. In the
                background is a set of stairs. Aang is at the top of the stairs and he calls after
                the former champion.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Going after her.</charAction> Please, listen! I need an earthbending
            teacher, and I think it's supposed to be you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Whoever you are, just leave me alone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph earthbends a doorway and exits through it. She turns and closes the
                door with a motion of her hands.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Wait!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang reaches the wall too late. He turns and looks sad. Cut to Xin Fu
                holding the belt and the bag of gold, the crowd cheering behind them. Katara and
                Sokka enter the frame from the right. Sokka hugs Xin Fu and takes the money and the
                belt. He puts his arm around Aang's shoulder, but the Avatar is still
                morose.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gets the belt and gold.</charAction> Way to go, champ!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang looks down sorrowfully. Cut to the next morning, featuring a wide shot
                of Gaoling before zooming in on Team Avatar walking within the town.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I've got to admit, now I'm really glad I bought this bag. It matches the belt,
            perfectly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> That is a big relief.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>If we want to find the Blind Bandit, the Earthbending Academy is a great place to
            start.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The same two male students from yesterday are seen
                practicing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech>Oh great, you again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Glares at them, causing them to back off.</charAction> Yeah, I didn't
            think so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smugly.</charAction> Nicely done.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! You're that kid who beat the Blind Bandit!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We need to talk to her. Do you guys know where she lives?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech>The Blind Bandit's a mystery. <charAction>Raises fist dramatically.</charAction> She
            shows up to fight, then disappears.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lays hands on Aang's shoulder.</charAction> Let me handle this.
                <charAction>Approaches the second student with a stern look; says
                accusingly.</charAction> You're not telling us everything!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student #2">Male student #2</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holds hand up defensively.</charAction> No, no, I-I swear it's true. No
            one knows where she goes, or who she really is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's because we're asking about the wrong person. In my vision, I saw a girl, in a
            white dress, with a pet flying boar. Know anybody like that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech>Well, a flying boar is the symbol of the Beifong family. They're the richest people
            in town. Probably the whole world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student #2">Male student #2</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, but they don't have a daughter.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>A flying boar is good enough for me. Let's check it out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male student">Male student</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Quietly.</charAction> Yeah, you better leave.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, I got my eye on you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>States coolly.</charAction> Water Tribe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the Earth Rumble VI venue.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>I'm telling you, The Boulder was standing right there. I saw the kid strike, but
            there was no earthbending. Nothing made contact. The Blind Bandit just fell out of the
            ring. She must've took a dive and split the money with the kid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slams the wall, causing rocks to land on his feet; cries out in anger
                and pain.</charAction> Nobody cheats Xin Fu.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Shift to a wide, overhead shot of a walled country estate with a lovely
                garden and many ponds. It is daylight. A shot of the gate tilts up to reveal a crest
                with a flying boar emblazoned upon it. Cut to the three kids spying on the
                gate.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's the flying boar from my vision. Come on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They enter the courtyard. Suddenly, part of the ground lifts up, launching
                them into the air. They yell as they fall and land unceremoniously; Aang and Katara
                land in some rose bushes, but Sokka slams painfully onto the solid ground. Aang
                looks up; cut to an upside down shot of the Bandit, now in her fancy
                gown.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing here, Twinkle Toes?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>How did you know it was me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Don't answer to Twinkle Toes, it's not manly!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're the one whose bag matches his belt.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>How did you find me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Well, a crazy king told me I had to find an earthbender who listens to the earth.
            And then I had a vision in a magic swamp, <charAction>Toph raises her eye in
                disbelief.</charAction> and -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cutting off Aang.</charAction> What Aang is trying to say is, he's the
            Avatar. And if he doesn't master earthbending soon, he won't be able to defeat the Fire
            Lord.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Not my problem. Now, <charAction>Begins walking away.</charAction> get out of here,
            or I'll call the guards.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Look, we all have to do our part to win this war, and yours is to teach Aang
            earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Guards! Guards, help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The gang scatters as two guards arrive.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, what happened?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I ... thought I heard someone. I got scared.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Guard">Guard</speaker>
        <speech>You know your father doesn't want you wandering the grounds without supervision,
            Toph.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They escort her and Aang peers at them from over a rooftop. He smiles and
                climbs down. Fade quickly to a shot of a teapot being picked up by a pair of arms
                that belong to someone in a brown or gold robe. The fingers have two gold rings on
                them. The camera follows the teapot as it is lifted up and opened. Lao and Poppy sit
                on a sofa drinking tea.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes a sip of tea.</charAction> I'm pleased to hear that Toph's private
            lessons are going well. But I want to be sure she's not trying anything too
            dangerous.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech>Absolutely not. I am keeping her at a beginner's level. Basic forms and breathing
            exercises only.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Very good. <charAction>A servant comes in.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>Excuse me, sir, but you have a visitor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Who thinks they are so important they can just come to my home unannounced?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Servant">Servant</speaker>
        <speech>Uh ... the Avatar, sir. <charAction>Toph's eyes widen in shock and
                surprise.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Lao and Poppy look at each other. The servant goes away. Toph blows her
                hair in annoyance. The scene fades to inside the dining room, where the Beifongs,
                Yu, and Team Avatar gather for a dinner of soup, tea, roast duck, and tea. Aang sits
                across from Toph. Sokka devours his food. Servant brings a cup of soup to Toph. Lao
                notices.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Blow on it. It's too hot for her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Allow me. <charAction>Sends a small tornado at the cup. Everyone
            claps.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Poppy">Poppy</speaker>
        <speech>Avatar Aang, it's an honor to have you visit us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>In your opinion, how much longer do think the war will last?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'd like to defeat the Fire Lord by the end of summer, but I can't do that without
            finding an earthbending teacher first. <charAction>Close-up of Toph with a annoyed
                look.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> Well, Master Yu is the finest teacher in the
            land. <charAction>The camera pans to Yu.</charAction> He's been teaching Toph since she
            was little.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Then she must be a great earthbender! Probably good enough to teach someone else!
                <charAction>Toph sends a fissure under the table at him.</charAction> Ow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang sits up a little. Lao casts an odd glance at his daughter who merely
                eats her soup.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech>Toph is still learning the basics.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, and sadly, because of her blindness, I don't think she will ever become a true
            master.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I'm sure she's better than you think she is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph sends another fissure at him, causing his face to fall into the soup.
                Everybody stops eating. Aang rubs some soup out of his eyes and sneezes on purpose,
                sending the food flying at the Beifong family.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What's your problem?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Just as angrily.</charAction> What's your
            problem?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Lao and Poppy wipe their faces with napkins.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Poppy">Poppy</speaker>
        <speech>Well, shall we move to the living room for dessert, then?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Later that night, the three are in a guest room. Appa is outside the window
                and Aang is patting Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Good night, buddy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph enters, causing Aang to move into a defensive position.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Relax. Look, I'm sorry about dinner. Let's call a truce, okay? <charAction>Aang lets
                down his defensive position and the two head out to the yard. Toph walks along the
                side of a bridge.</charAction> Even though I was born blind, I've never had a
            problem seeing. <charAction>Jumps down.</charAction> I see with earthbending. It's kind
            of like seeing with my feet. I feel the vibrations in the Earth, and I can see where
            everything is. <charAction>The camera shows an aerial view.</charAction> You, that tree
            ... <charAction>Cut back to the ground.</charAction> even those ants.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks around.</charAction> That's amazing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>My parents don't understand. They've always treated me like I was helpless.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Is that why you became the Blind Bandit?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Then why stay here where you're not happy?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>They're my parents. Where else am I supposed to go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You could come with us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. You guys get to go wherever you want. No one telling you what to do, that's
            the life. It's just not my life. <charAction>She detects something and touches the
                ground.</charAction> We're being ambushed!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They try to run, but get cut off by underground digging from The Gopher.
                They are imprisoned in metal cages. The Hippo jumps onto the two cages and starts
                stomping. The rest of the Earth Rumble wrestlers jump down onto the
                ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech>I think you kids owe me some money.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Later, the Beifongs, Yu, Katara, and Sokka discover what has happened. They
                spot a note attached to a dagger, which Sokka takes.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Whoever took Aang and Toph left this. <charAction>Hands the note to
                Katara.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>"If you want to see your daughter again, bring five hundred gold pieces to the
            arena." It's signed Xin Fu and The Boulder.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Serious.</charAction> I can't believe it ... <charAction>Grabs the note
                much to Katara's surprise and runs off a few feet. Cut to a further off shot;
                enthusiastically.</charAction> I have The Boulder's autograph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka dramatically sinks to his knees and holds the scroll above his head.
                Cut to a close-up of Katara, who stares at him in annoyance. Behind her, Poppy wipes
                the tears out of her eyes and leave her husband's embrace, exciting the
                screen.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Master Yu, I need you to help me get my daughter back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We're going with you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Poppy">Poppy</speaker>
        <speech>Poor Toph, she must be so scared ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At the Earth Rumble VI venue, Toph and Aang are suspended high above the
                air in their cages. The Boulder and Xin Fu guard the two hostages.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You think you're so tough? <charAction>The camera zooms back to show her case and
                Aang's suspended from chains. She points somewhere below her.</charAction> Why don't
            you come up here so I can snap that grin off your face? <charAction>Cut to Xin Fu and
                The Boulder looking from below them on the floor of the arena.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Narrows his eyes. Dryly.</charAction> I'm not smiling.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Toph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Here's your money. <charAction>Sets the bag of gold on the ground.</charAction> Now
            let them go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yu earthbends the money across the ring to Xin Fu. He grabs the money,
                signals for Toph to be sent down, and releases her. Toph goes to Lao. They exit the
                arena.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What about Aang?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Xin Fu">Xin Fu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Showing the Fire Nation wanted poster.</charAction> I think the Fire
            Nation will pay a hefty price for the Avatar. Now, get out of my ring.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fire Nation Man appears in an earth tornado. The Gecko jumps down from the
                ceiling. The Hippo stomps on the ground and crushes a boulder. Headhunter jumps onto
                the ring from the bleachers. The Gopher pops up from underground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Go, I'll be okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, there's too many of them. We need an earthbender. We need you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>My daughter is blind. She is blind and tiny and helpless and fragile. She cannot
            help you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, I can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She lets go of her father's hand and walks back to the ring. Xin Fu's
                wrestlers prepare to leave with The Boulder holding Aang's cage on his shoulder.
                Toph bends up a small part of the ring to stop them from leaving.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Let him go! I beat you all before and I'll do it again!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>The Boulder takes issue with that comment.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Hippo throws the cage to the side. Katara and Sokka prepare to strike
                but Toph stops them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Wait! <charAction>Listens to their vibrations as they run toward her; turns head to
                Sokka.</charAction> They're mine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Water Tribe siblings watch in surprise. She shakes the ring up,
                shooting back the oncoming wrestlers. She enters the resulting dust crowd, unnerving
                Lao.</description>
            <description>Toph creates a large cloud of dust, walks in, and encounters the Fire
                Nation Man, who takes some time to notice her. As he moves his foot to attack, she
                smirks. He fires an wave of earth at her, which she dodges. She bends up part of the
                ring and sends her own wave, ejecting him from the ring as he slams against the
                sidelines and lands on the ground. Lao and Yu watch from the sidelines in
                shock.</description>
            <description>Katara and Sokka try to release Aang. Sokka repeatedly bangs a rock against
                the cage.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hit it harder!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm trying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The Gecko crawls along the floor and becomes aware of Toph's presence. He
                fires two rocks which she easily dodges. She bends up a series of pillars, sending
                him flying out of the ring. Cut to a disoriented Fire Nation Man who slowly gets up
                before he realizes the Gecko heading to him and he crashes into him. The Gopher
                tunnels and behind Toph and sends a rock at Toph's head. She grabs the rock and
                returns it. Cut to The Gopher turning to a distressed look before he gets knocked
                out of the ring and right into Fire Nation Man and the Gecko. Sokka finally breaks
                the cage open, releasing Aang, who prepares to fight. Sokka shakes his head and
                calls his attention to the battle already going on. The Boulder and The Hippo
                prepare to attack Toph. Lao looks on the fight biting his nails. Headhunter flies in
                from behind to complete the ambush. However, Toph hears him and turns the center of
                the ring around to put Headhunter on a collision course with the other two
                wrestlers. With the three men down, Toph ejects them all onto the other defeated
                wrestlers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech>I never knew. Your daughter's amazing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph clears the dust cloud; only her and Xin Fu remain in the ring. Cut to
                Toph who spits. A quick shot of her father, who looks shocked at her lack of
                manners, and Yu. and gets into a fighting stance and they circle the central ring.
                Xin Fu fires several rocks at her. She brings up an earth shield, deflecting them
                all. She turns part of the shield on him. He dodges one piece, but when he hits the
                ring again, Toph picks up his vibrations in it and senses an attack. She dodges a
                rock and creates a fissure, sending him flying out of the ring between Yu and Lao.
                Sokka collapses in shock at the sight. Aang and Katara are left amazed and run
                toward her. Cut back to Yu and Lao.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yu">Yu</speaker>
        <speech>She's the greatest earthbender I've ever seen.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene fades to that night at the Beifong estate. Toph confronts her
                parents.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Dad, I know it's probably hard for you to see me this way. But the obedient little
            helpless blind girl that you think I am just isn't me. I love fighting. I love being an
            earthbender, and I'm really, really good at it. I know I've kept my life secret from
            you, but you were keeping me secret from the whole world. You were doing it to protect
            me, but I'm twelve years old and I've never had a real friend. So, now that you see who
            I really am, I hope it doesn't change the way you feel about me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Of course it doesn't change the way I feel about you, Toph. It's made me realize
            something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It has?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Yes. I've let you had far too much freedom. From now on you'll be cared for and
            guarded twenty-four hours a day.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>But, Dad!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Poppy">Poppy</speaker>
        <speech>We're doing this for your own good, Toph.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>Please escort the Avatar and his friends out. They are no longer welcome
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry, Toph.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry too. Goodbye, Aang. <charAction>She sheds a tear.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Outside, back at Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, we'll find you a teacher. There are plenty of amazing earthbenders out
            there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a wider shot from behind them. The full moon shines in the
                distance.</charAction> Not like her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka polishes the championship belt on Appa's saddle Katara jump up onto
                the saddle and Aang takes the reins. Suddenly, they notice Toph running toward them
                and panting.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Toph! What are you doing here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>My dad changed his mind. He said I was free to travel the world. <charAction>Katara
                and Sokka look at each other with unsure looks, but smile at
            Toph.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, we'd better get out of here, before your dad changes his mind again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Good idea.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're going to be a great teacher, Toph.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Speaking of which, I want to show you something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang jumps down from Appa and she bends up a rock, sending him into the air
                and landing in a tree.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Now we're even. Um, I'll take the belt back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka tosses the belt down, hitting Toph on the head with a sound effect
                and knocking her down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Ow! <charAction>Cut to a wide shot Appa and Toph still laid out
            flat.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang falls down from the tree in the background. Back at the Beifong
                estate, Lao meets with Yu and Xin Fu.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Lao">Lao</speaker>
        <speech>I know you two are very different. But I believe you have a common interest.
                <charAction>A servant brings out a chest of gold. Xin Fu and Yu exchange glances at
                one another.</charAction> The Avatar has kidnapped my daughter. I want you to do
            whatever it takes to bring her home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yu and Xin Fu bow in agreement. A final scene shows Toph, now content, as
                they all fly off on Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
