<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Chase</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to a forested area at sunset. The camera pans downward to
                show Team Avatar, now including Toph, preparing to set up the campsite. Aang hands
                Sokka a sleeping bag. Toph stands on the ground near Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hey! You guys picked a great campsite. <charAction>This directs everyone's attention
                to her. She wriggles her toes in the thick mat of fur covering the ground around the
                bison.</charAction> The grass is so soft.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's not grass. <charAction>Somewhat displeased.</charAction>  Appa's
            shedding.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Displeased, raises foot warily.</charAction> Oh, gross!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to Aang sitting on Appa, a bluebird perched on his head and a yellow
                butterfly fluttering past. Momo jumps up in an attempt to catch the
                butterfly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> That's not gross, it's just a part of spring!
            You know, rebirth, flowers blooming and Appa gets a new coat.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Ah, the beauty of spring.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa, who had currently been grooming himself, sneezes, releasing a thick
                cloud of fur.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waving arms about, now coated in fur.</charAction> Stop! Appa, stop!
            Ugh! <charAction>Coughs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bending over, his back turned to her.</charAction> It's not that bad,
            Katara. <charAction>He turns to reveal a wig made of fur, done up in a towering
                beehive.</charAction> It makes a great wig!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wearing a beard of fur.</charAction> And a great beard! <charAction>Aang
                and Sokka laugh while pointing at each other.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wiping fur off her clothing with her eyes closed.</charAction> I'm just
            glad we finally have another girl in the group, because you two are disgusting.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking up from behind the two boys.</charAction> Excuse me, does anyone
            have a razor? Because I've got some hairy pits!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She raises her arms, revealing that she had stuffed fur in her sleeves. The
                three laugh; Aang sneezes, sending himself flying backward. The big sneeze causes
                him to crash against Appa's leg and for fur to blow off his friends and himself. The
                impact leaves some fur on his back. They continue to laugh joyfully, causing Katara
                to chuckle slightly. The scene cuts to later in the evening where the group is
                setting up camp. Aang sets up the tent while Sokka throws down a pile of firewood he
                collected. Katara, who spends her time stirring around water in a pot, notices Toph
                slumped lazily against a rock, chewing a piece of wheat. She approaches
                her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So Toph, usually when setting up camp, we try to divide up the work.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shrugging casually.</charAction> Hey, don't worry about me. I'm good to
            go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Well, actually what I'm trying to say is, <charAction>Holds arms out in
                gesture.</charAction> some of us might fetch water, while someone else might set up
            the fire pit, or put up the tent. <charAction>Momo flies over to her, dropping several
                berries he had collected into her hands.</charAction> Even Momo does his fair
            share.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Breezily.</charAction> Katara, I'm fine. I can carry my own weight. I
            don't need a fire, <charAction>Pats bag.</charAction> I've already collected my own food
            and look, <charAction>Earthbends a rock tent over her.</charAction> my tent's all set
            up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly irritated.</charAction> Well, that's great for you, but we
            still need to finish -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angered.</charAction> I don't understand what's the problem
            here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waves her hand dismissively and walks away.</charAction> Never
            mind.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph earthbends herself into her tent. Later that day, set up continues.
                Standing on top of Appa, Aang uses airbending to lift the saddle. He mistakenly
                causes it to land directly on top of Sokka, who had been standing on the ground
                beside the bison.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Landing onto the ground to aid Sokka.</charAction> Sorry!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to Katara, who sets down a jug of water. She looks over at Toph,
                sitting comfortably beneath her earth tent. Her dull expression changes to one of
                slight happiness. She approaches Toph who is eating some sort of food
                item.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rubs back of head sheepishly.</charAction> Hey Toph, I wanted to
            apologize for earlier. I think we're all just a little tired and getting on each other's
            nerves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Casually.</charAction> Yeah, you do seem pretty tired.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Growing disgusted.</charAction> I meant all of us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of inside Toph's earth tent as she lazily tosses the food item
                onto the ground and lays her head down to rest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Well, good night.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly irked.</charAction> Good night.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara turns around and leaves. The scene changes to nightfall hours later
                where everyone is asleep. Toph is suddenly startled awake. She rises and presses her
                left hand to the ground to feel the vibrations within the earth. Close-up on her
                left hand and ear, indicating she hears something. She rises to her feet and runs
                out of the tent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>There's something coming toward us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pressing hand to the ground.</charAction> It feels like an avalanche,
            but also not an avalanche.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Your powers of perception are
            frightening.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Should we leave?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Better safe than sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of the forest, a cloud of smoke billowing toward them in a
                clearing in the distance. Appa appears on screen, the team riding atop him. Aang
                leans against the saddle to peer at the object.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What is that thing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to a shot of a tank train mechanism racing speedily along the ground.
                Cuts to shot of the night sky, the moon partly obscured by clouds. Cuts to Aang who
                yawns sleepily, dark circles beginning to form under his eyes. Cuts to Sokka who
                appears ready to fall asleep as he leans his head on his hand. Cuts to Toph and
                Katara sitting on Appa's saddle idly. Cuts to Appa who flies over mountainous
                terrain and lands on a smooth, rocky surface.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Leaping off Appa and lying on the ground, relieved.</charAction> Ah,
            land sweet land! <charAction>Rises and says cheerfully.</charAction> See you guys in the
            morning!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, can you help us unload?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Really? You need me to help unload Sokka's
            funky-smelling sleeping bag?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang hands Sokka his sleeping bag which he proceeds to smell. Sokka turns
                away, his disgusted face growing red, and falls backward, passing out.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curtly.</charAction> Well, yeah. That and everything else. You're a part
            of our team now, and -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points a finger at Katara in irritation.</charAction> Look! I didn't ask
            you to help unload my stuff! <charAction>Turns and begins walking away.</charAction> I'm
            carrying my own weight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> That's not the point. <charAction>Approaches
                Toph.</charAction> Ever since you joined us, you've been nothing but selfish and
            unhelpful!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enraged.</charAction> What? Look here, sugar queen, <charAction>Points
                finger at Katara.</charAction> I gave up everything I had so that I could teach Aang
            earthbending. So don't you talk to me about being selfish!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>While she is saying this, a fuming Katara is seen tensing her muscles in
                frustration and raising her hand in an attempt to speak. After finished speaking,
                Toph sits down on the ground and earthbends an earth tent over her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Furiously.</charAction>
            <description>"Sugar queen"</description>?! <charAction>Toph uses earthbending to close
                the door of the tent.</charAction> D-did you just slam the door in my face?! How can
            you be so infuriating?!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Sokka and Aang standing several feet away. Katara angrily
                bangs her fists against the door of the wall and kicks the tent's walls with her
                feet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Should we do something?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Amused.</charAction> Hey, I'm just enjoying the show.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching Katara.</charAction> Okay, okay, you both need to calm
            down.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>"Both"?! <charAction>Rapidly turns to face Aang, her expression crazed and her eyes
                bloodshot.</charAction>
            <description>I'm completely calm!!</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Awkwardly.</charAction> I ... can see that. <charAction>Backs
                off.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to later at night, showing shot of the dark forest. Cuts to
                shot of Aang, Sokka and Katara lying on the ground. Aang is lying on the ground with
                Momo beside him while Sokka and Katara lie in sleeping bags.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> The stars sure are beautiful tonight. Too bad
            you can't see them, Toph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph uses earthbending to release a fissure that channels underground and
                sends Katara flying into the air. She lands on top of Sokka, startling
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed; pushes Katara off to the side.</charAction> Hey, how's a guy
            supposed to sleep with all this yelling <charAction>To Toph.</charAction> and
            earthquaking?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Reopens her tent.</charAction> That thing is back!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, how far away is it? <charAction>Lies down and pulls covers of his sleeping bag
                over his head; says in a muffled voice.</charAction> Maybe we can close our eyes
            just for a few minutes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans upward to reveal smoke billowing from behind the
                treetops.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Notices the smoke.</charAction> I don't think so, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to a shot of Appa soaring away from the scene over the mountainous
                terrain. Cuts to a side-view of the tank train speeding across the
                land.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Seriously, what is that thing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>And how does it keep finding us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Resting against the saddle; Sokka is seen lying on his back,
                sleeping.</charAction> I don't know. But this time, I'm going to make sure we lose
            it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to a side-view of Appa flying past a mountain. Fades to scene of him
                flying between two mountain ridges. The bison lands on his side on a flat-surfaced
                rock bed, throwing everyone onto the ground along with their
                belongings.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Lands onto the ground.</charAction> Okay, forget about setting up camp.
                <charAction>Crawls along the ground in sleeping bag.</charAction> I'm finding the
            softest pile of dirt and going to sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily; pulling her sleeping bag under her head as a
                pillow.</charAction> That's good because Toph wasn't going to help anyway!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated; lying on bag.</charAction> Oh, I didn't realize the baby
            still needed someone to tuck her in bed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Come on guys, there's something after us and we don't even know what
                <charAction>Pulls top part of his shirt over his head; says in a muffled
                voice.</charAction> or who it is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It could be Zuko. <charAction>Rolls over on her side.</charAction> We haven't seem
            him since the North Pole.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Who's Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Puts his head down.</charAction> Oh, just some angry freak with a
            ponytail who's tracked us all over the world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Mockingly.</charAction> What's wrong with ponytails, Ponytail?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points to his top-knot.</charAction> This is a warrior's wolf
            tail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Jokingly.</charAction> Well, it certainly tells the other warriors that
            you're fun and perky.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Raises head, unamused.</charAction> Anyway, whoever's chasing us
            couldn't have followed us here, so, now would everyone just shhh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo hops onto his sleeping bag and chitters excitedly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hold up finger to silence the lemur.</charAction> No Momo, shhh.
                <charAction>Relaxes.</charAction> Sleepy time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo hops off Sokka and over to the ledge of the rock. He continues to
                chitter and raises his ears up in alert. Aang rises, followed by Toph and
                Katara.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Buries face in hands.</charAction> Oh, don't tell me ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That's impossible. There's no way they could have tracked us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I can feel it with my own two feet!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang runs to the edge of the cliff next to Momo and notices smoke rising
                from the far end of the rocky pathway. Cuts to a shot of the tank train as it
                rumbles up a slope and onto level ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Let's get out of here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Maybe we should face them. Find out who they are.
            Who knows, maybe they're friendly.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Hopelessly.</charAction> Always the optimist ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to a side-view of the tank train as it slows to a halt. The door to
                one compartment opens, releasing a burst of steam. From the mist emerges three
                Mongoose Lizards. Cuts to side-view as Ty Lee appears on screen, followed by Mai and
                Azula. Cuts to shot of Katara and Aang looking on in shock. The camera pans downward
                to where the three girls stand atop the Lizards. Cuts to shot of Azula, a determined
                look on her face. The three begin racing toward the group.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> It's those three girls from Omashu!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone assumes fighting stances.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> We can take them. Three on three.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Actually Toph, there's four of us.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't count you. You know, no
            bending and all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to her, his face distorted with rage.</charAction> I can still
            fight!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smugly.</charAction> Okay, three on three plus Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Face turns red.</charAction> Errrgh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph earthbends three columns in an attempt to hinder the girls, however,
                the Mongoose Lizards merely leap over the pillars and continues on their
                way.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, we wanted to find out who they were and we found out. <charAction>Puts
                boomerang away; Aang and Katara are seen fleeing.</charAction> Now let's get out of
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph earthbends a huge rock wall in front of the trio. Cuts to Azula who
                moves her arms in a circular motion, generating lightning. She fires the bolt at the
                wall, blowing a huge hole in it. Shows the lizards as they clamber through the hole.
                Toph is clearly shocked at this. Cuts to Mai who swings her arm, releasing a flurry
                of stilettos. Toph launches herself off a pillar. The darts strike the pillar and
                she lands on Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Appa, yip yip!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They manage to escape successfully, narrowly avoiding a blue fire blast.
                Cuts to shot of Azula who lowers her arm and looks up at the retreating group. Cuts
                to a sleepy Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> I can't believe those girls followed us all the
            way from Omashu.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grumpily.</charAction> I still think we could have taken them.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Are you kidding me? <charAction>Points fingers upward repeatedly in
                gesture.</charAction> The crazy blue firebending and the flying daggers are bad
            enough, but last time we saw them, one of those girls did something that took my bending
            away. That's scary.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the landscape, a prairie below, mountains in
                the distance. The sun is seen rising over the horizon as Appa soars
                past.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Complaining.</charAction> Oh no, the sun is rising. We've been up all
            night with no sleep!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Sokka, we'll be okay.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Are you sure? I've never not slept before!
                <charAction>Holds hands up to his head.</charAction> What if I fall asleep now and
            something happens? <charAction>Freaks out; eyes bulge out.</charAction> And something
            always happens!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Every time we land, those girls are there. So we'll just have to keep
            flying.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Appa flying past the sun.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We can't keep flying forever.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a field where a few flowers are growing. The tank
                train speeds by rapidly, slicing the heads of the flowers off. Cuts to ground level,
                indentation marks from the train in the ground and a pair of ostrich horse legs
                galloping by. Zuko is seen riding on his ostrich horse, a look of determination on
                his face. Cuts to an overhead view of him running to the left of the indentation
                marks. The scene changes back to Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Yawns.</charAction> So what's our plan?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slumped against the saddle, exhausted.</charAction> Don't know ... too
            tired to think.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sure we'll come up with something after a short nap.
                <charAction>Smiles.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Relieved.</charAction> Yes ... sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two begin nodding off before slowly rising into the air, wind blowing
                through their clothing as they lose altitude. The camera pans to the right, showing
                Toph hanging onto the saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frantically.</charAction> What's going on?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera pans to the right to reveal Aang hanging in the air, gripping Appa's
                reins tightly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Appa fell asleep!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Appa, whose eyes are closed and legs are sprawled out, as
                he falls through a cloud toward the ground. Katara hangs onto her brother tightly.
                Aang crawls over to Appa's head and leans over to face the bison.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Urgently.</charAction> Wake up, buddy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of one of Appa's eyes as it slowly creaks open and widens in
                realization of the current situation. Having awakened, he resumes his normal flight,
                soaring just above the treetops. Toph, Sokka, Katara and Momo sway to the side still
                tightly gripping the saddle. Appa soars through the trees, colliding into and
                snapping several branches. Cuts to shot of the team members who brace against the
                impact. The camera zooms out to depict a flock of birds resting in the trees,
                fleeing from the incident, before panning downward to show Appa on the ground,
                having created a channel way behind him from the impact. Cuts to shot of Appa
                sleeping once more; Aang slides off his head and onto the ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Appa's exhausted.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Trudging across the ground, carrying his sleeping bag.</charAction>
            Okay, we've put in a lot of distance between us and them. The plan right now is to
            follow Appa's lead and get some sleep.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> Of course, we could've gotten some sleep
            earlier, <charAction>Depicts shot of Toph lying on the ground sleepily.</charAction> if
            Toph didn't have such issues.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wakes up and slams the ground; screams furiously.</charAction>
            What!?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Trying to calm the tension.</charAction> All right, all right,
            everyone's exhausted! Let's just get some rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises and faces Katara.</charAction> No, I want to hear what Katara has
            to say. You think I have issues?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> I'm just saying. Maybe if you helped out
            earlier, we could have set up our camp faster and gotten some sleep
                <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> and then maybe we wouldn't be in this
            situation!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of entire campsite, Katara, Toph and Aang standing by Appa,
                while Sokka lies sleepily on his sleeping bag several yards away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You're blaming me for this?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara tosses aside her sleeping bag and gestures with her hands,
                challenging Toph to move closer. Aang jumps in between the two.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Desperately.</charAction> No! No, she's not blaming you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> No, I'm blaming her!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, <charAction>Shoves Aang out of the way.</charAction> I never asked you for
            diddly-doo-dah. <charAction>Points her thumb at herself.</charAction> I carry my own
            weight. Besides, if there's anyone to blame, it's Sheddy over here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting on Appa's tail.</charAction> What? You're blaming Appa?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, you want to know how they keep finding us? <charAction>Grabs a handful of
                Appa's fur and lets the sheddings blow away in the wind.</charAction> He's leaving a
            trail everywhere we go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Jumps down to face her.</charAction> How dare you blame Appa! He saved
            your life three times today! If there's anyone to blame it's you! You're always talking
            about how you carry your own weight, but you're not. He is! Appa's carrying your weight.
            He never had a problem flying when it was just the three of us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stomps the ground, launching her pack into the air which she
                catches.</charAction> I'm out of here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Moves in front of Toph, his arms outstretched to halt her.</charAction>
            Wait!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph uses earthbending to shift Sokka off to the side, leaving him
                surprised. Cuts to shot of fur drifting in the sky. Cuts to ground level view of the
                tank train speeding across the terrain. Cuts to overhead shot of Aang who raises his
                arms up, his eyes sorrowful.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What did I just do? <charAction>Slumps.</charAction> I can't believe I yelled at my
            earthbending teacher. Now she's gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Regretfully.</charAction> I know. We're all just trying to get used to
            each other. And I was so mean to her.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>From afar, drinking from a cup.</charAction> Yeah, you two were pretty
            much jerks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Thanks, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No problem.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We need to find Toph and apologize.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, but what are we going to do about the tank full of dangerous ladies chasing
            us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs a handful of fur and watches as it blows away in the
                wind.</charAction> I have a plan.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Appa lies in the water. The camera zooms out to
                a shot of him lounging in the Nan Shan River, two arched streams of water showering
                him on either side. Cuts to shot of the river's surface where clumps of fur collect
                in the water. Cuts to a shot of the top of Appa's head where Momo lands, holding a
                brush. He scrubs the bison's head and is forced to hastily take flight when a stream
                of water is bent his way. Cuts to shot of Appa's head, Sokka standing in the river
                several feet away, holding a brush. He groans as he becomes drenched by the stream
                of water. The scene changes to the campsite where Appa stands on the ground, his fur
                still wet from the bath. Sokka can be seen standing by the riverbank, wringing out
                his shirt.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Toph was right. The fur was leaving a trail right to us. But now that he's clean, no
            more trail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Are you sure he's okay to fly?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>He'll be fine as long as we leave his saddle and all our stuff here.
                <charAction>Kneels down and places pieces of Appa's fur into his
                satchel.</charAction> I'm going to use Appa's fur to make a fake trail to lead the
            tank off-course.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of the treetops. Appa grunts and takes flight, Sokka and
                Katara riding atop him. As he flies away, his body accidentally brushes against the
                treetops, snapping the topmost limbs off and causing them to fall to the ground.
                Aang watches as the bison flies away and turns. Taking a running start, he flies
                away from the scene on his glider, releasing patches of fur from the bag along the
                way, creating a misleading trail.</description>
            <description>Cuts to shot of a mountain range, fog partially obscuring their peaks. The
                camera pans downward to show Toph walking slowly along a pathway on her own. Cuts to
                side-view of her as she halts, having detected something nearby. Cuts to ground
                level shot of her foot which shifts abruptly in the opposite direction. Cuts to shot
                of her as she turns her head swiftly. She uses earthbending to send a stream of
                earth toward the unknown source. The stream of earth travels its way to a large rock
                ahead and a dust cloud erupts in the air from the impact. A grunt of pain is heard
                from behind the rock. Cuts to shot of Toph who approaches the rock still assuming a
                fighting stance. Cuts to shot of Iroh, his back to the camera as he kneels over and
                rubs his rear in pain. Cuts to shot of his face as he grimaces from the
                incident.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Ow ... That really hurt my tailbone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to the Nan Shan River, the camera panning slightly
                downward to show patches of Appa's fur clinging to rocks. Azula's hands appear on
                screen as she grabs hold of two patches of fur and lifts to examine
                them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off camera; dryly.</charAction> Wads of wet fur. How
            delightful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thoughtfully.</charAction> Hmmm ... they're not wads, they're more like
            bundles, or bunches? <charAction>Scratching her head.</charAction> It's got an "uh"
            sound.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unamused.</charAction> Clumps?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Clasps her hands together and says brightly.</charAction> Clumps!
            They're clumps! <charAction>Hugs Mai.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to close-up of Mai, still being embraced by Ty Lee, who peers down.
                Cuts to shot of the fake fur trail, the camera panning upward to reveal the
                direction in which it is traveling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Azula, pointing in direction of the trail.</charAction> The trail
            goes this way.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula, who had been bending over, examining the fur, rises and looks in the
                direction of the trail. She averts her gaze upward. Cuts to shot of the broken
                treetops.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar's trying to give us the slip. <charAction>Pointing to the broken
                treetops.</charAction> You two head in that direction and keep your eye out for the
            bison. <charAction>Looking down at fur trail.</charAction> I'll follow this
            trail.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Azula who narrows her eyes. Cuts to ground level shot as
                Mai and Ty Lee ride away on their mongoose lizards. As they disappear from sight,
                Azula's mongoose lizard comes into view, the Fire Nation princess mounted on top.
                She pulls on the reigns and heads in the opposite direction, following the fake
                trail. Cuts to overhead shot of the area, Mai and Ty Lee seen traveling to the right
                of the screen, Azula to the left. Cuts to shot of Azula, who races toward the
                camera.</description>
            <description>The scene changes to another area of the forest, a cluster of trees growing
                on a rocky ledge overlooking the rest of the forest, the river channeling right
                through the landscape. Mountains are seen in the distance. Aang comes into view,
                flying on his glider, releasing the fur from his satchel. He exits the lush, green
                landscape area and soars over a more arid, rugged terrain. Camera briefly focuses on
                him, his eyes tired from lack of sleep as he peers down and looks
                forward.</description>
            <description>The camera pans upward to depict an old abandoned town, Tu Zin, similar to
                historical Western towns. Aang heads toward the town, still dropping fur. Cuts to
                side-view of the front of the town as he lands on the ground. Cuts to show the rest
                of the town. Aang's legs come into view and he twirls his glider staff closed. Cuts
                to overhead shot of him walking through the middle street way of the town, casually
                dropping fur. Cuts to shot of old store, the shutters creaking and a bell tolling in
                the wind. Cuts to side-view of Aang as he continues walking forward. Cuts to
                close-up of him as he averts his eyes sleepily from side-to-side. Cuts to shot of
                building and a side-view of him walking shown from in between two
                buildings.</description>
            <description>Cuts to shot of the ground, the camera panning upward to show the satchel
                being held upside-down, the remaining fur dropping onto the ground. Cuts to overhead
                shot of him as he opens his glider. He turns to face the horizon. Cuts to shot of
                him looking into the distance, his back to the screen. He looks down. Cuts to shot
                of him standing at the end of the town as he twirls his glider closed. He sits down
                on the ground cross-legged. The camera zooms out on the town. The scene changes to
                where Appa lazily soars overhead in the forest. Cuts to shot of Sokka and Katara
                mounted on him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surveying the woods.</charAction> Toph couldn't have made it too far.
                <charAction>Momo begins to chitter and rears up defensively.</charAction> What is
            it, Momo? Ooooh, no! Katara!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to overhead shot of Sokka sitting on Appa's tail, Mai and Ty Lee
                following the bison in hot pursuit, mounted on mongoose lizards.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked; urges Appa forward.</charAction> How did they find us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to side-view of Appa who flies dangerously close to the tree line,
                growing more and more tired.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Urgently.</charAction> Appa, come on, we need to go faster!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He's too tired!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frantically.</charAction> Not good, not good! <charAction>Appa grunts.
                Cuts to ground level view of Mai and Ty Lee chasing after them. Cuts to shot of Appa
                heading toward the river.</charAction> We just need to make it across that
            river!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pleading.</charAction> Come on Appa, just a little further ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to side-view of Appa who continues his descent, snapping off several
                treetops in the process. Cuts to shot from directly beneath Appa who crashes into
                another treetop, causing it to fall toward the screen. Cuts back to Mai and Ty Lee
                who chase after them. Cuts to Mai who swings her arm, firing a flurry of stilettos.
                Cuts back to Sokka who narrowly avoids the weapons by ducking. Cuts to view of Appa
                skimming the surface of the Nan Shan River before crashing into the ground on the
                opposite side of the river. Cuts to shot from the other side of the river, Appa's
                backside seen in the distance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> We made it! We're safe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> You did it Appa!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to riverbank where the siblings embrace. Katara opens her eyes and
                gasps. Sokka turns around and becomes horrified. Cuts to side-view of the mongoose
                lizards paddling the water rapidly, allowing for them to walk over the surface of
                the river. Katara steps forward and spins around, sending a wave of water crashing
                into Ty Lee's mongoose lizard. Ty Lee leaps off the beast just in time and emerges
                from the water. She lands near the treetops where she gracefully dodges from tree
                trunk to tree trunk in pursuit of Katara, who opens her water skin.</description>
            <description>Ty Lee somersaults onto the ground. Katara attempts to lash a water whip in
                her direction, however, is forced to quickly dodge several of the acrobat's blows.
                She narrowly avoids having her chi blocked and fires several sharp discs of water at
                her enemy, who cartwheels repeatedly to escape. Cuts to shot of Mai still mounted on
                her lizard. She turns around and fires several stilettos from uploaded holsters in
                her sleeves. Cuts to quick shot of the stilettos before one of Katara still fending
                off Ty Lee, her back to the camera. Sokka steps on-screen and knocks the stilettos
                off-target with his machete and boomerang.</description>
            <description>He throws his boomerang in Mai's direction, however, the knife thrower
                merely leaps off her lizard, avoiding the attack. She spins around and fires
                stilettos from a holster in her leg. Sokka knocks them away again with his machete.
                Cuts to shot of Mai, who runs forward. Cuts to view of Katara, Sokka seen in the
                background. Katara turns around and is forced on the run when Mai comes charging
                toward her. Cuts to shot of Ty Lee, who runs toward the camera. She somersaults and
                leaps into the air where she flips and lands on the ground near Sokka.</description>
            <description>She lands several quick blows on Sokka, using chi blocking to incapacitate
                Sokka's right arm. Sokka drops his boomerang as a result of this. He swings his left
                arm toward Ty Lee who merely incapacitates that arm, resulting in him dropping his
                machete. Sokka looks about him nervously and resorts to kicking his leg in order to
                fend off the acrobat who proceeds to render his leg useless. Sokka proceeds to use
                his forehead as a shield. Ty Lee strikes his skull and injures her hand in the
                process. She backs away and shakes her fist in pain before turning to glare at
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Well off-balance.</charAction> Good try, but no.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of a tree growing near the riverbank. Katara appears on screen
                and halts in front of the tree. She begins to draw a stream of water with which to
                attack Mai, however, the knife thrower hurls two shuriken knives her way. Each of
                the two knives pins her wrists to the tree trunk. Katara gasps in horror. Cuts to
                side-view of the riverbank as the stream of water falls into the river again and
                Sokka hobbles on-screen as a result of the paralysis. He falls to the
                ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>How are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frantically.</charAction> Well, you know ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mai">Mai</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Dryly.</charAction> I thought when Ty Lee and I finally caught you guys,
            it would be more exciting. Oh well, victory is boring.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two are suddenly swept off their feet by a powerful gust of wind
                conjured by Appa's tail. They incidentally somersault into the air and land several
                yards away in the water. Cuts to shot of riverbank, Appa shaking his tail, his back
                facing the camera.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Still lying on the ground.</charAction> Thanks Appa, I don't know what
            we'd do without you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa sweeps his large tongue over Sokka's face, covering him in drool.
                Sokka expresses irritation at this, his eyebrow twitching. Cuts to overhead shot of
                the forest behind the river and pans downward to the opposite side of the riverbank
                where Mai and Ty Lee arrive at its edge, drenched.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ty Lee">Ty Lee</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Wringing out her braid.</charAction> Was it just me, or was that guy
            kind of cute?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Mai casts an annoyed glance off to the side. The scene changes to Tu Zin
                where Aang still sits cross-legged, awaiting his enemy. Cuts to close-up of his face
                before a shot of him looking out over the horizon where Azula appears, riding on her
                mongoose lizard in a cloud of dust. Cuts to a side-view shot of her as she closes in
                on the town. Cuts to faraway shot of Aang sitting at the end of the village. Azula
                appears on-screen. Cuts to shot of the ground, covered in fur, where Azula's feet
                land as she dismounts. Cuts to overhead shot of the town.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>All right, you've caught up with me. Now, who are you and what do you want?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Coolly.</charAction> You mean you haven't guessed? You don't see the
            family resemblance? Here's a hint. <charAction>Covers her eye and deepens her voice,
                imitating Zuko.</charAction> I must find the Avatar to restore my honor!
                <charAction>Aang remains silent; back in her normal voice.</charAction> It's okay,
            you can laugh. It's funny.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So what now?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts to view of her left side.</charAction> Now? Now, it's over. You're
            tired and you have no place to go. <charAction>Cuts to view of her face.</charAction>
            You can run, but I'll catch you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises to face her.</charAction> I'm not running.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to close-up of Azula, who smirks. Cuts to shot of the sun setting over
                the mountains. The camera pans downward to show Toph and Iroh sitting in a rocky
                outcrop. Cuts to shot of a tea kettle heating over a fire. Iroh can be seen in the
                background, sitting next to it. He pours tea into two tin cups.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Handing her a cup of tea.</charAction> Here is your tea.
                <charAction>Cuts to shot of Toph staring blankly at the ground and back to
                Iroh.</charAction> You seem a little too young to be traveling alone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Taking the tea from his hand.</charAction> You seem a little too
            old.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Perhaps I am.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Casually.</charAction> I know what you're thinking ... I look like I
            can't handle being by myself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I wasn't thinking that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You wouldn't even let me pour my own cup of tea!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I poured your tea because I wanted to and for no other reason.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>People see me and think I'm weak. They want to take care of me, but I can take care
            of myself, by myself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You sound like my nephew, always thinking you need to do things on your own, without
            anyone's support. There is nothing wrong with letting the people who love you help you.
            Not that I love you, I just met you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> So where is your nephew?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I've been tracking him actually.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Is he lost?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks away; slightly sad.</charAction> Yes, a little bit.
                <charAction>Cuts to shot of the rocky ledge where the two sit, the mountain region
                in the background; voice-over.</charAction> His life has recently changed and he's
            going through very difficult times. He's trying to figure out who he is and he went
            away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>So now you're following him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I know he doesn't want me around him right now, but if he needs me, I'll be
            there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Your nephew is very lucky, even if he doesn't know it. <charAction>Gets up to
                leave.</charAction> Thank you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>My pleasure. Sharing tea with a fascinating stranger is one of life's true
            delights.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> No, thank you for what you said. It helped
            me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I'm glad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises to leave, but turns around briefly.</charAction> Oh, and about
            your nephew, maybe you should tell him that you need him, too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh remains silent and sips his tea. The scene changes back to Tu Zin, the
                camera panning down to depict the town, Azula standing on the opposite side of town
                as Aang. Cuts briefly to Aang and to Azula who smiles smugly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech>Do you really want to fight me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Zuko suddenly appears from an alleyway, leaping off his ostrich horse onto
                the ground, creating a cloud of dust. He stands up straight and throws his conical
                hat aside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, I really do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Zuko!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calmly.</charAction> I was wondering when you'd show up, Zuzu.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Covers mouth to suppress laughter.</charAction> "Zuzu"?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> Back off, Azula! He's mine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Assumes a fighting stance.</charAction> I'm not going anywhere.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the street way where the three opponents stand,
                prepared for battle. Cuts to shot of Azula, confident as ever. Cuts to shot of Zuko,
                who averts his gaze first to Azula before looking toward Aang. Cuts to Aang who
                assumes a fighting stance, pointing his glider at Zuko in fright. Cuts to shot of
                the three from the perspective of the front porch of a store, the camera panning to
                the left from Aang to Azula. Cuts to shot of Zuko, who shifts the position of his
                fingers a bit. Cuts to Aang, who looks about him nervously. Cuts to Azula, who
                continues to smirk in confidence. Cuts to close-up of Zuko, a shot of Aang, before
                switching back to Zuko. Cuts to close-up of Azula, whose smile widens. Cuts to brief
                shot of Zuko.</description>
            <description>Cuts to Azula, who moves her arm forward, firing a blast of blue fire at
                Zuko, who conjures up a fire shield to deflect it. He falls backward onto a front
                porch. Aang, upon seeing this, expresses horror and attempts to flee the town on his
                glider. He begins soaring toward the back end of Tu Zin. Cuts to Azula, who swings
                her arm downward, sending a stream of fire at Aang, who turns over mid-air and
                closes his glider, twirling the object to deflect the flames. Cuts to side-view of
                the town as he lands on the ground, still deflecting the flames. He stops twirling
                his glider.</description>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Azula running along the beam of a rooftop, prepared to
                strike him. Cuts to ground level shot of Aang who rolls over, grabbing hold of his
                glider just as Azula lands nimbly on the ground, sweeping around, sending a stream
                of fire his way. Cuts to shot of the street where Azula rises and turns around, Zuko
                seen standing in the background. Aang leaps on-screen and lands on the ground, in
                between the other two. Zuko fires a blast at Aang who steps to the side, managing to
                avoid the attack. Azula fires at the Avatar and misses.</description>
            <description>After the three perform several unsuccessful attempts to land a blow, Aang
                runs past Azula, who sends another sweep of fire his way. Cut to slanted shot of
                three, Aang trying to escape toward the back end of town, Azula turning to face him
                and Zuko firing blasts of his own. Aang rounds a bend and runs past Azula once more,
                this time heading toward the front of town. Azula fires another blast at him, only
                to miss. Azula fires several more blows, one of which Zuko manages to deflect. He
                fires a shot at Azula and misses.</description>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Azula, who swings her arms about, sending attacks at her
                opponents. Cuts to overhead shot of the town, the three of them continuing to battle
                each other. Cuts to shot of Azula, Zuko appearing on-screen, leaping into the air
                directly behind her and striking the ground, unleashing a firebending attack in the
                process. Cuts to side-view of the two siblings as two walls of fire, one blue and
                one orange are created as a result of the impact. Azula fires a blast at Zuko, who
                ducks and attempts to knock her off her feet. He fires a blast her only for the
                princess to duck. She sweeps her arm upward, sending a stream of fire his way. Zuko
                leaps into the air to avoid the attack. Azula turns around and fires at Aang. Cuts
                to shot of the Avatar, who leaps into the air and lands onto an upper outdoors level
                of a nearby building.</description>
            <description>Azula runs up the stairwell leading to the upper level, forcing Aang to run
                through the open doorway. Cuts to shot of the inside of the doorway; Azula appears
                on-screen and her expression suddenly grows alarmed. She halts in her tracks and
                nearly stumbles. Cuts to view of the entire inside of the building, revealing that
                there is no floor, merely some jagged wooden paneling lining the edges of the wall.
                She windmills in an attempt to steady herself. Cuts to Aang perched atop an air
                ball, smiling gleefully and waving to her. After leaping about a few times, Azula
                manages to prop herself against the wall and regains her balance. Zuko suddenly
                appears in the doorway. He has the misfortune of inaccurate timing and falls roughly
                onto the first level floor with a yell, sending up a cloud of dust. Aang grimaces in
                sympathy.</description>
            <description>The air ball Aang is riding suddenly begins to dissipates. Cuts to Azula,
                who nimbly sends a blast of fire at him. Cuts back to Aang, who leaps out of the way
                just as the air ball is terminated. He runs along the edges along the thin floor
                paneling and knocks Azula onto the first floor in the process. Azula lands nimbly
                onto the ground near Zuko, who is still recovering from his fall. Cuts to the
                outside of the building as Aang exits through the doorway, narrowly avoiding a blue
                fire blast sent by Azula off-screen.</description>
            <description>He lands onto the ground just as Azula bursts through the wall of the
                building through the use of firebending. Zuko lands on the ground unconscious. Cuts
                to shot of Aang, who looks at Zuko before turning around and seeing Azula heading
                straight toward him. He flees and leaps out of the way just as Azula sends another
                blast at him. Aang begins alternately jumping between two buildings, with Azula
                firing blasts off-screen at each spot he lands on. Aang finally reaches the rooftop
                of the left building and scrambles to prop himself up.</description>
            <description>Azula sends a blast of fire, slicing a portion of the rooftop off. Aang
                leaps off the crumbling portion onto another spot on the roof, only for Azula to
                repeat the same action. Cuts to shot Aang, who scrambles to prop himself up only for
                the ceiling to cave in. He lands on the ground inside the building, trapped beneath
                a pile of wooden planks. Azula enters the building through the doorway and sends two
                streams of fire along the sides of the wall. The blue fire spreads around the
                perimeter of the room and turns an orange hue. Cuts to Aang, who looks horrified and
                attempts to break free.</description>
            <description>Cuts to Azula, who smirks and holds up one hand, two fingers pointing
                outward, her typical lightning generation pose. Katara suddenly appears in the
                doorway and sends a water whip at Azula, guiding her hand off course. Katara bends
                the stream of water around her and slices the wooden planks, thus freeing
                Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thrilled.</charAction> Katara!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula swiftly turns around and fires a blast at the waterbender, who races
                out of the building along the porch. Azula follows her in hot pursuit, only to be
                halted by Sokka, who emerges from another doorway and swings his machete her way.
                Katara runs off-camera, while Azula is forced to duck. Sokka begins chasing her.
                Cuts to overhead shot of the town where Azula is now being cornered by him, Katara
                and Aang. Cuts to shot of Zuko still lying on the ground as he regains
                consciousness. Cuts to shot of Iroh standing over him from his perspective, the shot
                slightly blurred to show the effect of being knocked out.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Slightly dazed.</charAction> Uncle ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Get up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He helps Zuko get up. Cuts to shot of Aang as he runs straight toward
                Azula, his back facing the camera. He leaps over her just as Azula fires a blast at
                him which heads directly toward the camera. She turns around and blocks a water whip
                Katara sends at her. She fires a blast at Sokka and swings her arm outward to
                prolong the blast. Aang appears on-screen behind her. She turns around and nearly
                manages to strike him with another blast. Cuts to overhead shot of the three Team
                Avatar members and Azula, who swings her arm outward, sending an arched fire blast
                at the three. Cuts to shot of Azula who stands, poised for attack. Camera pans
                downward to her feet. She suddenly falls over to the side; Toph appears from an
                alleyway, having just shifted the ground beneath her feet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I thought you guys could use a little help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> Thanks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Azula rises to her feet and begins running away. Cuts to shot from the view
                of an alleyway, where Azula appears on-screen and runs through the alley. She leaps
                over some crates and tries to escape, however, Iroh intervenes, using his rotund
                belly to knock her off her feet. Zuko appears on-screen next to him. Cuts to
                overhead shot of Aang, Katara, Sokka, Toph, Zuko and Iroh all cornering Azula
                against the ruins of a stone wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Azula">Azula</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Coolly, backing up as her enemies surround her.</charAction> Well, look
            at this. Enemies and traitors, all working together. I'm done. <charAction>Raises her
                hands in surrender.</charAction> I know when I'm beaten. You got me. A princess
            surrenders with honor.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Iroh, who averts his gaze toward the other members, who
                remain on high alert. The camera switches to his point of view, zooming in on Toph
                and shifting upward to Aang, Katara and Sokka, who still assume fighting stances.
                Cuts briefly to Azula, who smirks, before switching to Toph from Iroh's point of
                view. Cuts to Azula, who smiles and takes a step forward, firing a blast at Iroh,
                who gets hit. He screams in pain and falls to the ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Horrified.</charAction> Aaaah!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The remaining five turn to face Azula, four of them bending their
                respective elements and Sokka throwing his boomerang straight for her. The impact of
                the elements creates a minor explosion, sending a thick cloud of smoke everywhere.
                Cuts to buildings in the town now set alight, burning embers falling from the sky.
                Cuts to shot of Aang as the smoke clears, who looks from his defensive position at
                the effect. Cuts overhead shot of the group surrounding the corner, the smoke
                clearing to reveal Azula having vanished from the scene without a trace. Cuts to
                Zuko, who kneels before his uncle, dismayed at the turn of events.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Ugggh! <charAction>Looks at Team
                Avatar.</charAction> Get away from us!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to Toph, the camera shifting to her foot, showing that she can detect
                the vibrations using seismic sense. Cuts to Iroh, who is still breathing, indicating
                that he is still alive. Katara approaches Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Zuko, I can help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Blasts an arc of fire.</charAction> Leave!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The members of Team Avatar all run away off-screen, leaving Zuko still
                kneeling over Iroh. The camera pans upward to show thick smoke billowing from the
                fire. The scene fades to a mountain at nightfall where Appa lands. Cuts to shot of
                Team Avatar sleeping on the saddle. Camera zooms in on Toph and Katara resting next
                to each other.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
