<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Serpents Pass</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The team is situated at the waterfall pond. Sokka is surveying a map. Toph
                is sitting with her feet in the water, moving it back and forth. Aang is swimming
                while Katara is located at the top of the lake near the waterfall. Aang goes
                underwater for a moment and bends an ice cube around himself for
                amusement.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Waterbending bomb! Yeah! <charAction>Jumps into
                the water.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The splash sends Aang out of the water, breaks his ice prison, and soaks
                Sokka, Toph, and the maps which he tried to protect.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Sure, five thousand year-old maps from the
            spirit library. Just splash some water on 'em.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry. <charAction>Wrings her hair dry and bends the water off the
            map.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So, did you figure out what route we're going to take?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, we just got out of the desert, so we must be around here. And we need to go to
            Ba Sing Se, which is here. It looks like the only passage connecting the south to the
            north is this sliver of land called the Serpent's Pass.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You sure that's the best way to go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's the only way. I mean, it's not like we have Appa to fly us there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Quietly.</charAction> Shush up about Appa. Can't you at least try to be
            sensitive?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, it's okay. I know I was upset about losing Appa before, but I just want to
            focus on getting to Ba Sing Se and telling the Earth King about the solar
            eclipse.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Oh ... well, okay. I'm glad you're doing
            better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Then to Ba Sing Se we go. No more distractions.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly, three refugees arrive.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>Hello there, fellow refugees!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So, you guys are headed to Ba Sing Se, too?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>Sure are. We're trying to get there before my wife Ying has her baby.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Great! We can travel through the Serpent's Pass together.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The three refugees look up in shock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>The Serpent's Pass? Only the truly desperate take that deadly route!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Deadly route. <charAction>Punches Sokka in the arm.</charAction> Great pick,
            Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, we are desperate.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>You should come with us to Full Moon Bay. Ferries take refugees across the lake.
            It's the fastest way to Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>And it's hidden, so the Fire Nation can't find it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hmm ... peaceful ferry ride or deadly pass?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>At Full Moon Bay.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe how many people's lives have been uprooted by the Fire
            Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>We're all looking for a better life, safe behind the walls of Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A ferry departs. Zuko and Iroh are on board.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Who would have thought after all these years, I'd return to the scene of my greatest
            military disgrace ... <charAction>Turns away for a second before turning back with a
                floral hat on his head.</charAction> as a tourist!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Look around. We're not tourists, we're refugees. <charAction>Sips food and spits it
                out.</charAction> Ugh! I'm sick of eating rotten food, sleeping in the dirt. I'm
            tired of living like this!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Aren't we all? My name's Jet and these are my Freedom Fighters, Smellerbee and
            Longshot.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Hey. <charAction>Longshot nods.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Hello.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>Here's the deal. I hear the captain's eating like a king while the refugees have to
            feed off his scraps. Doesn't seem fair, does it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>What sort of king is he eating like?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>The fat, happy kind. <charAction>At this, Iroh's mouth hangs open as he starts to
                drool.</charAction> You want to help us "liberate" some food?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tosses the bowl of rotten food into the water.</charAction> I'm
            in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Jet smirks. </description>
            <description>Back at the station.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>I told you already ... no vegetables on the ferry! One cabbage slug could destroy
            the entire ecosystem of Ba Sing Se! Security!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A platypus bear destroys the cabbage cart.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Cabbage merchant">Cabbage merchant</speaker>
        <speech>Ahhh! My cabbages! <charAction>He is carried away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Next!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Um, four tickets for the ferry to Ba Sing Se, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Passports?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Uh ... no one told us we had to have passports.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Don't you know who this is? He's the Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, I see fifty Avatars a day and, by the way, not a very impressive costume.
                <charAction>The screen pans to show several impostors; notices Momo.</charAction>
            Besides, no animals allowed. Do I need to call security?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The platypus bear chomps down on the cabbage. Momo hides in
                fear.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>That won't be necessary.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Next!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'll take care of this. My name is Toph Beifong, and I'll need four tickets.
                <charAction>Presents her passport.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, the golden seal of the flying boar! It is my pleasure to help anyone of the
            Beifong family.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It is your pleasure. As you can see, I am blind and these three imbeciles are my
            valets. <charAction>Sweeps her arm behind her, presenting her friends to the hesitant
                clerk.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>But, the animal-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>-is my seeing-eye lemur.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Well, normally it's only one ticket per passport, but this document is so official
            ... I guess it's worth four tickets. <charAction>Stamps an approval seal on the
                tickets.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you very much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>All right, we scammed that lady good!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly, a security guard, actually Suki without makeup, grabs
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Tickets and passports please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Is there a problem?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, I got a problem with you! I've seen your type before. Probably sarcastic,
            think you're hilarious and let me guess, you're traveling with the Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Do I know you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>You mean you don't remember? Maybe you'll remember this! <charAction>Kisses Sokka on
                the cheek.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Suki! <charAction>Embraces her.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, it's good to see you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Later, in a different location of the station. The gang and Suki
                talk.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You look so different without your makeup! And the new outfit.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>That crabby lady makes all the security guards wear them. And look at you,
            sleeveless guy. Been working out?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Ahhh, I'll grab a tree branch and do a few chin touches every now and then. Nothing
            major.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Are the other Kyoshi Warriors around?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. After you left Kyoshi, we wanted to find a way to help people. We ended up
            escorting some refugees and we've been here ever since. <charAction>Momo jumps up next
                to her.</charAction> Hi, Momo! Good to see you too! <charAction>Scratches his head
                near his ear.</charAction> So why are you guys getting tickets for the ferry?
            Wouldn't you just fly across on Appa?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Appa is missing. We hope to find him in Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>I'm so sorry to hear that. <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Are you doing
            okay?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm doing fine. Would everybody stop worrying about me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>Avatar Aang, you have to help us! Someone took all of our belongings; our passports,
            our tickets, everything's gone!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll talk to the lady for you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the desk.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>No passports, no tickets! <charAction>Stamps a "denied" stamp on Aang's
                forehead.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But she's pregnant and all of her stuff was stolen! You have to make an
            exception!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>No exceptions! If I just gave away tickets willy-nilly to anyone, there would be no
            more order! You know what that means, no more civilization!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What if we gave them our tickets?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>No!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>But ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ticket lady">Ticket lady</speaker>
        <speech>Next!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, you'll get to the city safely. I'll lead you through the Serpent's
            Pass.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Moments later.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe we gave up our tickets and now we're going through the Serpent's
            Pass.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I can't believe you're still complaining about it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In her normal Kyoshi Warrior attire.</charAction> I'm coming
            too!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Are you sure that's a good idea?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, I thought you'd want me to come.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I do, it's just–</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Just what?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Nothing. I'm glad you're coming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Outside, at the pass.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This is the Serpent's Pass? I thought it would be a little more wind-y, you know,
            like a serpent. Huh, I guess they misnamed it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>Look at this writing! How awful!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What does it say?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It says, "abandon hope".</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>How can we abandon hope? It's all we have!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know. The monks used to say that hope was just a distraction, so maybe we do
            need to abandon it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What are you talking about?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hope is not going to get us into Ba Sing Se and it's not going to help find Appa. We
            need to focus on what we're doing right now and that's getting across this
            path.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, if you say so.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Within the pass.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>The Fire Nation controls the western lake. Rumor has it they're working on something
            big on the other side of it and don't want anyone to find out what it is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They all pass by a sailing Fire Nation ship. A part of the rock gives out,
                causing Than to fall. Toph stops it from falling and lifts him back up with
                earthbending.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>I'm okay! <charAction>The rock falls to the water, which the Fire Nation ship
                notices. It fires.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>They've spotted us! Let's go, let's go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang gets on his glider and deflects the fireball back. Another fireball
                hits the mountain, causing several pieces of rock over Suki to fall. Sokka pushes
                her out of the way. Toph bends out a part of the mountain to keep the rocks from
                falling on Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Suki, are you okay? You have to be more careful! Come on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pretending to be Sokka.</charAction> "Thanks for saving my life, Toph."
            Hey, no problem, Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hours later, at sunset, the travelers set up their camp. Sokka approaches
                Suki.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Suki, you shouldn't sleep there. Who knows how stable this ledge is, it could give
            away at any moment! <charAction>Moves her sleeping bag.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, I'm fine, stop worrying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're right, you're right, you're perfectly capable of taking care of yourself!
            Wait! Oh, never mind, I thought I saw a spider, but, you're fine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back on the ferry. Zuko, Jet, and Smellerbee sneak up to the food storage
                area. Jet breaks the door open with his twin tiger hook swords, and he and Zuko take
                some food.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Guard's coming!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot fires an arrow with a rope attached to it, allowing the three to
                slide down it. Longshot pulls it away before the guard notices. Back at the pass,
                Aang is standing at the edge of the rock, looking out at the ocean, blankly. Katara
                approaches him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You know, it's okay to miss Appa. <charAction>Aang remains silent.</charAction>
            What's going on with you? In the desert, all you cared about was finding Appa and now
            it's like you don't care about him at all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You saw what I did out there. I was so angry about losing Appa that I couldn't
            control myself. I hated feeling like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But now you're not letting yourself feel anything. I know sometimes it hurts more to
            hope and it hurts more to care. But you have to promise me that you won't stop caring.
                <charAction> Holds out her arms.</charAction> Come on, you need a hug.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Bows before her.</charAction> Thank you for your concern, Katara.
                <charAction>Exits.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara shows visible concern.</description>
            <description>In another part of the Pass, Sokka stands by himself, until Suki
                approaches.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>It's a beautiful moon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, it really is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Look, I know you're just trying to help, but I can take care of myself.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know you can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Then why are you acting so overprotective?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's so hard to lose someone you care about. Something happened at the North Pole
            and I couldn't protect someone. I don't want anything like that to ever happen
            again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>I lost someone I care about. He didn't die, he just went away. I only had a few days
            to get to know him, but he was smart and brave and funny ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Jealous.</charAction> Who is this guy? Is he taller than me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>No, he's about your height.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Is he better-looking?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>It is you, stupid!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Oh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two prepare to kiss, but Sokka pulls back at the last
                moment.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I can't.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, you shouldn't be. <charAction>Exits.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back on the ferry. Jet passes out food to other travelers. The other
                Freedom Fighters, Zuko, and Iroh sit together.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>So, Smellerbee. That's an unusual name for a young man.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe it's because I'm not a man ... I'm a girl! <charAction>Walks
                away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Calling out to her.</charAction> Oh, now I see. It's a beautiful name
            for a lovely girl!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot approaches Smellerbee and gestures at her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Smellerbee">Smellerbee</speaker>
        <speech>I know, you're right. As long as I'm confident with who I am, it doesn't matter what
            other people think. Thanks, Longshot.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Longshot nods at her. Jet approaches Zuko and Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>From what I heard, people eat like this every night in Ba Sing Se. I can't wait to
            set my eyes on that giant wall.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>It is a magnificent sight.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>So you've been there before?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Once. When I was a ... different man.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>I've done some things in my past that I'm not proud of, but that's why I'm going to
            Ba Sing Se: for a new beginning. A second chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>That's very noble of you. I believe people can change their lives if they want to. I
            believe in second chances.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the Serpent's Pass. The travelers notice that a section of the pass
                is below the sea level, and not able to be navigated.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone single file! <charAction>She divides the water, allowing everyone to walk
                through the drowned out path.</charAction> Aang, I need help! <charAction>Aang helps
                by creating an air bubble.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Momo's curiosity is aroused by the fish. He dives in the water, only to
                return back when he sees a large shadow. The rest of them notice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What is that thing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shadow breaks through the water, breaking the divide. Toph quickly uses
                her earthbending to raise the ground they are standing on above the water. The
                shadow is actually a large serpent, which appears from the water with a
                shriek.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I think I just figured out why they call it the Serpent's Pass! Suki, you know about
            giant sea monsters, make it go away!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Just because I live near the unagi doesn't mean I'm an expert!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Holds up Momo.</charAction> Oh great and powerful sea serpent, please
            accept this humble and tasty offering. Thank you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Blasts the Serpent back with a burst of air.</charAction> I'll distract
            it. Katara, get everyone across! <charAction>Takes off on his
            glider.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara freezes the water to create an ice trail. Everyone except for Toph
                crosses. Katara tries to ice up the serpent, but it fails.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Toph, come on, it's just ice!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Feels the ice but her sense of sight is restricted.</charAction>
            Actually, I'm going to stay on my little island, where I can see! <charAction>The
                serpent takes out half the island.</charAction> Okay, I'm coming! <charAction>Slowly
                crosses the ice.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're doing great! Just follow the sound of my voice!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It's hard to ignore.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You're almost there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The serpent slams down the ice trail, dropping Toph into a struggle to stay
                above water.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Help! I can't swim!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm coming, Toph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Before he can do anything, Suki jumps in for the save.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph falls below the water, but Suki pulls her up before she
                drowns.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Thinking it is Sokka.</charAction> Oh Sokka, you saved me!
                <charAction>Kisses Suki on the cheek.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, it's me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Oh ... well ... <charAction>Chuckles. Embarrassed.</charAction> you can go ahead and
            let me drown now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, the serpent is caught in a whirlpool created by Aang and Katara.
                The force of it slams the serpent into the mountain, causing it to fall back below
                water. Upon seeing the two return, the rest of the travelers cheer. Moments later,
                near Ba Sing Se's wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>There's the wall! Now it's nothing but smooth sailing to Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Groans in pain.</charAction> Oh no!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What's wrong?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>The baby's coming!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Panicked.</charAction> What? Now? Can't you hold it in or
            something?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, calm down. I helped Gran-Gran deliver lots of babies back home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This isn't the same as delivering an arctic seal! This is a real ... human ...
            thing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's called a baby and I helped her deliver plenty of those, too. Aang, get some
            rags. Sokka, water. Toph, I need you to make an earth tent, a big one. <charAction>Toph
                earthbends the rock to form a tent.</charAction> Suki, come with me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back on the ferry. Jet approaches Zuko.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Jet">Jet</speaker>
        <speech>You know, as soon as I saw your scar, I knew exactly who you were. You're an
            outcast, like me. And us outcasts have to stick together. We have to watch each other's
            backs. Because no one else will.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I've realized lately that being on your own isn't always the best path.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The ferry closes in on the walls. </description>
            <description>Back at the pass. Ying is breathing heavily as the baby delivery
                continues.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're doing great, Ying. Sokka, where's that water? Now get ready to push. One ...
            two ... <charAction>Sokka enters.</charAction> ... three, push!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ying groans; Sokka passes out. Moments later, the baby arrives and begins
                to cry. Aang, Toph, and Sokka are all outside the tent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>From inside the tent.</charAction> It's a girl!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>So, you want to go see the baby, or are you going to faint like an old lady
            again?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No, no, I'm good this time. <charAction>Toph and Sokka enter the
            tent.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, you have to come see this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang enters to see the new life.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>She sounds healthy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>She's beautiful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It's so ... squishy looking.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang begins to smile.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>What should we name her?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>I want our daughter's name to be unique. I want it to mean something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sheds some tears.</charAction> I've been going through a really hard
            time lately. But you've made me ... hopeful again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ying">Ying</speaker>
        <speech>I know what I want to name our baby now. Hope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Than">Than</speaker>
        <speech>That's a perfect name. Hope.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Outside the tent. Aang meets with Katara. Suki, Sokka, and Toph stand next
                to the tent.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I thought I was trying to be strong. But really I was just running away from my
            feelings. Seeing this family together, so full of happiness and love, it's reminded me
            how I feel about Appa ... and how I feel about you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara sheds some tears. Aang and Katara embrace, Katara's eyes still
                watering. The other three approach.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I promise, I'll find Appa as fast as I can. I just really need to do this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>See you in the big city.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Say hi to that big fuzzball for me. <charAction>Punches Aang in the
                arm.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You'll find him, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I know. Thank you, Katara. You ready, Momo? <charAction>Aang and Momo fly off. The
                rest wave goodbye.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suki approaches Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, it's been really great to see you again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Whoa, hold on. Why does it sound like you're saying goodbye?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>I came along because I wanted to make sure you got through the Serpent's Pass
            safely. But now I need to get back to the other Kyoshi Warriors.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So you came along to protect me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Suki">Suki</speaker>
        <speech>Listen, I'm really sorry about last night. We were talking ... and saying things ...
            and I just got carried away and before I knew it -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Kisses Suki.</charAction> You talk too much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two share a deep kiss. Aang and Momo fly to the top of the Outer Wall
                of Ba Sing Se. However, Aang quickly notices a large drill with a Fire Nation
                insignia, heading for the wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry Momo, Appa's going to have to wait.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
