<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Siege of the North Part 1</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to under the water. The camera pans upward to sea level,
                and higher up into the city. The scene changes to where Katara is set to spar with a
                young boy named Sangok. She eyes her opponent with a look of determination. Sangok
                looks at her with a frightened expression on his face, shaking slightly. He summons
                a globule of water, freezes it into an iceball, and fires it at her. Katara,
                however, is quick to melt the iceball and, turning around swiftly, bends a wave of
                water at him, which she proceeds to freeze, thus suspending Sangok in an icy
                trap.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pakku">Pakku</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Displeased.</charAction> Nice try, Pupil Sangok. <charAction>Shows
                Sangok trying to break free.</charAction> A couple of more years and you might be
            ready to fight a sea sponge. <charAction>He unfreezes the ice; Sangok falls to the
                ground dazed.</charAction> Would anyone care for a rematch with Katara?
                <charAction>The scene cuts to several students sitting by the sidelines, the camera
                panning to the right showing all of them to be tired and unamused.</charAction>
            Katara, you've advanced more quickly than any student I've ever trained.
                <charAction>Cuts to a shot of Katara, who smiles brightly.</charAction> You have
            proven that with fierce determination, passion and hard work, you can accomplish
            anything. <charAction>Turns to Aang irritably.</charAction> Raw talent alone is not
            enough. <charAction>Cut to Aang who is lying on the ground with a lazy smile, floating
                Momo around on an airball above him.</charAction> Pupil Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops bending at the sound of his name; Momo lands on his
                head.</charAction> Yes, Master Pakku?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pakku">Pakku</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Care to step into the sparring circle? I
            figure since you've found time to play with house pets, you must have already mastered
            waterbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Jumps off the ground with airbending.</charAction> I wouldn't say
            mastered, but check this out.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He twists around, bending some snow around him to make a snowman of
                himself, which Momo knocks over. Cut to Pakku and Katara who wear similar
                expressions of disdain. Pakku shakes his head in disappointment, while Katara looks
                on in irritation. The scene changes to another part of the city where Sokka and Yue
                are taking a walk along a bridge. Sokka is walking along the top of bridge's wall
                while balancing.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>So they don't have palaces in the Southern Tribe?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting down on the ledge.</charAction> Are you kidding? I grew up in a
            block of ice. It's not exactly a cultural hub.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs and places her hand on Sokka's shoulder; when Sokka smiles at
                her, she gets a little upset and looks at him seriously.</charAction> Sokka, this is
            wrong.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Protesting.</charAction> What's wrong? We're taking a walk!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unsurely.</charAction> I'm engaged. It just feels ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brightens.</charAction> I know what you need. <charAction>He hops off
                the rail to stand by her side.</charAction> You need to meet my good friend,
            Appa.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Curiously.</charAction> Who?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where the two approach the stables, where Appa is
                resting.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Opening his arms out in enthusiasm.</charAction> Appa and I go way back,
            don't we, boy? <charAction>The thunder of Appa's shifting bulk is heard and Sokka's
                features turn to surprise. Appa enters from the left and lands on top of him and
                licks him, much to Sokka's dismay.</charAction> Ah, ah, easy! Down boy! Agh! No,
            up!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Looks like you haven't been giving Appa enough attention!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yue laughs. Sokka attempts to pull himself free of Appa, who continues to
                lick his face. The scene changes to the two sitting on Appa's saddle, Sokka holding
                the reins in his hand.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> So, how does this work?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You holding on tight? <charAction>Yue nods; in a cool tone.</charAction> Yip ...
                <charAction>Cut to a close up of Sokka's face.</charAction> yip.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms out to a shot of the entire city as Appa takes
                off.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Impressed.</charAction> Oh ... my ... goodness! <charAction>Cuts to
                where Appa is soaring over the ocean; Yue is looking over the saddle.</charAction>
            Wow, I can't believe you do this every day.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stretches.</charAction> Yeah, we pretty much live up here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Is it always this cold in the sky? <charAction>Moves closer to
            Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Happily.</charAction> Not when you're with someone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to face Sokka, blushing.</charAction> It's beautiful up
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah ... <charAction>The two turn to each other and slowly begin to lean in, but at
                the very last moment, Sokka widens his eyes, turns away and pretends to act cool
                again.</charAction> Woo, yeah! Ahhh, good times, good times. <charAction>Snow and
                black soot start to fall from the sky.</charAction> Hey, look!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera zooms out to Appa flying through the gray snowfall;
                worried.</charAction> What's happening?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervous.</charAction> Oh no ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to where civilians have stopped to observe the sooty snow.
                Cuts to Aang, who laughs as he gleefully rolls around in the snow in a circular
                pattern. Cuts to Momo, who opens his mouth and catches a sooty snowflake only to
                bristle and spit out the contents. Aang stops playing around and looks up at the
                snowfall with a concerned face. Cuts to civilians standing near a fountain. Camera
                pans down to show the fountain's water turning black.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Picking up handful of black snow.</charAction> Soot.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene reveals Sokka, Yue, and Appa having landed right outside the
                outskirts of the city, near the shores of the North Pole seas. Sokka is kneeling
                down, observing the snow.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I've seen this before, right before my village was attacked. It's soot mixed with
            snow. <charAction>Rises.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>But, why?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking out over the horizon.</charAction> It's the Fire Nation.
                <charAction>Looks at Yue concerned.</charAction> They've closed in on the North Pole
            and from the looks of this stuff, <charAction>Camera zooms out to show the enormity of
                the sooty snowfall.</charAction> I'd say there's a lot of them.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to the lead ship sailing toward the Water Tribe, under the command of
                Admiral Zhao and Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> This will truly be one for the history books,
            General Iroh. <charAction>Cuts to Zhao and Iroh standing on deck.</charAction> Just
            think, centuries from now, people will study the great Admiral Zhao, who destroyed the
            last of the Water Tribe civilization. You're lucky you're here to see it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tersely.</charAction> Be careful what you wish for, Admiral. History is
            not always kind to its subjects.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>I suppose you speak from experience, but rest assured. This will be nothing like
            your legendary failure at Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Walks forward.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sadly.</charAction> I hope not, for your sake.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Tell the captains to prepare for first strike.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh walks away. Cuts to the bow of the lead ship breaking through thick
                ice floes floating in the water. Cuts to the interior of the ship, where Iroh is
                confronting Zuko disguised as a Fire Nation soldier. Zuko is forced to wear the
                disguise to keep the secret from Zhao that he survived an attempted
                assassination.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Secretly.</charAction> We'll be landing soon. Do you have a
            plan?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Removes his mask to reveal his face covered in cuts.</charAction> I'm
            working on it, Uncle. <charAction>Puts covering back in place.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two head off in separate directions. Back at the Northern Water Tribe,
                citizens flee to the town hall, as two watchmen hit a drum to signal the Fire
                Nation's approach. Sokka and Yue make their way up the steps, but Yue stops the
                approach.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Trying to drag her along.</charAction> What's wrong?
                <charAction>Pointing up to the citadel.</charAction> We have to go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sadly; lets go of Sokka's hand.</charAction> No, Sokka, wait, I can't
            see you anymore. Not at all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Protesting.</charAction> What? We're just friends.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>I wish we could just be friends, but I like you too much and it's too confusing to
            be around you. I'm marrying someone else! <charAction>Turns away
                sorrowfully.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You don't love him, do you? You don't even seem to like him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>But I do love my people.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Objecting.</charAction> You're not marrying
                <description>them.</description></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns to face Sokka.</charAction> You don't understand. I have duties to
            my father, to my tribe. I have to do this. Goodbye.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She runs past Sokka up the stairs quickly. Closes up on Sokka, who looks on
                with dismay. The scene cuts to inside the chief's Royal Palace.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>The day we have feared for so long has arrived. The Fire Nation is on our doorstep.
            It is with great sadness I call my family here before me, knowing well that some of
            these faces are about to vanish from our tribe, <charAction>While saying this line, the
                scene flashes from Yue to Pakku to Hahn.</charAction> but they will never vanish
            from our hearts. Now, as we approach the battle for our existence, I call upon the great
            spirits. Spirit of the Ocean! Spirit of the Moon! Be with us! I'm going to need
            volunteers for a dangerous mission.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rising from his seat.</charAction> Count me in!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Be warned, many of you will not return. <charAction>Several Water Tribe men rise and
                walk forward.</charAction> Come forward to receive my mark, if you accept the
            task.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Arnook paints three red line marks with his fingers on one man's forehead.
                The man walks away, slightly sorrowful. Sokka steps forward and Arnook paints the
                same three marks. He begins walking away sadly and turns to look at Yue. After
                staring at each other for a few moments, Sokka continues walking. Yue averts her
                gaze, closes her eyes and begins crying.</description>
            <description>The scene changes to outside the city where Aang is perched on a snow
                mound, holding his staff. Arnook approaches him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>The stillness before battle is unbearable. Such a quiet dread.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara joins them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I wasn't there when the Fire Nation attacked my people.
                <charAction>Determined.</charAction> I'm going to make a difference this
            time.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He rises and holds his staff behind his back in a similar pose as seen in
                the opening sequence. The camera pans upward to the sky. The scene changes to where
                Aang, Katara, Sokka, Appa and all the warriors are gathered at the wall. Something
                distant can be seen soaring toward the city from the horizon. Aang squints his eyes
                before realizing the object is a fireball. Cuts to Sokka and Katara, who look on in
                terror. The fireball collides into the wall of the city, sending Team Avatar and
                several warriors flying back. Cuts to the wall of the city, damaged and beginning to
                fall apart.</description>
            <description>Cuts to another fireball being launched into the air. The fireball
                disintegrates a bridge within the city. Cuts to a trebuchet operator launching
                another fireball into the air, which hits the wall.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yip-yip!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He and Appa take flight, heading toward the fleet. Cuts to the warriors who
                regather themselves, helping each other up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pulls his arm free from the snow.</charAction> Katara!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara uses waterbending to free herself from a snow mound she became
                buried underneath. Sokka smiles and hoists his sister onto her feet. The two cast
                their eyes upward, catching sight of two fireballs that soar overhead. Cuts to Appa
                who grunts, Aang guiding him, a determined look on his face. Cuts to bird's-eyes
                view of the ocean, Aang flying toward a single Fire Navy ship. Two fireballs are
                launched. Cuts to the deck of the ship, where trebuchet operators launch another
                fireball back to Appa and Aang. Cuts to fireball soaring straight toward Aang, who
                uses his glider to direct it into an icy cliff side near the city.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll take it from here, boy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He jumps down from Appa and flies downward on his glider onto the first
                ship. Using airbending, he sweeps several trebuchet operators off their feet and
                leaps onto one trebuchet. An operator comes forward and slams a sledgehammer onto
                the machine, nearly striking Aang who manages to back-flip away. Cuts to where he
                stands on top of the contraption, two more operators approaching him from opposite
                directions, each holding a sledgehammer. The one on his right brings the
                sledgehammer down proceeded by the one on his left. He jumps into the air, avoiding
                both blows and completely collapses the trebuchet with his glider and the use of
                airbending. He lands onto the deck, triumphant.</description>
            <description>He runs over to an unoccupied trebuchet, already loaded with a flaming
                boulder. He sticks a sledgehammer in another launcher's chain. When a soldier
                approaches him, Aang blasts him away, activating the catapult which launches the
                fireball straight into the deck, leaving a large hole. The camera zooms out on the
                damage.</description>
            <description>Cuts to Aang, who runs past two operators who quickly chase after him. He
                arrives at two trebuchets, one before him and one behind him, and tangles their
                chains together. He leaps onto the machine before him as the soldiers approach and
                slams his foot onto the pedal that activates the catapult. The catapult lunges
                forward, causing the second trebuchet to collide into the first, destroying
                both.</description>
            <description>Smiling happily, Aang proceeds to another machine. Cuts to a burly man, who
                observes him evilly. Aang prepares to strike the machine with a sledgehammer only to
                turn around and catch sight of the man who attempts to land blows from afar with two
                sledgehammers, each attached to long chains. Aang jumps out of the way of several
                blows. Cuts to the man who swings the chains around. Aang leans against a beam only
                for the two chains to wrap around the beam thus trapping him. He struggles to break
                free.</description>
            <description>Cuts to the soldier, who is suddenly knocked over by Appa's paw. The chains
                snap and Aang breaks free.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brightening.</charAction> Appa!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa leans over the deck of the ship and tosses the man overboard before
                turning to Aang, who runs over and embraces him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks for the rescue, buddy!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>His expression of relief becomes one of alarm when the ship begins to
                rumble. Cuts to an undamaged trebuchet that collapses when a gigantic spike of ice
                pierces straight through the hull and deck of the ship. Cuts to dozens of Water
                Tribe warriors riding on boats, who are using waterbending to suspend the ship. Cuts
                to the entire ship being uprooted. Cuts to Appa, who stands on the sloping deck, the
                ruins of machinery sliding downward past them. He and Aang take off. Cuts to the
                horizon, where an entire fleet comes into view, the ships large in
                quantity.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shocked.</charAction> You've got to be kidding me ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to the training for the mission.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Men, you'll be infiltrating the Fire Nation Navy. That means you'll all need one of
            these uniforms.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans upward, revealing a young man, Hahn, who appears in the
                uniform that will be used. Sokka laughs. The rest of the warriors turn to stare at
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What's your problem?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Fire Navy uniforms don't look like that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritably.</charAction> Of course they do. These are real uniforms
            captured from actual Fire Navy soldiers.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> When, like, a hundred years ago?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Eighty-five.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks over and flings one of the shoulder spikes with his
                finger.</charAction> The Fire Nation doesn't wear shoulder spikes anymore. The newer
            uniforms are more streamlined.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka bends the tip of one of the shoulder spikes back with the tip of his
                finger and lets go. It bounces back to its original shape with a little comic sound
                effect.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech>How do we know we can trust this guy? <charAction>Turns to growl at Sokka, who
                glares at him in return.</charAction> Such bold talk for a new recruit.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka is from our sister tribe, Hahn. He's a capable warrior and I value his input.
                <charAction>Sokka shoots Hahn a smug look; Arnook turns to the rest of the
                regiment.</charAction> Now, our first objective is to determine the identity of
            their commanding officer.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>His name is Zhao. Middle-aged, <charAction>Tracing imaginary sideburns with his
                fingers.</charAction> big sideburns, bigger temper ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, I want you to tell everything you know to Hahn. He's leading this mission.
            Hahn, show Sokka your respect. <charAction>Beginning to walk away.</charAction> I expect
            nothing less from my future son-in-law.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stares at Hahn, mouth agape; points at him and narrows his
                eyes.</charAction> Princess Yue's marrying you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated.</charAction> Yeah, what of it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns away from Hahn, upset.</charAction> Nothing.
            Congratulations.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene fades to sunset where fireballs are continually launched. A
                bird's-eye view is shown of the fleet attacking the city. Cuts to several fireballs;
                camera pans downward to show them hitting the city.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pakku">Pakku</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pointing to the sky.</charAction> Stop those fireballs!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of oncoming fireball. The waterbenders bend up a column of
                water and freeze it, capturing the fireball. Cuts to side-view of the leading ships
                of the fleet, the uprooted ship in view. The scene cuts to the interior of Zhao's
                ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>It's almost twilight, Admiral. As your military consultant, I must advise you to
            halt your attack. <charAction>Cuts to shot of the ship, sailing past a rising
                moon.</charAction> The waterbenders draw their power from the moon, and it is nearly
            full tonight. You should wait and resume the attack at daybreak. <charAction>Cuts back
                to Iroh and Zhao.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, I'm well aware of the moon problem and I am working on a solution. But for now,
            daybreak it is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The lead ship drops its anchor, followed by the rest of the ships, who drop
                their anchors and cease the attack. Cuts to a shot of the city, smoke billowing from
                several spots. Yue can be seen looking out over the horizon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>They've stopped firing.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yue and Katara stand side by side, viewing the city. Appa appears over the
                horizon, flying toward them.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang lands on the ground, exasperated. Katara and Yue approach
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Clearly exhausted, placing his hands on his head.</charAction> I can't
            do it ... I can't do it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What happened?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Dimly.</charAction> I must have taken out a dozen Fire Navy ships, but
            there's just too many of them. I can't fight them all.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Pleadingly.</charAction> But, you have to. You're the Avatar.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Solemnly.</charAction> I'm just one kid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He buries his face in his arms. Katara kneels down beside him in an attempt
                to comfort him. The scene changes to nightfall on the lead ship. Cuts inside a room
                where Zuko prepares a boat, winding up some rope. Iroh enters.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>If you're fishing for an octopus my nephew, you need a tightly woven net, or he will
            squeeze through the tiniest hole and escape.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I don't need your wisdom right now, Uncle.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry. I just nag you, because ... well, <charAction>Voice breaking
                slightly.</charAction> ever since I lost my son ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle, you don't have to say it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>... I think of you as my own.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Faces his uncle, a softer expression on his face.</charAction> I know,
            Uncle. We'll meet again. <charAction>Iroh hugs him.</charAction> After I have the
            Avatar. <charAction>He turns away and gets on the boat.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Remember your breath of fire. It could save your life out there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I will. <charAction>Lowers the boat, suspended by ropes, down the side of the ship
                into the water.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>And put your hood up. Keep your ears warm!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'll be fine!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The shot cuts to the city, several ships lying stationery ahead of him.
                Back inside the warriors' base. Hahn and Sokka sharpen their axes against
                grindstones.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smugly.</charAction> Let me tell you Sokka, I've courted a lot of girls,
            but Yue is the finest and she comes with the most perks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Perks? What does that mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech>I mean, Yue's nice and everything, but the points I'll gain with the chief aren't
            bad either.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angered.</charAction> Princess Yue is wasted on a self-absorbed weasel
            like you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera begins closing up on Hahn.</charAction> Whoa, hang on. What do
            you care? <charAction>Sokka closes his eyes sorrowfully.</charAction> You're just a
            simple rube from the Southern Tribe. What would you know of the political complexities
            of our life? <charAction>Smirking.</charAction> No offense.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shouts and tackles Hahn; the two begin rolling around on the floor in a
                struggle.</charAction> You're just a jerk without a soul, no offense!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two continue to roll about on the floor. Cuts to a shot of Sokka and
                Hahn, each pulling the other's ponytail in fury. They are suddenly separated by
                Arnook.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>That's enough! Sokka, you're off the mission!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka, his hair loose and hanging in locks, appears stunned before crossing
                his arms in anger.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hahn">Hahn</speaker>
        <speech>All right, fall in men! Everybody listen to what I say and we'll take out this
            Admiral Chō in no time!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Irritated, waves arms in gesture.</charAction> It's Admiral
            Zhao!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to outside on the water where Zuko rows past, navigating
                his way through the path of ice spikes. Cuts to a view of a Water Tribe guard on
                patrol, pausing and looking out over the horizon just as Zuko's canoe disappears
                behind an ice spike. The guard continues walking. Cuts back to Zuko who continues to
                paddle toward the wall, before switching to a shot of him peering from behind an ice
                spike, his canoe pulled up onto the ice. Camera cuts to and zooms in on a shot of
                several Water Tribe guards marching atop the wall. Zuko turns around and sees a
                group of turtle seals resting by a hole in the ice. One seal plunges head first into
                the icy water. Zuko looks back up to the wall and begins approaching the
                hole.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Peering down into the hole.</charAction> Where are they going?
                <charAction>Cuts to a shot of the hole, his face reflected in the
                water.</charAction> They're coming up for air somewhere.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He pulls down the mask covering his mouth and nose and inhales deeply. Cuts
                to shot of Zuko from beneath the water; he plunges into the water. The scene
                changes, cutting to a shot of the waxing gibbous moon hanging in the
                sky.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off camera.</charAction> The legends say the moon was the first
            waterbender. <charAction>Cuts to shot of her, Katara and Aang standing on a balcony,
                looking up at the sky.</charAction> Our ancestors saw how it pushed and pulled the
            tides and learned how to do it themselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I've always noticed my waterbending is stronger at night.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Our strength comes from the spirit of the moon. Our life comes from the spirit of
            the ocean. <charAction>Camera pans slightly downward, showing Aang with a dull
                expression on his face.</charAction> They work together to keep balance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brightening.</charAction> The spirits! <charAction>Raises head,
                startling Momo.</charAction> Maybe I can find them and get their help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>How can you do that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching her.</charAction> The Avatar is the bridge between our world
            and the Spirit World! Aang can talk to them!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Maybe they'll give you the wisdom to win this
            battle!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waves arms out in gesture.</charAction> Or maybe they'll unleash a crazy
            amazing spirit attack on the Fire Nation! <charAction>The two girls look at him oddly;
                Aang looks at them and straightens up.</charAction> Or wisdom. That's good,
            too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>The only problem is, last time you got to the Spirit World by accident. How are you
            going to get there this time?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>I have an idea. Follow me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She begins walking away. Cuts to a shot of the chief's Royal Palace, the
                camera panning downward to the ground where Yue walks by, followed by Aang and
                Katara. Cuts to shot of Yue standing by a small, round wooden door, Aang approaching
                close behind.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking up to the door.</charAction> So, is this the way to the Spirit
            World?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Laughs.</charAction> No. You'll have to get there on your own.
                <charAction>Leans inward.</charAction> But I can take you to the most spiritual
            place in the entire North Pole. <charAction>Opens the door.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang steps inside. The camera pans upward and zooms in to reveal a small
                verdant oasis lying ahead, a waterfall flowing directly behind it. Zooms in on Aang,
                who gasps in amazement.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Runs to the back of the oasis and rolls around on the
                ground.</charAction> I never thought I'd miss grass this much!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaching the oasis.</charAction> It's so warm here! How is that
            possible?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>It's the center of all spiritual energy in our land.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two girls remove their coats. Cuts to view of two fish, one black and
                one white, swimming about in the pond. Momo sticks his hand in the pond and tries to
                grab the two fish in the water. Cuts to shot of the two girls standing over him,
                looking rather irritated.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're right, Yue. I can feel ... something. It's so tranquil. <charAction>Positions
                himself to meditate.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Meanwhile, Zuko emerges from the water through another hole in the ice. He
                lies on his back on the ice and catches his breath. He rolls over onto his side,
                begins shivering and breathes fire to warm himself.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To the barking turtle seals.</charAction> Be quiet!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The pack of seals quiets down. Cuts to shot of several seals, who watch as
                Zuko walks past, pushing aside the heads of two of them. They resume barking. He
                makes his way through another opening where water is pouring out. Cuts to shot of
                his foot boring into the wall as he tries to steady himself and make his way through
                the channel of water. Cuts to inside the channel, where he slowly crawls his way
                through. Cut back to the warriors' base. Sokka is crouched on the floor, sharpening
                his boomerang when he is approached.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Is something wrong, Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh, no. Hahn's out there on the top-secret
            mission while I'm here sharpening my boomerang. Everything's fine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>Listen to me. I took you off the mission for selfish reasons. I have a special task
            in mind for you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What, you want me to scrub the barracks?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Arnook">Arnook</speaker>
        <speech>I want you to guard my daughter, Princess Yue.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises and tries to act cool.</charAction> Oh ... Sure. That ...
            shouldn't be too hard.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Arnook exits the scene; Sokka's face falls. Zuko continues to make his way
                through the channel of water. He exits from the channel and floats to the surface of
                the water. He emerges from the surface and inhales deeply several times. He proceeds
                to duck his head under the water, surveying the area. The camera zooms in on another
                channel. Zuko swims toward the channel and upward. As he attempts to resurface,
                however, the surface of the water had frozen into a thick ice patch. Zuko tries to
                break through the ice. He suddenly exhales, signaling his need for air. He heats his
                hands using firebending and melts a hole in the ice. Cuts to a tunnel way in the
                city, the ice steaming and finally melting away. Zuko emerges and catches his
                breath. He relaxes against the wall of the tunnel. The scene changes back to the
                Spirit Oasis, where Aang is meditating, Katara and Yue watching him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Why is he sitting like that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He's meditating, trying to cross over into the Spirit World. <charAction>Aang
                scrunches up his face in concentration.</charAction> It takes all his
            concentration.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Is there any way we can help?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> How about some quiet? Come on guys, I can hear
            every word you're saying!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms in on the pond, where the two koi fish are shown circling
                each other. Cuts to shot of beneath the pond, showing an underside-view of the two
                fish. Cuts to shot of Aang staring at the fish, seemingly mesmerized. Cuts back to
                two fish circling each other before switching back to Aang. Cuts back to image of
                the two fish, which morphs into an image of the symbols for yin and yang. Cuts back
                to Aang, as his eyes and tattoos to light up.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Worried.</charAction> Is he okay?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>He's crossing into the Spirit World. He'll be fine as long as we don't move his
            body. <charAction>Cuts to overhead shot of the pond.</charAction> That's his way back to
            the physical world.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe we should get some help.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling.</charAction> No, he's my friend. I'm perfectly capable of
            protecting him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Well, aren't you a big girl now.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Alarmed and dismayed.</charAction> No ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> Yes. Hand him over and I won't have to hurt
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Yue runs from the scene as Katara assumes a defensive stance, Zuko
                appearing on screen. Cuts to Zuko, who kicks up his leg, sending a fire blast
                Katara's way. He fires more blasts from his hands. Cuts to shot of Zuko and Katara,
                Zuko continually firing as Katara conjures up water shields to deflect the attacks.
                Cuts to Katara, who draws water from the pond and sends the stream at Zuko, who is
                preparing another attack. The blast pushes Zuko back several feet and knocks him to
                the ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rising.</charAction> I see you've learned a new trick, but I didn't come
            this far to lose to you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He turns around and fires another blast which Katara blocks by summoning
                another shield of water. Cuts to shot of Zuko, Katara, and Aang as Katara sends a
                powerful jet of water at her opponent. The jet collides into Zuko, who is sent
                farther back. As he attempts to steady himself from the impact, small juts of ice
                form around his feet. Cuts to close-up of Katara, a determined look on her face.
                Water begins rising around Zuko and encircling him. Katara waves her arms about
                wildly, forming a ball of water around him which she freezes solid. Cuts to close-up
                of her as she smiles triumphantly. Cuts to Zuko imprisoned in the ice.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You little peasant. You've found a master, haven't you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The globule of ice begins glowing bright orange with heat and the ground
                rumbles. Cuts to view of entire globule as it heats up intensely before melting. He
                fires repeated attacks at Katara, who draws water from the oasis to deflect the
                attacks. She prepares to strike him with a water blast, however, Zuko manages to
                slip away and head toward Aang. Just as his fingers grasp Aang's collar, Katara
                fires a water blast, throwing Zuko to the other wall. She whips up a large wave and
                sends the attack at Zuko. The rush of water sends Zuko up the side of the cliff; she
                freezes the water, encasing him in ice. Cuts to Pakku who looks over the horizon in
                the city as the sun rises. The scene cuts to Zhao's ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>It's daybreak at last. Let's write history.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back to the Spirit Oasis, rays of sunlight beam down on Zuko, who remains
                imprisoned in the ice, his head bent down. He feels the heat and sharply raises his
                head. With a determined look on his face, he breathes steam from his nose, melting
                the ice quickly. He lands on the ground and fires a blast at Katara, who had her
                back turned to him at that moment. She turns around swiftly and attempts to deflect
                the blast by conjuring a water shield; however, she creates the shield too late. The
                blast sends her slamming into the gate to the Spirit World, knocking her out. Smoke
                from the impact fills the screen. Cuts to shot of Zuko standing over her, holding
                Aang by the collar.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You rise with the moon ... I rise with the sun.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to where Fire Navy ships break through the city wall,
                their bows crumbling the wall, allowing soldiers armed with spears to rush
                in.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zhao">Zhao</speaker>
        <speech>The Water Tribe can try to resist the inevitable, but their city will fall
            today.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts back to the oasis. Camera focuses on a close-up of Katara, whose eyes
                suddenly snap open as she regains consciousness, only to realize Aang is gone. She
                crawls around, desperately searching for him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka and Yue enter on Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What happened? Where's Zuko?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Dismayed.</charAction> He took Aang. He took him right out from under
            me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Momo looking sorrowfully from the edge of the
                pond.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> Where did they go ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera pans upward to above the oasis where Zuko is seen walking
                through a blizzard with Aang in tow. Cuts to shot of them walking away. The camera
                pans upward to show the snow falling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
