<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Puppetmaster</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Avatar Roku">Avatar Roku</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Narrating a preview.</charAction> Previously on Avatar ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're looking at the only waterbender in the whole South Pole. This ship has
            haunted my tribe when Gran-Gran was a little girl. It was part of the Fire Nation's
            first attacks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Yue">Yue</speaker>
        <speech>The legend said the moon was the first waterbender. Our ancestor saw how it pushed
            and pulled the tides, and learned how to do it themselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I always noticed my waterbending is stronger at night.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>What are you doing?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm making my own water!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to a waxing gibbous moon glowing in the night sky. The
                scene cuts to a shot of a field of fire lilies, a mountain in the distance. Cuts to
                a forested area, where Team Avatar is camping out among the trees. The darkness of
                the night gives the landscape an ominous feeling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Telling a ghost story.</charAction> Suddenly, they heard something down
            the hall in the dark. Oooh ... It came into the torchlight ... and they knew the blade
            of Wing Fung was haunted! <charAction>Draws sword, stands up and points it toward the
                fire; yells dramatically.</charAction> Ooh-aaah!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of the entire group sitting around the campfire. Aang is lying
                down, Katara is hunched over in a sitting position and Toph sits casually, all three
                looking unamused.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unimpressed.</charAction> I think I like "the man with a sword for a
            hand" better.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Water Tribe slumber parties must stink.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, wait! I've got one! And this is a true Southern Water Tribe story.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sitting down.</charAction> Is this one of those "a friend of my cousin
            knew some guy that this happened to" stories?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No, it happened to Mom.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Upon hearing this, Sokka stiffens. Cuts to Aang, who sits up to listen
                intently.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>One winter when Mom was a girl, a snowstorm buried the whole village for weeks. A
            month later, Mom noticed she hadn't seen her friend Nini since the storm. So Mom and
            some others went to check on Nini's family. When they got there, no one was home.
                <charAction>Cuts to ground-level shot of the group sitting around the fire, the
                camera panning slightly to the right.</charAction> Just a fire flickering in the
            fireplace. While the men went out to search, Mom stayed in the house. When she was
            alone, she heard a voice. <charAction>In a scary voice.</charAction> "It's so cold and I
            can't get warm!" <charAction>Sokka stiffens in fear.</charAction> Mom turned and saw
            Nini standing by the fire. She was blue like she was frozen. Mom ran outside for help,
            but when everyone came back, Nini was gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang uses Momo's ears to cover his face in fear. The camera shifts to show
                Sokka hiding behind a gnarled tree stump.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Peering from behind a tree trunk.</charAction> Where'd she go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No one knows. Nini's house stands empty to this day, but sometimes, people see smoke
            coming up from the chimney, like little Nini is still trying to get warm.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms out to where the gang is all huddled by the fire.
                Suddenly, Toph straightens up and places her hands on the ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gasping.</charAction> Wait! Guys, did you hear that? <charAction>Aang,
                Katara, and Sokka clutch each other tightly, too stiff to move, with Toph standing
                alertly.</charAction> I hear people under the mountain. And they're
            screaming.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka, assuming Toph is joking, relaxes his grip.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Pfft! Nice try.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts to shot of the campsite viewed through the ominous-looking tree
                branches.</charAction> No, I'm serious. I hear something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're probably just jumpy from the ghost stories ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>It just ... stopped.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts back to him and Katara, still hugging, Sokka sitting close
                by.</charAction> All right, now I'm getting scared.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera from behind group.</charAction> Hello, children.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Everyone screams in terror upon hearing the strange woman's voice and
                scrambles from the ground. An elderly woman emerges from the shadows.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Sorry to frighten you. My name is Hama. <charAction>Cuts to side-view of the
                campsite.</charAction> You children shouldn't be out in the forest by yourselves at
            night. <charAction>Cuts to ground-level shot of Hama standing over the
                fire.</charAction> I have an inn nearby. Why don't you come back there for some
            spiced tea and warm beds?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sheepishly, places arm behind head.</charAction> Yes, please.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hama smiles and begins walking away. The scene changes to a village, her
                local inn lying atop a small hill. Cuts to inside the building, where tea is being
                poured into a teacup. Cuts to shot of the group sitting around the kitchen
                table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks for letting us stay here tonight. You have a lovely inn.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sets teapot down.</charAction> Aren't you sweet? <charAction>Walks over
                to her seat and sits down.</charAction> You know you should be careful. People have
            been disappearing in those woods you were camping in.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What do you mean "disappearing"?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sets her teacup down.</charAction> When the moon turns full, people walk
            in and they don't come out. <charAction>Stand up and holds up her teapot; cheerfully
                smiling.</charAction> Who wants more tea?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of the group, who has by now fallen completely silent, the
                camera panning to the right to show all of them sitting around the
                table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, you'll all be completely safe here. <charAction>Clasps hands together
                and smiles.</charAction> Why don't I show you to your rooms and you can get a good
            night's rest?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to Sokka's room, where he is lying in bed with Momo
                asleep on the floor. Cuts to shot of him in bed as he rolls over. A creaking noise
                comes from outside, frightening him. He draws his sword quickly while Momo scampers
                under the covers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I know, Momo. <charAction>Places sword back inside holster and sets it
                down.</charAction> This place is creepy! <charAction>Lies back down on the pillow
                and pulls the covers over him.</charAction> I don't know if I'm gonna be able to
            fall asleep!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene switches over to later in the night, where Sokka is fast asleep
                in his bed, snoring and drooling on his pillow. As it fades to the morning, he is
                lying sideways, next to the bed, though still fast asleep. Cut to a close-up of his
                face as a shadow approaches him. He slowly awakens, rubbing his eye.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera.</charAction> Wakey, wakey! <charAction>Cuts to shot of the
                innkeeper, standing brightly over him.</charAction> Time to go shopping!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara appears by her side, dressed and happily smiling. The camera shifts
                counter-clockwise, showing Sokka later in the day, dressed in his ordinary clothes,
                standing in the marketplace where Hama has just made her purchase. A friendly old
                man smiles and waves to her as she walks away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That Mr. Yao seems to have a thing for you. Maybe we should go back and see if he'll
            give us some free komodo sausages?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Seriously.</charAction> You would have me use my feminine charms to take
            advantage of that poor man? <charAction>Cheerfully.</charAction> I think you and I are
            going to get along swimmingly!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two walk off-camera with Katara smiling at this remark. The scene
                switches over to two villagers having a conversation by a stand.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager">Villager</speaker>
        <speech>You won't have any ash bananas till next week?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Shop owner">Shop owner</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I have to send the boy to Hing Wa Island to get them, and it's a two-day
            trip.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager">Villager</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, right. Tomorrow's the full moon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Shop owner">Shop owner</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>In a lowered voice.</charAction> Exactly. I can't lose another delivery
            boy in the woods.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Aang, Sokka, and Toph walking through the marketplace. Aang
                carrying a package slung over his shoulder, Sokka carrying a package attached to his
                sword, while Toph carries a large, round basket on her head.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>People disappearing in the woods, weird stuff happening during full moons? This just
            reeks of Spirit World shenanigans.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I bet if we take a little walk around town, we'll find out what these people did to
            the environment to make the spirits mad.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Makes gesture with his hand.</charAction> And then you can sew up this
            little mystery lickety-split, Avatar style!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Proudly.</charAction> Helping people ... that's what I do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the group standing in the marketplace as he, Sokka
                and Toph approach Katara and Hama.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Why don't you take all those things back to the inn? I just have to run a couple
            more errands. I'll be back in a little while.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks up to her.</charAction> This is a mysterious little town you have
            here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Extremely close-up. Ominously.</charAction> Mysterious town for
            mysterious children.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She smiles creepily and saunters away, leaving Sokka feeling suspicious.
                The scene changes to a shot of Hama's inn, starting outside, before moving inside,
                where the gang is unpacking groceries. Sokka walks over to a counter and sets his
                basket down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That Hama seems a little strange. Like she knows something, or she's hiding
            something.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unpacking items.</charAction> That's ridiculous. She's a nice woman who
            took us in and gave us a place to stay. <charAction>Picks up cabbage.</charAction> She
            kinda reminds me of Gran-Gran.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But what did she mean by that comment, "mysterious children"?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Gee, I don't know. Maybe because she found four strange kids camping in the woods at
            night? Isn't that a little mysterious?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I'm gonna take a look around. <charAction>Walks away and up a flight of wooden
                stairs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Appears along with the others at the bottom of the
                stairwell.</charAction> Sokka! Sokka, what are you doing? <charAction>Off-camera as
                Sokka peers around the inn.</charAction> You can't just snoop around someone's
            house.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It'll be fine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera while Sokka peers into a room.</charAction> She could be home
            any minute.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking down hallway with the rest of the team.</charAction> Sokka,
            you're gonna get us all in trouble and this is just plain rude!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tugging on a cupboard door.</charAction> I'm not finished yet.
                <charAction>Grunts, as he tries to pull it free.</charAction> Come on ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The cupboard suddenly opens, revealing several wooden puppets stowed
                inside. The dolls fall forward, held together only by their strings. Everyone gasps;
                Sokka withdraws his sword, backs up and points it straight at the
                puppets.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Okay, that's pretty creepy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks over and closes the cupboard; a bit weirded out.</charAction> So
            she's got a hobby. There's nothing weird about that. <charAction>Angrily.</charAction>
            Sokka, you've looked enough. <charAction>Off-camera as Sokka ascends into the
                attic.</charAction> Hama will be back soon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Just an ordinary puppet-loving innkeeper, huh? Well then why does she have a locked
            door up here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> Probably to keep people like you from snooping
            through her stuff!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We'll see. <charAction>Peers through the keyhole into the room. Cuts to shot of the
                attic from his perspective. Through the keyhole, a small room can be seen, with a
                chest lying on the ground in the middle. The camera zooms in on the
                chest.</charAction> It's empty, except for a little chest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe it's treasure!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka grows excited, his eyes growing wide, and uses his sword to pick the
                lock.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches him.</charAction> Sokka, what are you doing? You're breaking
            into a private room!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I have to see what's in there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The door unlocks and creaks open. The four step cautiously inside; Sokka
                puts away his sword and approaches the small chest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We shouldn't be doing this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka picks up the chest and tries to pry it open, only to discover it is
                locked.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe there's a key here somewhere ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Ooh! Hand it over!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She takes the chest, removes her meteor bracelet from her arm and
                earthbends it into the shape of a small key, which she sticks into the keyhole of
                the chest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Eagerly.</charAction> Come on, come on!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Annoyed; Katara appears from behind her, peering nervously over her
                shoulder.</charAction> This isn't as easy as it looks!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Guys, I don't know about this ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>This is crazy! I'm leaving!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Suit yourself! Do it, Toph!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara turns to leave the moment Toph signals that she has successfully
                opened the chest, holding her thumb up. All four eagerly surround the box in a
                comical fashion, anticipating what they will find inside.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-camera from behind them.</charAction> I'll tell you what's in the
            box.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>All, except Toph, scream and turn sharply to find Hama standing in the
                doorway. Cuts to shot of the group, still looking stunned, except Toph. Sokka
                guiltily hands her the box. Cuts to shot from inside the chest, as Hama lifts the
                lid and reaches her hand inside. Cuts to close-up of Sokka, his eyes wide in
                anxiousness, and a shot of Hama still in the process of lifting the object. Cuts to
                shot of the team standing together from her perspective. Her left arm appears
                on-screen, a blue whale tooth comb in her hand. Cuts to shot of her holding the
                comb, smiling.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Surprised.</charAction> An old comb?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>It's my greatest treasure. It's the last thing I own from growing up in the Southern
            Water Tribe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera zooms in on Katara and Sokka, who stare at her in
                astonishment.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stunned.</charAction> You're from the Southern Water Tribe?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sets down comb.</charAction> Just like you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How did you know?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>I heard you talking around your campfire.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>But why didn't you tell us?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>I wanted to surprise you! I bought all this food today so I could fix you a big
            Water Tribe dinner. Of course, I can't get all the ingredients I need here, but ocean
            kumquats are a lot like sea prunes if you stew them long enough.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sticking his tongue out in disgust.</charAction> Great ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I knew I felt a bond with you right away.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>And I knew you were keeping a secret, so I guess we're both right.
                <charAction>Grimaces as Katara hits him in the arm.</charAction> But I'm sorry we
            were sneaking around.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Apology accepted. <charAction>Turns to the side and motions with her
                hand.</charAction> Now, let's get cooking!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to later that night, where Aang races from the inn to the
                barn located toward the back of the property. Cuts to overhead shot of inside the
                barn, where Appa and Momo lie. The doors creak open and Aang steps inside. Cuts to
                ground-level shot of him standing before the bison, tossing a cabbage-like vegetable
                into Appa's mouth. Momo dances in front of the bison's face and chitters, irritated.
                Appa opens his mouth and releases the cabbage, which Momo grabs. The lemur skitters
                away. Cuts to shot of Hama's kitchen table, as she sets down a bowl of soup. Cuts to
                shot of the entire room, the team and the innkeeper sitting around the table. Sokka
                is seen chewing on a food item, as Hama takes her seat at the head of the
                table.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispering to Toph.</charAction> I'd steer clear of the sea
            prunes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I thought they were ocean kumquats.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Close enough.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Who wants five flavor soup?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>All four raise their hands in acceptance. Hama situates her hands over the
                bowl and suddenly uses waterbending to summon a globule of soup and fill each of
                their bowls. Cuts to shot of the team looking at the spectacle in astonishment, the
                camera panning to the right. Four streams of soup land gracefully into each of their
                bowls.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Delighted.</charAction> You're a waterbender! <charAction>Faces Hama in
                delight.</charAction> I've never met another waterbender from our tribe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cuts to side-view of her; sadly.</charAction> That's because the Fire
            Nation wiped them all out. I was the last one ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cuts to shot of Sokka and Katara, Katara clasping her hands together, an
                expression of pity on her face.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>So how did you end up out here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grimly.</charAction> I was stolen from my home.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene fades to a flashback of a much younger Hama peacefully sauntering
                through her Southern Water Tribe village.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> It was over sixty years ago when the raids
            started.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She approaches her friend, Kanna, and they share a laugh before they notice
                ashen snow falling from the sky. The two race to the shores, where five Fire Nation
                ships are rapidly approaching the tribe. Five fireballs are launched from trebuchets
                and strike the village. Fire Nation soldiers swarm the area, battling the
                waterbenders, who desperately attempt to fend them off.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> They came again and again, each time rounding
            up more of our waterbenders and taking them captive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The battle scene fades to another scene, where Hama and several other
                waterbenders use waterbending to capsize a Fire Nation vessel.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> We did our best to hold them off, but our
            numbers dwindled as the raids continued.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>As she is narrating, Water Tribe civilians who aided in the suspension of
                the vessel are seen slowly fading, signaling their capture by the Fire Nation. The
                camera rotates around her and zooms out, revealing dozens of firebenders surrounding
                her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Finally, I too was captured.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The younger Hama is seen being led by Fire Nation soldiers onto one of
                their naval vessels, having now been captured herself.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> I was led away in chains. The last waterbender
            of the Southern Water Tribe.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A final scene shows her looking out onto her tribe's members, including her
                friend, Kanna, in tears as the bow creaks upward. The flashback ends. Now in present
                time, Katara is seen walking over to Hama and placing her arms around her shoulder
                comfortingly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>They put us in terrible prisons here in the Fire Nation. I was the only one who
            managed to escape.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>How did you get away? And why did you stay in the Fire Nation?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry. It's too painful to talk about anymore.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We completely understand. We lost our mother in a raid.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sympathetically.</charAction> Oh, you poor things.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Sokka cast their heads down solemnly.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I can't tell you what it means to meet you. It's an honor. You're a hero.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>I never thought I'd meet another Southern waterbender. I'd like to teach you what I
            know so you can carry on the Southern tradition when I'm gone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Yes! Yes, of course! To learn about my heritage, it would mean everything to
            me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She bows to her newfound friend, who smiles warmly. The scene changes to
                the next day, where Hama and Katara are strolling on the outskirts of Hama's
                village.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Growing up in the South Pole, waterbenders are totally at home surrounded by snow
            and ice and seas. But as you probably noticed on your travels, that isn't the case
            wherever you go.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I know! When we were stranded in the desert, I felt like there was almost nothing I
            could do.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops walking.</charAction> That's why you have to learn to control
            water wherever it exists.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I've even used my own sweat for waterbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling.</charAction> That's very resourceful, Katara. You're thinking
            like a true master. But did you know you could even pull water out of thin air?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In a quick movement of her right arm, Hama uses waterbending to manipulate
                the water vapor in the air, liquefying it and coating her fingertips.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>You have got to keep an open mind, Katara. <charAction>The water around her
                fingertips freezes, creating ice claws.</charAction> There's water in places you
            never think about.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She proceeds to fire the small daggers at a nearby tree, while Katara looks
                on in amazement.</description>
            <description>Meanwhile, Aang, Sokka, and Toph are wandering about the landscape
                surrounding the village, trying to uncover any signs of disruption that would anger
                the spirits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>This has got to be the nicest natural setting in the Fire Nation. I don't see
            anything that would make a spirit mad around here.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera focuses on Toph and Sokka. Toph is standing casually near where
                Sokka is deeply inhaling the aroma of a bundle of flowers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe the Moon Spirit just turned mean.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> The Moon Spirit is a gentle, loving lady. She
            rules the sky with compassion and ... lunar goodness!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Catches sight of a villager walking past.</charAction> Excuse me, sir.
            Can you tell us anything about the spirit that's been stealing people?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Villager">Villager</speaker>
        <speech>Only one man ever saw it and lived and that's Old Man Ding.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Where does Old Man Ding live?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to a field of fire lilies, where Hama continues to tutor
                Katara in waterbending.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Wow, these flowers are beautiful.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>They're called fire lilies. They only bloom a few weeks a year, but they're one of
            my favorite things about living here. And like all plants and all living things, they're
            filled with water.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I met a waterbender who lived in a swamp and could control the vines by bending the
            water inside.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>You can take it even further.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In a sharp, swiveling motion, she draws water from dozens of the
                surrounding fire lilies and slices a nearby rock clean through.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That was incredible! <charAction>Sees the wilted lilies.</charAction> It's a shame
            about the lilies, though.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>They're just flowers. When you're a waterbender in a strange land, you do what you
            must to survive. Tonight I'll teach you the ultimate technique of waterbending. It can
            only be done during the full moon, when your bending is at its peak.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cautiously.</charAction> But isn't that dangerous? I thought people have
            been disappearing around here during the full moon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Oh, Katara. Two master waterbenders beneath a full moon? <charAction>Begins walking
                away.</charAction> I don't think we have anything to worry about.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The two exit the field. The scene fades to later that night, where Aang,
                Sokka, and Toph are approaching Old Man Ding, who is boarding up his
                windows.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Old Man Ding?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ding">Ding</speaker>
        <speech>Huh? <charAction>Accidentally hammers his thumb.</charAction> Ow, dang blame it!
            What? Can't you see I'm busy? Got a full moon rising. And why does everyone call me
            that? I'm not that old! <charAction>Attempts to lift a wooden plank off the ground, but
                fails to do so. Sighs.</charAction> Well, I'm young at heart.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang approaches and helps Ding lift the board.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ding">Ding</speaker>
        <speech>Not ready to get snapped up by some moon monster yet at least.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Proceeds to nail the board to the window frame.</charAction> We wanted
            to ask you about that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Did you get a good look at the spirit that took you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ding">Ding</speaker>
        <speech>Didn't see no spirit, just felt something come over me, like I was possessed. Forced
            me to start walking toward the mountain. <charAction>Points to the
                mountain.</charAction> I tried to fight it, but I couldn't control my own limbs. It
            just about had me into a cave up there. <charAction>Imitates a walking
                puppet.</charAction> And I looked up at the moon for what I thought would be my last
            glimpse of light. <charAction>Cuts to shot of the trio, Sokka quivering in
                fear.</charAction> But then the sun started to rise and I got control of myself
            again! I just high-tailed it away from that mountain as quick as I could!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why would a spirit want to take people to a mountain?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>Oh no! <charAction>Sokka and Aang assume defensive positions.</charAction> I did
            hear people screaming under the mountain. The missing villagers must still be
            there!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They all stare at the mountain. The scene changes to where Aang, Sokka, and
                Toph are racing through the dark forest in search of the imprisoned
                villagers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Feels the ground with her hand.</charAction> I can hear them. They're
            this way!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The trio proceeds to sprint toward the mountain. Meanwhile, Hama and Katara
                venture into the moonlit forest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>Can you feel the power the full moon brings?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She inhales deeply through her nose and stretches her arms outward, flexing
                her limbs which causes her veins to bulge out, while Katara looks on in
                disgust.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>For generations it has blessed waterbenders with its glow, allowing us to do
            incredible things!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera depicts a shot of her standing beneath the full
                moon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Extreme close-up; in a sinister tone.</charAction> I've never felt more
            alive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene changes to Aang, Sokka, and Toph, who have arrived at the
                mountain and are standing before the mouth of the cave.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>This is the place.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I can't see anything down there.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grabs Sokka's hand.</charAction> That's why you have me. Let's
            go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The three descend into the dark cave and approach a solid metal door,
                torches nearby. Using metalbending, Toph breaks it down, while the trio proceeds to
                make their way through the tunnel, Aang and Sokka lighting their path with the
                torches. They arrive to see several villagers chained to the walls of the
                cave.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male prisoner #1">Male prisoner #1</speaker>
        <speech>We're saved!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph unfastens her meteor bracelet and begins to unlock the prisoners'
                shackles.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I didn't know spirits made prisons like this. Who brought you here?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female prisoner">Female prisoner</speaker>
        <speech>It was no spirit.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male prisoner #2">Male prisoner #2</speaker>
        <speech>It was a witch!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>A witch? What do you mean?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female prisoner">Female prisoner</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Speaking, as Toph unlocks her shackles.</charAction> She seems like a
            normal old woman, but she controls people like some dark puppetmaster!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Gritting.</charAction> Hama!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male prisoner #1">Male prisoner #1</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, the innkeeper!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I knew there was something creepy about her!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We have to stop Hama!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I'll get these people out of here. You go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Sokka flee from the scene, while Toph stays behind. The scene
                switches to the forest. A cat owl hoots and flies away. The camera focuses on Hama
                and Katara, their backs facing the camera, the wind blowing their hair slightly,
                looking toward the moon.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>What I'm about to show you, <charAction>Cuts to close-up of Hama glaring
                menacingly.</charAction> I discovered in that wretched Fire Nation prison.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene fades to a flashback of a younger Hama imprisoned within a cage.
                She peers through the bars of her cell and looks down mournfully. The camera zooms
                out to the entire prison room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> The guards were always very careful to keep any
            water away from us. They piped in dry air and had us suspended away from the ground.
            Before giving us any water, they would bind our hands and feet so we couldn't bend.
                <charAction>A side-view is shown of Fire Nation guards giving water to a tied up
                prisoner.</charAction> Any sign of trouble was met with cruel retribution.
                <charAction>Cuts to shot of the full moon in the sky during present
                day.</charAction> And yet each month, I felt the full moon enriching me with its
            energy. <charAction>Cuts to shot of Hama.</charAction> There had to be something I could
            do to escape. <charAction>Scene fades to flashback of the prison.</charAction> Then I
            realized that where there is life, there is water. <charAction>A younger Hama is shown
                bending the water inside an elephant rat that had wandered its way into her
                cage.</charAction> The rats that scurried across the floor of my cage were nothing
            more than skins filled with liquid and I passed years developing the skill that would
            lead to my escape. <charAction>A close-up is shown of Hama smiling at her discovery. The
                scene fades back to present day. Ominously.</charAction> Bloodbending.
                <charAction>Cut to a scared Katara.</charAction> Controlling the water in another
            body, <charAction>Cut to ground shot of both Hama and Katara.</charAction> enforcing
            your own will over theirs. <charAction>The scene fades back to a flashback of young Hama
                controlling a horde of rats using bloodbending.</charAction> Once I had mastered the
            rats, I was ready for the men.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera switches over to show a Fire Nation guard strolling past the
                cages when a sudden feeling comes over him. Using bloodbending, Hama forces the
                guard to grab hold of his keys and unlock her cell, thus marking her
                escape.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> And during the next full moon, I walked free
            for the first time in decades. <charAction>The guard attempts to get up, but Hama
                quickly forces him back down to the ground. She walks unsteadily away.</charAction>
            My cell unlocked by the very guards assigned to keep me in. <charAction>Scene changes
                back to present day; camera focuses on a close-up of Hama.</charAction> Once you
            perfect this technique, you can control anything or <charAction>Looks at Katara from the
                corner of her eyes sadistically.</charAction> anyone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unsure.</charAction> But ... to reach inside someone and control them?
                <charAction>Casts unsure glance off to the side.</charAction> I don't know if I want
            that kind of power.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera zooms out to the two standing in the forest.</charAction> The
            choice is not yours. The power exists. And it's your duty to use the gifts you've been
            given to win this war. <charAction>Closes up to Hama.</charAction> Katara, they tried to
            wipe us out, our entire culture, your mother!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of her face.</charAction> I know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera changes back to Hama.</charAction> Then you should understand
            what I'm talking about! We're the last two waterbenders of the Southern Tribe.
                <charAction>Camera focuses on Katara; off-camera.</charAction> We have to fight
            these people whenever we can, wherever they are, with any means necessary!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Widens eyes in realization.</charAction> It's you ...
                <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You're the one who's been making people disappear
            during the full moons!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Close-up of her face, as she tilts her head downward.</charAction> They
            threw me in prison to rot, along with my brothers and sisters! They deserve the same!
            You must carry on my work!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Points to Hama, stretching out her left hand.</charAction> I won't! I
            won't use bloodbending and I won't allow you to keep terrorizing this town!
                <charAction>Her hand suddenly twists to one side. She tries desperately to stop it,
                but fails to do so.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Now using bloodbending to subdue to her.</charAction> You should've
            learned the technique before you turned against me! <charAction>Forces Katara into a
                strained position.</charAction> It's impossible to fight your way out of my grip! I
            control every muscle, every vein in your body!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>With swift motions of her hands and arms, Hama uses bloodbending to twist
                Katara around and throw her from side to side. She positions Katara directly before
                her and uses a downward motion of her hand to force her into a submissive
                state.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tearfully.</charAction> Stop! Please ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hama laughs cruelly and keeps Katara subdued. The shot is showing the full
                moon slowly fades to a close-up of Katara's face as she is crying. Several moments
                pass as the young waterbender begins to break free from Hama's grip. Hama stares in
                shock as Katara inhales deeply and rises, now free from her grasp.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Determined.</charAction> You're not the only one who draws power from
            the moon! <charAction>Assumes a fighting stance.</charAction> My bending is more
            powerful than yours, Hama. Your technique is useless on me!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>A waterbending duel ensues between the two. Katara pulls a ring of water
                around her waist and sends the stream of water at Hama, who halts it and sends it
                back to Katara. In a swift spinning motion, Katara sends the stream toward Hama
                again, who draws water from nearby trees, deflects the attack and sends a highly
                pressurized water jet at her. Katara uses her hands to block the attack,
                disintegrating the water into droplets. Upon seeing Katara's bending prowess, Hama
                becomes shocked, allowing for her opponent to use waterbending to knock her to the
                ground.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shouts.</charAction> Aahhh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka and Aang approach the scene as Hama rises to her knees.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We know what you've been doing, Hama!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Give up! <charAction>Takes a fighting stance.</charAction> You're
            outnumbered!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>No! <charAction>Rising.</charAction> You've outnumbered yourselves.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She begins bloodbending Aang and Sokka, who yell in fear, and sends them in
                Katara's direction. Katara pushes them out of her way and draws water from the
                ground, sending a stream at Hama, who in turn draws water from a vine and uses a
                water wheel to deflect the attack.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Unwillingly draws his sword.</charAction> Katara, look out!
                <charAction>Forced to walk like a puppet, while waving the blade back and forth
                rapidly.</charAction> It's like my brain has a mind of its own! Stop it arm, stop
            it!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara pulls up a ring of water and pushes Sokka away.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>This feels weird!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Using waterbending to freeze him to a nearby tree.</charAction> I'm
            sorry, Aang!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She catches sight of Sokka, still under Hama's power, unwillingly prepared
                to strike her with his sword. She draws water from a vine and freezes his sword and
                hand to a tree as well.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sinisterly.</charAction> Don't hurt your friends, Katara! And don't let
            them hurt each other!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She uses bloodbending to break Aang and Sokka free from their ice
                encasement and send them colliding straight into one another with Sokka's sword
                pointing straight at Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Horrified.</charAction> No!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang and Sokka abruptly halt in their tracks and look at their hands in
                confusion. The camera focuses in on Hama, who has suddenly stiffened, and cuts to
                Katara, an unsure look on her face as she uses bloodbending to subdue the elder.
                Focusing first on Hama, who grunts in discomfort, the camera turns to show the
                imprisoned villagers and Toph approaching the scene before cutting to moments later
                when the elderly waterbender is arrested, handcuffs placed around her
                wrists.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male prisoner #1">Male prisoner #1</speaker>
        <speech>You're going to be locked away forever.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hama">Hama</speaker>
        <speech>My work is done. <charAction>Turns to Katara.</charAction> Congratulations, Katara.
            You're a bloodbender.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera focuses on Katara, who is clearly distressed and breaks down in
                tears. Hama is shown laughing evilly as she is dragged away by the villagers. The
                camera returns to focus on Katara, who is crying underneath the full moon as Aang,
                arm around her, and Sokka, hand on her back, attempt to comfort her. Fades to
                credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
