<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>The Day of Black Sun Part 1</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode starts in the Black Cliffs, with the scene cutting to a shot of
                three maps lying splayed out on the ground. Cut to Sokka who ponders over the maps
                intensely. He closes his eyes and rubs his forehead, seemingly confused. Two gloved
                hands suddenly appear, one holding a cup and the other moving Sokka's hand aside
                from his forehead to hand him the cup. The hand comes to rest on his shoulders
                comfortingly. Cut to zoomed out shot of Sokka sitting by a cliff-edge, the maps laid
                out before him. Katara is kneeling right beside him, having been the one to hand him
                the cup. Toph can be seen in the background, sitting idly on a rock. Aang suddenly
                appears on-screen, leaping into the air and landing beside Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Momo jumps onto his shoulder; cheerfully.</charAction> Top of the
            morning, Momo!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Rises and places hands on hips.</charAction> Sounds like you slept
            well.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Moves his hand aside in a sweeping motion.</charAction> Like a baby
            moose lion. <charAction>Assumes a fighting stance and raises fists;
                exuberantly.</charAction> I'm ready to face the Fire Lord.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>So, what's your strategy for taking him down? <charAction>Smiling and raises her
                hands to her eyes, her fingers wiggling outward in a mimicry of the Avatar
                State.</charAction> Gonna get your glow on and <charAction>Punches the air with a
                determined expression on her face.</charAction> hit him with a little Avatar State
            action?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks down sorrowfully.</charAction> I can't. <charAction>Cut to
                side-view of him, the camera panning slightly to the left.</charAction> When Azula
            shot me with lightning, <charAction>Close his eyes briefly.</charAction> my seventh
            chakra was locked, cutting off my connection to all the cosmic energy in the universe.
                <charAction>Cut back to shot of him and Toph.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>You know what I just heard? <charAction>Holds up one hand and opens and closes it in
                a "gibber-gabber" expression.</charAction> Blah, blah, spiritual mumbo jumbo blah,
            blah, something about space. <charAction>Bored.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to a wide shot of the ocean; thick fog is visible on the
                horizon.</charAction> Oh, no. <charAction>Cut to a shot of Katara, appearing
                concerned.</charAction> Sokka, do you think the fog will delay the
            invasion?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands up.</charAction> No. <charAction>Cut to close-up of the fog, five
                Water Tribe ships suddenly appearing from amid the mist.</charAction> That is the
            invasion!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to shot of Hakoda standing on the deck of one ship, peering through a
                telescope; Bato stands in the background. Hakoda lowers the telescope and smiles
                confidently. Scene fades to shot of the shoreline where Aang and Toph stand in the
                background by the water. They utilize earthbending to raise rock from beneath the
                water and form a dock. Cut to overhead shot of the Black Cliffs to show four Water
                Tribe ships already docked. The last Water Tribe ship is seen coming into port. Cut
                to closer shot of one ship by the dock, Hakoda standing nearby. Katara and Sokka run
                over to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You made it, Dad! <charAction>Cut to shot of Katara embracing her father
                happily.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Spirited.</charAction> Were you able to locate everyone I told you to
            find?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>I did. <charAction>Two members of the Foggy Swamp Tribe disembark.
                Doubtfully.</charAction> But I'm a little worried, Sokka. Some of these men aren't
            exactly the "warrior type". <charAction>Turns head slightly toward the two swamp
                dwellers.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to frontal shot of Tho and Due as they descend the wooden ramp from the
                ship.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enthusiastically, swinging his arm.</charAction> Oooh-whee!
                <charAction>Cut to shot of the two men standing on the dock.</charAction> This place
            ain't nothing like a swamp. <charAction>Points accusingly to a rock in the
                water.</charAction> What you reckon that is, Tho? Some sort of Fire Nation exploding
            trap what eat ya?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Impartial.</charAction> It's just a rock, Due.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Grins.</charAction> Well, I'll be. <charAction>Scratching his
                head.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Is it just me, or are those fellas a little loose in the leaf-hat?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bato">Bato</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walks past, behind the chief and his family, stopping beside
                Sokka.</charAction> I just wish they would wear pants.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Huu">Huu</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to shot of Huu standing alone on the dock. Scratches his
                stomach.</charAction> Pants are an illusion, and so is death.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to shot of the Hakoda, Katara, and Bato appearing less than reassured;
                Sokka, on the other hand, grins widely. Scene fades to far shot of Katara, Aang,
                Toph, and several Foggy Swamp members clustered by the shore, talking among
                themselves. A pair of legs appears on screen, boasting Earth Kingdom clothing. A
                voice speaks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> Hi, Katara. <charAction>Cut to close-up of the
                figure who reveals himself to be Haru; he smiles, now sporting a small mustache and
                goatee.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to zoomed out shot of Haru.</charAction> Haru! <charAction>Runs over
                and embraces him.</charAction> It's so good to see you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Appears on screen with Toph.</charAction> Toph, this is Haru. When we
            met him, his town was controlled by the Fire Nation. So he had to hide his
            earthbending.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Haru">Haru</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With Katara resting a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> Katara inspired
            me and my father to take back our village. <charAction>Turns to Katara who blushes and
                looks away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Tyro appears and lays his hands on Haru's and Katara's
                shoulders.</charAction> You helped us find our courage, Katara. <charAction>Katara
                turns to him.</charAction> Now we're here to help you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph suddenly senses someone on her left. She angrily turns and takes a
                fighting stance.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>No way! Is that-</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>She is lifted off the ground by two big arms. The camera shows that the
                arms actually belong to the Big Bad Hippo, a former competitor at Earth Rumble VI.
                He is joined by the Boulder, another former competitor. The Hippo hugs
                Toph.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Big Bad Hippo">Big Bad Hippo</speaker>
        <speech>Hippo happy to see Blind Bandit!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You guys here for a rematch?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>Negatory. The Boulder and The Hippo no longer fight for others' entertainment. Now,
            we fight for our kingdom!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Sweet.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera cuts to Sokka, while The Hippo puts Toph down. He turns to his
                dad. Suddenly, a bomb explodes on a boat, making Sokka, Hakoda, and Aang run toward
                it. The mechanist appears from below deck, coughing. Teo leaves the boat, followed
                immediately by his father, and Pipsqueak carrying The Duke on his
                shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Was that a new invention?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mechanist">Mechanist</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Teo licking his fingers clean.</charAction> Yes, but unfortunately the
            incendiary capabilities of peanut sauce prove to be a failure.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>The others seems disgusted.</charAction> You're making peanut sauce
            bombs?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Pipsqueak">Pipsqueak</speaker>
        <speech>They're destructive.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech>And delicious. <charAction>They both lick the sauce that splashed all over their
                faces. Momo flies over to Pipsqueak and starts licking his face, much to his and The
                Duke's amusement.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Where you able to complete work on the plans I send you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mechanist">Mechanist</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, I was, and I think the Fire Nation will be quite surprised.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Teo">Teo</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, my dad and I made this for you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hands a staff to Aang. Aang taps it on the ground and it opens, revealing a
                brand new glider.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>A new glider! This is amazing!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mechanist">Mechanist</speaker>
        <speech>And as a special feature, I added the snack compartment. <charAction>Rotates the
                handle, making the snacks come out.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Oh ... well, I'm sure that will come in handy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to the Fire Nation prison where Iroh was sent
                to.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden Poon">Warden Poon</speaker>
        <speech>I bet you're tired of being in this cell old man. Well too bad. <charAction>Camera
                shows Iroh's face.</charAction> You're never stepping outside these walls
            again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ming">Ming</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Enters.</charAction> Breakfast.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Warden Poon">Warden Poon</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stands.</charAction> Careful, Ming, don't get too close. His stench will
            knock you right out. <charAction>Leaves, laughing.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ming">Ming</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks at Poon contemptuously and approaches Iroh.</charAction> I snuck
            in some white jade tea. I know you like rare teas.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Ming places the tray of tea inside Iroh's cell.</charAction> Thank you,
            Ming. Ever since I was put in here, you have been very kind to me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show a very nervous Sokka standing on a podium with his
                father and Team Avatar</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Don't worry, you'll do great.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Good morning everyone. Ahh! <charAction>Trips on stage.</charAction> Umm ... so, as
            you know, today, we're invading the Fire Nation! I mean I know you know that because
            otherwise why else would you be here? <charAction>Laughs nervously.</charAction> Uh
            anyway, <charAction>Dropping scrolls. Unraveling one on a board.</charAction> the Fire
            Lord's palace is here <charAction>Points at map, realizing it isn't the map, flips the
                chart several times until it is the map.</charAction>. Uh nope, uh wait, uh wait, uh
            wait, it's here, <charAction>Brief shot of Due scratching his head.</charAction> and uh,
            there's an eclipse today and Aang's gonna fight the Fire Lord and the firebenders won't
            have any fire to use so that's good for us! <charAction>Brief shot of Teo and the
                mechanist looking on.</charAction> And ... um ... I'm sorry let me start at the
            beginning <charAction>Stands up straight, and begins talking very fast.</charAction>.
            Katara and I discovered Aang frozen in an iceberg, now I didn't like Aang at first but
            grew to love him over time, then we went to the Southern Air Temple where Aang used to
            live and then we met Suki, <charAction>Water Tribe warrior yawns.</charAction> who's a
            Kyoshi warrior. She dressed me like a woman and then she kissed me, and then Aang's
            friend was a crazy old king and ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Cut to Katara speaking over Sokka as he continues talking.</charAction>
            Wow, when he says the beginning he means the beginning beginning. <charAction>Hakoda
                gets up and approaches Sokka.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>... And then Katara got Haru arrested and then now he's grown a mustache which if
            you look at him in the front row you can see it ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Interrupting.</charAction> Thank you, Sokka. It's okay why don't you
            take a break? <charAction>Sokka leaves the stage to sit down, disappointed in himself.
                Hakoda addresses the crowd.</charAction> Let me just clarify a few points for
            everyone. <charAction>Shot of Haru stroking his chin. Everyone pays attention to
                Hakoda.</charAction> Today, is the day of black sun, and I want to thank you all for
            your self-sacrifice, and your courage. There are two steps to the invasion, a naval
            stage, and then a land stage. <charAction>Shot of Sokka looking down, sad, Katara, Momo
                and Aang looking at Hakoda and Toph.</charAction> To gain sea access to the Fire
            Nation capital, we need to get past our first major obstacle here, <charAction>Points at
                map.</charAction> The Great Gates of Azulon. Next, we hit the land, and we hit hard.
            We must fight past their battlements and secure the plaza tower. Once we do that, it's
            up to the Royal Palace. At that point, the eclipse will begin.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Boulder">The Boulder</speaker>
        <speech>Excuse me. The Boulder is confused. Isn't the point to invade during the eclipse,
            when the firebenders are powerless?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>The eclipse only lasts eight minutes, not enough time for the whole invasion. And
            the Royal Palace is heavily guarded by firebenders. So that's where we'll need the
            eclipse's advantage the most. When this is finished, the Avatar will have defeated the
            Fire Lord. We will have control of the Fire Nation capital, and this war will be
            over!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The entire crowd cheers, and Sokka looks dismayed.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show the team preparing for the upcoming battle. Katara
                is bending four streams of water into water skins, Toph is putting on her Blind
                Bandit battle armor, Hakoda is putting on a black Water Tribe helmet, Appa is shown
                fully dressed in his armor which Sokka made, and Aang is shaving his head to show
                his Air Nomad tattoos. He is joined by a koala sheep. The scene cuts again to the
                Fire Nation Palace. Zuko takes off his head piece and armor, revealing the clothes
                underneath it and letting his hair hang down. He sits and starts to write a letter.
                The camera cuts once again to show Sokka, still dismayed, standing on the cliff side
                and Aang flying up to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>We've been looking everywhere for you. The boats are ready to leave.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I messed up, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The invasion plan was my moment of truth and I completely flubbed it. I just fell
            apart.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches, putting a hand on his shoulder.</charAction> Sokka, that
            speech wasn't your moment of truth. That was just public speaking, and nobody's really
            good at that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>My dad is! He explained the plan perfectly and inspired everyone, like a real leader
            should.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Look, your moment of truth isn't gonna be in front of some map; it's gonna be out
            there on the battlefield.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You seem so confident about everything, how do you know we're gonna win?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Because I already failed the world once at Ba Sing Se. I won't let myself fail
            again.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera cuts to show the fleet of ships traveling across the sea. Cut to a
                view through a Bato's telescope.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>There they are, the Great Gates of Azulon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I don't see any gates.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Katara and Hakoda's boat.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, you and the swamp benders whip up a fog cover.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <speech>We'll sneak by them statues just like we sneak by that Fire Navy blockade!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to show Katara, Due, and other swamp benders waterbending a thick fog
                cover.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Keep it up, we're almost through!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly a bell rings as a huge net rises out of the water and is set on
                fire. Sokka and the others are shocked to see patrol boats racing toward
                them</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone below deck! <charAction>Everyone goes into the boats; to
                Sokka.</charAction> Let's hope your invention works.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Camera shows several Fire Nation soldiers climbing onto the boats. They are
                shown to search the boats thoroughly, but find no one.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Male Fire Nation soldier">Male Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>No one's on board, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Female Fire Nation soldier">Female Fire Nation soldier</speaker>
        <speech>Where'd they go?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Several submarines are shown traveling beneath the gates. Inside,
                waterbenders are moving the subs. Cut inside a sub as the mechanist is sitting at
                the front. Hakoda, Sokka, Pipsqueak, and Bato are standing behind him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Placing a hand on Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> You've really outdone
            yourself this time, son.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to Toph, who is sitting on the floor behind them with the Duke. She is
                getting seasick.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, congratulations, Sokka. You managed to
            invent a worse way of travel than flying. <charAction>She holds her mouth, about to
                throw up.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="The Duke">The Duke</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Takes off his helmet and offers it to Toph.</charAction>
            Helmet?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph accepts his offer and vomits into the helmet. The Duke just places his
                hand on Toph's back, trying to comfort her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Well, I just came up with the idea. The mechanist did all the work.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Mechanist">Mechanist</speaker>
        <speech>Now don't sell yourself short, my boy. <charAction>Cut briefly to Katara and Huu
                waterbending.</charAction> It was your idea to use waterbending to make the subs
            sink and float, brilliant! <charAction>Cuts back to the mechanist opening a scroll,
                revealing a very crude drawing of a submarine.</charAction> Though your original
            designs were a bit difficult to decipher. Unfortunately there is one problem I couldn't
            fix. <charAction>Cut to outside of submarine as the submarines swim past, along with
                Aang on Appa.</charAction> The subs have a limited air supply. Before we land on the
            beaches, we'll need to resurface.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show Ming coming back into Iroh's cell.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ming">Ming</speaker>
        <speech>Lunchtime, General Iroh. <charAction>Whispers and looks back.</charAction> And this
            time, I brought you an extra bowl of rice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you, Ming. Your little gestures of kindness have made my days in prison
            bearable. <charAction>Thinks for a moment and smiles.</charAction> I think you should
            take the rest of the day off.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ming">Ming</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Confused.</charAction> What?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You don't look well. Maybe you should go home and rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Ming">Ming</speaker>
        <speech>No, I feel fine.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Brief close-up of his face.</charAction> Trust me. It is better that you
            are not here this afternoon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Ming nods, indicating that she understands. She gets up and walks out. The
                scene cuts to show the fleet of submarines surfaced on the water. The Duke is
                dipping his helmet into the water, trying to wash out Toph's vomit. Everyone is
                stretching as Aang lands on the submarine from Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>To Toph, Sokka, and Katara, who approach him.</charAction> So, this is
            it huh?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Are you ready for the Fire Nation to know the Avatar is alive?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm ready. <charAction>Sokka and Aang shake hands and the group
            hugs.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Toph">Toph</speaker>
        <speech>I hope you kick some serious Fire Lord butt, Twinkle Toes.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone listen up. <charAction>Team Avatar comes out of the hug.</charAction> The
            next time we resurface, it'll be on the beaches. So stay alert, and fight smart. Now
            break time's over, back in the subs. <charAction>Sokka, Toph, and Momo leave Katara and
                Aang standing alone together.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turning to see Katara.</charAction> Katara, I ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Speaking at the same time.</charAction> Aang, I ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You go first.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>We've been through so many things together, and I've seen you grow up so much.
            You're not that little goofy kid I found in the iceberg anymore. <charAction>Aang
                blushes.</charAction> I guess what I'm trying to say is, I'm really proud of
            you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Everything's gonna be different after today, isn't it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Yes, it is.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What if ... what if I don't come back?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, don't say that, of course you'll- <charAction>Katara is cut off as Aang kisses
                her. After the kiss, Katara blushes and stares sadly after Aang as he confidently
                snaps his glider and flies away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Katara, what are you doing? It's time to submerge.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What? Right, I'm on it. <charAction>Jumps onto Appa and waterbends a sphere of water
                around his head before submerging.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show Zuko walking into Mai's room. He looks at a painting
                of them and becomes downcast.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sorry Mai.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He leaves a note on her bed and leaves. The scene cuts to show Aang flying
                over land. His stomach growls, and he rotates the handle of his glider to release
                food.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What do you know? It did come in handy.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show the submarine fleet approaching land. The other end
                of a periscope emerges above water, looking around. Cut to inside the sub, Hakoda
                manning the periscope. Realizing where they are he turns around to address the
                earthbenders.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone in position. Earthbenders, into your tanks. This is gonna be a rough
            ride.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Toph and other earthbenders climb down a ladder in the sub and get ready.
                Cut to an overview of the Fire Nation port. An alarm goes off as the subs approach
                the gate. Several harpoons are launched at the subs, but most miss. One hits,
                causing a leak which is quickly sealed by a foggy swamp waterbender turning the
                water to ice, and pulls the attached sub out of the water. Katara quickly responds
                by piloting Appa out of the water and using waterbending to slice through the chain,
                dropping the sub back down.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Ready the torpedo. <charAction>An ice-covered torpedo is loaded.</charAction>
            Launch!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Huu launches the torpedo with waterbending. Cut outside as six torpedoes
                make holes in the underwater barrier, making it possible for the subs to pass
                through.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show Toph, the Boulder, and other earthbenders standing
                in a metal tank. Cut to Water Tribe warriors and foggy swamp waterbenders with Sokka
                among them, he lets out a sigh. Cut to the subs rising from the water, being
                instantly attacked by missiles. The subs open and several tanks exit while the other
                soldiers yell and charge out. The battle commences as they make their way inland,
                destroying battlements as they go. Earthbenders use rocks provided by a truck
                containing many rocks. Appa arrives and Katara jumps off as Fire Nation tanks
                appear. Teo is seen inside an earthbender tank before it destroys a battlement by
                crushing it. Another tank lifts its front up to slam down and crush a Fire Nation
                tank. More Fire Nation tanks arrive as the army pushes on. The swamp benders use
                water provided to destroy enemy tanks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tho">Tho</speaker>
        <speech>We're a man down. Where in tarnation is Huu? <charAction>He and Due continue
                waterbending, launching a tank into the water.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Suddenly a large seaweed monster is shown coming out of the water and
                destroys several enemy tanks, throwing one into a battlement on the ledge
                above.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Due">Due</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Waves.</charAction> Hey Huu! Where you been? <charAction>The seaweed
                opens to reveal Huu standing inside.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Huu">Huu</speaker>
        <speech>Communin' with nature. Takes a while to collect this much seaweed.
                <charAction>Closes the seaweed again as he sees a large fireball coming straight
                toward him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Several Fire Nation soldiers on rhinos appear shooting fireballs at a group
                of Water Tribe warriors. They charge, and Sokka quickly disarms one of the riders
                and steals his rhino.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Dad, look out!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hakoda grunts as he turns and deflects a fireball with his shield. He turns
                back to disarm a soldier and quickly defeats others before jumping on the rhino to
                join Sokka. The vehicle full of rocks for earthbenders is destroyed. Huu, inside the
                seaweed, is shown destroying more tanks. An earthbender tank is destroyed by a
                battlement above. Cut to Hakoda and Sokka who saw this happen.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, we've gotta take out those battlements! It's our only chance.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>I've got an idea.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka, Hakoda, and Katara are shown riding a fully armored Appa. Sokka
                draws his sword and slices the end of a missile launcher off. As they fly past
                another, Hakoda throws two bombs inside the battlement. Cut to two soldiers running
                out as it explodes. Cut back to Appa as Katara breaks two barrels of water attached
                to either side of Appa as it forms around her arms. They fly past another battlement
                she freezes the soldier and launcher inside. Appa lands between two still
                operational battlements. The three jump off Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>You two take out that battlement. <charAction>Pointing to a battlement in the
                distance before leaving to another.</charAction> I got this one. Watch each other's
            backs. <charAction>Cut to Sokka and Katara, shown breaking into their battlement, Katara
                freezing the soldiers inside. Sokka uses his sword to cut through the launcher,
                causing part of it to fall out and explode outside as Katara and Sokka exit the
                battlement. They see Hakoda on the roof of his as he climbs inside. They hear noises
                from the ensuing fight until the launcher shoots and explodes, hearing Hakoda
                yelling out in pain. Cut to Sokka and Katara's worried faces as Hakoda exits,
                wounded, and falls to the ground.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Dad?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Dad! <charAction>The two run to his side.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The camera cuts again to show Zuko kneeling at a painting of his
                mother.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>I know I've made some bad choices, but today, I'm gonna set things right.
                <charAction>He rises, picks up his sword, covers his head with the hood of his robe,
                turns his back to the camera and leaves.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show Appa landing on the edge of the battlefield. Sokka
                and Katara help Hakoda onto the ground, and Katara starts trying to heal
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>How does that feel, dad?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, a little, better. I need, to get back to the troops. <charAction>Attempts to
                stand but is too weak to.</charAction> Ahh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're hurt, badly. You can't fight anymore.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>Everyone's counting on me to lead this mission Katara, I won't let them down.
                <charAction>Attempts to stand again but can't.</charAction> Ahh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Can't you heal him any faster?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm doing everything I can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks around before looking confidant.</charAction> I'll do it.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>No offense Sokka, but you're not exactly Mr. Healing Hands.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>No. <charAction>Stands confidently.</charAction> I'll lead the invasion
            force.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Don't be crazy Sokka.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Maybe I am a little crazy, but the eclipse is about to start and we need to be up
            that volcano by the time it does.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Hakoda">Hakoda</speaker>
        <speech>You can do this. <charAction>Cuts to a close-up of him.</charAction> I'm proud of
            you son.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I still think you're crazy, but I'm proud of you too.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Nods, puts his helmet on and boards Appa.</charAction> Yip yip.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Appa flies away as the scene cuts to show the battlefield, a mess of Fire
                Nation tanks destroyed everywhere. Several raised battlements fire on the army
                below. Appa lands and takes out an enemy tank as Sokka makes his way to the back of
                the saddle to rally the soldiers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Listen up, everyone. I want the tanks in wedge formation. Warriors and benders in
            the middle. We're taking that tower, and heading for the royal palace. <charAction>All
                the tanks come together in wedge formation behind Appa, soldiers protected in the
                middle. Cut to Sokka, on Appa, who draws his sword and thrusts it
                forward.</charAction> Charge!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to show Aang standing on the edge of the volcano. He glides
                down to a building attempting to hide. He rises, confused, as there is nobody
                there.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking around.</charAction> That's strange. <charAction>He continues
                onto the Royal Palace, breaks open the door, and takes a fighting
                stance.</charAction> The Avatar is back! <charAction>Realizing no one is around he
                relaxes, looking confused.</charAction> Hello? Anyone home?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to the tanks, which are making their way up the volcano,
                unaffected by fire blasts from firebenders in front. Cut to Sokka steering a vehicle
                full of explosives into a wall before jumping off. Cut to an aerial view showing two
                explosions at the inner walls. Cut to Sokka, soldiers behind him, as they charge
                forward. Firebenders attempt to stop them but are pushed back. Cut to Tyro running
                in with the other troops as Bato appears behind him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Tyro">Tyro</speaker>
        <speech>The Fire Nation is falling back!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Bato">Bato</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, we're on our way to victory!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks ahead as the camera cuts to show Aang airbending his way into
                an empty, darkened throne room.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>No. <charAction>Kneels down on the ground; frustrated.</charAction> No, no, no! Fire
            Lord Ozai, where are you!?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Scene fades to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
