<root>
    <metadata>
        <title>Winter Solstice Part 1</title>
    </metadata>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The episode opens to a cloudy sky, looking toward the ground. The point of
                view switches to one above the clouds as they pass by. A messenger hawk floats into
                view, emitting a cry. When Appa overshadows the bear and roars, it shrieks again and
                stoops down, swiveling out of view. The camera shifts to a side-view of Appa soaring
                along with Aang, Katara and Sokka in his saddle.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over; somewhat dreamily.</charAction> Those clouds look so soft,
                <charAction>Cut to Aang sitting lazily atop Appa's head, a twig in his mouth; the
                view pans to the left, showing Sokka carving something with an uninterested look on
                his face, Katara lying on her stomach, popped up on her elbows, staring dreamingly
                over the rim of Appa's saddle, and Momo sleeping on the luggage.</charAction> don't
            they? Like you could just jump down and you'd land in a big, soft, cottony
            heap?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Turns to Katara; mockingly with a smile.</charAction> Maybe you should
            give it a try.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looks at Sokka with annoyance; sarcastically as she looks away from
                him.</charAction> You're hilarious.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Frontal shot; excitedly.</charAction> I'll try it! <charAction>Carrying
                his staff, he jumps off Appa with a big smile on his face. As he begins to fall, he
                turns once around his axis, winking at the camera as he passes. He falls down
                spreadeagled, laughing joyously.</charAction> Yeah!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a side-view of Appa's saddle as Katara and Sokka pop their heads
                over the rim, looking down in the direction Aang went. Cut to an upward looking shot
                following Aang falling down, still smiling broadly. As he passes the camera, it
                tilts down, following him as he vanishes in a cloud. Cut back to the siblings;
                Katara looks somewhat worried, while Sokka gazes wide-eyed at the point where Aang
                vanished. When he leans over to search the sky, Aang comes back up from behind them
                on his glider. The siblings turn around as they hear the snapping noise of Aang's
                glider being closed, and they watch how the airbender plops down on the saddle, his
                legs spread apart and a big smile on his face. Cut to a side-view of an unimpressed
                looking Sokka, before switching back to a frontal shot of Aang who is dripping
                wet.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Looking at himself.</charAction> Turns out, clouds are made of
            water.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He breaths in deeply and slams his balled, right fist against his stretched
                left hand, creating an expanding air ball around him in the process, drying himself
                off. As Aang leans back to rest on both his hands, he contently looks at Momo, whose
                fur got all fluffed by Aang's airbending. Cut to a side-view of Sokka, who is still
                looking at Aang unimpressed. Katara glances at her brother, but her attention is
                drawn to something over his shoulder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, what is that?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Sokka looks over his right shoulder in the direction Katara is looking as
                well. Katara gets up and walks to the front of Appa's saddle. Cut to a shot of the
                landscape in front of them, a large, dark patch of burned land standing out among
                the lush green of the forest. Cut to a frontal view of the trio now all looking over
                the front rim of Appa's saddle, surprised looks on their faces.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Camera zooms in.</charAction> It's like a scar ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene fades to a ground view of the scorched forest. The camera pans to
                the right, showing many burned trees, and Team Avatar standing in the middle of a
                gray, barren patch.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Listen. <charAction>Cut to a frontal shot of a
                sad-looking Aang, his friends behind him.</charAction> It's so quiet. There's no
            life anywhere.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang? Are you okay?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Noticing footprints; angrily.</charAction> Fire Nation! Those evil
            savages make me sick! They have no respect for -</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Shhh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Whispering angrily.</charAction> What? I'm not allowed to be
            angry?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara points to Aang with a somewhat concerned look on her face as he
                slumps over, downcast at the sight.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Kneels down and sighs. He picks up some ash as it slowly seeps through
                his hand and drops to the ground; sadly.</charAction> Why would anyone do this? How
            could I let this happen?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, you didn't let this happen. It has nothing to do with you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sadly.</charAction> Yes, it does. It's the Avatar's job to protect
            nature. But I don't know how to do my job.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That's why we're going to the North Pole. <charAction>Smiling softly.</charAction>
            To find you a teacher.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah. A waterbending teacher. But there's no one who can teach me how to be the
            Avatar. Monk Gyatso said that Avatar Roku would help me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar before you? He died over a hundred years ago; how are you supposed to
            talk to him?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't know. <charAction>Momo comes up to Aang and settles in his
            lap.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>In another area, Zuko comes looking for Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle! It's time to leave! Where are you? Uncle Iroh!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Relaxing in a hot spring.</charAction> Over here!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle? We need to move on. We're closing in on the Avatar's trail and I don't want
            to lose him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You look tired, Prince Zuko. Why don't you join me in these hot springs and soak
            away your troubles?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>My troubles cannot be soaked away. It's time to go!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>You should take your teacher's advice and relax a little. The temperature's just
            right. I heated it myself. <charAction>He breathes steam through his
            nose.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Enough! We need to leave now. Get out of the water!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Very well! <charAction>He gets up, exposing himself.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Shielding his eyes.</charAction> On second thought, why don't you take
            another few minutes? But be back at the ship in a half-hour or I'm leaving without
            you!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh sighs as he slumps back into the water.</description>
            <description>The scene returns to the forest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Approaches Aang.</charAction> Hey, Aang! You ready to be cheered
            up?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sadly.</charAction> No. <charAction>An acorn is thrown at
                him.</charAction> Ow! Hey, how is that cheering me up?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> Cheered me up. <charAction>An acorn gets thrown
                at him.</charAction> Ow. Yeah, I probably deserved that.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>These acorns are everywhere, Aang. That means the forest will grow back! Every one
            of these will be a tall oak tree someday, and all the birds and animals that lived here
            will come back. <charAction>She places the acorn in his hand and closes
            it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Thanks, Katara.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Katara smiles at him before gasping at the sight of an old man
                approaching.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, who are you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>When I saw the flying bison, I thought it was impossible! <charAction>Approaches
                Aang.</charAction> But, those markings ... are you the Avatar, child?
                <charAction>Aang look to Katara, who nods. He nods himself.</charAction> My village
            desperately needs your help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The scene cuts to them at Senlin Village at sunset. The village has been
                partially destroyed. The wanderer leads them into the center building.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>This young person is the Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>So, the rumors of your return are true! It is the greatest honor of a lifetime to be
            in your presence.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Nice to meet you too! So ... is there something I can help you with?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not sure ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>Our village is in crisis, he's our only hope! <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> For
            the last few days at sunset, a spirit monster comes and attacks our village. He is Hei
            Bai, the black and white spirit.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Why is it attacking you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>We do not know, but each of the last three nights, he has abducted one of our own.
            We are especially fearful because the winter solstice draws near.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>What happens then?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>As the solstice approaches, the natural world and the Spirit World grow closer and
            closer until the line between them is blurred completely.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>Hei Bai is already causing devastation and destruction. Once the solstice is here,
            there's no telling what will happen.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>So, what do you want me to do, exactly?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>Who better to resolve a crisis between our world and the Spirit World than the
            Avatar himself? You are the great bridge between man and spirits.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Right ... that's me.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Hey great bridge guy, could I talk to you over here for a second? <charAction>She
                leads him toward a window.</charAction> Aang, you seem a little unsure about all of
            this.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, that might be because I don't know anything at all about the Spirit World.
            It's not like there's someone to teach me this stuff!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>So ... can you help these people?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I have to try, don't I? Maybe whatever I have to do will just ... come to me.
                <charAction>Momo lands on his shoulder.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With a kind and reassuring smile.</charAction> I think you can do it,
            Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>With a similar expression.</charAction> Yeah. <charAction>Brief
                pause.</charAction> We're all going to get eaten by a spirit monster.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to the hot spring. A sleeping Iroh is awoken by nearby stirring in
                the trees.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Who's there? <charAction>He sees a rat-like animal.</charAction> A meadow vole! I
            should have known. <charAction>He takes the creature into the palm of his
                hand.</charAction> You startled me, little one. <charAction>Sighs.</charAction> It
            seems I dozed off and missed my nephew's deadline, but it was a very sweet nap.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The meadow vole leaps up and down. This is followed by shaking and the
                ground moving toward Iroh. Suddenly, the rock at the bottom of the spring jumps up,
                capturing him. Three Earth Kingdom soldiers surround him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Soldier">Soldier</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Picks up Iroh's clothes.</charAction> He's a Fire Nation
            soldier.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>He's no ordinary soldier. This is the Fire Lord's brother, the Dragon of the West.
            The once-great General Iroh, but now, he's our prisoner.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh gives the captain a stern look.</description>
            <description>Cut back to Senlin, near sunset. Aang steps outside the center building and
                awaits the Hei Bai.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Walking toward the village entrance.</charAction> Hello, Spirit? Can you
            hear me? This is the Avatar speaking. I'm here to try to help stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to the building interior. Sokka and Katara watch.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>This isn't right. We can't sit here and cower while Aang waits for some monster to
            show up.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>If anyone can save us, he can.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>He still shouldn't have to face this alone.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sun sets and night falls. Cut back to Aang.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>The sun has set. Where are you, Hei Bai? Well ... spirit ... uhhh ... I hereby ask
            you to please leave this village in peace. <charAction>He spins his staff and sticks it
                down, in apparent authority.</charAction> Okay ... well ... I guess that's settled,
            then.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He walks away. Behind him, however, the Hei Bai fades into the real world.
                He walks right behind Aang, who turns to see him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You must be the Hei Bai spirit. My name is–</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The spirit releases a burst of energy at him. It moves past
                him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>My name's Aang! I'm the Avatar and I would like to help. Hey, wait up!
                <charAction>Hei Bai wreaks havoc, smashing buildings and destroying a tower with
                energy.</charAction> Uhhh ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar's methods are ... unusual.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>It doesn't seem too interested in what he's saying. Maybe we should go help
            him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>No. Only the Avatar stands a chance against the Hei Bai.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang will figure out the right thing to do, Sokka. <charAction>Closes her eyes in
                satisfaction.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Hei Bai smashes another building.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Please, would you stop destroying things and listen? I'm trying to do my job as
            spirit bridge! Excuse me, would you please turn around? <charAction>Shouts.</charAction>
            I command you to turn around now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The spirit hits Aang and sends him flying to the roof of another building,
                and Aang grunts.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>That's it. He needs help. <charAction>Exits the building.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, wait! <charAction>Starts to follow him.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Stops her.</charAction> It's not safe!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Hei Bai, over here! <charAction>He throws his boomerang at him, but it barely
                affects the monster. He runs toward it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka, go back!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>We'll fight him together, Aang.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I don't want to fight him unless I– <charAction>Sokka is taken by the Hei Bai, and
                the spirit flees. Aang chases it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Running to the village entrance.</charAction> Sokka! <charAction>The
                villagers go the entrance as well. Katara is left standing
            fearful.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back near the hot spring. Two soldiers and Zuko look for
                Iroh.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Uncle! Uncle, where are you?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation Soldier">Fire Nation Soldier</speaker>
        <speech>Sir, maybe he thought you left without him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Something's not right here. That pile of rocks.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Fire Nation Soldier">Fire Nation Soldier</speaker>
        <speech>It looks like there's been a landslide, sir.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Land doesn't slide uphill. Those rocks didn't move naturally. <charAction>Stands up
                straight.</charAction> My uncle's been captured by earthbenders!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back to the forest. Aang continues to pursue the Hei Bai, looking for
                Sokka.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Aang! Over here! Help!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hang on, Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Aang pulls out his hand, trying to free Sokka. Sokka grunts, trying to
                reach him. However, before he can grab him, the spirit fades away, taking Sokka with
                it. Aang shouts and falls in front of a bear-like statue, knocked out.</description>
            <description>A couple of hours later, Aang awakens.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka! <charAction>He realizes Sokka is nowhere to be seen.</charAction> I
            failed.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The next scene cuts back to the soldiers who captured Iroh. They are riding
                ostrich horses. One soldier carries a torch with him for light.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Where are you taking me?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>We're taking you to face justice.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Right, but where, specifically?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>A place you're quite familiar with, actually. You once laid siege to it for 600
            days, but it would not yield to you.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Ah, the great city of Ba Sing Se.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>It was greater than you were, apparently.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>I acknowledge my defeat at Ba Sing Se. After 600 days away from home, my men were
            tired, and I was tired. <charAction>Yawns.</charAction> And I'm still tired.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He falls off one of the horses. He is quickly picked back up. However, he
                leaves one of his sandals behind and smiles cunningly.</description>
            <description>Cut back to Senlin Village. Katara awaits at the village entrance for Sokka
                and Aang. The Kay-fon approaches her.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>I'm sure they'll be back.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I know.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Places a blanket around her.</charAction> You should get some
            rest.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Everything's going to be okay ... <charAction>She turns her
            blanket.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>Your brother is in good hands. I would be shocked if the Avatar returned without
            him. <charAction>As he is speaking, Aang approaches.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Katara? Katara, I lost him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The sun rises.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Kay-fon">Kay-fon</speaker>
        <speech>The sun is rising. Perhaps he will return soon.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>His appearance is blue.</charAction> What? No, I'm right here!
                <charAction>He waves his hand in the Wanderer's face, only to notice his own
                appearance.</charAction> I'm in the Spirit World!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to the forest. Zuko comes up on Iroh's sandal.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech><charAction>Sniffs and gets a disgusted look.</charAction> Yeah, that's Uncle Iroh.
                <charAction>He re-mounts his rhino.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Back at the Village.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'll figure this out, Katara. I promise. Like they said, I'm the bridge between the
            worlds, right? All I have to do is ... figure out what I have to do. But once I do that,
            no problem. <charAction>Appa approaches.</charAction> Appa! Hey buddy, I'm right here!
                <charAction>He breathes on Katara.</charAction> But, I guess you can't see me
            either.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's okay, Appa, don't worry. I'm sure they're on their way back. I bet they even
            found you a bunch of moon peaches for a treat. <charAction>The two return the
                village.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>What am I supposed to do? Avatar Roku, how can I talk to you? <charAction>He turns
                his head in disappointment, when he hears something.</charAction> Sokka?
                <charAction>He notices a dragon coming toward him.</charAction> That's definitely
            not Sokka. <charAction>He tries to fly away but cannot. He notices his airbending is not
                working at all.</charAction> What? I can't airbend in the Spirit World.
                <charAction>The dragon lands just before him.</charAction> You don't know where
            Sokka is, do you? <charAction>The dragon touches him. He sees a vision of Roku flying on
                this dragon.</charAction> You're Avatar Roku's animal guide! Like Appa is to me! I
            need to save my friend and I don't know how! Is there some way for me to talk to Roku?
                <charAction>The dragon curls around him, and he gets on him.</charAction> I'll be
            back, Katara. <charAction>It gets up.</charAction> Take me to Roku! <charAction>The
                dragon flies away.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut to a mountain where the earthbenders are leading Iroh through. Iroh
                looks at the skies and notices the dragon and Aang. He gasps in
                wonder.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>What's the problem?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Nothing. <charAction>Pauses.</charAction> Actually, there is a bit of a problem. My
            old joints are sore and aching, and these shackles are too loose.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>Too loose?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>That's right. The cuffs move and jangle around and bump my wrists. It would help me
            if you tighten them so they wouldn't shake around so much.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>Very well. Corporal, tighten the prisoner's handcuffs.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>They all stop. The corporal dismounts and moves to Iroh. As he touches his
                handcuffs, Iroh breathes deeply and heats them up. He pushes the corporal's hand to
                the cuffs, causing him to scream in pain. Iroh jumps free and blasts fire at the
                soldiers. He rolls down the hill as the soldiers try to get control of their ostrich
                horses.</description>
            <description>Cut back to Aang and Fang. Fang takes him to a temple on an unknown island.
                He flies into the temple and toward the roof.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Hey, what are you doing? <charAction>He screams, but they fly right through the roof
                and into a mysterious room. Within is a celestial calendar and a statue of
                Roku.</charAction> I don't understand, this is just a statue of Roku.
                <charAction>Fang presses one of his feelers to Aang's forehead. A vision of a comet
                appears to him.</charAction> Is that what Roku wants to talk to me about? A comet?
            When can I talk to him? <charAction>Fang moves his head, allowing a light beam to
                appear. This is just to the right of Roku's statue. With another feeler press, he
                sees a vision of the sun setting and rising repeatedly, and the light closing in on
                Roku.</charAction> It's a calendar, and the light will reach Roku on the solstice!
            So, that's when I'll be able to speak to Roku? <charAction>The dragon breathes an
                apparent yes.</charAction> But I can't wait that long! I need to save Sokka now!
                <charAction>The dragon takes Aang from the temple.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Iroh rolling down the hill. One of the soldiers hits him with a
                rockslide. All of the soldiers chase after him, reaching him at the bottom of the
                hill.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Soldier">Soldier</speaker>
        <speech>He's too dangerous, Captain! We just can't just carry him to the Capital! We have to
            do something now!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>I agree. He must be dealt with immediately and severely.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Iroh spits a rock out.</description>
            <description>Meanwhile, Katara is flying on Appa over the forest.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>It's no use, Appa. I don't seem them anywhere. Our best hope is to go back to the
            village and wait. <charAction>She re-directs Appa to the village's
                direction.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>While following the ostrich horse footprints, Zuko notices
                Appa.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>The Avatar!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He turns slightly, but looks back at the footprints, debating whether he
                should save his uncle or follow Appa.</description>
            <description>Cut to Fang, who takes Aang back to the statue at high speed. Aang notices
                his body is there and also prepares for impact.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Whoa!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>He tries to shield himself, bracing the collision. Suddenly, Fang
                disappears into the statue and Aang is returned to his body. He looks scours the
                area and jumps down from the statue. There he stares at the statue he was returned
                to, before opening his glider and flying back to the village.</description>
            <description>Cut to the village, sunset. Katara stands outside the center building and
                notices Aang's return. Aang lands and Katara runs to him.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You're back! <charAction>She embraces Aang.</charAction> Where's Sokka?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I'm not sure ...</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The evening gives way to night.</description>
            <description>Back to Iroh, who is surrounded by the soldiers.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>These dangerous hands must be crushed. <charAction>He brings up a boulder and
                prepares to drop it. However, Zuko jumps in and kicks the rock away before breaking
                Iroh's chain with his boot.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Excellent form, Prince Zuko.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>You taught me well.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Earthbender captain">Earthbender captain</speaker>
        <speech>Surrender yourselves. It's five against two. You're clearly outnumbered.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Iroh">Iroh</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, that's true, but you are clearly outmatched.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The solders fire rocks, but Iroh destroys them with the chains. Zuko takes
                out two soldiers with fire. A rock is fired at him, but Iroh catches it and throws
                it back at the soldiers, knocking them down. The captain fires three rocks at Zuko,
                which he dodges. Zuko counters with fire blasts that are dodged. The captain brings
                up a large mass of rock, however, Iroh throws his chains around his ankles, knocking
                him and causing the rocks to fall on top of him. The soldiers are heard groaning
                underneath the rocks.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Zuko">Zuko</speaker>
        <speech>Now would you please put on some clothes?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Cut back to Senlin. Aang awaits at the entrance for the Hei Bai. After some
                time, he gives up and returns to the center building. Just as he exits, however, the
                spirit appears to his left. He throws up an air shield to stop its
                attack.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Aang, what are you doing?! Run!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The spirit prepares to resume its attack when Aang jumps in front of it. He
                feels its forehead and notices that a panda lurks below it.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>You're the spirit of this forest! Now I understand. You're upset and angry because
            your home was burned down. When I saw the forest had burned, I was sad and upset, but my
            friend gave me hope that the forest would grow back. <charAction>He shows it the acorn
                and leaves it at his feet. The spirit picks it up and reverts to the panda form. It
                walks away peacefully. As it exits, a series of branches grow, and three villagers
                and Sokka emerge from it.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka! <charAction>She runs to him and embraces him, while other villagers embrace
                their loved ones.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What happened?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>You were trapped in the Spirit World for 24 hours! How are you feeling?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Like I seriously need to use the bathroom. <charAction>Sokka waddles away,
                displaying a nauseated look. She gives him an unsure gaze.</charAction></speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>Thank you, Avatar. If only there were a way to repay you for what you've
            done.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>You could give us some supplies, and some money.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>Sokka!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What? We need stuff.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Senlin Village leader">Senlin Village leader</speaker>
        <speech>It would be an honor to help you prepare for your journey.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>I'm so proud of you, Aang. You figured out what to do, all on your own.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Actually, I did have a little help and there's something else.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>What is it?</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>I need to talk to Roku and I think I found a way to contact his spirit.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>That's great!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Sokka">Sokka</speaker>
        <speech>Creepy, but great.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>There's a temple on a crescent-shaped island and if I go there on the solstice, I'll
            be able to speak with him.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Katara">Katara</speaker>
        <speech>But the solstice is tomorrow!</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speaker name="Aang">Aang</speaker>
        <speech>Yeah, and there's one more problem. The island is in the Fire Nation.</speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>The siblings grow fearful. The shot slowly moves up to the moon over the
                hills.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
    <p>
        <speech>
            <description>Fade to credits.</description>
        </speech>
    </p>
</root>
