<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>Sokkas Master</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins a shot of a meteor shower. Camera pans down with Aang,
                Katara, Toph and Sokka watching the meteor shower.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Wow, this is amazing to watch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut closer to a side-view of the group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Kind of makes you realize how insignificant we are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Close-up. Causally.</charAction> Eh, you've seen nothing once, you've
            seen it a thousand times.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut further away showing the meteor shower above them. They see a big
                meteor heading for the ground and let out gasps of amazement.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh man, <charAction>Close-up. Standing.</charAction> you've <description>never
            </description>not seen anything like this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The others, minus Toph, stand up next to him. Cut to panning shot as the
                meteor flies past. Cut to overhead shot of meteor as it flies past the group. Cut to
                side-view of the group as the meteor passes over head. Cut to Sokka as he turns to
                see the meteor crash nearby. Cut to the other side of a hill as Toph climbs up. Cut
                to wide shot as the camera zooms out with the group looking toward the crash site.
                Frontal view of Aang, Katara and Sokka who look at each other concerned. Cut to the
                team arriving at the crash site on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The fire is gonna destroy that town!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not if we can stop it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Appa landing next to the crash site. Everyone but Katara jumps
                off.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Jumps onto Appa's head, taking the reins.</charAction> There's a creek
            over here. I'll bend the water onto the fire. <charAction>Signals Appa to take
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Toph, Sokka, and Aang.</charAction> Toph, let's make a
            trench to stop the fire from coming any closer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph and Aang move off. Sokka looks down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What should I do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to view from Sokka's perspective as Toph and Aang stop to respond. Momo
                flies by.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slight pause, points at Momo.</charAction> Keep an eye on Momo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to aerial view of Sokka. Momo lands on his shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So what, I'm just a lemur sitter? <charAction>Pets Momo; sarcastically.</charAction>
            There, there, feel better?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang and Toph as they begin to earthbend. Cut to aerial shot as a
                trench forms. Briefly cut back to Aang and Toph continuing to earthbend. Cut to
                aerial shot as they finish the trench, pushing the fire back. Cut to aerial view of
                Sokka as flames fly near him and land on the ground. Sokka puts out one with his
                machete, however Momo ups him by putting out five in the same time, much to his
                dismay. Cut to Katara on Appa flying over a river. Katara grabs some water and they
                return to the crash site. Cut to side-view of Katara, on Appa, with a large globule
                of water following behind. Frontal view of Katara as she begins to waterbend the
                water behind her. Side-view of the crash site as Sokka and Momo look on while Katara
                puts out some of the fire with her waterbending. Cut to Toph beginning to earthbend.
                Cut to aerial view of her and the nearby crash site as she uses earthbending to put
                some of the fire out. Cut to Sokka, who sits, watching, along with Momo as the earth
                Toph is using rolls past. Cut to Aang as Appa flies past with Katara. Katara gives
                Aang some water to bend.waterbending and airbending to put the rest of the fire out,
                but the water hits Sokka and Aang's blast also makes it snow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka, stand clear!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view of the crash site with Sokka and Momo looking
                left.</charAction> Right. <charAction>Picks up Momo and makes to move
                away.</charAction> Staying clear, got it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang as he begins to use both the water and airbending. Cut to
                frontal view of Sokka still walking away as the water overwhelms him. Cut to aerial
                view of the crash site as the water expands to put out the fire. The dome of water
                explodes into snow. Cut to frontal view of Aang as Appa, along with Katara, lands
                behind him as Toph walks toward him, too.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good work, everybody.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aerial view of the town and crash site. Cut to Sokka as he emerges from a
                pile of snow. Momo slides across the icy surface.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to a Fire Nation prison. Cut inside. A door opens, lighting up the
                    face of Iroh. Cut outside the cell as Warden Poon enters the room and approaches
                    the cell. Frontal view of Poon as he drops a bowl. Side close-up view of the
                    floor as the bowl lands on the ground which is kicked into the cell by Poon. The
                    camera follows the bowl which tips over and the contents spill out. Iroh
                    approaches hurriedly and eats it like an animal.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Warden Poon">Look at you, <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> you're just a fat, disgusting
            old man. <charAction>Panning aerial view from behind.</charAction> You do nothing, you
            say nothing, you just eat and roll around in your own filth like a pig.
                <charAction>Frontal view of Poon as Iroh continues to eat.</charAction> You're a
            disgrace. <charAction>Spits on the floor in front of him and
            leaves.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Frontal view of Iroh as the door shuts. Close-up of Iroh as he stops
                eating. Iroh moves his hair out of his face. Cut to a frontal view further away as
                he sits up and starts eating like a normal person, not eating anything from the
                floor as the camera pans out. </description>
      <section>
         <description>Scene changes to aerial view of the town Team Avatar saved. Cut to
                    side-view of an outdoor restaurant. Aang joins Katara and Toph at a
                    table.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">These people have no idea <charAction>Closer side-view of the three.</charAction>
            how close they were to getting toasted last night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, the worst thing about being in disguise is that we don't get the hero worship
            anymore. I miss the love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Boo-hoo, <charAction>Shot of Sokka from
                behind looking back.</charAction> poor heroes. <charAction>Turns
            away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Frontal view of Sokka with the others sat further behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What's your problem? You haven't even touched your smoked sea slug.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's just, all you guys can do this awesome bending stuff like putting out forest
            fires, and flying around and <charAction>Side-view of Toph, Aang and
                Katara.</charAction> making other stuff fly around. I can't fly around, okay?
                <charAction>View of Sokka from behind.</charAction> I can't
                do anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Side-view of the group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's not true. No one can read a map like you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I can't read at all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, and who keeps us laughing with sarcastic comments all the time?
                <charAction>Frontal view of Katara and Aang.</charAction> I mean, look at Katara's
            hair, right? What's up with that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What? What's wrong with my hair? <charAction>Blushes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Realizing his mistake.</charAction> Nothing. I was just trying to
            ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look, I appreciate the effort, <charAction>Cut to view from behind.</charAction> but
            the fact is each of you is so amazing and so special and I'm ... not.
                <charAction>Side-view close-up.</charAction> I'm just the guy in the group who's
            regular.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Approaches and sits next to him.</charAction> I'm sorry you're feeling
            so down, but I hope you know, none of us see you that way. <charAction>Frontal view of
                the two. Looks down for a moment before putting her hand on his
                shoulder.</charAction> I know something that's going to make you feel
            better.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view. Sadly.</charAction> You do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Sokka's face as the camera quickly pans out to reveal
                they are inside a shop full of weapons and armor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Shopping! <charAction>Clapping excitedly. Runs toward the camera. Cut to side-view
                as he approaches to view some weapons.</charAction> Maybe a little something to
            reinvigorate my battling. <charAction>Spots some nunchaku.</charAction> Hey, how about
            these? <charAction>Frontal view of Sokka. Sokka tests the nunchaku, making attacking
                noises, but he hits himself on the head and falls into some of the other
                weapons.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Katara trying on some gloves.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> What do you think? <charAction>Cut to Aang as
                the camera pans up to see him wearing strange, scary armor.</charAction> Pretty
            slick, huh? <charAction>Close-up of Katara with a scared and surprised expression.
                Side-view of Katara approaching Aang, holding a hand up to avoid the glare coming
                off Aang's helmet.</charAction> All I need to complete the outfit is a wind
            sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What's a wind sword?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's where I get a sword handle and then I just swing this around and bend air out
            like a blade. <charAction>Raises a sword handle, swishing it around like a
                sword.</charAction> Whoosh, whoosh, whoosh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Unconvincingly.</charAction> Yeah ... nice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang begins to fall over. Katara tries to stop him from falling, but Aang
                and the armor fall to the floor with a loud noise, causing Katara to cover her
                ears.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'll just stick to what I got.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Sokka holding a guan dao. He swings it to one side, swings it over
                his head and spins it in a circle. The weapon flies up toward the ceiling and Sokka
                puts his hands behind his back, innocently. Sokka is next seen dragging an enormous,
                metal club across the floor. He groans as he tries to lift it, but loses his grip
                and falls. Sokka is next seen holding two swords. He marches and chops downward with
                them. Sokka is next seen spinning a chain over his head, but he wraps the chain
                around himself and falls over. Sokka is seen running, carrying a very wobbly spear.
                Cut to close-up shot of Sokka standing up into the frame inspecting a sai, before
                using it as a toothpick. At that moment, something to his left gets his attention.
                Sokka turns to look as the camera pans round behind him. Sokka sees a sword rack on
                the wall, and a particular sword framed and positioned above the others. Cut
                close-up as the camera pans rights, showing all the details of the hilt and
                scabbard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Ooh! <charAction>Walks to the sword. Side-view of
                Sokka inspecting the sword.</charAction>
         <description>That's</description> what Sokka's talking about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Weapons store shopkeeper">You have a good eye. <charAction>Aerial view of Sokka as shopkeeper
                approaches.</charAction> That's an original from Piandao, <charAction>Katara, Toph
                and Aang approach.</charAction> the greatest swordsmaster and sword maker in Fire
            Nation history. <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> He lives in the big castle up the
            road from here. <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Side-view of group.</charAction> That's it! That's what you needed all
            along, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">A sword?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not the sword, a master. <charAction>Sokka takes the sword from the
                rack.</charAction> We've all had masters to help us get better. You should see if
            you can study with Piandao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Sokka with Katara behind.</charAction> That's a great
            idea. I could've never gotten to where I am without Master Pakku. Everyone needs a
            teacher.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Side-view of group.</charAction> I learned from badgermoles. They don't
            talk, but they're still good teachers.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up. Pulling out the blade, inspecting it.</charAction> It would be
            nice to be a master sword fighter. All right, I'll talk to him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the top of the bars of Iroh's cell. A ray of
                sunlight shines through a small window. It goes to an overhead shot of Iroh lying on
                his back on straw mat in the corner, hands behind his head. Cut to close-up
                side-view of his face. The camera suddenly zooms in as his eyes open wider. Cut to
                frontal view as Iroh begins to do a series of sit ups, grunting as he does so. The
                scene cuts to a shot of Piandao's castle, located on top of a large bluff. It goes
                down to a side-view of Sokka at the front gates. Cut closer behind Sokka as he grabs
                a knocker and taps it against the large door a few times. He waits a moment and
                looks around, but there is no answer. Sokka knocks the door and waits again. Still
                receiving no answer, Sokka becomes frustrated and grabs both knockers, banging them
                loudly and frantically. The right door is opened by the butler, Fat, frightening
                Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fat">
         <charAction>A little annoyed.</charAction> Can I help you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a close-up of Sokka still looking frightened. He quickly
                composes himself and assumes a more mannered persona.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I've come to train with the master.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fat">
         <charAction>Side-view of both.</charAction> You should know The Master turns almost
            everyone away. <charAction>Holds hand out in front of Sokka.</charAction> What did you
            bring him to prove your worth?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Well, uhh ... <charAction>Feels around,
                patting his clothes for something to offer.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fat">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Right ... <charAction>Shakes head
                sadly.</charAction> Let's get this over with.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fat gestures for Sokka to enter. Sokka steps through the gate and Fat
                closes the door. The scene cuts to an overhead shot of the castle courtyard as Sokka
                and Fat walk toward the main structure of the castle. The camera tilts up to the
                tallest tower. It cuts to a large room with a red carpet and tall windows, giving a
                view of the valley. Rows of lit candles are places on both sides of the windows.
                Piandao sits at a small table in front of the windows, his back to the camera. He
                has dark skin and wears a black cheongsam. Cut to a close-up of Piandao's hand
                holding a calligraphy brush and dipping it into a tray of ink, carefully holding his
                sleeve with the other hand. His hands move off screen and Sokka and Fat are seen in
                the background. The camera zooms in on Sokka as he steps forward.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Master, my name is Sokka, and I wish to be instructed in the way of the
            sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of Piandao, his back still toward Sokka. His sword
                is placed next to the table.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Sokka. That's an unusual name.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Nervously.</charAction> Oh, uh, really, uh where I come
            from, the Fire Nation colonies, it's a pretty normal name... for Fire Nation
            colonials.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Side-view. Writing calligraphy on a piece of parchment.</charAction> Let
            me guess. You've come hundreds of miles from your little village where you're the best
            swordsman in town. And you think you deserve to learn from the master.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Well, actually, I've been all over the
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Side-view of his arm and hand as he continues to write.
                Knowingly.</charAction> Yep, here we go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> And I know one thing for sure:
                <charAction>Gets down on his knees and hangs his head.</charAction> I have a lot to
            learn.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Shot from behind. Glancing back.</charAction> You're not doing a very
            good job of selling yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view of room.</charAction> I know. Your butler told me that when I
            met you, I would have to prove my worth. <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> But the
            truth is... I don't know if I am worthy.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up side-view.</charAction> Hm, I see. <charAction>Smiles and turns
                his head. Cut to his hand picking up his sword.</charAction> Well, then,
                <charAction>Close-up of Sokka.</charAction> let's find out together how worthy you
            are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka looks up as Piandao's shadow passes over him. Cut to a shot of the
                red carpet the end of Piandao's sword's scabbard strikes the floor. The camera
                quickly zooms out to a shot of Piandao standing before Sokka, sword firmly planted
                before him. Cut to a close-up of Piandao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">I will train you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of Sokka as a huge smile spreads across his face. The camera
                switches to Sokka and Piandao standing in a sword fighting ring in front of the
                building they were in earlier. Sokka is wearing an almost identical outfit to
                Piandao's.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> The first thing you must learn is that your
            weapon is an extension of yourself. <charAction>Cut further away as he unsheathes his
                sword and begins performing a sword form.</charAction> You must think of it as
            another part of your own body.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Like a second head.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> Well, more like an extra-long, really sharp
            arm. <charAction>Side-view of both. Continuing his demonstration.</charAction> The sword
            is a simple tool, but in the hands of a master it becomes
                <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> the most versatile of weapons,
                <charAction>Frontal view from below. Sheathes his sword and assumes a
                stance.</charAction> and just as the imagination is limitless, <charAction>Close-up
                of Sokka smiling in amazement.</charAction> so too are the possibilities of the
            sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka nods his head in understanding. Cut to Aang, Toph, Katara, Appa, and
                Momo in the countryside. Appa is sleeping under the makeshift roof.  </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What should we do today‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an overhead shot of Aang, Toph, and Katara lying on their backs in a
                circle. Momo runs up to them and lies down next to Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I'm tapped out. I already picked my toes, twice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Twice?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">The first time was for cleaning, but the second time's just for the
                <charAction>Wiggles her toes.</charAction> sweet picking sensation!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka's been in charge of the schedule. I'm not sure what we should be
            doing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Frontal view of Aang with Toph behind. Picking her nose.</charAction>
            Plus, it's so hot today.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Attempting to joke.</charAction> How hot is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I dunno. Real hot‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Camera pans across to show Katara.</charAction> I-It's so hot, it's
                so hot ... Momo is shedding like Appa. <charAction>Pets
                Momo and flicks tufts of fur from her fingers.</charAction> Huh, huh‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang scratches his head and Katara's joke receives no laughs, leaving her
                disappointed. It goes back to the overhead shot.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess the jokes don't run in the family.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to view of the countryside.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, everyone's a critic.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa grunts in response. The scene cuts to a shot of Iroh hanging upside
                down and doing crunches, panting with effort. It switches to a shot of his feet as
                he hangs from the overhead bars. Cut to and zoom out from a wide shot of Iroh doing
                the upside down crunches in his cell. The scene shifts to Piandao and Sokka standing
                in front of a table inside the building. On the table is calligraphy
                stationary.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">The warrior practices a variety of arts to keep his mind sharp and fluid.
                <charAction>Flattens out a piece of paper on the table.</charAction> The first you
            will learn is calligraphy. <charAction>Cut to his hands as Piandao delicately hands a
                brush to Sokka, who takes it, messing the bristles up with his thumb.</charAction>
            Write your name.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up. Skeptical.</charAction> Writing my name will make me a better
            swordsman‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Takes the brush and positions it correctly in Sokka's hand. Cut to a
                wide shot of both.</charAction> When you write your name, you stamp the paper with
            your identity. You must learn to use your sword to stamp your identity on a battlefield.
                <charAction>Sokka holds his sleeve back. Cut to close-up of the ink as Sokka dips
                the brush in to it. Cut to frontal view of Sokka readying himself to paint as
                Piandao looks on.</charAction> Remember, you cannot take back a stroke of the brush,
            or a stroke of the sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka's hand quivers and he sweats nervously, the brush barely an inch
                above the paper. He scratches his head and places the tip of the brush on his chin,
                thinking hard about what to do.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up as he moves forward.</charAction> You are getting ink on your
            face.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view of both.</charAction> I am? <charAction>Looks at the
                brush.</charAction> I am! So this is about putting my identity on the page,
            right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao nods. It cuts to a close-up of Sokka. He smiles and the camera
                zooms out as he proceeds to brush the ink over his face. The camera tilts down as
                Sokka presses his face onto the paper and rolls his head around. Cut behind Sokka as
                he picks up the paper and shows it to Piandao, smiling cheerfully. On the paper is a
                large inkblot which vaguely resembles a face. Piandao simply closes his eyes in
                response.</description>
      <section>
         <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the main building. The camera tilts down to
                    show Sokka and Fat facing off in the sword fighting ring, both wearing training
                    equipment and holding wooden swords. Piandao sits at the top of the steps
                    leading to the building, watching. Close-up of Fat as he wipes his nose as he
                    waits for Sokka to make a move. Cut to Sokka as he lunges at Fat and thrusts his
                    sword. Cut to side-view as Fat effortlessly parries the attack and knocks the
                    sword from Sokka's hands. Sokka runs away in fright and Fat chases after,
                    whacking him in the rear with the wooden sword.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the sky. The camera tilts down to a
                    blindfolded Sokka being guided through the countryside by Piandao.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Landscape painting teaches a warrior to hold the lay of the land in his
            mind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Side-view. Piandao stops Sokka, turns him to face left, and pulls off the
                blindfold.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">In battle, you only have an instant to take everything in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Sokka rubbing his eyes. The camera rotates around to
                his front as his eyes grow wide and he smiles with excitement and amazement. It cuts
                to a shot of Sokka and Piandao, their backs to the camera, standing before a
                majestic view of a mighty river flowing into a series of waterfalls that drop into a
                canyon. Cut back to Sokka. Piandao grabs his head and turns him away, making him sit
                in front of a table with a piece of paper, paint, and paint brushes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Now, paint it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Frontal view of Sokka, who gasps in disbelief. Side-view as he turns to
                look at the waterfall, but Piandao turns his head back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">And no peeking.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao walks away as Sokka takes a brush and begins to paint the intricate
                view. Cut to a wide shot of the landscape. The camera pans right, toward Piandao and
                Sokka. Fade to a shot of Piandao's back with his sword in his hands behind his back.
                The camera tilts up to his front, his eyes closed in silent
                meditation.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm finished!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao opens his eyes and looks at Sokka. Cut to a shot of Sokka
                presenting a very childish and colorful drawing of the landscape, which bears little
                resemblance, including a rainbow and a sun with a smiling face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> You added a rainbow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Worried.</charAction> Is that ok‌ay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up view as Piandao sighs and shakes his head. The scene cuts to the
                main building. The camera tilts down to Sokka and Fat in the sword fighting ring
                with the training gear. Sokka thrusts forward and he and Fat begin their practice
                fight. Sokka fares much better than before. Frontal view as he grunts as he parries
                a strike and attempts to swing his wooden sword down, but is
                distracted.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to and zooms out to show the fighting ring with Piandao still sitting
                above. Sokka looks over to Piandao, giving Fat the opportunity to circle behind him
                and kick him in the back, causing a slightly painful fall to the ground. Cut to
                Sokka looking up at Piandao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Concentrate on what you're doing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Sokka, who frowns and drops his head, giving Piandao a
                half-hearted thumbs up. Cut to a wide shot of Piandao's castle. The camera tilts
                down to Sokka and Piandao walking to the top of a stairway leading down to an empty,
                tiled area. A small statue of a lion turtle comes into the foreground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Rock gardening teaches the warrior to manipulate his surroundings and use them to
            his advantage.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a close-up of Sokka. He places a hand on his chin and
                thinks carefully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hm, manipulate them to my advantage ... oh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wide-view of the tiled area below. Piandao watches as Sokka runs
                down the steps. Cut to a shot of Piandao. A look of worry comes over him and the
                camera quickly zooms out to show Sokka rolling a huge stone across the ground. Sokka
                groans at the strain of it. Cut to a shot of a sheet of moss lying on a rock. Sokka
                appears from behind and examines its texture before taking it and running back to
                the other side of the area. Sokka throws the moss on the huge stone and lays down on
                it, sighing in relaxation. The camera quickly zooms out to a shot of Sokka lying on
                the easy chair he made from rocks and moss, expressing his content. Cut to a shot of
                Fat walking up from behind Piandao. Fat suddenly gasps in shock. It cuts to a shot
                of stones scattered all over the tiled floor, creating a mess. Sokka waves at
                Fat.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, would you mind grabbing a cold drink for me‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to Fat and Piandao. Fat gasps and turns to Piandao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">I'll take a slice of lemon in mine, please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <section>
         <description>Fat groans in resignation, hangs his head, and walks off to fetch the
                    drinks. Cut to Sokka and Fat dueling in the sword fighting ring again, Piandao
                    sitting in the foreground. Sokka and Fat thrust and parry a few strikes. Sokka
                    swings his sword in a circle and tries to hit Fat's leg, but Fat pulls his leg
                    up and he avoids the attack. Cut to a close-up of the two from behind Sokka. The
                    scene goes into slow motion as Fat swings his sword and Sokka parries it. Sokka
                    returns the strike and is also parried. The camera cuts to behind Fat as Sokka
                    continues his offense with four quick thrusts. Fat blocks all the attacks and
                    tries to attack Sokka. He misses, and Sokka uses this opportunity to slip the
                    blade of his wooden sword under Fat's hand and fling the wooden sword from it.
                    Fat is shocked and raises his hands in defeat as Sokka thrusts his sword forward
                    and places the blade on the side of Fat's neck, ending the duel. Sokka steps
                    away from Fat, puts his hands together and bows to Piandao, while Fat frowns
                    angrily at him. It cuts to a shot of Piandao sipping a drink from a cup with a
                    slice of lemon stuck on it.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>The scene cuts to a shot of the outside of the Fire Nation prison and
                    zooms in. Cut to the inside of Iroh's cell and zoom in on Iroh doing push-ups on
                    his knuckles, clapping his hands together at the apex of each push. Cut to a
                    shot of Warden Poon sitting and eating a piece of bread. He hears the clapping
                    and goes to investigate. Cut to Iroh continuing to do push-ups. Cut to Warden
                    Poon walking toward the door to Iroh's cell. Cut to a shot from inside the cell
                    of him looking in through the barred window in the door.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Warden Poon">What's going on in there‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Iroh sitting against the wall and lazily clapping his
                hands side to side with a delirious expression. Cut back to Warden
                Poon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Warden Poon">Crazy old man.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Warden Poon leaves. Cut back to Iroh. He claps a few more times and smiles
                when he is sure the warden is gone, ceasing his clapping and pushing back the stray
                hair hanging over his face. The scene cuts to a far shot of the Avatar group's
                campsite near the river. </description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">So where are we going next‌? <charAction>Cut to a shot of Aang and Katara sitting
                around a map of the Fire Nation. Pointing to the map.</charAction> We're starting
            from here ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Pointing at a different spot.</charAction> No, we're over on this
            island.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Lying down.</charAction> You noodle-brains don't know what you're doing.
            I miss Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ooh, I got one: if you miss him so much, why don't you marry him‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara grins at her joke. The camera quickly zooms out and a groan is heard
                in the background. Toph rolls over on her side, away from Katara. A winged insect
                buzzes in front of Aang, who simply blows it away with a quick blast of wind from
                his breath. Cut to a shot of the sword fighting ring in front of the main building
                at Piandao's castle. The camera tilts down to Sokka and Piandao sitting on the
                ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">You've had a good first day of training.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> I have‌? But I thought I messed up every
            single thing we worked on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view of feet. Camera pans up to his face.</charAction> You
            messed things up in a very special way. You are ready for a real sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Excited.</charAction> Are you giving me one of
            yours‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view.</charAction> No.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Frontal view of Sokka, who groans disappointedly and slumps
                down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Frontal view. Camera zooms in on his face.</charAction> Your sword must
            be an extension of yourself. So tomorrow, you will make your own sword.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to and zoom in on Sokka. He immediately perks up and grins. Cut to a
                shot of a rack of swords. Weapons are hung all about the room. The camera pans left
                to Sokka and Piandao standing at a table. On the table are several bricks of
                steel.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Choosing the correct material is the most important step in crafting a sword.
                <charAction>Close-up and zooms out showing the steel in front of him.</charAction>
            You must trust your steel with your life. Choose carefully.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka takes two bricks and weighs them in each hand. Sokka sets them down
                and takes another brick. He sniffs it and bites the brick to test its quality. Cut
                to side-view as Sokka puts the brick down and puts a hand to his chin thoughtfully.
                An idea comes to his mind and he turns to Piandao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Master, <charAction>Side-view of Sokka looking at Piandao.</charAction> would it be
            possible for me to leave and bring back a special material for my sword‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Side-view of Piandao looking at Sokka.</charAction> I wouldn't have it
            any other way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao smiles at Sokka. Cut to Aang, Katara, Toph and Appa all asleep and
                sitting around the map as they were before. Toph suddenly sits up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Sokka's coming!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Katara wake up, gasping and smiling excitedly. Cut to a shot of
                Sokka walking up to the top of the hill.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, guys. What are you doing‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, Katara, and Toph all jump at Sokka and give him a group
                hug.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sokka!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You're back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close-up of Sokka and Katara with Aang in the foreground.</charAction>
            We missed you so much!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up as he steps back slightly.</charAction> Say something
            funny!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up. Confused.</charAction> Funny how‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to overhead view as Aang and Katara both laugh heartily. Toph smiles
                and crosses her arms.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Side-view of Sokka with Toph in the foreground. To Toph.</charAction>
            What's their deal‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly.</charAction> I don't know. They missed you or something. I
            didn't care. <charAction>Turns away, blushing and smiling.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Overhead side-view of group.</charAction> Thanks. That warms my heart.
            Anyway, I need some help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the gang running over to the edge of the crater created
                the night before. Cut to a shot of the group, their backs to the camera, as they
                stare at the meteorite at the bottom of the crater.</description>
      <section>
         <description>The camera zooms in on the meteorite before cutting to an overhead shot
                    of Iroh sitting in his cell, looking through the bars in the ceiling. Cut to a
                    close-up of Iroh's eyes. They are closed for a brief moment before opening. Iroh
                    leans forward and puts his head on the floor. The camera cuts to a shot of
                    Iroh's legs rising into the air and tilts down as Iroh stands on his hands.
                    Close-up of Iroh sweating heavily, as he begins to perform hand-stand
                    push-ups.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>The camera cuts to outside the cell as it zooms out. The scene cuts to
                    a shot of Sokka, Aang, and Katara pushing the meteorite up the slope to
                    Piandao's castle. Toph is behind the meteorite, pushing it forward with her
                    earthbending. Fade to an overhead shot of the group and the meteorite at the
                    large doors. Sokka runs to the doors. Cut to behind Sokka as he bangs both
                    knockers frantically. Piandao opens one of the doors almost immediately and
                    steps out.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Who's this‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Overhead view from behind Piandao.</charAction> Oh, these are my
            friends. Just other good Fire Nation folks. <charAction>They bow to Piandao. Cut to
                Piandao, who bows back. The camera zooms out to show the meteorite and
                Sokka.</charAction> Do you think we can make a sword out of a meteorite‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao lays a hand on the meteorite and examines it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> We'll make a sword unlike any other in the
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a fiery forge. The camera zooms out and turns left to
                Sokka bare-chested and shoveling coal into it, before switching to Piandao and Fat,
                who is carrying a large sledge hammer. The camera cuts and tilts up to a shot of
                Sokka holding a chisel against the meteorite while Fat hammers it, Piandao watching
                in the back. Cut to a shot of Sokka tapping the chisel with a smaller hammer. A
                piece of the meteorite breaks off and falls to the floor. Sokka takes a moment to
                wipe the sweat from his brow. Cut to a shot of a wooden bucket filled with the
                meteorite fragments. Fat takes the bucket and the camera follows him as he brings it
                over to the forge. Sokka is seen working the bellows diligently. The camera zooms in
                as Katara and Aang peer in at Sokka from around the corner. Fade to a shot of the
                bucket sitting in the fires of the forge. Cut to a shot of Sokka holding his legs to
                his chest, asleep. He wakes up and looks behind him at the forge. He stands up and
                resumes shoveling in coal. The camera zooms out to show Piandao observing Sokka from
                outside. Fade to a shot of the bucket being pulled from the forge by Sokka with iron
                tongs. He carefully positions the liquid space metal over a mold of a blade and
                pours it in. Cut to a shot of the red hot metal being hammered against a stone. Cut
                to Piandao as he raises the hot blade and looks carefully at it. An excited Sokka
                can be seen behind him. Cut to a shot from inside a trough of water as Piandao dips
                the blade in. The blade makes the water bubble and boil as it hisses and cools,
                turning black. </description>
      <section>
         <description>Fade to a shot of the outside of the main building, the camera tilting
                    down to the open doors. Cut to a shot of the inside. Sokka is seated in front of
                    Piandao. Aang, Katara, and Toph sit behind Sokka while Fat stands behind
                    Piandao, holding Sokka's sword.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Sokka, when you first arrived, you were so unsure. You even seemed down on yourself.
                <charAction>Frontal view of Piandao as the camera pans across to the right revealing
                Fat.</charAction> But I saw something in you right away. <charAction>Side-view of
                Sokka.</charAction> I saw a heart as strong as a lion turtle, and twice as big.
                <charAction>Side-view of the room.</charAction> And as we trained, it wasn't your
            skills that impressed me. <charAction>Fat kneels to Piandao and gives him the sword.
                Frontal view of Piandao as he turns back to face the camera.</charAction> No, it
            certainly wasn't your skills. <charAction>Brief close-up of Sokka, who looks down in
                shame, before cutting back to a close-up of Piandao.</charAction> You showed
            something beyond that. <charAction>Unsheathes the sword, showing its black blade. Cut to
                side-view of Piandao as the camera zooms out and follows the blade as he strikes out
                to the side.</charAction> Creativity, versatility, <charAction>Frontal view of Sokka
                with the sword in the foreground.</charAction> intelligence ... <charAction>Sokka
                looks down.</charAction> these are the traits that define a great swordsman.
                <charAction>Side-view of Piandao as he sheathes the sword.</charAction> And these
            are the traits that define you. <charAction>Kneels and presents the sword to Sokka. Cut
                to frontal view of Sokka, from Piandao's perspective, who takes it.</charAction> You
            told me you didn't know if you were worthy, <charAction>Close-up shot as he stands
                up.</charAction> but I believe that you are more worthy than any man I have ever
            trained.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of the sword in Sokka's hands. The camera tilts up to Sokka
                as he lowers his head in shame.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm sorry, Master. You're wrong. <charAction>Close-up of Piandao.</charAction> I am
            not worthy. <charAction>Side-view of Sokka.</charAction> I'm not who you think I am. I'm
            not from the Fire Nation. I'm from the Southern Water Tribe. <charAction>Cut to
                side-view of Aang, Katara, and Toph who all gawk at Sokka with shock and disbelief.
                Close-up side-view of Piandao and Sokka.</charAction> I lied so that I could learn
            swordsmanship from you. I'm sorry. <charAction>Offering his sword
            back.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> I'm sorry, too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao quickly turns back around and swings his sword at Sokka. Cut to
                Sokka who stands and avoids the attack. Side-view of Sokka who, after unsheathing
                his sword, blocks a thrust from Piandao. Side-view of Aang, Katara, and Toph who get
                up and go to help Sokka. Cut to frontal view of the three that quickly zooms out to
                show Sokka who raises his hand to stop them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">No, this is my fight, alone.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Piandao before cutting to Iroh's cell. Warden Poon
                enters, carrying a tray of food. The camera pans right to a close-up of
                Iroh.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Warden Poon">You used to be the pride of the Fire Nation. Our top general, the Dragon of the
            West. Now, look at you. <charAction>Drops the food to the floor. Cut to aerial shot of
                the floor as the trays contents go everywhere. Iroh grabs a green fruit from behind
                the bars. Cut to close-up of Iroh on the ground as he moves the fruit to his
                mouth.</charAction> Look what you've become.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh watches the warden leave and stands up. Cut to frontal view as he puts
                the fruit to his mouth and holds it in his teeth as he begins to untie his belt.
                Close-up side-view as his shirt comes off and a thick, folded sheet that had been
                covering his belly falls to the floor. Cut to shot of the sheet hitting the ground
                and the camera tilts up to reveal Iroh's new, incredibly buff physique. Iroh takes
                the fruit from his mouth, bites into it, and jumps up. Cut to close-up shot above
                the cell bars as Iroh grabs a bar above with one hand. Side-view of Iroh who takes
                another bite of the fruit and begins doing one handed pull-ups. Cut to and zoom out
                on a side-view of Iroh and his cell.</description>
      <section>
         <description>The scene cuts to a shot of Sokka and Piandao squared off in the sword
                    fighting ring. Aang, Katara, Toph, and Fat watch from the upper part of the main
                    building. Cut to and zoom in on Sokka, ready with his black sword. Cut to a shot
                    of the tip of Piandao's sword pointed at the ground. The camera tilts up to him,
                    his other hand raised and pointed. Panning side-view of the others who watch
                    nervously.</description>
      </section>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to a panning right close-up of Sokka, before switching to a panning
                    left close-up of Piandao. Piandao lunges forward and begins his attack. Frontal
                    view of Piandao as Sokka backs away. Cut to a side-view of the scene as Piandao
                    strikes four times, each one parried by Sokka. Cut behind Piandao as Sokka
                    attempts a strike of his own. Piandao moves his head out of the way and stabs at
                    Sokka, who sways back and avoids the attack; Piandao sweeps his sword at Sokka's
                    legs, but Sokka jumps over it and lunges at Piandao, thrusting his sword
                    forward. Side-view of Piandao who deflects Sokka's blade and pushes him back.
                    Cut to behind Sokka as he is knocked back several feet and slides over the
                    ground. Frontal view of Sokka as he flips himself backward and grabs a post of a
                    small bridge to regain his balance. He quickly climbs onto the post and leaps to
                    the other one just as Piandao thrusts his sword at him, the camera pans to the
                    left to follow Sokka. Piandao spins around and tries to slice Sokka's foot. Cut
                    to Sokka's feet as he jumps away. Wide shot of entrance to the bridge as Sokka
                    jumps to the other rail of the bridge. Piandao stabs at Sokka again, but Sokka
                    jumps off the rail and rolls to the side. Piandao strikes again, but Sokka rolls
                    under the blade. Frontal view of Sokka as he blocks Piandao's next strike. The
                    camera pans to the left as Sokka runs to the left and jumps on to the railing
                    again. Cut to a view shot of bridge as Sokka leaps away to the end of the
                    bridge, dodging as Piandao swings his sword at him.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Excellent! <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Using your superior agility against an
            older opponent ... smart.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao charges at Sokka again. Close-up of Sokka as he readies his sword.
                Shot from behind Sokka as Piandao strikes at him and pushes him up a large stone
                stairway with the camera panning down to follow their movements. Cut to behind
                Piandao, titled up toward the stairs, as Sokka blocks all of the attacks, but the
                force pushes him against the wall of the stairway. Cut to Sokka as his back hits the
                wall and he deflects a thrust from Piandao upward, and ducks as the blade slices
                through the part of the wall above his shoulder. Cut to Piandao as he swings his
                sword around his head and body in two large circles. Frontal view of Sokka as he
                barely dodges Piandao's blade, cart wheeling to the right as the camera pans with
                him. Camera pans back left as Sokka spins back around, hops a foot off the ground
                and pushes off the wall with his legs, propelling himself forward, sword extended.
                Side-view as Piandao deflects the attack. Wide-view of the stairs as Sokka rolls
                across the stair to the other wall, climbing to the top. Frontal view of the wall as
                Sokka reaches the top.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Good use of terrain ... fighting from the high ground.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka swings at Piandao below him, who parries and swings at Sokka. Piandao
                thrusts his sword at Sokka, who pins the blade under his own blade, weighted down
                under his feet. Cut to Sokka standing on the swords before switching back to
                Piandao, who tries to wrench his sword free. Cut to Piandao's feet as he steps
                forward and the camera pans up as he pushes his sword upward, throwing Sokka off.
                View from behind Sokka as he grunts, stumbling back into a tall stalk of bamboo. Cut
                to a shot of Toph, Aang, and Katara all wincing at the sight. Cut back to Sokka as
                he looks up fearfully, strands of hair falling over his face. Frontal view of
                Piandao as he raises his sword and charges at Sokka. Cut back to Sokka as he ducks
                Piandao's attack that slices through the bamboo just above his head. He turns to run
                off into the bamboo thicket. Frontal view of Sokka as he runs away. Cut to frontal
                shot of Sokka running through the bamboo thicket, slicing through as many
                surrounding stalks of bamboo that he can. As Piandao chases after, the stalks all
                begin to fall. Close-up of Piandao skillfully cutting through the bamboo. Side-view
                of Sokka as he runs through the bamboo and turns, grabbing a stalk and pulling it.
                He lets it go just as Piandao catches up. Cut to the stalk whipping around. Cut to
                side-view of Piandao cutting through it with ease as Sokka tries to attack from
                behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Yes, use your surroundings. <charAction>Piandao deflects the attacks as Sokka runs
                away. Sokka grabs two stalks and pulls them back before releasing them. They whip
                around at Piandao, who slices through them.</charAction> Make them fight for
            you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Sokka running out of the bamboo and back toward the sword
                fighting ring, screaming in terror and Piandao not far behind. The camera shifts to
                Sokka's front. He is very frightened and takes a look behind, but Piandao has run
                off to the side and out of sight. Side-view of Sokka who turns to look ahead only
                for Piandao to strike out in front of him, trying to make him run into it. However,
                Sokka leans back. The scene goes into slow motion and the camera cuts to an overhead
                close-up of Sokka sliding under the blade. The scene comes back to normal speed and
                cuts to a frontal view as Sokka stands back up and stumbles forward, stabbing his
                sword into the ground to stop his fall. Cut behind Sokka as he uses his momentum to
                swing his sword back around, flinging dirt and dust at Piandao. The scene goes into
                slow motion again and the camera cuts to a close-up of Piandao as the dirt hits him
                in the face, blinding him. The scene comes back to normal speed and cuts to a
                frontal shot of Piandao as he spins around and positions his sword behind his back
                to defend any sneak attacks. Cut to a close-up of Piandao, his eyes
                closed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Very resourceful.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Piandao turns his head and listens for any sounds. Cut close-up to Sokka
                and zooms out as he nervously raises his sword defensively. He slowly tries to sneak
                away, careful not to make any noises that would give away his location. Cut to a
                twig on the ground as Sokka steps on it, snapping it. Close-up of Piandao who turns
                his head toward Sokka when he hears it. Camera zooms out as he twirls his sword
                around into an offensive position and charges forward. Close-up of Sokka who takes a
                step back as Piandao closes in. Side-view of the fight as Piandao strikes. Sokka
                parries the attack. Cut behind Sokka as Piandao catches Sokka's blade with his own.
                He pushes Sokka's sword around in two circles and flings Sokka's sword out of his
                hands. Side-view of the fight as Sokka watches his sword fly into the air and stab
                into the ground several feet away.</description>
      <section>
         <description>Cut to side-view of Sokka looking worried as Piandao moves to attack.
                    The scene goes into slow motion and cuts to a side-view of the two as Piandao
                    swings his sword in large, horizontal arc at Sokka. Sokka is not cut by the
                    blade, but is instead hit in the chest by Piandao's arms, knocking him on his
                    back. Cut to Sokka landing on the ground and he looks up fearfully. Cut to
                    frontal view of Piandao from the ground as Piandao turns and points his sword at
                    Sokka's head. Cut to Sokka who leans back in fear. Frontal view of Aang, Katara,
                    and Toph as they all jump from the building to the ground and run toward Sokka
                    and Piandao. Cut to a close-up of Piandao. The camera zooms out as he swings his
                    sword away from Sokka, halting Aang, Katara, and Toph.</description>
      </section>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Excellent work, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Sokka squinting at Piandao curiously. Cut to a shot of
                Piandao with Aang, Katara, and Toph in the background. He raises his hand and the
                camera tilts up slightly as he signals to Fat. Cut to a frontal view of Fat as he
                flings the scabbard of Piandao's sword toward him. Frontal view of the still blinded
                Piandao as he turns and points his sword upward. Side-view as the scabbard flies
                right onto the blade.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">I think I'm a little old to be fighting the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Aang, Katara, and Toph in their bending stances. They come
                out of their stances and Aang and Katara look at each other in
                surprise.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">How did you know‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to a shot of Piandao and Sokka. Sokka stands back up as Fat
                walks on screen carrying a drink and a white cloth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">Oh, I've been around a while. You pick things up. <charAction>Wipes the dirt off his
                face with the cloth.</charAction> Of course, I knew from the beginning that Sokka
            was Water Tribe. <charAction>Close-up of Sokka.</charAction> You might want to think of
            a better Fire Nation cover name. <charAction>Camera zooms out to show
                Piandao.</charAction> Try "Lee." There's a million "Lees". <charAction>Sips his
                drink.</charAction>.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a frontal shot of Aang, Katara and Toph with Fat and Piandao facing
                toward them, their backs to the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But why would you agree to train someone from the Water Tribe‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Piandao">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> The way of the sword doesn't belong to any one
            nation. <charAction>Frontal shot of Piandao, Sokka and Fat as the other three look on,
                their backs to the camera.</charAction> Knowledge of the arts belongs to us all.
                <charAction>Gives his sword to Fat. Cut to Sokka's sword as he pulls it out of the
                ground. Cut to side-view of Piandao and Sokka as Piandao gives the sword back to
                Sokka.</charAction> Sokka, you must continue your training on your own.
                <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> If you stay on this path, I know that one day
                <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> you will become an even greater master than I
            am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Aang, Katara, and Sokka all smiling warmly. Cut back to
                Sokka and Piandao as they bow to each other. The scene cuts to a wide shot of the
                group leaving Piandao's castle through the front gates. It cuts to a closer shot of
                the group from the front. Fat is running up to them from behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fat">Wait! <charAction>Everyone turns to him. Side-view.</charAction> The Master wanted
            you to have this, as something to remember him by.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a close-up of Fat giving a small, brown bag to Sokka. Overhead view
                as they all bow as a farewell and Fat walks back to the castle. The camera zooms in
                as Sokka opens the bag and pulls out a white lotus Pai Sho tile.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's a Pai Sho tile.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a close-up of the tile in Sokka's hands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The White Lotus. Huh.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What does it mean‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to close-up of Aang and Sokka as Fat is seen in the background
                closing the doors. Sokka and Aang look back and the camera zooms in on the doors,
                clearly showing a lotus design on the doors surrounding the Fire Nation
                symbol.</charAction> I have no idea. <charAction>Overhead view. Sokka reaches into
                his pocket.</charAction> Ooh, that reminds me! Toph, I thought you might like this
                <charAction>Close-up view of Sokka offering her a chunk of the
                meteorite.</charAction> since you've probably never had a chance to bend space earth
            before.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Taking the rock. Side-view.</charAction> Sweet! <charAction>Cut to a
                close-up of the space earth floating between Toph's hands. She shapes it into a
                swirl, a star, and a splatter shaped similar to the Nickelodeon logo.</charAction>
            Check this out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a shot of the group as they walk off down the trail.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You know, I don't think there's such a thing as "space earth". If it's from space,
            then it's not really "earth".</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Must you ruin everything‌?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wide, overhead shot of Piandao's castle and Team Avatar walking
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I can't believe I missed you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to white. Fade to end credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
