<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Runaway</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens in Fire Fountain City, where a giant statue of Fire Lord
                Ozai roaring is shown with flames coming from the fists and out of the mouth. The
                camera moves down to Toph, who is seen running from someone, but turns around and is
                caught with a net and falls to the ground. She angrily looks in front of her at
                someone.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> How could you do this to me? You betrayed
            me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to a shot of Katara, who is glaring back at
                Toph.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Crosses her arms.</charAction> You brought this on yourself. I had no
            choice. <charAction>Turns away from Toph with her arms folded.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph is dragged away in the net, all the while glaring back at Katara. The
                screen fades to three days earlier. Toph and Katara are seen facing each other, each
                taking a fighting stance, the latter controlling two streams of water in her hands.
                Aang appears on the screen, tying his headband over his eyes like a
                blindfold.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay. I'm ready for some training.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He turns to face the girls and takes two steps forward in a stance similar
                to Toph's. Upon impact with the second step, he picks up vibrations from the ground
                with seismic sense. He quickly dodges three earth pillars that appear out of the
                ground near him. He hears a water attack coming from Katara and redirects it at her.
                He quickly launches a boulder at Toph who catches it and stops it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Good job, Twinkle Toes. Visualize, then attack.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She launches the boulder back at Aang, who burrows into a hole with
                earthbending. The boulder instead hits Katara square in the chest, knocking her
                down. She stands back up and brushes dust off of her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Maybe you should take your own advice, Toph!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">What's the matter? Can't handle a little dirt, Madame Fussy-Britches?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara's eyebrow twitches and she glares at Toph with her vein shown on her
                head before she angrily creates a wave and sends it at Toph, who gets splashed by it
                and becomes annoyed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, sorry. Did I splash you, Mud-Slug?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara creates an ice ramp, and Toph creates an earth ramp, both proceeding
                to head straight for each other. They crash and both of the girls go
                flying.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Are we taking a break?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, Sokka is seen hiding behind Aang with an evil smile. He quickly
                gets up and charges at Aang. The background changes to a rushing one.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Screaming.</charAction> Sneak Attack!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, casually and still looking away from Sokka, creates an earth wall,
                which stops Sokka dead in his tracks. He lowers the wall, which causes Sokka to fall
                down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>While raising his blindfold and turning to face Sokka.</charAction>
            Sokka, sneak attacks don't work if you yell it out loud.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Toph are seen wrestling in a puddle of mud.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Hungry for a mud pie? <charAction>Kicks mud in Katara's face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Wiping mud off of her face.</charAction> I'll give you a mud
            pie!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara waterbends a stream of mud at Toph, knocking her down. She quickly
                gets up and earthbends a pillar underneath Katara, which sends her flying toward a
                wall. She starts running toward Katara, but stops at the last second when they hear
                Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh guys, I thought we were supposed to be training me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Takes a few steps forward, covered in mud; calmly.</charAction> Very
            well, pupil. I believe we've had enough training for today. <charAction>Turns and walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">While Katara cleans up, <charAction>Earthbends the mud off of herself and runs
                toward Aang and Sokka.</charAction> let's go have some fun!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Simultaneously with Aang.</charAction> Yes!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, Sokka and Toph head to Fire Fountain City. Sokka is carrying his
                sword horizontally across his shoulders. He looks up and sees messenger hawks flying
                in and out of a large coop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Look at all those messenger hawks! You know, I've been thinking about getting one
            for myself. That way, I wouldn't have to talk to anyone. I could just send them
            messages.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I gotta say, I like the idea of not talking to you. <charAction>Sokka glares at
                her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>While holding up a silver piece.</charAction> So, guys. What are we
            gonna get with our last silver piece?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Stops walking.</charAction> We can get more money. <charAction>They both
                look back at her.</charAction> Right there. <charAction>Points to an area beneath
                them. Aang and Sokka move back to look where she is pointing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In the area is a table with two men sitting across from each other, with
                people around them watching the action. The table has three shells on it, all upside
                down. The first man places some money on the table and the second man, a scam
                artist, lifts the shells to reveal that the middle one has a rock underneath it. He
                places the shells back down as they were and starts moving them
                around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">This is where you seeing people are at a disadvantage. Everyone guesses wrong
            because the dealer moves the rock at the last minute. But I can feel it with my
            earthbending. <charAction>As she says this, the scam artist continues to move the shells
                around as the gambler tries to focus on the shell with the rock, and right before
                stopping, the scam artist quickly and inconspicuously earthbends the rock from
                underneath one of the shells into his sleeve.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scam artist stops moving the shells and arranges them how they
                originally were: Horizontally right in front of him. The gambler points at the shell
                in the middle, which the scam artist lifts to reveal nothing underneath. The gambler
                stands up and walks away crying. A few more people move and the dealer notices Toph,
                and that she is blind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">
         <charAction>To Toph.</charAction> You there. Wanna play a friendly game?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">How can I possibly play? <charAction>Waves her hand in front of her
                face.</charAction> I'm blind.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">You don't have to see to be lucky.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph sits in front of the table and feels around it, pretending to be
                helpless. She places their last silver piece on the table. The scam artist shows the
                rock under the shell in the middle and starts moving them around. This time, he
                tosses one rock from his sleeves into each of the two empty shells. Toph senses this
                and smiles slyly. When he stops, Toph points to the one on her left, which has a
                rock underneath, winning about two silver pieces.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Flamey-O, Toph.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">Wow. Fancy guessing. You are amazing at this. <charAction>Plays with a few silver
                pieces in his hands.</charAction> Would you like to make the game a little more
            interesting?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Curiously.</charAction> More interesting? How?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">
         <charAction>Points at Sokka's sword.</charAction> Well, let's say you toss in your
            friend's fine sword there, <charAction>Grabs a big bag of money.</charAction> then I'll
            put up twenty silver pieces against it, and that's more interesting.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Grabs Sokka's sword.</charAction> I'll do it for forty silver pieces.
                <charAction>Sokka stares at them with his mouth wide open.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">Forty silver pieces it is. <charAction>Drops some more money into the bag and starts
                moving the shells, faster this time.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scam artist moves the first two rocks into his sleeves, which Toph
                senses as she smiles slyly again. He attempts to do the same with the third rock,
                but Toph inconspicuously clutches her fist, causing the rock to move back underneath
                the shell, which the scam artist does not notice. When he stops, she smiles and
                points at the shell in the middle.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Dealer">
         <charAction>Moves his hand over to the shell, about to lift it.</charAction> Sorry,
            little lady, but- <charAction>Lifts up the shell and sees the rock, which shocks and
                confuses him.</charAction> Huh? <charAction>Stares closely at the
            rock.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I won! <charAction>She grabs the bag of money, and Sokka grabs his sword as they run
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Toph, Aang, and Sokka heading back to camp, laughing and carrying
                baskets full of goods. Katara is seen cooking something in a pot as they all drop
                their baskets onto the ground and Katara looks at the baskets with
                curiosity.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Where did you guys get the money to buy all this stuff?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Toph got us money. <charAction>Grabs an apple and takes a bite out of it as he sits
                down.</charAction> She scammed one of those guys in town who moves the shells around
            all sneaky-like. <charAction>He mimics the scam artist moving the shells with his hand.
                Katara's expression shows disapproval.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sits down too.</charAction> She used earthbending to win the game!
            Classic!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ah, so she cheated.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Starts to bite her apple, but stops to defend herself.</charAction> Hey!
            I only cheated because he was cheating! <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> I cheated a
            cheater. <charAction>Closes her eyes in confidence.</charAction> What's wrong with
            that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm just saying this isn't something we should make a habit of doing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Why? Because it's fun? And you hate fun?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't hate fun! <charAction>Places Momo on her head like a hat while grinning
                unconvincingly.</charAction> See? Fun! <charAction>Momo slips off her head,
                screeches at her, and runs away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Katara, <charAction>Slightly lifts his headband
                to reveal his airbender tattoo and bows.</charAction> I'll personally make you an
            Avatar Promise that we won't make a habit of doing these scams.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera switches to the city, where Aang goes from bowing to doing
                tricks with the money in his hands and runs off. A few citizens are seen playing a
                dice like game. The two winners see Toph holding a bag of money and call her over.
                She tosses the two die. One lands on three, which is the highest number, and the
                other is about to go from three to zero. Cut to Toph, who twitches her head to the
                left slightly without any of the others seeing, causing the die to move back to the
                three, meaning she wins much to the winners' dismay and Sokka's and Aang's
                joy.</description>
      <description>Cut to an area where a carnival is being hosted, where a big man tries a
                test-your-strength game, in which you need to use a hammer to launch a ball up to
                ring the bell, but can only make it about halfway. Toph jiggles a bag of money and
                walks over. Aang and Sokka watch from behind as she hands the man in charge of the
                game the money and places her hands on the hammer. She struggles to move it over her
                head and behind her, which makes all in the crowd snicker and laugh. Toph smiles
                again as she uses earthbending to launch the hammer's head from behind her to the
                lever with great force. The ball is launched so hard that it launches out of the
                game, destroying the top of it, which leaves everyone shocked. She casually grabs
                her winnings and leaves as the ball crashes into a tent behind, causing everyone to
                cringe at the sound, and looks back to see the damage.</description>
      <description>The camera next cuts to a street where a carriage is being pulled by a
                dragon moose. Cut to a side-shot of the inside of the carriage where a noble opens
                his cup of tea to his delight and waves the aroma to his face. Toph emerges from a
                dark alley and creates a small rock right in front of one of the wheels to stop the
                cart. She falls back, pretending to have been hit. The noble peeks outside the
                carriage window and sees Toph. He jumps out of the carriage and starts to run, but
                is stopped by what looks like a Fire Nation guard, who is really Sokka in his Wang
                Fire costume. He notices Toph being "run over" and crosses his arms angrily at the
                noble, who gets on his knees and begs Sokka. He places twelve small bags of money as
                bribery, one after another in Sokka's arms, and Sokka smiles and winks at him to
                assure him that Sokka will keep this secret. The camera cuts to back at
                camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Guys, I think these scams have gone far enough. If you keep doing them, something
            bad is gonna happen.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Could you for once stop being such a sourpuss and just lighten up?
                <charAction>Tosses some money to Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Oh, I'm sorry! You think I should be more like
            you? Like some wild child? <charAction>Tosses the money back at
            Toph.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah! Maybe! Maybe then you'd see <charAction>Sokka grabs the money off the
                ground.</charAction> how great we have it! I mean, look at us! <charAction>Leans
                back on the rock behind her and crosses her arms behind her head.</charAction> We're
            traveling around the world! Making easy money! Having fun! With no parents to tell us
            what to do!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ah. I see. You're acting like this because of your parents.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Whatever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">They were controlling over you, so you ran away, and now you act like your parents
            don't exist. You act like you hate them, but you don't. You just feel guilty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I do hate them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't think so. I think you miss them, but you just don't wanna deal with that, so
            instead you act like this crazy person.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Stands up; angrily.</charAction> Look, I ran away to help Aang!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">You know what? It doesn't matter. These scams put us all at risk, and we don't need
            that. <charAction>Points at her forehead.</charAction> We've already got some third-eyed
            freak after us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Speaking of that "third-eyed freak", I think I've come up with a name for him. What
            do you think of "Sparky-Sparky-Boom Man"? <charAction>Silence.</charAction> Just think
            about it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> We have enough money! You need to stop
            this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> I'll stop when I wanna stop and not when you tell
            me! <charAction>Uses earthbending to launch the bag of money behind her into her hand
                and walks away angrily. Katara shakes her head angrily as Toph sits and creates an
                earth tent.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Grabs his bag of money and his sword and stands up.</charAction>
            Speaking of money, I'm off to spend some. See you guys later. <charAction>Walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In town, Sokka just bought a messenger hawk, which he names
                Hawky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hawky, welcome to Team Avatar. My name's Sokka, and I'm your new owner, and as such
            I should warn you that there's already a lemur in our group, so I don't wanna see any
            fighting. <charAction>Scratches Hawky on the stomach.</charAction> Good little messenger
            hawky. Who's got pretty feathers? <charAction>While walking away, he notices a wanted
                poster he had just past with Toph's picture on it. He gasps in horror and rips it
                off the wall. Hawky screeches.</charAction> You're right, Hawky. This is bad.
                <charAction>Suddenly, the bird poops while standing on Sokka's
            arm.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to back at camp. Katara and Aang are practicing
                waterbending, while Toph is counting her money. Sokka walks up to her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Toph, while I was in town, I found something that you're not gonna like.
                <charAction>Pulls out the wanted poster and shows it to her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Well it sounds like a sheet of paper, but I guess you're referring to what's on the
            sheet of paper.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's a wanted poster. Of you. They've nicknamed you the Runaway.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> A wanted poster! That's so great! "The Runaway." I
            love my new nickname. Is there a picture of me? Does it look good?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Looks a few times at both the wanted poster and Toph.</charAction> Well
            yeah, actually, it does look pretty good. <charAction>Gets back on topic.</charAction>
            But, Toph, you're missing the point. Maybe Katara was right. These scams are drawing too
            much attention to us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Don't be such a worrywart like your sister. <charAction>Stands up and walks up to
                Sokka.</charAction> Think of it this way: Now you've got plenty of money to help
            with the invasion plan. <charAction>Holds up a bag of money and jiggles it in front of
                him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Ponders for a moment.</charAction> Well, that is true. I had this idea
            of making armor for Appa. <charAction>Looks at Appa, who is napping, but opens one eye
                upon hearing this.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Takes some money out of the bag and hands the money to him.</charAction>
            Here's a little extra, so you can get yourself a nice map of the Fire Nation. You know
            what? <charAction>Gives the entire bag to him.</charAction> Make it an atlas.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>While taking the bag.</charAction> I do like expensive atlases.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Of course you do. <charAction>Grabs the wanted poster and tucks it into her
                outfit.</charAction> And that's why this wanted poster is going to stay our little
            secret. <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Katara walk up to Sokka, who tucks his new money into his
                outfit</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sokka, <charAction>Places her hand on her face; annoyed.</charAction> tell me you
            didn't buy a bird.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Not just a bird, a messenger bird. Now we can send messages all over the world. Even
            to Gran Gran.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Wow, how does it work?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hm. Uh, I never actually thought about that. Hawky, <charAction>Points away from
                himself.</charAction> Gran Gran, South Pole. <charAction>Hawky shakes
                himself.</charAction> I think he gets it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo appears on Aang's shoulder and screeches at Hawky. He jumps to Sokka
                and starts chasing Hawky around Sokka's head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hawky! Make nice! Bad Hawky!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Later on at camp, Katara is mixing something in a cooking pot via
                waterbending. She waterbends some of it out of the pot and into Appa's mouth, which
                causes him to lick his lips, while Aang sits on a ledge in front of Appa and drinks
                something out of a cup. Toph and Sokka, the latter with Hawky on his shoulder, show
                up carrying big bags of money.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Well. Look who decided to join us.
                <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Where have you two been? Off scamming
            again?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yes, we were. <charAction>Puts her bag down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slides to the right to behind Toph.</charAction> And I suppose you don't
            think what you're doing is dangerous at all?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">No, I don't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yes. Really.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Starts to pull something out.</charAction> Well then. What's this?
                <charAction>Shows Toph her wanted poster.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> I don't know! I mean, seriously! What is with you
            people? I'm blind! <charAction>Points at her eyes and pulls down her bottom eyelids to
                emphasize her words.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's a wanted poster of you! "The Runaway!" Is that what you're called now? Are you
            proud of this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Where did you get that!?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It doesn't matter where I got it. The fact is-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">You went through my stuff! You had no right!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Your stuff was messy and I was just straightening up, and I happened to stumble
            across it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">That's a lie! <charAction>Points at her.</charAction> You're lying, Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to a surprised Katara who glares at Toph. Pushes Toph's pointing
                hand out of her face.</charAction> Fine! It's a lie! But you've been so out of
            control lately, I knew something was up! I knew you were hiding something and you were!
                <charAction>Shows her the poster again, but Toph grabs it, tosses it and starts to
                walk past Katara.</charAction> Don't you walk away from me while I'm talking to
            you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Oh really, Mom? Or what are you gonna do?
            Send me to my room?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I wish I could!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Well you can't! Because you're not my mom, and you're not their mom!
                <charAction>Extends her arm at Aang and Sokka, who are sitting on a
                ledge.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I never said I was!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">No, but you certainly act like it! You think it's your job to boss everyone around,
            but it's not! You're just a regular kid like the rest of us! So stop acting like you can
            tell me what to do! I can do whatever I want!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't act that way! <charAction>Looks at Sokka, who jumps as she says his
                name.</charAction> Sokka, do I act motherly?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Puts his hands up defensively.</charAction> Hey. I'm staying out of this
            one.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks at Aang.</charAction> What do you think, Aang? Do I act like a
            mom?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs his eye.</charAction> Well. I, uh-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Slightly annoyed.</charAction> Stop rubbing your eye and speak clearly
            when you talk!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He and Sokka sit straight.</charAction> Yes, ma'am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I can't be around you right now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Well, I can't be around you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Both girls turn and walk away. Hawky, sitting on Sokka's shoulder,
                screeches.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Rests his head in his hands.</charAction> I know, Hawky. Why can't they
            just get along?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Later on at camp, Sokka and Aang are sitting together. Toph and Katara are
                sitting at separate edges of the cliff, their backs to one another.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, Aang. You wanna test out my messenger hawk with me? I've got an idea.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sure. <charAction>Leans his head closer to Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Talks into Aang's ear.</charAction> I'm going to send a note to Katara
            and say it's from Toph, who wants to apologize. Then everyone will be friends
            again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I gotta say, Sokka, you continue to impress me with your ideas.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's a gift. <charAction>Pulls out a pen and ink and a piece of paper and starts to
                write.</charAction> "Dear Katara, sorry for everything. Your friend, Toph."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka positions Hawky on his arm and places the note in Hawky's message
                holder. Hawky flies to Katara, who takes the note out, reads it, and angrily stands
                up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know this is from you, Sokka! Toph can't write! <charAction>Tears the note up into
                pieces.</charAction> Ugh! You're all driving me crazy! <charAction>Turns and walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't believe we forgot Toph can't write.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yup. We're idiots. <charAction>Hawky flies back onto his arm.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess Plan B is we send a note to Toph pretending it's from Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I think we're gonna run into a similar problem. <charAction>Hawky
                screeches.</charAction> Sorry, Hawky. Looks like I'm gonna have to do this without
            your help. <charAction>Walks to Toph.</charAction> Come on. We need to talk.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph exhales, annoyed. The camera cuts to another area of the camp. Katara
                is bathing in a lake directly below a cliff. Sokka and Toph walk up to the edge of
                the cliff and sit down, not noticing Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">So lemme guess: You brought me out here to tell me that your sister's not as
            annoying as I make her out to be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nah, she's pretty much a pain. <charAction>Katara, looking up at their feet from
                below and behind, glares and looks away.</charAction> She's always got to be right
            about everything and she gets all bossy and involved and in your business ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah. I don't know how you could deal with it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Actually, in a way, I rely on it. <charAction>Katara looks back up at
                them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I don't understand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">When our mom died, that was the hardest time in my life. Our family was a mess, but
            Katara? She had so much strength. She stepped up and took on so much responsibility. She
            helped fill the void that was left by our mom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I guess I never thought about that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I'm gonna tell you something crazy. I never told anyone this before, but honestly?
            I'm not sure I can remember what my mother looked like. It really seems like my whole
            life, Katara's been the one looking out for me. She's always been the one that's there.
            And now, when I try to remember my mom, Katara's is the only face I can picture.
                <charAction>Katara, touched by what Sokka says, is reduced to
            tears.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">The truth is sometimes Katara does act motherly, but that's not always a bad thing.
            She's compassionate and kind, and she actually cares about me. <charAction>Wipes away
                tears from her left eye.</charAction> You know, the real me. That's more than my own
            mom. <charAction>Katara, deeply touched by Toph's words, sinks slightly into the water.
                Toph punches Sokka in the arm.</charAction> Don't ever tell her I said any of
            this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, my lips are sealed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At around nightfall, Katara is sitting next to Momo, who is napping with
                Katara rubbing the top of his head. Katara is looking down in front of her,
                saddened. She sees Sokka and Toph walking toward her and walks up to Toph. When they
                reach each other, Sokka keeps walking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hi, Toph. Um, I wanna-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Holds up her hand in a "stop" fashion.</charAction> Katara, stop. You
            don't need to apologize. I was the one being stupid. These scams are out of control, and
            I'm done with them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> Actually I wasn't going to apologize. I was gonna
            say ... I wanna pull a scam with you. <charAction>Aang and Sokka stare at her from
                behind, extremely shocked.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Also shocked.</charAction> What? You wanna pull a scam?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Not just any scam. The ultimate scam. <charAction>Sokka and Aang, still staring at
                her with shock, look at each other and faint, foaming from the mouth slightly.
                Katara puts her arm around Toph's shoulder, who gives a sly smile.</charAction>
            Whaddaya say, Toph? Just me and you. One last go. You in?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> You know I'm in! Now what's this idea of yours?
                <charAction>They walk away and leave Aang and Sokka behind, who are now unconscious
                and foaming at the mouth.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to Katara and Toph going over the plan. Katara is looking
                at Toph's wanted poster.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The plan is simple: This wanted poster says you're worth a lot of money; Ten times
            more than you've made in all of your scams. So I'm gonna turn you in and collect the
            reward. Then you metalbend yourself out of jail, and we're on our way. <charAction>As
                she speaks, the screen fades to the beginning of the episode, where Toph is seen
                running from the authorities and is caught in a net.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> How could you do this to me? You betrayed
            me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Crosses her arms.</charAction> You brought this on yourself. I had no
            choice. <charAction>Turns away from Toph.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph is dragged away in the net, all the while glaring back at Katara.
                Katara glances back slightly and gives a sly smile. She is joined by the chief of
                authorities.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Town authority">You did the right thing by turning in the Runaway.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">The right thing is its own reward.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Town authority">Well, I'm happy to hear you say that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pauses for a moment.</charAction> But, I still want the actual
            reward.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Town authority">Of course. Right this way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, a female guard drags Toph into a jail. She throws Toph from the
                net into a wooden cell and closes it. Toph feels the floor of her cell, but is
                shocked when she can't sense any earth in it. She gets up and looks outside the cell
                at the guard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Hey! What kind of cell is this?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Female guard">A wooden one. <charAction>She walks away as Toph becomes visibly
                worried.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In an office, the town authority grabs a box underneath a desk and looks
                around in it. A door opens behind Katara, who is standing across the desk from the
                chief. The chief closes the box and points at Katara.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Town authority">That's her! That's the girl you were looking for!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara turns and sees the assassin with the third eye tattooed on his head,
                aka "Sparky-Sparky-Boom Man", walk in, leaving her shocked and horrified. Meanwhile,
                at camp, Sokka and Aang are worried, the latter pacing back and forth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Do you think this scam of theirs should be taking this long?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I was just wondering the same thing. We'd better check it out. <charAction>To Hawky
                and Momo.</charAction> You two behave. <charAction>Pointing at Appa.</charAction>
            Appa's in charge. <charAction>Appa lifts his head as the two animals start screeching at
                each other as soon as Sokka and Aang leave, but stop as soon as Appa roars at
                them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts to Toph's cell, which now holds Katara too. They both are
                sitting on the floor, downcast, when Toph suddenly realizes something.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Wait! It's a trap!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Really? No kidding! Is that why we're
            sitting in a wooden cage right now? Gee, how'd you figure out it was a trap?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Not for us, Katara! We're the bait! He wants Aang! <charAction>Katara's eyes widen
                with realization.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I can't believe I'm so stupid! See? This is exactly why I'm against these scams! I
            knew this would happen!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">But, this was your idea.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know. I wanted to show that I'm not so motherly. I wanted to show you that I can
            have fun too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Katara, you are fun. If nothing else, you're at least fun to argue with.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I know your relationship with your parents is complicated. And I shouldn't have said
            what I said.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">It's okay. I was really mad when you said that because ... well because, maybe it's
            true. <charAction>Starts to cry.</charAction> I try not to think about it, but when I
            left, I probably really hurt them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara embraces Toph. Meanwhile, Sokka and Aang walk around town looking
                for Katara and Toph. The town is seemingly abandoned.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Where do you think they might be?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Where do you think anyone is? <charAction>The assassin is seen walking across a
                rooftop behind them. Aang hears him inhaling and becomes shocked when he turns and
                sees him.</charAction> Sokka, watch out! <charAction>He grabs Sokka as they dodge a
                blast from the assassin and take cover behind an Ozai statue.</charAction> It's
            Sparky-Sparky-Boom Man!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You know, I'm starting to think that name doesn't quite fit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The assassin jumps down from the roof and fires another blast at them. They
                barely dodge it, but get sent flying back by the blast, which shakes the ceiling of
                Toph and Katara's cell. Toph is trying to break out, while Katara is sitting
                down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What are we gonna do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I don't know. I wish we had some earth or water. We need bendables.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What about your meteor bracelet? You can make a saw.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I left it back at camp. <charAction>Sits down.</charAction> I was worried they would
            take it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara exhales deeply and wipes her forehead with the back of her hand. Her
                eyes widen with realization as she notices her hand is covered in sweat. She smiles
                and quickly stands up to start running in place.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Um, Katara? Are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Just fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Still confused.</charAction> Well, what are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm making my own water.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara stops running and wipes her forehead again. This time, she uses
                waterbending to use the midair sweat as blades to cut through the wooden cage. Toph
                stands up upon noticing this.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Amazed.</charAction> Katara! You're a genius! A sweaty, stinky
            genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara waterbends another blade of sweat, this time from under her arms.
                Cut to Aang and Sokka being chased by the assassin. The assassin fires a blast at
                them which they dodge but still get sent flying. Sokka crashes onto a wheelbarrow,
                which they hide behind.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This guy is too good! He shoots fire from his brain!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We should split up. He can't chase us both.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The assassin walks out of the smoke. Aang runs off from his left and Sokka
                from his right. The assassin fires a blast at the wheelbarrow and blows it up. Aang
                runs past him on a roof to his left. The assassin quickly turns and fires another
                blast, which sends Aang flying into the Ozai statue. He falls from the statue to the
                ground. He looks up and sees the assassin standing above him inhale, about to fire
                another blast at Aang, but his head is suddenly encased in ice. The assassin moves
                and Aang sees Katara, Sokka, and Toph standing behind the assassin.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, get up! <charAction>She helps him up and they run away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Let's get out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The assassin breaks the ice with brute force. He launches another blast at
                Team Avatar, but Toph quickly launches a boulder at the blast, blowing the boulder
                up. A pebble from the boulder flies toward the assassin and hits him square in his
                third eye, which momentarily stuns and angers him. He tries to fire another blast,
                but with his chi is blocked, he ignites the air around him and gets sent back,
                head-first into a wall. When he stands up and shakes it off, Team Avatar is
                gone.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Still running.</charAction> Hey, I got it! The perfect name for that
            guy: "Combustion Man!"</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Good job, Sokka. Now let's get outta here before Combustion Man catches us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">See? It fits so well!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Later that night, the gang flies to another camp spot on
                Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Yawns.</charAction> Well, I'm exhausted. Hawky, how about you, buddy?
                <charAction>Hawky makes a bird call.</charAction> Yeah. You're such a lazy little
            bird.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Sokka get off Appa. Katara is about to dismount Appa, but is
                stopped by Toph.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Katara? I need your help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sits back down.</charAction> What is it, Toph?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Pulls out a sheet of paper.</charAction> I need you to write some things
            down for me. I wanna send a letter to my parents.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> I'll be happy to help.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They place a letter inside Hawky's holder and send him off as he flies
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, where'd Hawky go?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
