<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Guru</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode starts with a view of the exterior of Zuko and Iroh's
                apartment. Cut to the interior. Iroh is preparing food when Zuko
                awakens.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What's that smell?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">It's jook. I'm sure you wouldn't like it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sniffs.</charAction> Actually, it smells delicious. I'd love a bowl,
            Uncle. <charAction>Holds a bowl up.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Now that your fever is gone, you seem different somehow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Optimistically.</charAction> It's a new day. We've got a new apartment,
            new furniture, and today's the grand opening of your new tea shop. <charAction>Moves to
                a table and sits.</charAction> Things are looking up, Uncle. <charAction>Starts
                drinking the jook. Iroh's shocked expression changes to a
            smile.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Sokka fly on Appa to a Water Tribe camp, where Hakoda
                is.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You haven't seen your dad in over two years. You must be so excited!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Almost throwing up.</charAction> I know I should be, but, I just feel
            sick to my stomach. <charAction>Holds his stomach.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't be nervous. He's going to be so happy to see you! <charAction>He puts his hand
                on Sokka's shoulder who smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So what about you? Are you nervous to meet this guru?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not at all. I'm ready to master the Avatar State. I'll do whatever it takes.
                <charAction>Sokka gets off Appa.</charAction> See you in a week. Yip yip!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Appa fly away. Sokka arrives at the camp, where all the warriors
                greet him warmly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Water Tribe warrior">Sokka, good to see you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He looks and sees the main tent. Inside, Hakoda, Sokka's father, is looking
                at a map with more warriors, including Bato, now with scars on his arm. Bato nudges
                Hakoda and Hakoda becomes happy upon seeing Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hi, Dad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two embrace. Back at the Earth King's Royal Palace, the "Kyoshi
                Warriors", Azula, Mai, and Ty Lee in disguise, sit before King Kuei.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">Look Bosco! The Kyoshi Warriors are here to protect us! Aren't you excited?
                <charAction>Bosco yawns.</charAction> It's been a difficult week for me. My most
            trusted advisor, Long Feng, and his Dai Li agents tried to take control of Ba Sing Se
            from me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">It's terrible when you can't trust the people who are closest to you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kuei">
         <charAction>Pets Bosco.</charAction> But there is good news. As we speak, the
            Council of Five is meeting to plan an invasion of the Fire Nation this summer, on the
            day of a solar eclipse.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>For a second, Azula's eyes slightly widen with shock and worry upon hearing
                this, but she quickly hides it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Really? Now that sounds like a fascinating and brilliant plan. <charAction>Glances
                off as Mai and Ty Lee look at each other.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Council of Five meeting, where Katara and Momo are
                present.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="General How">General Fong's base will serve as the launching point for the attack. In exactly two
            months, the army and navy will invade the Fire Nation on the Day of Black Sun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo jumps on the map and begins knocking over the pieces.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Or we could send in Momo to do some damage! <charAction>Chuckles. The Council of
                Five are unamused.</charAction> 'Cause, the ... sorry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="General How">
         <charAction>Uses earthbending to stand the pieces back up, scaring
                Momo.</charAction> All we need is the Earth King's seal in order to execute the
            plan. <charAction>Sends the scroll across the table to Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'll get these scrolls to him right away. Thank you, General How.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang continues his journey to the Eastern Air Temple. He spots Guru Pathik,
                who is meditating, and lands Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uhhh ... hello? You're Guru Pathik, right? <charAction>Aang approaches
                Pathik.</charAction> The person who attached the note to Appa's horn?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Indeed. I was a spiritual brother of your people and a personal friend of Monk
            Gyatso. <charAction>Aang looks slightly surprised to hear this.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">In your note, <charAction>Aang sits.</charAction> you said you could teach me how to
            gain control of the Avatar State. How?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">You must gain balance within yourself, before you can bring balance to the world.
            And the first step to gaining balance begins with this. <charAction>Hands Aang a yellow
                beverage in a wooden cup.</charAction> Drink up!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Takes it and looks at it. Drinks it and quickly spits it out to his left
                in disgust.</charAction> Uggh! It tastes like onion and banana juice!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">That's because it is! <charAction>Pathik empties another bowl and holds it over his
                head.</charAction> Yum yum!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang blinks in disbelief. Meanwhile, Xin Fu and Master Yu are working to
                bring Toph back to the Beifong Estate.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">I believe we need to go right!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">What are you talking about? The Beifong Estate's this way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">I'm quite certain you're mistaken.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Banging at the cell.</charAction> Hey! Can you two old ladies quit your
            bickering for a second? <charAction>Cut to inside the cell.</charAction> I got to go to
            the bathroom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">Oooh ... uhhh, okay, but make it quick! <charAction>Getting up with a key in
                hand.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">
         <charAction>Stopping Yu.</charAction> What's wrong with you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">Ooh, very sneaky Toph! Nice try, but you can't trick me! <charAction>Sits
                down.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Let me out of here so I can kick both your butts!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">Quit your banging! <charAction>Bangs the metal box.</charAction> You might think
            you're the greatest earthbender in the world, but even you can't bend metal!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph looks sad as she places her hand on a side of the metal box. The scene
                cuts to that night, and where Azula, Mai and Ty Lee are staying which is a small
                building in the Upper Ring. Mai and Ty Lee are removing their make-up. A smiling Ty
                Lee is looking in a mirror. She is wiping the last traces of her Kyoshi makeup from
                her face. Mai is seated next to Ty Lee, still working on her own face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">We have been presented with an extraordinary opportunity, girls.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Mai finally gets to wear make-up that's not totally depressing? <charAction>Azula
                walks past toward a window.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>With large, dark splotches of black makeup dripping down her eyes;
                Sarcastically.</charAction> Ha, ha.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">I'm talking about conquering the whole Earth Kingdom. <charAction>The two girls turn
                with shocked looks.</charAction> For one hundred years, the Fire Nation has hammered
            away at Ba Sing Se from the outside. <charAction>Walks away from the girls and smirks
                while looking out of a window.</charAction> But now we're on the inside, and we can
            take it by ourselves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Admiringly.</charAction> Gosh, you're so confident. I really admire that
            about you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">From the inside, we're in perfect position to organize a coup and overthrow the
            Earth King. The key is the Dai Li. Whoever controls the Dai Li <charAction>Turns back
                into the room.</charAction> controls Ba Sing Se.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the Eastern Air Temple at a creek.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">In order to master the Avatar State, you must open all the chakras. Aang, tell me
            everything you know about chakras.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs eyes.</charAction> What are chakras?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">
         <charAction>Disappointedly.</charAction> Oh, I see. I guess we'll start with the
            basics. <charAction>As he explains he points to the water and the moss
                within.</charAction> The water flows through this creek, much like the energy flows
            through your body. As you see, there are several pools where the water swirls around
            before flowing on. These pools are like our chakras.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So chakras are pools of spiraling energy in our bodies?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Exactly. If nothing else were around, this creek would flow pure and clear. However,
            life is messy, and things tend to fall in the creek. And then what happens?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The creek can't flow?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Yes. But, if we open the ponds between the pools ... <charAction>He removes moss
                blocking the exit for the water.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The energy flows! <charAction>The water that was blocked by the moss becomes clear.
                Aang and Pathik smile at each other.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In another part of the temple, a cavern.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">There are seven chakras that go up the body. Each pool of energy has a purpose, and
            can be blocked by a specific kind of emotional muck. Be warned, opening the chakras is
            an intense experience, and once you begin the process, you cannot stop until all seven
            are open. Are you ready?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Momentarily looks down.</charAction> I'll do whatever it takes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">First we will open the Earth Chakra, located at the base of the spine. It deals with
            survival, and is blocked by fear. What are you most afraid of? Let your fears become
            clear to you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sees images of things that cause him great fear, including the Blue
                Spirit attacking him, General Fong sinking Katara into the ground, himself merging
                with La at the North Pole, Fire Lord Ozai, and Sozin's Comet, which make him
                scream.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Aang, your vision is not real. You are concerned for your survival, but you must
            surrender those fears. Let your fears flow down the creek. <charAction>Aang clears the
                image away.</charAction> You have opened your Earth Chakra! <charAction>Aang wipes
                sweat off his forehead.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Later, behind a waterfall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Next is the ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Water Chakra?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Brilliant! Maybe one day you will be a guru too! This chakra deals with pleasure and
            is blocked by guilt. Now, look at all the guilt with burdens you so. What do you blame
            yourself for?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sees the image of him leaving home.</charAction> I ran away.
                <charAction>Sees images of him in the Avatar State at General Fong's
                base.</charAction> I hurt all of those people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Accept the reality that these things happened, but do not let them cloud and poison
            your energy. If you are to be a positive influence on the world, you need to forgive
            yourself. <charAction>Aang takes a deep, focused breath, opening his Water
                Chakra.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene cuts to the next day at the Water Tribe camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">This bay leads directly to the outskirts of Ba Sing Se. We've been using these
            tangle mines to stop the Fire Nation ships from getting through.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Filling the mine with skunk fish and seaweed before moving
                away.</charAction> Your father invented tangle mines himself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Destructive? Buoyant? And ... <charAction>Sniffs and immediately becomes
                disgusted.</charAction> Aggh, ehhh! Terrible smelling!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Very perceptive. The mines are filled with skunk fish and seaweed. When a ship
            detonates the mine, the seaweed tangles up the propeller and the foul smell forces
            people to abandon the ship. I call it the "stink and sink."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Good one, Dad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bato">
         <charAction>Nearby, unamused.</charAction> You're definitely your father's
            son.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Warrior">
         <charAction>Approaching.</charAction> Hakoda, our scouts have spotted four Fire
            Nation ships!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Bato, get these mines loaded up! The rest of you men, prepare for battle!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The warriors run off to prepare as Sokka looks around before looking back
                to his father.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Uhhh ... what should I do, Dad?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Aren't you listening? I said, "The rest of you men, get ready for battle".</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka smiles, nods, and departs. Hakoda smiles proudly. Back in Ba Sing Se,
                at the Jasmine Dragon. Zuko and Iroh observe the happenings standing at the
                back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Who thought when we came to this city as refugees, that I'd end up owning my own tea
            shop? Follow your passion, Zuko, and life will reward you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Congratulations, Uncle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I am very thankful.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You deserve it. The Jasmine Dragon will be the best tea shop in the city.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">No. I'm thankful because you decided to share this special day with me. It means
            more than you know. <charAction>The two embrace.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Now let's make these people some tea! <charAction>Walks away to the
                back.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Overjoyed.</charAction> Yes, let's make some tea!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the Eastern Air Temple, Aang and Pathik sit on a
                ledge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Third is the Fire Chakra, located in the stomach.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Holding his stomach.</charAction> My Fire Chakra would like to eat
            something other than onion-banana juice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">
         <charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> Good one! Moving on. This chakra deals with
            willpower, and is blocked by shame. What are you ashamed of? <charAction>Cuts to Aang's
                vision of his first attempt at firebending, which resulted in him accidentally
                burning Katara's hands.</charAction> What are your biggest disappointments in
            yourself?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm never going to firebend again. I can't.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">You will never find balance if you deny this part of your life. You are the Avatar
            and therefore, you are a firebender. <charAction>Aang breathes deeply.</charAction> Hmmm
            ... that chakra opened less like a flowing creek, and more like a ... burping
            bison.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Loud belch.</charAction> Tastes like onions and bananas, but strangely
            something else. Pickles? <charAction>Pathik shrugs, and hums as if to say "I don't
                know".</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the palace, two Dai Li agents hide on two pillars and secretly spy
                on a conversation between Mai and Ty Lee. The former is sitting on the stairs and
                the latter is practicing chi blocking and acrobatics.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Sighs.</charAction> I'm tired of wearing this girly disguise. I don't
            know how anyone could fight in this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Maybe that's why it was so easy to beat the Kyoshi Warriors and take their clothes.
                <charAction>Punches the air, imitating her chi blocking.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">How much longer do we have to serve the Earth King? If I have to clean up one more
            pile of bear poop, I'm going to throw up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">
         <charAction>Walks on her hands.</charAction> Princess Azula promised we would go
            back to the Fire Nation as soon as we captured the Avatar. We just have to be
            patient.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> Shush up! Do you want the whole palace to know
            we're Fire Nation?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Ty Lee">Sorry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The agents smile and climb away. Azula, who was hiding behind another
                pillar, walks up to them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Good work, girls. I'm sure the Dai Li will deliver the message.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Air Temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">The fourth chakra is located in the heart. It deals with love and is blocked by
            grief. <charAction>Aang smiles and looks at a Air Nomad statue nearby before looking
                sad.</charAction> Lay all your grief out in front of you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sees images of many airbenders, including Gyatso and Yangchen. He
                smiles upon seeing them, but becomes saddened as they start to vanish into
                smoke.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">You have indeed felt a great loss. <charAction>The airbenders appear floating in the
                clouds.</charAction> But love is a form of energy, and it swirls all around us.
                <charAction>Aang is lifted into the air and sees the Air Nomads floating in the
                smoke.</charAction> The Air Nomads' love for you has not left this world. It is
            still inside of your heart, and is reborn in the form of new love.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The smoke in front of Aang forms a face and shows the first thing he saw
                upon waking up from his iceberg: Katara. Back in the real world, Aang is starting to
                cry tears of joy.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Let the pain flow away. <charAction>Aang wipes away his tears.</charAction> Very
            good.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Choking up.</charAction> Can I have some onion-banana juice,
            please?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Inside another part of the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">The fifth in the chain is the Sound Chakra, located in the throat. It deals with
            truth and is blocked by lies. The ones we tell ourselves.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang flashes back to when he, Katara, and Sokka first began their journey
                to the North Pole.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara (flashback)">Why didn't you tell us you were the Avatar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to the real world, Aang finds himself answering the
                question.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Because I never wanted to be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">You cannot lie about your own nature. You must accept that you are the Avatar.
                <charAction>Aang inhales and, seeing an image of himself on a cliff looking down at
                the ground, exhales, and accepts his nature.</charAction> Very good, Aang. You have
            opened the chakra of truth.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Outside the temple interior.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">The sixth pool of energy is the light chakra, located in the center of the forehead.
            It deals with insight and is blocked by illusion. The greatest illusion of this world is
            the illusion of separation. Things you think are separate and different are actually one
            in the same.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>An image is shown of the world, with the four nations' territories
                marked.</charAction> Like the four nations.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">
         <charAction>The image changes so the territories become the same color.</charAction>
            Yes. We are all one people, <charAction>The territories become separate
                again.</charAction> but we live as if divided.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We're all connected. Everything is connected.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">That's right! Even the separation of the four elements is an illusion. If you open
            your mind, you will see that all the elements are one. Four parts of the same whole.
            Even metal is just a part of earth that has been purified and refined.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Pathik speaks, the camera fades to Xin Fu and Yu trying to take Toph
                home. She feels around the metal cage with seismic sense and feels tiny particles of
                earth in the metal. She smiles, exhales deeply and begins to push against the
                metal.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Struggling.</charAction> Come on, metal. Budge! <charAction>She punches
                a hole in the metal and shakes her hand in pain.</charAction> Wooo! Toph, you
            rule.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She takes another punch as we cut back to Ba Sing Se. Katara walks by the
                Jasmine Dragon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">What do you say, Momo? A cup of tea before we get back to the king?
                <charAction>Arrives at the shop.</charAction> Table for two, please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Uncle! I need two jasmine, one green, and one lychee!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">I'm brewing as fast as I can!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara notices Zuko and Iroh. Stunned, she runs away from the
                shop.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene returns to Aang and Pathik, who sit at the top of the temple at
                night.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is the last chakra, isn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Yes. Once you open this chakra, you will be able to go in and out of the Avatar
            State at will and when you are in the Avatar State, you will have complete control and
            awareness of all your actions.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiles with determination.</charAction> Let's do this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">The Thought Chakra is located at the crown of the head. It deals with pure cosmic
            energy, and is blocked by earthly attachment. Meditate on what attaches you to this
            world. <charAction>Images of Katara appear before Aang.</charAction> Now, let all of
            those attachments go. Let them flow down the river, forgotten.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Coming out of his meditation.</charAction> What? Why would I let go of
            Katara? I ... I love her!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Learn to let her go, or you cannot let the pure cosmic energy flow in from the
            universe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Why would I choose cosmic energy over Katara? <charAction>Aang throws his hands
                up.</charAction> How could it be a bad thing that I feel an attachment to her? Three
            chakras ago that was a good thing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">You must learn to let go. <charAction>Aang contemplates
            worriedly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the palace, Katara runs to inform the Earth King, only to encounter
                the "Kyoshi Warriors".</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Thank goodness you're here, Suki. Something terrible is going on. The Fire Nation
            has infiltrated the city, I just saw Prince Zuko and his uncle! <charAction>Azula widens
                her eyes in surprise and smiles slyly.</charAction> We have to tell the Earth King
            right away!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Oh, don't worry, I'll be sure to let him know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara notices "Suki" has gold eyes and is shocked upon realization that
                the "Kyoshi Warriors" are actually Azula, Mai, and Ty Lee. She prepares to attack,
                but Ty Lee quickly jumps forward and blocks her chi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>While the three girls gather around the fallen Katara; pans to camera
                looking up to the three girls.</charAction> So, Zuzu's in the city, too? I think
            it's time for a family reunion. <charAction>Momo flies off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm sorry, but I can't let go of Katara.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Aang, to master the Avatar State, you must open all the chakras. Surrender
            yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay, I'll try.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">Now think of your attachments and let them go. Let the pure cosmic energy
            flow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sees an image of him letting Katara go, and a bridge that will lead
                him to Avatar State mastery. His image looks down, smiles at the bridge, and walks
                up to the Avatar Spirit, which is an enlarged image of himself in the Avatar State.
                The Avatar Spirit is holding a ball of energy, and Aang walks directly inside of it.
                As he does so, his tatooes glow, and he closes his eyes. Right before he is able to
                completely open the final chakra and master the Avatar State, however, he hears a
                shriek from Katara and sees a vision of her in chains. At this, he jumps out of the
                energy sphere and runs away from the Avatar Spirit. The energy bridge that lead him
                there slowly vanishes behind him until it catches up and falls from underneath him,
                causing his image to plummet toward Earth. This cuts his connection to the Avatar
                State, which forces him back to reality.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara's in danger! I have to go! <charAction>Prepares to
            exit.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Pathik">No, Aang! By choosing attachment, you have locked the chakra! If you leave now, you
            won't be able to go into the Avatar State at all!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang hesitates but leaves anyway, leaving Pathik concerned and
                disappointed. Meanwhile, the journey to take Toph back to her home is stopped when
                Xin Fu and Yu hear a loud noise. They go to investigate, and notice a hole in the
                cage and that Toph is gone.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">It's another one her tricks!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">There's a giant hole in the box! How is that a trick!?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>From behind them.</charAction> It's not! It's the real deal!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She earthbends the two men together, throws them in the cage, and
                metalbends the cage shut.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Jumps on top of the box.</charAction> I am the greatest earthbender in
            the world! Don't you two dunderheads ever forget it! <charAction>Stomps on the box and
                exits using earth surfing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Xin Fu">
         <charAction>Inside the box.</charAction> I'm going to be stuck in here forever with
            you, aren't I?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yu">I have to go the bathroom. <charAction>Xin Fu groans and slams his head against the
                box.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back at the Water Tribe camp, Hakoda approaches Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Ready to go knock some Fire Nation heads?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You don't know how much this means to me, Dad. I'll make you proud and I'll finally
            prove to you what a great warrior I am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">
         <charAction>Placing his hand on Sokka's shoulder.</charAction> Sokka, you don't have
            to prove anything to me. I'm already proud of you and I've always known you're a great
            warrior.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Why do you think I trusted you to look after our tribe when I left?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Just as the two are boarding the ship, Aang and Appa appear. Aang shows a
                clear look of concern.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">This can't be good news.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Sokka depart. Just as they're leaving, Sokka looks back at Hakoda,
                who looks back and grins. Back in Ba Sing Se, Azula is led into a prison by two Dai
                Li agents. She is taken to Long Feng's cell.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">What is this about? Your agents show up in the middle of the night and drag me down
            here? You will not treat a Kyoshi Warrior this way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">But you're not a Kyoshi Warrior, are you, <charAction>Standing.</charAction>
            Princess Azula of the Fire Nation?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">What do you want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">I want to make a deal. It's time that I regain control of Ba Sing Se and you have
            something I need.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Oh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">The Earth King's trust.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Why should I help you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Long Feng">Because I can get you the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Smirks.</charAction> I'm listening ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Long Feng smiles. Back at the Jasmine Dragon, a royal messenger
                enters.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Royal messenger">A message from the Royal Palace.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Reads through, becomes shocked, and smiles.</charAction> I ... I can't
            believe it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What is it, Uncle?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Excited.</charAction> Great news! We've been invited to serve tea to the
            Earth King! <charAction>Runs off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko smiles as he continues sweeping. Back in the prison hold, the door to
                Long Feng's cell is closed. Azula leaves Long Feng's presence and gives a smirk.
                Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
