<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Northern Air Temple</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode begins with the gang sitting around a camp site with several
                other groups, listening to a man telling a story of 'airbenders'.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">
         <charAction>Dramatically; out of view.</charAction> So, travelers. The next time you
            think you hear a strange, large bird talking, take a closer look. It might not be a
            giant parrot, but a flying man. A member of a secret group of air walkers, who laugh at
            gravity, and laugh at those bound to the earth by it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cuts to a wide shot, showing the gang and the other travelers
                surrounding a small campfire. The Storyteller, having finished his story, is going
                around collecting coins from the other travelers.</charAction> Aren't airbender
            stories the greatest? <charAction>Talking to Katara and Sokka, who are sitting next to
                him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Was it realistic? Is that how it was back
            then?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to the three kids.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I laugh at gravity all the time. <charAction>Chuckling to himself.</charAction>
            Gravity.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">
         <charAction>Arrives in front of the gang, having already collected money from the
                rest of the audience.</charAction> Jingle, jingle! <charAction>Jingles the hat in
                front of Sokka, asking for money.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka searches inside his heavy cloak, and manages to pull out a bug, a
                worm and a few crumbs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Sorry ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">
         <charAction>Upset and somewhat downcast.</charAction> Aww, cheapskates!
                <charAction>Walks away as Sokka puts the bugs back in his
            pocket.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang stands up and runs after the storyteller, who is kneeling in front of
                an old man.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Happily.</charAction> Hey! Thanks for the story.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">
         <charAction>Holds out his cap.</charAction> Tell it to the cap,
                <description>boy.</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Storyteller shakes his cap behind him as he kneels in front of an old
                man. The shaking causes a coin to come loose and fall from the cap. As Aang searches
                his clothes for some money, Momo picks up the coin and puts it in the cap as the
                Storyteller turns around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">Aww, much obliged, little bat-thing. <charAction>He pets Momo on the
                head.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Having given up trying to find a coin.</charAction> It means a lot to
            hear airbender stories. It must have been a hundred years ago your great grandpa met
            them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Storyteller">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What are you prattling about, child? Great
            Grandpappy saw the air walkers last week. <charAction>He indicates to the old man he was
                kneeling in front of before. The old man makes a sound in his throat akin to a
                laugh, and waves a greeting to Aang. The shot cuts to Aang, who has a shocked and
                disbelieving expression.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes from the campsite to a shot of clouds, and Appa flying
                above them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sitting on Appa's neck, steering. He is talking to Katara and Sokka, who
                are riding in Appa's saddle.</charAction> Hey, we're almost at the Northern Air
            Temple. This is where they had the championships for Sky Bison polo.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Moving to sit at the back of the saddle with her brother.</charAction>
            Do you think we'll really find airbenders?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He is whittling a piece of wood. The design is
                indecipherable.</charAction> You want me to be like you, or totally honest?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Crossing her arms, obviously angry with him.</charAction> Are you saying
            I'm a liar?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He shrugs, unconcerned with her mood.</charAction> I'm saying you're an
            optimist. Same thing, basically.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Hey, guys, look at this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera moves to show Appa, who is flying toward a mountain with a large
                structure on top. It looks very similar to the Southern Air Temple, with obvious
                spires reminiscent of a temple's architecture. Around them are several dark specks.
                The camera zooms in, and the specks are revealed to be people, flying around the
                temple in plane-shaped contraptions.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Amazed.</charAction> They really are airbenders!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>His face falls as he sees the 'airbenders', and after Katara's excited
                outburst, he leans back and scowls while crossing his arms.</charAction> No, they're
            not.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Exuberantly.</charAction> What do you mean "they're not"? Those guys are
            flying!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Bitterly. He is glaring at the direction of the people flying around the
                temple.</charAction> Gliding maybe, but not flying. You can tell by the way they
            move, they're not airbending. Those people have no spirit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Suddenly, a boy sitting in an oddly shaped chair flies right above them,
                nearly hitting them, and laughing as he does so.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I don't know, Aang.<charAction>Katara points to the boy.</charAction> That kid
            seemed pretty spirited. <charAction>Katara indicates to the boy, who is flying
                dangerously close, but still laughing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The boy begins to fly away, shooting Aang one more look back as he does so
                while grinning. Aang grins devilishly, and opens up his glider to follow the boy. He
                leaves Katara and Sokka on Appa, and they quickly become surrounded by gliders as
                they get closer to the temple. Several gliders almost hit Appa, which causes Katara
                to knock into her brother and shout in pain as Appa moves sharply to avoid
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We better find some solid ground, before it finds us. <charAction>The siblings land
                Appa on the temple courtyard, out of the hazardous sky. Aang is still flying with
                the boy, and seems to be having fun at the surprise
            competition.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Colonists">
         <charAction>Several children are on the ground, cheering on their
                friend.</charAction> Go Teo! Show that bald kid how it's done!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Teo and Aang do two loop-de-loops as they fly around the air temple. The
                two boys do a spiral downwards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>The boy doesn't seem upset at Aang, and seems happy that he isn't angry
                for nearly flying into him.</charAction> Hey there, you're pretty good!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Nonchalantly, but with a smirk.</charAction> Yeah, I know. But I can do
            more than fancy gliding.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang begins flying closer to the temple, under a bridge. Cut to a scene of
                Aang jumping off his glider and allowing it to fly forward on its own. He begins
                running along a wall, switching to an air scooter halfway, before jumping off onto
                his glider again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>He is looking amazed, before thinking of his own plan.</charAction> Wow,
            I don't think I can do that. But here's a good one.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Teo turns on a small canister that is positioned under his glider. White
                smoke begins to stream from the strange contraption, and Teo flies around in the
                sky. The camera pans to show the sight from the ground, where it is revealed that he
                has created an image of Aang's face, complete with an annoyed expression. The crowd
                below cheers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">What do you think?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Annoyed; his face mimics the one Teo has just drawn.</charAction> It's
            great.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang lands beside Katara and Sokka. Teo lands soon after and pulls on the
                brakes. Other children take the glider off of the top of his wheel chair. Teo rolls
                up to Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Hey, you're a real airbender. You must be the Avatar! That's amazing! I-I've heard
            stories about you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs his head, embarrassed.</charAction> Thanks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sokka ignores all formalities, instead going over to Teo's chair and
                examining the strange shape and design.</charAction> Wow! This glider chair is
            incredible!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">You think this is good, wait until you see the other stuff my dad designed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>All four walk inside the building. They enter a room filled with pipes and
                machinery. Aang looks around worriedly. Beneath the pipes, an original mural can be
                seen, although it has been destroyed by the pipes, which are sticking into the
                walls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Wow! <charAction>Runs up to machines.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Yeah, my dad is the mastermind behind this whole place. Everything's powered by hot
            air. <charAction>Shows women using an elevator like contraption.</charAction> It even
            pumps hot air currents outside to give us a lift while we're gliding.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Monotonously.</charAction> This place is unbelievable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Yeah, it's great, isn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, just unbelievable. <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Katara approaches Teo, who seems disappointed at Aang's
                reaction.</charAction> Aang used to come here a long time ago. I think he's a little
            shocked it's so ... different.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So better!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara walks up to Aang, who is looking at a painted wall with pipes going
                through it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is supposed to be the history of my people.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara puts her hand on his shoulder. He walks over to a fountain with an
                air bison statue on it. He looks at his reflection in the dirty green water, Aang
                looks at it squeamishly. The sky bison statue suddenly has black smoke coming out of
                it's mouth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ugh!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Walks up and puts her hand on his shoulder.</charAction> I'm sure some
            parts of the temple are still the same.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen pans off to show Aang, Katara, Sokka and Teo walking across a bridge
                to a large room that looks well kept. The room has no roof, although around the
                walls there are statues of monks, mostly meditating.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's nice to see that at least one part of the temple that isn't ruined.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara and Aang look at a statue of a long-bearded airbender
                meditating.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Man">
         <charAction>Off-screen.</charAction> Look out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The statue is knocked down by a wrecking ball and all four cover their
                heads. Dust is coming from the statue, so all four cough. The dust clears to show
                six men standing where the statue used to be.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">What the doodle? Don't you know enough to stay away from construction sites? We have
            to make room for the bathhouse! <charAction>He has approached Aang and the group,
                looking more surprised than upset.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He turns to the mechanist and yells angrily at him.</charAction> Do you
            know what you did!? You just destroyed something sacred! For a stupid
            bathhouse!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Well, people around here are starting to stink. <charAction>Waves his hand in front
                of his face, as though trying to dissipate a bad smell.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Points at the mechanist.</charAction> This whole place stinks!
                <charAction>Using his airbending, Aang flips the crane contraption off of the edge
                of the building.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to exterior shot, showing the crane falling and landing heavily against
                the side of the cliff the temple is situated on. It is covered by a cloud of dirt
                and snow as it is utterly destroyed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is a sacred temple! You can't treat it this way! <charAction>Walks closer to
                the mechanist.</charAction> I've seen it when the monks were here! I know what it's
            supposed to be like!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">The monks? But, <charAction>Scratches his beard.</charAction> you're
            twelve.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Teo rolls up.</charAction> Dad, he's the Avatar. He used to come here a
            hundred years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang takes a menacing step closer to the mechanist, who takes a step
                back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What are you doing? Who said you could be here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Turns away from Aang.</charAction> Hmm, doing here ... A long time ago,
                <charAction>Points finger up.</charAction> but not a hundred years, my people became
            refugees <charAction>Walks behind his son's wheelchair.</charAction> after a terrible
            flood. My infant son, <charAction>Teo looks down sadly.</charAction> Teo, was badly hurt
            and lost his mother. <charAction>Sniffles.</charAction> I needed somewhere to rebuild
            and I stumbled across this place. Couldn't believe it! Everywhere! Pictures of flying
            people! But empty, <charAction>Looks around.</charAction> nobody home. Then,
                <charAction>Does a airplane like gesture, like he's flying up to Aang.</charAction>
            I came across these fan-like contraptions!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Our gliders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Yes! Little, light flying machines! <charAction>Waves his hands up and
                down.</charAction> They gave me an idea. Build a new life for my son, in the air!
            Then everyone will be on equal ground! So to speak. We're just in the process of
            improving upon what's already here. <charAction>Katara wipes her tears on Aang's shirt,
                and Sokka looks like he's holding back tears.</charAction> And, after all, isn't
            that what nature does?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Nature knows where to stop.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">I suppose that's true. Unfortunately, progress has a way of getting away from us.
            Look at the time! <charAction>Points at candles.</charAction> Come! <charAction>To other
                workers.</charAction> The pulley system must be oiled before dark.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Wait, how can you tell the time from that thing? The notches all look the
            same.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">The candle will tell us. Watch. <charAction>Candle pops four
            times.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You put spark powder in the candle!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Four flashes. So it's exactly four hours past mid-day. Or, as I call it: four
            o'candle. <charAction>Sokka laughs. Cut to a frontal shot of the mechanist, pleased that
                Sokka is interested.</charAction> If you like that, wait till you see my finger-safe
            knife sharpener. <charAction>He holds up his left hand, revealing that three of the
                fingers are made of wood.</charAction> Only took me three tries to get it right.
                <charAction>He pulls off the three wooden fingers, and throws them into Sokka's
                hand.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Horrified.</charAction> Aaah!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Pokes Sokka in the back with his one remaining finger and gestures for
                him to come.</charAction> Follow me! <charAction>Sokka runs after
            him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Hey, Aang. I want to show you something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen fades to black before reappearing with Katara, Teo and Aang walking
                inside a building.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I just can't get over it. There's not a single thing that's the same.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">I don't know about that. The temple might be different <charAction>Picks up hermit
                crab from the ground.</charAction> but the creatures that live here
                <charAction>Hands it to Katara.</charAction> are probably direct descendants of the
            ones who lived here a long time ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pokes hermit crab.</charAction> You're right. They're kind of keepers of
            the temple's origins. <charAction>Katara hands it to Aang. It moves around in his hand
                and he smiles.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Besides, there's one part of the temple that hasn't changed at all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen fades slightly and reappears at a long hallway with airbending
                symbols through it. Shows all three looking at a door with an airbending contraption
                on it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Hey, it's just like the one in the other temple!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Confidently, with a matter-of-fact tone.</charAction> Only an airbender
            can open it, so inside it's completely untouched. Just the way the monks left it. I've
            always wondered what it's like in there ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>She looks at him, as though slightly scared of his reaction. Her tone is
                gentle and questioning.</charAction> Aang?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He turns away from the door and his friends.</charAction> I'm sorry.
            This is the last part of the temple that's the same as it was. I want it to stay that
            way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Somewhat disappointed, although he tries not to let it
                show.</charAction> I completely understand. I just wanted you to know that it's
            here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks. <charAction>All three start to walk away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Screen cuts to Sokka and the mechanist walking down a dark stairway holding
                lanterns.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">These lanterns are terrible. I can't see! <charAction>Opens the top of his lantern
                only to find them filled with fireflies.</charAction> Why would you want to use
            fireflies for light? <charAction>One flies out.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Hey! Close that up! They'll get loose! <charAction>Sokka closes it.</charAction>
            Fireflies are a non-flammable light source. <charAction>Both begin to walk
                again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They continue for a while until they arrive at a wooden door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Cover your nose <charAction>Both plug their noses.</charAction> and hold your
            breath. <charAction>The mechanist opens an eye slot in the door, both look inside a
                pitch-black room.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Nasally, due to his nose being blocked.</charAction> Okay ... so you
            brought me all the way down here to see an empty room.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Closes eye slot.</charAction> Wrong. It's filled to the brim with
            natural gas. Came across it my first time here. Unfortunately, I was carrying a torch at
            the time. Nearly blew my self and the whole place even more sky high! Thought my
            eyebrows would never grow back. <charAction>Pans up to his eyebrows.</charAction>
            Anyway, there's a vital problem that needs solving. From time to time, we have gas
            leaks. And they're nearly impossible to find.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, this place is an explosion waiting to happen.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Yes, until I figure out how to locate something I can't see, hear, smell, or
            touch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a exterior of temple with people flying in the sky. Aang, Katara and
                Teo are on the ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">The wind will carry you. It supports something inside you. Something even lighter
            than air. <charAction>Shows Katara holding a glider and standing at the edge of a
                building.</charAction> And that something takes over when you fly.
                <charAction>Katara puts down her glider and looks up at the other people
                flying.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> I've changed my mind. I think I was born without
            that something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Impossible! Everybody has it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Spirit.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">What?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Spirit. That's the something you're talking about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Thoughtfully.</charAction> Yeah, I suppose it is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows Katara with the glider in her hands again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Are you ready?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">No! <charAction>Jumps off anyway.</charAction> Aaaaah! <charAction>Starts to fall
                down wards, but eventually starts to fly straight. Her scream peters off as she
                begins laughing.</charAction> I can't believe I'm flying!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Momo fly up beside her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Just make sure you keep your mouth closed so you don't swallow a bug!
                <charAction>Shows Momo flying by and eating a bug.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Teo was right about the air. All I had to do was trust it, let it carry me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Even though Teo's not an airbender, he really does have the spirit of one!
                <charAction>Aang lands beside him on the building.</charAction> I've been thinking.
            If you want to see what's in that room, I'd be happy to open the door for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Wait! <charAction>Katara flies by.</charAction> How do I land this thing? What if I
            land over <charAction>Swallows a bug.</charAction> a-ack-ack-bleck! Bug! Bug! Ack, that
            was a bug!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Back to Sokka and the mechanist. The mechanist is drawing on a large piece
                of paper and Sokka is looking through shelves. Sokka drops various things, including
                seven scrolls, four pieces of paper, a hard-boiled egg and a model of a hot air
                balloon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">I said don't touch anything! <charAction>Comes over to help Sokka pick things
                up.</charAction> Oh, don't worry. That experiment's old, <charAction>Referring to
                the hot air balloon.</charAction> and that egg was just part of last week's
            lunch.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He sniffs the air before wincing.</charAction> Ugh! Week old egg
            smell!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Quick, find that egg! <charAction>Both crawl around the floor looking for
                it.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows Aang, Teo and Katara at the door of the airbending
                room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">I can't believe I'm finally going to see what's inside!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends into the door's contraption, flipping three dials so air
                comes out of them. Cut to Sokka and the mechanist searching for the
                egg.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">How can something so small that you can't even see it make such a big
            stink!?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The mechanist looks up from searching.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">That's the solution to our problem!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah ... <charAction>Both turn toward each other.</charAction> if we put a whole
            mess of rotten eggs in the cellar where the gas seeps up ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">... The gas will mix with the smell of rotten eggs!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Then, if there's a leak ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">... You smell rotten eggs! Then, you just follow your nose to the place where the
            smell is coming from ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">And plug up the hole where the gas is escaping!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Both throw up their hands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Both">You're a genius! <charAction>Bell rings on one of his desks.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Something's wrong. <charAction>Stands up.</charAction> I've go to go!
                <charAction>Runs out the door and Sokka follows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shows Aang, Teo, and Katara walking into the large room. It's filled with
                Fire Nation weapons, tools and a red hot air balloon with the Fire Nation insignia
                on it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is a nightmare.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Walks in with Sokka behind him.</charAction> You don't
            understand!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Accusingly.</charAction> You're making weapons for the Fire
            Nation!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You make weapons for the Fire Nation?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Explain all this! Now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>He is hesitant, but resigned as he begins to explain.</charAction> It
            was about a year after we moved here. Fire Nation soldiers found our settlement. You
            were too young to remember this, Teo. They were going to destroy everything! Burn it to
            the ground! I pleaded with them, I begged them to spare us! They asked what I had to
            offer. I offered ... my services. You must understand. I did this for you!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Teo looks away in shame and the mechanist leaves. The scene cuts to him in
                his workshop, placing two eggs with smiley faces in his hot air balloon model, along
                with a candle to make it float. He looks rather depressed. He lets go of the bottom
                and it starts to float. As this happens, the door opens, with Aang and Teo standing
                in the doorway.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">When are they coming?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Soon. <charAction>Candle pops once.</charAction> Very soon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You can't give them more weapons.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">If I don't give them what they want, they will destroy this place! <charAction>The
                model of the hot air balloon catches fire and crashes. The mechanist puts the fire
                out with a cloth.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">How can I be proud of you when your inventions are being used for murder?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">I need some time to think. <charAction>Bell rings on his desk.</charAction> You need
            to leave! Go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">We're not leaving!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Then hide! Quickly! <charAction>They hide behind some of his inventions. the
                mechanist pulls a rope that opens a trapdoor, and a war minister from the Fire
                Nation is lifted into the room.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Qin">You know better than to keep me waiting. Give me what you owe us so we can be on our
            way. <charAction>The mechanist looks down.</charAction> Well? Is there a
            problem?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Hurredly.</charAction> No, right this way. <charAction>Gestures toward
                the door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Qin is about to go out the door, but Aang airbends it shut. He jumps in
                front of the door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The deal's off.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Qin">The Avatar ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Aang, don't get involved!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Qin">If I don't get what I came here for, the Fire Nation will burn this place to
            rubble!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Get out of here! <charAction>Slaps him in the face with an air swipe; continues off
                screen.</charAction> You're leaving empty-handed!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Qin">Then the destruction of this temple <charAction>Pointing at Aang.</charAction> will
            be on your head! <charAction>He leaves through the trap door and Aang airbends it
                shut.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The four children are now talking on the tall bridge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">This is bad.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Very bad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, what are we going to do? How can we possibly keep them all away?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'll tell you how. We have something they don't. <charAction>Points to the
                sky.</charAction> Air power. We control the sky. That's something the Fire Nation
            can't do. We can win!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">I want to help. <charAction>He appears at the door.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Good. We'll need it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to an aerial shot of the temple, before cutting to the mechanist's
                workshop. He is standing behind a table with Sokka. The model hot air balloon, a few
                plans, and a candle are resting on the table. Aang, Katara, and Teo are on the other
                side, surrounded by other colonists.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">We finally got the war balloon working, thanks to Sokka. This boy's a
            genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Thank you. You're a genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Thank you! <charAction>Katara and Aang exchange unamused
            glances.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">See, the problem with the old war balloon was you could get it air-borne,
                <charAction>Places the candle in the model.</charAction> but once it did, it just
            kept going. <charAction>He pulls a string connected to the model, putting it on the
                table.</charAction> You could put a hole in the top, but then all the hot air would
            escape. So the question became, how do you keep a lid on hot air?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Ugh, if only we knew. <charAction>Teo, Katara, and Aang laugh.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">A lid is actually the answer. If you control the hot air, you control the war
            balloon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Huh, that's actually pretty smart.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Okay, we've got four kinds of bombs: <charAction>He begins listing them off on his
                fingers.</charAction> smoke, slime, fire, and ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">Stink! Never underestimate the power of stink!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to exterior shot of temple. Everyone is outside, watching anxiously for
                any sign of the Fire Nation.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Girl">
         <charAction>Looking over a ledge.</charAction> They're coming!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">Are we ready?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Yes. But where's Sokka with the war
            balloon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jumping off Appa.</charAction> We'll have to start without it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to shot of people readying their flying machines for take off. They
                begin the assault as their gliders fly off into the air. Cheers from the crowd
                below. Cut to Fire Nation troops climbing the cliff path. They are attacked by the
                various bombs thrown at them. Cut back to Aang and the other flyers going down
                through the clouds. The gliders fly over the Fire Nation troops dropping bombs
                below. Cut to Fire Nation troops on the cliff edge.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Nation soldier">Take them out of the sky. Now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to more gliders dropping bombs. Fire Nation soldiers cough and some
                fall off the cliff. Cut to Aang jumping onto an air scooter, moving across a ledge,
                causing snow to fall onto soldiers below before jumping back onto his glider. Cut to
                the soldiers retreating.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We've got them on the run! We need more slime!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to gliders flying up through the clouds to Appa and receiving more
                bombs from Katara. Hooks fly through the clouds nearly hitting Appa and latching
                onto the cliff. Cut to tanks scaling the cliffs via the chains. Aang sees this and
                manages to remove one hook. The tank falls before sending out another hook. Cut to
                distance shot of temple with tanks closing in. Gliders continue to fly dropping
                bombs in an attempt to slow the tanks down. Many cuts to interiors of tanks showing
                soldiers firebending out of them. Aang lands and airbends the tanks away. The tanks
                flip over and readjust themselves before continuing on. Cut to Katara and Teo in
                sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Those things are unstoppable!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">
         <charAction>Thoughtfully, trying to remember what he knew.</charAction> I think I
            know how they work. I remember my dad tinkering with the counterbalancing system.
            Something to do with water. Works great, huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Water? Can you get me close to one?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">No problem!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to aerial view of Aang fending off firebending blasts. Cut to Katara
                landing next to him. Katara freezes multiple tanks with waterbending. Camera zooms
                out to show more tanks. Aang defends Katara from fire blasts before Appa drops in
                front and knocks the tanks away. Cut to behind Appa showing Katara and Aang climbing
                up his tail. Cut to Aang and Katara looking down at the oncoming force. Cut to the
                temple balcony with Katara, Aang and Teo.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">We're out of bombs!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Come on Sokka. <charAction>Side-view of Katara.</charAction> Where's that war
            balloon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The war balloon appears behind Katara. Cut to wide-view of temple balcony
                with war balloon in background. Cut to view of soldiers and tanks advancing forward
                with war balloon above. Cut to view of Sokka and the mechanist on the war
                balloon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hey, why aren't they shooting at us?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">The insignia! <charAction>Close-up of Fire Nation insignia.</charAction> They think
            we're on their side.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up of Sokka on war balloon.</charAction> Then I guess they won't
            see this coming. <charAction>Slices rope attached to a large bomb.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Cut to view of both balloon and advancing army.</charAction> Bombs
            away!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to ground view of soldiers being washed away by slime. Cut to above war
                balloon showing Sokka cut another rope. Cut back to view of soldiers and balloon
                showing the bombs stopping some of soldiers and tanks. Cut to shot under balloon
                showing Sokka and the mechanist looking down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh no, that was the last one. <charAction>Cut to tanks beginning to scale the
                cliffs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">
         <charAction>Cut back to Sokka and the mechanist.</charAction> Wait a second. You
            smell that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Rotten eggs! <charAction>Cut to a view of the balloon and a large crevice in the
                ground below.</charAction> There! That's were the gas is escaping.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to close-up of Sokka with the expression of having an idea. Cut to
                tanks scaling cliff side. Cut to Earth Kingdom civilians trying to knock the hooks
                away. Cut to Sokka and the mechanist on the balloon. Sokka is levering the engine
                away from the bottom of the balloon in an attempt to get it free.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mechanist">What are you doing? That's our fuel source.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">It's the only bomb we've got.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to view below the balloon as the engine drops to the crevice below. Cut
                to exterior of temple as the army advances on the temple. Cut to a view of Katara,
                Aang and Teo looking down. Cut to Sokka and the mechanist on balloon. Cut to
                wide-view of the temple and the war balloon in distance. An explosion goes off and
                the temple is blocked from view. Cut to Sokka and the mechanist on war balloon,
                smoke covers the view. Cut to Katara, Aang and Teo with smoke again covering the
                view. Cut to wide shot of temple with smoke dissipating. Cut to chains hanging off
                the cliffs, no tanks in sight. Cut to balcony and view of cliffs
                below.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Look! They're retreating! <charAction>Cheers from crowd.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>War balloon flies past.</charAction> We're going down!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang and Katara on balcony.</charAction> No, Sokka! Hold on!
                <charAction>Aang jumps on his glider and flies toward them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to view of war balloon falling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to close-up of Sokka swinging his boomerang around with a rope
                attached, the mechanist behind him.</charAction> Get ready!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang flying toward them. Cut to behind the war balloon as Aang
                circles it. Sokka throws the boomerang toward Aang which latches onto his glider.
                Cut to Sokka and the mechanist being pulled out of the balloon and dragged away with
                the mechanist moaning in fright. Cut to show war balloon floating away. The scene
                ends and cuts to the temple.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You know what? <charAction>Cut to close-up panning shot of Sokka, Katara, Aang, Teo,
                and the mechanist.</charAction> I'm really glad you guys all live here now.
                <charAction>Cut to shot above Aang picking up a hermit crab.</charAction> I
            realized, it's like the hermit crab. <charAction>Cut to close-up of Aang's hands
                surrounding the hermit crab.</charAction> Maybe you weren't born here, but you found
            this empty shell and made it your home. And now you protect each other.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Teo">That means a lot, coming from you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to Aang, Sokka and Katara.</charAction> Aang you were right about
            air power. As long as we've got the skies, we'll have the Fire Nation on the run.
                <charAction>Cut to wide-view of temple grounds, crowd
            cheering.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to panning shot of the people, with the mechanist turning away from the
                crowd and looking down as though sad. Cut to snowy trees in a forest below the
                temple. The Fire Nation capturing and figuring out how to use the war
                balloon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Qin">
         <charAction>Cut to Qin, surrounded by two other ministers.</charAction> This defeat
            is the gateway to many victories.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to behind the Fire Nation soldiers as they begin inflating the balloon
                up with firebending. Cut to close-up of Fire Nation insignia.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
