<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Headband</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens with a shot of the incline leading to the Royal Caldera
                city, as the camera pans above to an aerial shot of the city. Shot cuts to the Fire
                Nation Royal Palace, before cutting to Zuko's bedroom, to show Zuko tossing and
                turning in his bed, unable to sleep. He opens his eyes and gets up, donning a cloak.
                Cut to the rim of the volcano, as he walks through a path. Cut to the Capital City
                Prison as Zuko walks toward it. Cut to an overhead shot of him stopping and looking
                above. Cut to a guard walking around a balcony, who spots him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">Who's there?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko, without speaking a word, turns around and walks away. The guard,
                seeing Zuko leave, resumes his patrol. Scene changes to some islands at day time, as
                a mysterious cloud goes toward one of the islands at an abnormal speed. Cut to the
                cloud "descending" on one of the islands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>From inside the cloud.</charAction> I think I see a cave below.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Commanding.</charAction> Sh! Keep quiet!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends the cloud surrounding Appa as the flying bison lands. Sokka
                jumps to the ground from Appa and reconnoiters, before crossing his arms and looking
                toward Team Avatar.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Great job with the cloud camo, but next time, let's disguise ourselves as the kind
            of cloud that knows how to keep its mouth shut. <charAction>He reconnoiters
                again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Cut to the Toph, Katara, and Aang standing in front of Sokka, who is
                reconnoitering. Sarcastically.</charAction> Yeah, we wouldn't want a bird to hear us
            chatting up there and turn us in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Turning back toward the other three.</charAction> Hey, we're in enemy
            territory. <charAction>He points above as camera zooms back to show four toucan puffins
                standing on a rock behind him.</charAction> Those are enemy birds.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>One toucan puffin jumps onto Sokka's head and screeches. Cut to the other
                three as they laugh, and walk toward the cave, with Sokka following behind.
                Suddenly, he jumps above them and comes "diving" down. He looks suspicious, as shot
                cuts to an aerial shot of him running into the cave, followed by the rest of the
                group.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Well, this is it. <charAction>Cut to Sokka standing in front of the other
                three.</charAction> This is how we'll be living until the invasion begins.
                <charAction>His head drops each time he says the word, "cave".</charAction> Hiding
            in cave after cave after cave after cave ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut to Katara, standing near Aang, from behind Sokka.</charAction>
            Sokka, we don't need to become cave people. What we need is some new clothes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, blending in is better than hiding out. <charAction>Cut to Aang and
                Katara.</charAction> If we get Fire Nation disguises,
                <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> we would be just as safe as we would be hiding in
            a cave.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Cut to Toph, who is sitting down with her legs slightly
                folded.</charAction> Plus, they have real food out there. Does anyone want to sit in
            the dirt and eat cave hoppers?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Toph punches the cave wall, causing cave hoppers to jump out, Momo grabs
                one and eats it. He turns around and spits out a cave hopper limb.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Looks like we got outvoted, sport. Let's get some new clothes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to outside a Fire Nation home near a waterfall. Next to the home,
                clothes hang out to dry on clotheslines over natural steam vents. Katara, Aang,
                Sokka, and Toph hide behind a rock wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Whispering.</charAction> I don't know about this. <charAction>Cut to a
                view of Team Avatar from the clothes.</charAction> These clothes belong to
            somebody.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I call the silk robe! <charAction>Jumps out from behind the rock wall and grabs two
                outfits.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But if it's essential to our survival ... then I call the suit! <charAction>Jumps
                over the wall.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a view of the hanging clothes from inside a house through doorway
                where a man sleeps. Aang and Toph run across, grabbing clothes. Sokka stands still,
                examining shirts on the clothesline and grabs the third one.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Puts on a headband, revealing his whole new Fire Nation
                disguise.</charAction> Ta-dah! Normal kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Hm ... I should probably wear shoes. But then I won't be able to see as well.
                <charAction>Sits down.</charAction> Sorry, shoes! <charAction>Pulls on the shoe,
                launching the sole at Sokka's face, leaving a red mark.</charAction> Finally, a
            stylish shoe for the blind earthbender.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Walks partially on camera.</charAction> How do I look? <charAction>The
                camera pans from Katara's dress to her whole outfit.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Blushing, scratching his head.</charAction> Uh ... your mom's
            necklace.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, <charAction>Touches necklace.</charAction> oh, yeah. I guess it's pretty
            obviously Water Tribe, isn't it? <charAction>Takes off the necklace and holds it in her
                hand.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>In the city, Katara puts some money on a head-wear display. She puts on a
                Fire Nation necklace, Toph puts on a crown, and Sokka wears a top-knot. Aang pats
                down Momo's ears and hides him in his shirt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I used to visit my friend Kuzon here a hundred years ago. So, everyone just follow
            my lead and stay cool. Or, as they say in the Fire Nation, "stay flamin'".
                <charAction>Walks around the building corner. To a man eating meat on a
                stick.</charAction> Greetings, my good hotman.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Fire Nation man">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> Uh, hi. <charAction>Sokka shrugs at him as he
                passes.</charAction> I guess ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Looking at a meat display. Disappointedly.</charAction> Oh, we're going
            to a meat place?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Come on, Aang, everyone here eats meat. Even the meat! <charAction>Points at a hippo
                cow eating a piece of meat swarming with flies.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You guys go ahead. I'll just get some lettuce out of the garbage. <charAction>Aang
                and Katara wave each at each other as the rest enter. Turns around to greet random
                people on the street.</charAction> Hotman. Hotman. Hotman. Hotman. Hotman.
            Hotman.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Three soldiers approach Aang.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male soldier">It's over. We caught you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Guiltily.</charAction> Who, me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male soldier">It couldn't be more obvious that you don't belong here. <charAction>Cut to Aang
                looking very nervous.</charAction> Next time you play hooky, you might wanna take
            off your school uniform.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang laughs nervously and the soldier grabs Aang. Cut to the two guards
                push Aang into a classroom. The camera pans across the room, stopping at the
                teacher, Ms. Kwan.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Oh. Is this a new mind ready for molding?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's right. <charAction>Knocking on his head.</charAction> Let the molding begin.
                <charAction>The two guards turn away to leave.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Wait a minute. <charAction>The two guards turn back.</charAction> You're not from
            the Fire Nation. <charAction>Walks around Aang.</charAction> Clearly you're from the
            colonies.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, the colonies, of course. The Fire Nation colonies in the Earth Kingdom.
                <charAction>The two guards walk away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Your etiquette is terrible. In the homeland, we bow to our elders. <charAction>Walks
                in front of her desk.</charAction> Like so. <charAction>Bows.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sorry, ma'am.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bows to her. She taps his hands to correct him. A girl sitting in the front
                row shows the correct way to bow. Aang bows the proper way this time.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">And we don't wear head coverings indoors.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Um ... I have a scar. It's really embarrassing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Very well. What is your name? Or should we just call you "Mannerless Colony
            Slob"?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Chuckles.</charAction> Just "slob" is fine. Or, uh, Kuzon.
                <charAction>Camera pans out to Aang facing his classmates</charAction>.]</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The school bell rings and the students walk out of school. Momo peeks out
                of Aang's school uniform.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">[<charAction>Quietly.</charAction> We made it through the day Momo, and it was
            pretty fun.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="On Ji">
         <charAction>From behind Aang.</charAction> Don't let the headmaster catch you with
            that monkey. <charAction>The camera shifts to show her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turns around, trying to act innocent.</charAction> What monkey?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="On Ji">Don't worry, I'm not a tattletale. My name's On Ji. I like your headband, by the
            way.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hide">
         <charAction>Walks past Aang, slightly bumping him away and puts a hand around On
                Ji's shoulders.</charAction> On Ji, you don't have to baby-sit the new kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow. <charAction>Bows.</charAction> You must be one of those popular kids I've been
            hearing about.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hide">That's right. Now listen, friend. I know you're from the colonies, so I'll say this
            slowly. <charAction>Leans close to Aang, talking slowly.</charAction> On Ji is my
            girlfriend. <charAction>Pokes Aang's chest.</charAction> Don't forget it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo tries to get out of Aang's shirt and Aang pushes him back in. Aang
                pushes Momo back as Hide signifies to Aang that he is watching him and begins to
                leave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Waving goodbye to On Ji and Hide.</charAction> It was nice meeting
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">
         <charAction>Approaches Aang.</charAction> I don't believe it, he didn't beat you up.
            Not even a little.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess I'm just lucky.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">We were on our way to play hide and explode. You wanna come?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'd love to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shoji, his friends, and Aang all run off to play the game. </description>
      <description>Cut to Team Avatar's cave. Aang slides down the hill and enters the cave,
                covered in dirt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Concernedly.</charAction> Where have you been? We've been worried
            sick.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Undoing his headband.</charAction> I got invited to play with some kids
            after school.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Springs up to his feet in shock.</charAction> After what?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I enrolled in a Fire Nation school, and I'm going back tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>With an exasperated facial expression.</charAction> Enrolled in what?!
                <charAction>Falls backward in disbelief.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to an outside-view of the Capital City Prison. Cut to inside, where
                Zuko walks through the halls and the guard is alerted to his presence.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Readies his spear, with it pointed directly at Zuko.</charAction> You
            again? Stop where you are! <charAction>Zuko raises his head, looking at the
                guard.</charAction> Prince Zuko ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko grabs the guard by his collar and slams him against the
                wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm going in for a visit. You're going to stand guard here, and <description>no
                one</description> is going to know about this. <charAction>Zuko releases the guard,
                enters Iroh's cell, and approaches him.</charAction> Uncle, it's me.
                <charAction>Iroh, sitting on the floor, turns away from Zuko with a scowl on his
                face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts back to show the team inside the cave sitting around a
                fire.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Aang, I'm trying to be mature and not immediately shoot down your idea, but it
            sounds ... really terrible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Yeah, we got our outfits. What do you need to go to school for?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Every minute I'm in that classroom, I'm learning new things about the Fire Nation. I
            already have a picture of Fire Lord Ozai. <charAction>Holds up the picture.</charAction>
            And here's one that I made out of noodles! <charAction>Holds up his picture of
                Ozai.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Impressive, I admit, but I still think it's too dangerous.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I guess we'll never find out about the secret river then. It goes right to the Fire
            Lord's palace. We were supposed to learn about it in class tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Hmm, I am a fan of secret rivers ... fine, let's stay a few more days.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Flamey-O, Hotman! <charAction>Runs off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>To Katara.</charAction> Flamey-O?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara shrugs and murmurs as if to say "I don't know." Cut to the prison.
                Zuko is standing inside Iroh's cell.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You brought this on yourself, you know. We could have returned together. You could
            have been a hero! <charAction>Iroh shifts but does not look at him.</charAction> You
            have no right to judge me, Uncle. I did what I had to do in Ba Sing Se, and you're a
            fool for not joining me. <charAction>Iroh continues ignoring him.</charAction> You're
            not going to say anything? <charAction>Kicks up a small stool and destroys it with
                firebending.</charAction> You're a crazy old man! You're crazy! And if you weren't
            in jail, you'd be sleeping in a gutter! <charAction>Zuko leaves, slamming the door
                behind him as Iroh's head drops slightly and he closes his
            eyes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to show the classroom with the class assembled inside. Kwan
                walks in, and the class collectively rises to bow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Good morning class. Recite the Fire Nation oath. <charAction>Sits down at her
                desk.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The class turns to face a large painting of Ozai.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Class">
         <charAction>Turns to a large painting of Ozai at the back of the class.</charAction>
            My life I give to my country, with my hands I fight for Fire Lord Ozai and our
            forefathers before him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Glances around the room as the class recites the oath.</charAction> Fire
            Lord ... forefathers ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Class">With my mind I seek ways to better my country, and with my feet may our March of
            Civilization continue.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Firebenders ... Fire Lord ... wah, bah, blah, blah. <charAction>The class snickers
                at him as they sit down as the teacher looks on with a stern
                expression.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Since it's obviously hilarious to mock our national oath, we'll begin with a pop
            quiz on our great March of Civilization. <charAction>The class groans and picks up their
                pens.</charAction> Question one: What year did Fire Lord Sozin battle the Air Nation
            army? <charAction>Aang raises his hand.</charAction> Kuzon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Is that a trick question? The Air Nomads didn't have a formal military. Sozin
            defeated them by ambush. <charAction>The entire class stares at him,
                dumbfounded.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kwan">Well, I don't know how you could possibly know more than our national history book.
            Unless you were there a hundred years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'll just write down my best guess.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera fades to show the music teacher standing at a podium with the
                rest of the class before him, playing instruments. Aang plays loudly in very
                discordant notes, dancing while sitting.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Music teacher">Kuzon?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Stopping.</charAction> I know, I'm a terrible tsungi hornist.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Music teacher">No, child. That hullabaloo going on with your feet. Is that a nervous
            disorder?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I was just dancing. You do dances here in the homeland, right?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">Not really, no.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Music teacher">Dancing is not conducive to a proper learning environment. Young people must have
            rigid discipline and order.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">But what about expressing yourself?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Music teacher">I know sometimes we're so ruled by our love for our nation that we can't control our
            own bodies. <charAction>He puts his hand to his face at what he is saying before
                continuing on.</charAction> If you must, you may march in place quietly next time
            the urge hits you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He settles back down to the podium and the class resumes playing. Aang
                plays a few notes. marching in place, and stops, looking very dismayed at this. Cut
                to the school yard. Aang is walking through it, and all the other students stop and
                stare at him, murmuring among themselves.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="On Ji">
         <charAction>Waves at Aang.</charAction> Uh, hi, Kuzon. I really liked that crazy
            dance you were doing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks On Ji. I could show it to you again if you like. Ah! <charAction>He jumps as
                a blast of fire hits the ground at his feet.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hide">What'd you say, colony trash? You're gonna show her something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Nervously.</charAction> Just some dance movements.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hide">Nobody shows my On Ji anything, especially movements!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Hide attempts to strike Aang, but Aang easily steps out of the way. The
                other students gather around to watch. Hide continues trying to punch at Aang, but
                he continuously evades with ease, much to Hide's frustration. Aang gets behind
                Hide's back and moves to the side to match Hide's movements. Aang knocks back Hide
                by butting him. Hide tries to strike Aang two more times, but Aang slides behind
                Hide through his legs. Hide tries punching Aang two more times and falls down as
                Aang side steps and trips him. The Headmaster arrives, and Hide sniffles as he gets
                up to his knees. He is seen with tears in his eyes as the Headmaster
                talks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Picking fights on your second day? We need to have
            a conference to discuss your punishment. Bring your parents to my office after
            school.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Worriedly.</charAction> Parents? But-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">Don't be late!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Headmaster walks off and Hide smirks behind his back. Cut to a picture
                of Ozai, and the camera pans to show the Headmaster sitting at his
                office.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">Thank you for coming, Mr. and Mrs ... <charAction>Shot changes to show Sokka in
                diguise with a large fake beard, and Katara in disguise with a different hairstyle
                and appearing pregnant, with Aang sitting between them.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>With an exaggerated accent.</charAction> Fire. <charAction>Stroking his
                beard.</charAction> Wang Fire. <charAction>Pointing to Katara.</charAction> This is
            my wife, Sapphire.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Sapphire Fire. Nice to meet you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">Mr. and Mrs ... Fire, your son has been enrolled here for two days and he's already
            causing problems. He's argued with his history teacher, disrupted music class, and
            roughed up my star pupil.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">My goodness! That doesn't sound like our Kuzon.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">That's what any mother would say, Ma'am. Nonetheless, you're forewarned; if he acts
            up one more time, I'll have him sent to reform school- <charAction>Stands
                up.</charAction> by which I mean the coal mines. Are we clear?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Don't you worry, Mr. Headmaster. I'll straighten this boy out somethin' fierce!
                <charAction>Turns to Aang.</charAction> Young man, as soon as we get home you're
            gonna get the punishment of a lifetime! <charAction>Aang and Katara are visibly
                alarmed.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">That's what I like to hear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They turn to leave, and the scene cuts to show Zuko and Mai sitting on a
                cliff side together, watching the sunset.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">Orange is such an awful color.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Snickers.</charAction> You're so beautiful when you hate the
            world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">I don't hate you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I don't hate you too. <charAction>They kiss, but are interrupted by
                Azula.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Ahem. <charAction>They turn to look at her, clearly annoyed.</charAction> Zuko,
            could I have a word with you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Can't you see we're busy? <charAction>They kiss again.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Oh Mai, Ty Lee needs your help untangling her braid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Mai">
         <charAction>Stands up, smiling.</charAction> Sounds pretty serious.
                <charAction>Leaves, but throws an angry glance at Azula behind her
                back.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">So, I've heard you've been to visit your uncle fatso in the prison tower.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Standing angrily.</charAction> That guard told you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">No. You did. Just now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sits back down.</charAction> Okay, you caught me. What is it that you
            want, Azula?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">Actually, nothing. Believe it or not, I'm looking out for you. If people find out
            you've been to see Uncle, they'll think you're plotting with him. Just be careful,
            Dum-Dum.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to the cave where the Team is gathered. Momo attempts to pounce on
                birds, but he misses and they scatter.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Frontal shot, still acting as Wang Fire.</charAction> That settles it!
            No more school for you, young man! <charAction>Strokes his beard.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm not ready to leave yet. I'm having fun for once, just being a normal kid. You
            don't know what it's like, Sokka. You get to be normal all the time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">Ha ha! <charAction>Sokka glares at her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Listen guys, those kids at school are the future of the Fire Nation. If we want to
            change this place for the better, we need to show them a little taste of
            freedom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What could you possibly do for a country of depraved little fire monsters?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I'm gonna throw them, <charAction>Starts dancing.</charAction> a secret dance party!
                <charAction>Everybody stares at Aang.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>In Wang Fire voice.</charAction> Go to your room!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the cave with candles on the sides. Toph earthbends a stage. Aang
                puts on his headband.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Placing a candle.</charAction> I can't believe we're having a dance
            party. It seems so ... silly.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't think of it as a dance party, but as a cultural event celebrating the art of
            fancy footwork! <charAction>Dances.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot outside we see many pairs of feet as the guests arrive. Cut
                back to Toph.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Feeling their approach.</charAction> They're coming! Everyone stop
            bending.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Appa.</charAction> Sorry buddy, you should probably wait out back.
                <charAction>Appa grumbles as Aang herds him into the back.</charAction> I know, you
            got fancier feet than anybody. And six of 'em! <charAction>Turns around with his hands
                on his hips, grinning widely.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to several kids playing instruments on the earth platforms as the
                guests filter into the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jumps in front of the stage.</charAction> Ladies and gentlemen, the
            Flamey-O's! <charAction>To himself.</charAction> Yeah, this ought to get everybody
            moving. <charAction>He looks around at the kids standing shyly at the edge of the
                cave.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">Now what do we do?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">This is when you start dancing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male student #1">
         <charAction>Shyly hiding his face behind his collar.</charAction> I don't think my
            parents want me dancing in a cave ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male student #2">
         <charAction>Runs in front of the camera.</charAction> Yeah! What if someone finds
            out?! <charAction>Looks around nervously before exiting left.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Oh boy. Listen guys, dancing isn't something you think about. It's a form of
            self-expression that no one can ever take away from you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">Maybe it was different in the colonies, Kuzon, but we don't do that here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sure you do, you have for generations! It just so happens that I know several
            classic Fire Nation dances. A hundred years ago, this was known as the 'Phoenix Flight'.
                <charAction>The students ooh and aah as Aang runs low to the ground.</charAction>
            And, this was the 'Camelephant Strut'.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang jumps from side to side and does a rolls close to two nearby girls as
                they giggle. Aang finishes the dance with a back flip, landing on one foot. The boys
                stare in awe at Aang. Cut to Toph and Katara, who drink out of ice
                cups.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>To Katara.</charAction> Who knew Twinkle Toes could dance?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara smiles. Cut to Zuko back into Iroh's cell.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sliding food into Iroh's cell as Iroh keeps his back to
                him.</charAction> I brought you some komodo chicken. I know you don't care for it,
            but I figure it beats prison food. I admit it, I have everything I always wanted, but
            it's not as all how I thought it would be. The truth is, I need your advice.
                <charAction>Grips the bars.</charAction> I think the Avatar is still alive, I know
            he's out there, I'm losing my mind. <charAction>Iroh does not respond.
                Desperately.</charAction> Please, Uncle, I'm so confused I need your help.
                <charAction>Iroh still has nothing to say to him. Angrily.</charAction> Forget it,
            I'll solve it myself! Waste away in here for all I care! <charAction>He glances back
                before leaving, and a tear slides down Iroh's face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the cave, where Aang is still dancing, spinning through the
                air. Aang offers his hand to On Ji, who blushes and accepts. He pulls her to the
                middle of the room.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">And this is how they do it in the ballrooms of Ba Sing Se. <charAction>He starts
                tapping his feet from side to side and On Ji joins him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Watching as Aang dances with On Ji.</charAction> Wow, they look pretty
            good together.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Barely hiding her envy as she looks away.</charAction> Eh, if that's
            what you like ... <charAction>She looks back surreptitiously.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah, that's it! That's the sound of happy feet. <charAction>The rest of the kids
                start dancing with them.</charAction> All right, go with that! Everybody
            freestyle!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>One student dances crazily. Another student, standing amid a group of
                non-dancers, starts moving his arms and Shoji sways his head with the rhythm. Aang
                runs over to Katara and holds his hand out to her, inviting her to
                dance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looks away nervously.</charAction> I don't know, Aang.
                <charAction>Starts nervously pulling her hair.</charAction> These shoes aren't
            really right for dancing, and I-I'm not sure that I know how to-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> Take my hand.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Smiles back.</charAction> Okay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He pulls her out into the room and whispers into her ear, and everybody
                stops to stare at them as the two extend their arms to each other and begin circling
                each other and performing dance moves.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Looking around.</charAction> Aang, everyone's watching.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Don't worry about them. <charAction>Smiles.</charAction> It's just you and me right
            now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara blushes as they began to move around each other in an elaborate
                dance. The dance incorporates different moves including kicks and flips. At one
                point they come close together as if they are about to kiss, both just smile and
                continue on. Aang finishes the dance by catching Katara as she leans over his arm.
                Cut to a close-up view of them smiling at each other as they pant and sweat. The
                camera cuts to show the Headmaster and several soldiers coming to the
                cave.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">It is a dancing party. <charAction>Turns to Hide standing behind him.</charAction>
            You did the right thing by telling me, Hide.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hide">
         <charAction>Bows.</charAction> Anytime, Headmaster sir.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera cuts back to the dancing kids.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male student #1">
         <charAction>Waving a hand in the air.</charAction> This is incredible! It's like my
            inhibitions just disappear! <charAction>He sees the Headmaster come into the cave, and
                immediately stops dancing and attempts to shrink into his robes.</charAction> Okay,
            they're back again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang continues to dance past as everyone else stops until the Headmaster
                talks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">
         <charAction>Pointing.</charAction> He's the one we want! The boy with the
            headband!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh-oh. <charAction>Aang starts running away through the crowd as the soldiers chase
                him. One soldier sees a boy with a headband, and grabs him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male soldier #1">Gotcha! <charAction>The boy turns, but the guard is confused upon seeing a different
                boy there.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shoji">Looking for me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Headmaster and Hide.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">That's not the one. He's here somewhere. Don't let him leave the cave!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Headmaster points toward the back of the cave, Hide imitating him. Cut
                to two soldiers who continue searching. One soldier sees another kid with a
                headband, and turns her around. He is again confused upon seeing her
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="On Ji">Yes?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Another soldier sees two more children standing next to each other with
                headbands and turns them both around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male student #2">
         <charAction>Picking his nose.</charAction> Hi there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Male student #1">How're we doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Headmaster sees who he thinks is Aang in the crowd, and goes after him
                himself. Shoving people out of the way, he scoops up the boy in the
                crowd.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Female student #1">Looking for someone?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Headmaster looks around in horror as he sees all the children are now
                wearing headbands.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="On Ji">Who are you looking for?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Female Student #1">Do you need something?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Student">Over here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The students completely surround the soldiers and the Headmaster as Aang
                escapes through the back of the cave. Shoji winks at Aang, who bows in return. Aang
                leaves and earthbends the back of the cave shut, at which Shoji drops his jaw in
                astonishment.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the Headmaster surrounded by guards where two of them have started
                dancing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Headmaster">
         <charAction>To one of the soldiers, who starts dancing.</charAction> Stop that!
                <charAction>To another soldier, who is tapping her foot.</charAction> Stop
            that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to outside the cave where the team flies away on Appa.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're safe Sokka, you can take off the mustache, now.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>He is seen with his Wang Fire mustache on and begins stroking
                it.</charAction> Oh, no, I can't. It's permanently glued to my skin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> Way to go, dancy pants. I think you really did
            help those kids, you taught them to be free.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't know, it was just a dance party, that's all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Well, that was some dance party Aang. <charAction>She kisses him on the cheek, and
                Aang blushes.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Clapping lightly.</charAction> Flamey-O, sir ... Flamey-O.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Zuko walking alone in a dark alley. He lowers his hood as a huge man
                with a metal leg approaches him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You're sure you weren't followed? I've heard about you. They say you're good at what
            you do, and even better at keeping secrets. The Avatar is alive. I want you to find him,
            and end him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The man's face is shown. The camera zooms in on a strange third eye
                tattooed on his forehead. Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
