<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Blue Spirit</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The scene opens on a messenger hawk flying toward an imposing Fire Nation
                fortress as the scene changes to its tower. The camera pans across the tri-level
                fortress and it's tall balconies before settling on a courtyard where a group of
                archers stand at the ready. Switch to a closer shot of a single archer. The archer
                draws his bow and releases three times in succession, sharply and accurately. Switch
                to a shot of the bowman's target. The first arrow strikes dead center, the second
                arrow splits the first arrow in half, and the third arrow splits the second arrow in
                half and completely impales the target. Switch back to a shot of the archers as they
                draw their bows. The camera pans up to a balcony where Colonel Shinu is arguing
                heatedly with Commander Zhao.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">
         <charAction>In response to Zhao; somewhat angrily.</charAction> Absolutely not! The
            Yuyan Archers stay here. Your request is denied, Commander
            Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Colonel Shinu, please reconsider ... Their precision is legendary. The Yuyan can pin
            a fly to a tree from one hundred yards away ... without killing it.
                <charAction>Annoyed.</charAction> You're wasting their talents using them as mere
            security guards.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">I can do whatever I want with their talents, they're my
            archers, and what I say goes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao turns to face the colonel, frustrated and angry.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">But my search for the Avatar is-</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">
         <charAction>Cutting Zhao off mid-sentence while getting close to him and scoffing
                angrily.</charAction> Is nothing but a vanity project! We're fighting a
                real war here, and I need every man I've got,
            commander.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">But-!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">
         <charAction>Furiously.</charAction> That's final! I don't wanna hear another word
            about it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao fumes. In the background, the cry of a messenger hawk is heard. Camera
                shifts to an above view and follows a messenger hawk as it reaches Colonel Shinu.
                Shinu opens the container on the hawk's back and reads the message inside with a
                puzzled expression.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Intrigued.</charAction> News from Fire Lord Ozai?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shinu hands Zhao the message with irritation. Zhao takes the message,
                rudely brushing past the Colonel as he reads the news. Zhao smiles
                smugly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Pleased.</charAction> It appears I've been promoted to Admiral. My
            request ... is now an order.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Colonel Shinu bows respectfully, and leaves.</description>
      <description>Shot of the Yuyan archers practicing. Zhao surveys their work with a glad
                expression playing on his face. The camera pans up to the roof of the tower where a
                mysterious figure in a blue mask is perched, seemingly for the entire conversation.
                The masked man disappears into the shadows. Switch to a shot of a vast mountain
                range. The landscape is blanketed with a ruined city.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to a shot inside one of the ruined buildings where Team
                Avatar has set up camp. Sokka is lying against Appa, huddled in his sleeping bag. He
                is coughing, and there is sweat on his face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Pressing a wet rag onto Sokka's forehead.</charAction> This should bring
            your fever down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You know what I love about Appa the most? His sense of humor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That's nice. I'll tell him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa growls.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Laughs.</charAction> Classic Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">How's Sokka doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Not so good, being out in that storm really did a number on him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka starts sniffing pitifully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I couldn't find any ginger root for the tea. But I found a map. There's an herbalist
            institute on top of that mountain. We could probably find a cure for Sokka
            there.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, he's in no condition for travel. Sokka just needs more rest. I'm sure he'll be
            better by tomorrow. <charAction>Starts coughing.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Not you too!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Relax, it was just a little cough. I'm fi- <charAction>She coughs again, this time
                with greater force, and lightly groans after.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shielding his face.</charAction> That's how Sokka started yesterday. Now
            look at him! He thinks he's an earthbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Delirious.</charAction> Take that, you rock! <charAction>He flails his
                arms as if he is hitting something.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">A few more hours and you'll be talking nonsense, too. I'm going to go find some
            medicine! <charAction>He grabs his glider and begins to head out just as a flash of
                lightning strikes.</charAction> Uh, maybe it's safer if I go on foot. <charAction>To
                Appa and Momo.</charAction> Keep an eye on them guys. <charAction>Appa groans while
                Momo chitters.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Ha, ha! You guys are killing me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang jumps, and uses airbending to help him run faster. The scene switches
                to Prince Zuko's ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Captain">We haven't been able to pick up the Avatar's trail since the storm, but if we
            continue heading northeast ... <charAction>A larger Fire Nation ship pulls up next to
                theirs.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What do they want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Perhaps, a sporting game of Pai Sho!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A soldier from the other ship walks in.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> The hunt for the Avatar has been given prime
            importance. All information regarding the Avatar must be
            reported directly to Admiral Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Zhao has been promoted? Well, good for him! <charAction>As Iroh makes a move in his
                Pai Sho game, another player slaps his hand against his own forehead as if he
                lost.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Looking down.</charAction> I've got nothing to report to Admiral Zhao.
            Now get off my ship and let us pass.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">Admiral Zhao is not allowing ships in or out of this area.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Off my ship!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">
         <charAction>Iroh wins his game.</charAction> Excellent! I take the pot!
                <charAction>A crew member punches himself.</charAction> But you're all improving!
            I'm certain you will win if we play again.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to a hidden outpost. One soldier is looking at Aang's
                wanted poster while the other is on watch duty.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scout #1">
         <charAction>Reading Aang's wanted poster out loud.</charAction> Says here that the
            Avatar can create tornadoes and run faster than the wind. Pretty amazing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scout #2">Ah, that's just a bunch of Fire Lord propaganda! There's no way that's
            true!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scout returns to his task and sees a cloud moving swiftly along the
                ground which turns out to be Aang. Aang runs by wrecking the outpost on accident.
                One of the scouts blows a horn signaling that Aang has been spotted.</description>
      <description>The scene changes back to the gang's camp.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> Katara, please, water.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Also weak.</charAction> Listen carefully, Momo. <charAction>Holds up a
                water skin.</charAction> I need you to take this to the river, and fill it with
            water. <charAction>She is shown through Momo's eyes, speaking gibberish.</charAction>
            Got it? <charAction>Momo takes the skin and flies off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang runs up the stairs and enters the green house.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Speaking fast.</charAction> Hello, I'm sorry to barge in like this, but
            I need some medicine for my friends, they have fevers and
            they were coughing- <charAction>Gets cut off by the herbalist.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Settle down, young man. Your friends are going to be fine. I've been up here for
            over forty years you know, used to be others, but they all left years ago.
                <charAction>She pets Miyuki who begins to purr.</charAction> Now it's just me and
            Miyuki.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's nice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Wounded Earth Kingdom troops still come by now and again, brave boys, and thanks to
            my remedies they always leave in better shape they when they arrive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's nice. Are you almost done?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Hold on, I just need to add one last ingredient. <charAction>Walking among the
                shrubbery, looking around and muttering to herself.</charAction> Oh, sandalwood ...
            oh, er, uh, that won't do, banana leaf? Ah, nope, uh, ginger root, uh uh, oh where is
            that pesky little plant?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks exasperated in the background and face-palms himself. Cut to
                Zuko's ship steaming by the shore, the sunset in its last stages in the background.
                Cut to Zuko practicing firebending on the foredeck in the background. Iroh's arm
                comes into the frame.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Is everything okay? It's been almost an hour and you haven't given the men an
            order.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I don't care what they do.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Don't give up hope yet. You can still find the Avatar before Zhao.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Turning back, desperation and fear on his face.</charAction> How, Uncle?
            With Zhao's resources, it's just a matter of time before he captures the Avatar.
                <charAction>Turns back out to sea and whispers.</charAction> My honor, my throne, my
            country, I'm about to lose them all.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to an exterior shot of the herbalist institute, followed by a shot
                of the old woman in front of some bushes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Ah! Plum blossom! <charAction>She plucks a flower from the
            tree.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>He lifts up his head off the table.</charAction> Finally!
                <charAction>Close-up of the mixing bowl as the herbalist drops the flower into the
                mixture, and Aang grabs for the bowl.</charAction> Thanks for all your
            help!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene moves back, just as Aang wants to yank the bowl out of the
                herbalist's hands, and she slaps his hands roughly away with her
                spoon.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Hands off!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Ow!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">
         <charAction>Close-up, holding her spoon at the ready for a new attack.</charAction>
            What do you think you're doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Rubs his hand, flinching.</charAction> Taking the cure to my
            friends.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">
         <charAction>Lowers her spoon; laughs.</charAction> This isn't a cure! It's Miyuki's
            dinner. Plum blossom is her favorite.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">What about my friends?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Well, all they need are some frozen wood frogs. There's plenty down in the valley
            swamp.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Confused.</charAction> What am I supposed to do with frozen
            frogs?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">Why, suck on them of course!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shocked and disgusted; his eye twitches.</charAction> Suck on
            them?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">The frog skin excretes a substance that will cure your friends. Be sure to get
            plenty because once those little critters thaw out, they're useless!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You're insane, aren't you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Herbalist">
         <charAction>Crazily.</charAction> That's right! Well, don't stand there all day!
            Go!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang runs out and the storm gets worse; he wipes his face from the
                excessive rainfall. Several arrows comes out of nowhere and pins Aang's pants to the
                ground; he airbends a shield sending some off them away. Aang removes
                one.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Uh ... I think you dropped this ... <charAction>Screams as he sees the Yuyan Archers
                taking aim at him. Panicking, he frees himself from the arrow that had pinned his
                foot to the ground and runs. He falls off a cliff into a swamp and finds the frozen
                frogs.</charAction> A frog!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sticks the frog in his shirt and manages to get four more before
                getting one of his sleeves pinned to a rock. Aang waterbends an ice wall in front of
                himself. An arrow strikes the wall before two more land in the same spot and slice
                the arrows that came before it. The ice cracks and another set of arrows pin his
                other sleeve before a net is launched at him.</description>
      <description>The scene cuts to show Aang bounded at his legs and arms with chains,
                barely able to move. He looks angry and struggles against the chains.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">So this is the great Avatar. Master of all the elements. I don't know how you've
            managed to elude the Fire Nation for a hundred years, but your little game of hide and
            seek is over.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Angry.</charAction> I've never hidden from you! Untie me and I'll fight
            you right now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Uhh, no. Tell me, how does it feel to be the only airbender left? Do you miss your
            people? <charAction>Aang looks down sadly.</charAction> Don't worry, you won't be killed
            like they were. <charAction>Aang looks angry again.</charAction> See, if you die you
            will just be reborn and the Fire Nation would have to start searching all over again. So
            I'll keep you alive, but just barely. <charAction>Aang takes a deep breath and blows at
                gale force at Zhao, who falls over.</charAction> Blow all the wind you want, but
            your situation is futile. There is no escaping this fortress, and no one is coming to
            rescue you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zhao exits the room with the door slamming behind him. Back to Katara and
                Sokka snuggled up in their sleeping bags which lie between Appa's feet. Sokka has a
                coughing fit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> Water ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Weakly.</charAction> Momo should be back any minute.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo jumps into the shot, chittering happily. He jumps up close to Katara.
                He drops a dead mouse on to her chest. She looks at it in disgust.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Weakly; in disgust.</charAction> Ugh! No, Momo, water. Wa-ter!
                <charAction>Momo's ear go straight up. He jumps off her and scampers.</charAction>
            Aang, what in the world is taking you so long?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to an overhead shot of Aang still bound between the
                pillars, still trying to get out of the chains. The scene changes again, to several
                exterior night shots of the fortress, culminating in a long shot of the Blue Spirit.
                The camera zooms in three step changes to a close-up of the Blue Spirit, who moves
                left. Cut to a view of the road leading to the fortress where a wagon is making its
                way toward the gate. Cut to a view of the undercarriage of the wagon as it passes.
                The Blue Spirit is holding on to the underside of the wagon. The wagon reaches the
                gate.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">All clear.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A gate guard looks at the wagon and walks around it. When the guard checks
                the undercarriage, the Blue Spirit is gone. The guard gets back up. Cut to a wider
                shot of the wagon and the guards around it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">All clear. Go on in.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Shift to a view from inside the wagon where the Blue Spirit has hidden
                himself; cut to an overhead shot of the wagon as it enters the first of the
                fortress' three gates. The shot pans up to rest on the massive central tower where
                Aang is held prisoner. Cut to a view of the first courtyard where the boxes in the
                wagon have been unloaded. The Blue Spirit runs from them and ducks into the shadows.
                Cut to a shot of an ornate balcony with bonfire pots on either side. The balcony is
                festooned with gold and red spades. Admiral Zhao appears flanked by attendants.
                During his speech the view cuts to show the innermost courtyard full of Fire Nation
                soldiers standing at attention.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">We are the sons and daughters of fire, the superior element! Until today only one
            thing stood our path to victory, the Avatar. I am here to tell you that he is now my
            prisoner! <charAction>The crowd cheers.</charAction> This is the year Sozin's Comet
            returns to grant us its power! <charAction>The crowd cheers.</charAction> This is the
            year the Fire Nation breaks through the walls of Ba Sing Se and burns the city to the
            ground!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As Zhao speaks, various shots are seen of the Blue Spirit steadily and
                stealthily infiltrating the fortress. Cut back to Aang, still struggling fruitlessly
                against his chains. He finally stops, breathing heavily. It's useless. Suddenly,
                frogs start leaping out of his shirt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To the frogs.</charAction> What? No! Don't leave, frogs! My friends are
            sick and they need you! Please go back to being frozen!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He begins to struggle again as the frogs hop away toward the door,
                croaking. Cut to the four guards standing outside the chamber. They begin to look
                confused when they hear croaking. They look down to see the frogs coming from
                underneath the door. Suddenly they look up as a Fire Nation soldier's helmet comes
                bouncing down the corridor toward them. One of the guards walks up the corridor and
                turns right at the first junction, disappearing from view. A gout of flame erupts
                from the cross hallway as well as the sound of a brief scuffle. Two more guards go
                up to the junction and turn right, firebending stances at the ready. Cut to a view
                looking down the cross hallway. The first guard who went is hanging from the
                ceiling, tied up. Shift to the hanging soldier and pan up to reveal the Blue Spirit
                on the ceiling above the two new combatants. He drops down and melee begins, but it
                is over quickly. Cut back to the last guards, where they now see the Blue Spirit at
                the junction.</description>
      <description>Cut to a view of the door to Aang's chamber. The lone guard grabs the alarm
                horn next to him, but a knife knocks it out of his hand. The guard lets loose a gout
                of flame at the Blue Spirit as he runs down the hall toward the door, but the
                intruder extinguishes the blast with a bucket of water, and proceeds to sweeps the
                guard's feet out from under him with the empty bucket. Cut to Aang still struggling
                inside the chamber. He stops and looks at the noises of violence coming from through
                door. These stop abruptly and are replaced by the sound of the lock turning in the
                door. The door opens and the Blue Spirit enters. He brandishes two curved swords and
                runs forward to Aang, who screams in fear. The Blue Spirit approaches and two sword
                cuts are heard. Aang pulls his arms back in surprise – the Blue Spirit has freed
                him. He looks at his liberator in wonder. The Blue Spirit comes closer and cuts his
                remaining bonds, turns and walks back toward the door.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Who are you? What's going on? Are you here to rescue me? <charAction>The Blue Spirit
                opens the door and motions for him to follow.</charAction> I'll take that as a
            "yes."</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang follows him out past the gagged and tied guard at the door to his
                chamber. He hears frog noises and turns to see his half-frozen frogs crawling on the
                floor.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">My frogs! Come back! And stop thawing out! <charAction>The Blue Spirit comes back,
                picks him up by the collar and carries him out.</charAction> Wait! My friends need
            to suck on those frogs!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Meanwhile, back at the run-down temple, Momo has succeeded in piling up
                mountains of junk around Katara, but no water. Momo returns again with a
                crown.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>With a weak, sickly voice.</charAction> How many times do I have to tell
            you, Momo? We need water, wa-ter. Oh forget it. Aang, please, hurry.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Delirious.</charAction> Who's this "Aang" kid you keep talking about,
            Your Highness? <charAction>Katara gets an annoyed look on her
            face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene shifts back to a few exterior shots of the fortress before switching
                to Aang and the Blue Spirit walking silently in the sewer system underneath the
                fortress. Soldiers walk back and forth above them. They hope out of a grate and into
                one of the courtyards. Cut to Zhao walking in one of the torch-lit corridors of the
                fortress, followed by a scribe.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">I want a full transcription of my speech sent to the Fire Lord, along with glowing
            testimonials from all of the ranking officers present, and –</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He cuts himself off as he hears moans. Cut to Zhao's right, where the
                soldiers that the Blue Spirit tied still lie. Zhao, upset, slams open the door to
                Aang's prison cell. It is empty, except for a frog which croaks at him from the
                floor. Zhao turns in anger and leaves, the scribe in tow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Scribe">Sir, should I hold off sending that speech to the Fire Lord?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut back to the two would-be escapees who are now scaling a rope on the
                innermost wall of the fortress. They are spotted and the view zooms out as one of
                the guards shouts.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">There, on the wall!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A soldier appears at the top of the wall they are climbing. He cuts the
                rope and the pair fall down the wall, Aang screaming. Cut to side-view where Aang
                airbends them to a soft landing. When the dust clears, the Blue Spirit unsheathes
                his swords and they run. Cut to Zhao on the ornate balcony.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Shouting.</charAction> The Avatar has escaped! Close all the gates
            immediately! <charAction>Cut to the escapees running, Aang passes the Blue
                Spirit.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Stay close to me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The third gate is closing in front of them, as are the two beyond it, and
                it is blocked by many soldiers. Aang airbends a blast of air that blows them out of
                the way. Aang makes for the gate, but the Blue Spirit gets involved in melee and has
                to stop and fend them off. Aang turns to see the Blue Spirit in trouble. He grabs a
                spear from a guard near him, airbends him out of the way, spins it around and breaks
                the head off the spear on the ground and launches back into battle to save his new
                friend. The gate closes behind him. The Blue Spirit is surrounded, but Aang airbends
                them all out of the way. With a mighty effort, he catapults the Blue Spirit to the
                top of the third wall.</description>
      <description>He is instantly surrounded, but Aang appears using the stick as a
                helicopter blade. He plucks the Blue Spirit off the wall and heads into the next
                courtyard. Cut to a close-up of Aang struggling to keep them aloft. The Blue Spirit
                uses his swords to knock the spears sent up at them by the guards. They barely next
                the top of the next wall as they crash unceremoniously onto the battlement. Aang's
                stick goes spinning away as guards instantly rush them. Aang runs for his stick, but
                a guard stops him, taking several swings at Aang with his sword. The Blue Spirit
                throws the guard over the wall. Aang airbends the other guards off the
                wall.</description>
      <description>Cut to a wide shot of the second wall, where more soldiers are scaling
                ladders. Aang and the Blue Spirit knock off the soldiers as they reach the top. With
                two mighty blasts, Aang depopulates the two scaling ladders nearest him as the Blue
                Spirit knocks the one final soldier off his. Aang brings over his two scaling
                ladders and steps onto the one the Blue Spirit has just emptied. He hands one ladder
                to the Blue Spirit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Take this. Jump on my back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Blue Spirit complies and Aang begins to use the ladders as massive
                stilts, shedding one each time a step is taken. Cut to a wide shot of the second
                courtyard, where dawn is approaching in the background. The first ladder shed still
                has some Fire Nation soldiers on it, but it falls into the dust.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Give me the next one!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Blue Spirit again complies. Cut to the bottom of their final stilt
                where a Fire Nation soldier sends a gout of flame up the ladder. It is too late
                though, as Aang and the masked man jump from the last stilt and just manage to grab
                the edge of the final wall. They are unable to hold on, however, and fall to the
                ground. The Blue Spirit draws his swords. Four firebenders unleash their flame on
                them, but Aang puts the masked man behind him and airbends the flames
                away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Hold your fire! The Avatar must be captured alive!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Blue Spirit instantly comes up behind Aang and crosses his swords in
                front of Aang's throat, surprising him. Cut to a view behind the escapees that pans
                right slowly, accenting the stand-off, before cutting to the implacable blue mask of
                the intruder. Cut back to a close of Zhao's eyes.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">
         <charAction>Through gritted teeth.</charAction> Open the gate.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">Admiral, what are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Let them out, now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The gate is opened and the Blue Spirit backs out with his captives, swords
                still at his throat. Cut back to Zhao, the officer questioning him still visible
                over his left shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Shinu">How could you let them go?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">A situation like this requires ... precision.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Blue Spirit continues backing away from the fortress. Zhao now looks on
                from the top of the main gate. Cut to an arrow being strung on a bow by an unseen
                soldier; cut back to Zhao, who looks to his right as he speaks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Do you have a clear shot?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a Yuyan Archer, who is silent, but aims.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Knock out the thief. I'll deliver him to the Fire Lord along with the
            Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The archer releases his arrow, which the camera follows across the field to
                its impact point on the Blue Spirits masks. Cut to a side-view of Aang and the Blue
                Spirit as the masked man collapses backward in slow motion. Aang turns in horror,
                his eyes glazed. He recovers, turns around and airbends up a huge cloud of dust
                around him and the Blue Spirit.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zhao">Quick! Recover the Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the main gate opening and a crowd Fire Nation soldiers emerging and
                running toward the dust cloud. Cut to inside the dust cloud, where Aang removes the
                Blue Spirit's mask to reveal Zuko. Aang starts back in horror and falls backward on
                the ground. He jumps up and runs away, but turns to look at Zuko, his eyes huge and
                full of compassion. He sees the Fire Nation soldiers getting close through the
                smoke. Still, he hesitates. When the dust clears, however, the soldiers find
                nothing. Cut back to Zhao, looking insanely angry. A frog hops up onto the railing,
                croaks, and hops off. Fade to white, followed by a blurry shot of a forest looking
                straight up into the canopy overhead. It is morning. The screen pans down to Aang
                sitting on a nearby root, the view is still blurry. He looks forlorn. Cut to Zuko,
                whose view we were clearly just seeing. He looks a bit dazed still.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> You know what the worst part of being born over a
            hundred years ago is? I miss all the friends I used to hang out with. Before the war
            started, I used to always visit my friend Kuzon. The two of us, we'd get in and out of
            so much trouble together. He was one of the best friends I ever had, and he was from the
            Fire Nation, just like you. If we knew each other back then, do you think we could have
            been friends, too?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a wide shot of Zuko lying on the ground, Aang next to him, perched a
                large tree root. After a pause, Zuko lets loose a huge fireball at him, but Aang
                dodges and flies away on a current of air. Zuko watches him hop away from tree
                branch to tree branch and out sight. Cut to Zuko as the camera slowly zooms
                backward. Zuko raises his eye in consideration. Fade to a close-up of the swamp,
                where Aang is collecting frozen frogs once again. Cut back to a wide shot of Zuko's
                ship reeling in the cutter vessel back into the mother ship. Shift to Zuko, sullen,
                walking past his Uncle on the main deck.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Iroh">Where have you been, Prince Zuko? You missed music night! Lieutenant Jee sang a
            stirring love song.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'm going to bed. No disturbances.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Iroh rubs his head and begins to blow his horn again. Fade back to the
                ruins. Aang returns, downcast. He puts frogs in his friends' mouths.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Suck on these. They'll make you feel better.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang collapse backward onto Appa's tail with a sigh. Cut to Sokka with a
                frog in his mouth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>With his mouth full; still spouting out nonsense.</charAction> Aang, how
            was your trip? Did you make any new friends?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, I don't think I did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang rolls over. Fade to Prince Zuko lying awake in his own chamber, lost
                in thought. He looks at the Fire Nation symbol hanging on his wall, and rolls over
                himself. Cut back to the ruins and to Sokka, a happy expression on his face, still
                sucking on the frog in his mouth.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Mmmm! This is tasty! Mmm!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>It thaws out and begins moving around and croaking. Sokka realizes what it
                is and spits it out in disgust. Cut to Katara where her frog has also thawed. She
                cries out and it hops out of her mouth. Both Katara and Sokka begin spitting and
                coughing, Sokka rubs his tongue in panic against Appa's fur.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fades to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
