<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The King of Omashu</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens with a close-up of a snow-covered patch of grass. The
                scene pans up to reveal Aang, with Katara, Sokka, Appa and Momo in his trail,
                reaching the top of a hill. Aang spreads his arms wide while the camera shifts to a
                back view of the group to reveal their view.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The Earth Kingdom city of Omashu! <charAction>Camera pans up from the group to show
                the entire pyramid structured city of Omashu. Close-up of an excited
                Aang.</charAction> I used to always come here to visit my friend Bumi.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Close-up; impressed.</charAction> Wow. We don't have buildings like this
            in the South Pole!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Close-up; overwhelmed.</charAction> They have buildings here that don't
            melt!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Back view of the siblings, with Aang and the city visible between them.
                Excitedly.</charAction> Well let's go, slow pokes. The real fun's inside the
            city!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang leaps off the top of the hill with his airbending. The camera position
                shifts to show that he had landed a few meters below and in the snow and is starting
                to slide down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Stretching her arm out to him, halting Aang with her cry.</charAction>
            Wait, Aang! It could be dangerous if people find out you're the Avatar.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Somewhat seriously.</charAction> You need a disguise.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Shot of Aang looking up.</charAction> So what am I supposed to do?
                <charAction>In a slightly sarcastic tone.</charAction> Grow a mustache?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a shot of Aang wiggling his nose under which is now a patch of
                Appa's fur, serving as a mustache. The camera zooms back to show that Aang is also
                wearing a tall wig made of the same material.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Scratching underneath the wig.</charAction> Ugh. This is so itchy.
                <charAction>Cut to a broader shot; Aang is standing beside Appa. To
                Appa.</charAction> How do you live in this stuff?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa slowly turns his head toward Aang and snorts at him as if he was
                scoffing. Cut to a shot of Sokka sitting on a rock with Katara standing beside him,
                arms crossed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Great! Now you look just like my grandfather.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Glancing at Sokka.</charAction> Technically, Aang is 112 years
            old.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang nimbly kicks up his staff and spins it rapidly around before placing
                it upright on the ground to be used as a walking stick. He hunches his back and
                leans heavily on his staff like an old person.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In an old man's voice.</charAction> Now let's get to skippin', young
            whipper-snappers. The big city awaits!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang shuffles out of the frame, while Sokka and Katara questioningly look
                at each other. The scene fades to shot of the chasm, panning upward to show Aang,
                Katara, and Sokka walking down the long path to Omashu. The shot changes to an
                overview of the path while the camera pans down, before shifting to an upward
                panning shot of the back of the trio to end with a center shot of the
                city.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You guys are going to love Omashu. <charAction>Cut to front view shot as the three
                friends walk toward the gate. Aang looks over his shoulder at Sokka.</charAction>
            The people here are the friendliest in the world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang's eyes widen in surprise as he hears the harsh voice of the sentry.
                The trio stops walking.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gate guard">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Rotten cabbages?! <charAction>Far off shot of
                three guards and a cabbage merchant with his cart in front of the closed gate of
                Omashu; harshly.</charAction> What kind of slum do you think this is?!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Closer shot of the talking guard as he squishes the cabbage he is holding
                and knocks another two cabbages out of the merchant's hands. He proceeds by
                earthbending a rock under the cart, catapulting it high in the air, making it tumble
                down the chasm with all the cabbages.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">
         <charAction>Leaning over the rim of the path. Dramatically waving his arms in
                despair.</charAction> No! My cabbages!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera shifts to the left, where Katara, Sokka, and Aang appear and
                look over the rim, their mouths open in shock, as a loud crash is
                heard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up, broadly smiling; somewhat nervously.</charAction> Just keep
            smiling!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>While Aang walks over to the guards, Katara and Sokka give each other an
                uneasy look. Katara flashes her teeth in an awkward way and chuckles uncomfortably,
                while Sokka merely raises a doubtful eyebrow. Side-view as Aang approaches the
                sentries at the gate. The earthbender steps to the front and raises a boulder out of
                the ground before Aang and levitates it above his head.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gate guard">
         <charAction>Aggressively with a glare.</charAction> State your business!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang quickly runs from underneath the boulder and toward the guard; he
                halts right in front of the surprised man.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In old man voice, poking the chest of the sentry.</charAction> My
            business is my business, young man, <charAction>Shot of the boulder crashing down due to
                the guards lack of concentration beside Katara and Sokka as they jump up slightly
                from the impact; close-up of Aang pointing a finger at the camera.</charAction> and
            none of yours! <charAction>Close-up of the guard, taken aback by the threateningly
                pointing finger just centimeters from his face.</charAction> I've got half a mind to
                <charAction>Close-up of Sokka, eyes and mouth wide open in shock at Aang's audacity
                to talk to the sentry like that, and Katara, shaking her head with eyes wide open in
                shock.</charAction> bend you over my knee and paddle your backside!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gate guard">
         <charAction>In a calmer voice.</charAction> Settle down, old timer! Just tell me who
            you are.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sokka and Katara are still in shock in the background; in old man
                voice.</charAction> Name's Bonzu Pippinpaddleopsicopolis, the Third,
                <charAction>Sokka raises a questioningly eyebrow while Katara walks up, smiling
                friendly.</charAction> and these are my grandkids.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Waving.</charAction> Hi. June Pippinpaddleopsicopolis. Nice to meet
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gate guard">
         <charAction>Pensively rubbing his beard, while eying the two children before him.
                Pointing at Katara.</charAction> You seem like a responsible young lady. See that
            your grandfather stays out of trouble. Enjoy Omashu!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guard steps aside and motions at the city's entrance.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Lightheartedly.</charAction> We will!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to side-view as Katara, Aang, and Sokka start walking toward the
                gate. Sokka passes the guard with an uneasy look on his face, never letting the
                guard out of sight.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Gate guard">
         <charAction>Eying Sokka as he passes.</charAction> Wait a minute!
                <charAction>Close-up of Sokka as he halts, eyes widening in fear as the guard grasps
                his shoulder. Aang and Katara turn around to see what the holdup is. The guard turns
                Sokka around; sternly.</charAction> You're a strong young boy! Show some respect for
            the elderly and carry your grandfather's bag!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka's eyes change from fright to disbelief and annoyance while Aang
                removes his shoulder bag.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In old man voice.</charAction> Good idea!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang throws the bag at Sokka; the bag bounces off his head to drop into his
                arms. Sokka shoots Aang an annoyed glare over his shoulder. Overview shot as the
                trio resumes walking to the gate once more. Back shot view of the trio standing
                before a big Earth Kingdom emblem on the wall before them. The giant earthen wall
                splits open in the middle of the emblem, opening up to let any passengers through.
                The guard opens up the gate walls. As the first wall slides open, a second and third
                are bent aside as well. Upward panning shot of Katara and Sokka watching in awe at
                the spectacle while Aang is smiling behind them. They walk through as the walls
                already start to move again to close right after them. A back view of Aang as he
                walks through the opened gates, when suddenly Momo's ears pop out of his wig.
                Close-up of the guard that granted them entrance, as his eyes widen in surprise. He
                tries to keep an eye on Aang as long as he can, but the airbender is obscured from
                his view by the closing gates.</description>
      <description>Switch to an overview shot from inside the city as the trio pulls up at the
                parapet at the rim of a nearby chasm. Closer shot of Sokka and Katara, excitedly
                taking in the city spread out before them as Aang pulls up next to them, Momo's head
                now entirely popped out of his wig. He leans on the rim as well and joins the
                siblings in mouth open gazing at Omashu's scenery. Cut to a shot of the streets
                filled with people. The camera pans up, revealing an intricate system of chutes. The
                aqueduct like structures are built over and beside the houses with typical green
                roofs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Back to regular voice; voice-over.</charAction> This is the Omashu
            delivery system. <charAction>Camera shows the top of the city.</charAction> Miles and
            miles of tubes and chutes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to four earthbenders standing beside a platform where one earthen cart
                slides out of the picture and another one filled with vegetables comes into view. As
                the cart passed one earthbender, he uses his bending to change the cart's directing
                and pushes it to the front, where another earthbender bends it up a tube to two
                other earthbenders standing at the ready to receive it. One earthbender quickly
                bends stone lintels underneath the cart so it would not fall down again, while the
                other one thrusts it off the platform, where it slides down a chute at high
                speed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Earthbending brings the packages up, and
            gravity brings them down.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut back to the trio; unimpressed.</charAction> Great, so they get their
            mail on time.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> They do get their mail on time,
                <charAction>Close-up of Aang.</charAction> but my friend Bumi found
                <charAction>Squints eyes mischievously.</charAction> a better use for these
            chutes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene fades to a flashback to a hundred years ago, when Aang visited the
                city before. Back shot of a young Bumi watching over the city. When Aang walks up,
                he excitedly jumps around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Look around you! What do you see?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Unsurely.</charAction> Um ... The mail system?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Pointing his finger in the air and waving it around while Aang walks up
                to him.</charAction> Instead of seeing what they want you to see,
                <charAction>Leaning toward Aang.</charAction> you got to open your brain to the
            possibilities.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Uncomprehending.</charAction> A package-sending system?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Excitedly; camera moves back to show the start of one of the
                chutes.</charAction> The world's greatest superslide!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up of a crazed smiling Bumi, and a broadly smiling
                Aang.</charAction> Bumi, you're a mad genius!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi chuckles with an odd snort as the camera slowly moves to a close-up.
                Cut to a shot of Aang and Bumi riding down the "superslide", happily laughing. Bumi
                throws his hands in the air as they hurtle out of the scene.</description>
      <description>Slowly, the scene fades back to present day; the lush, green tree the duo
                passed, now old, snow-covered and without leaves. The camera moves up the slope,
                where the heads of Aang, with Momo in his wig, Katara and Sokka can be seen above
                the rim. Scene switches to a closer shot, revealing that they are sitting in a mail
                cart. Aang looks excited, while the siblings look around them, unsure and slightly
                frightened.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Raising one finger to emphasize his words; the cart rocking back and
                forth, creaking.</charAction> One ride. Then we're off to the North Pole.
            Airbender's honor.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Uneasy.</charAction> It sounded like fun at first, <charAction>Shot
                switches to a bird's eye view, fully revealing the steepness of the
                chute.</charAction> but now that I'm here, I'm starting to have second
                <charAction>Aang leans forward, tipping the balance of the box, sending it down the
                slope at a tremendous speed, making Katara scream out her last word.</charAction>
            th-o-o-oughts!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of a happily laughing Aang. The camera moves up to reveal Momo in
                Aang's wig, holding on to the hair, squinting his eyes due to the wind. Camera
                shifts to the Water Tribe siblings, Katara screaming in fear, Sokka gritting his
                teeth in terror. Camera moves back as the cart makes a turn, and follows it down the
                slope. The chute they are riding pulls up next to a parallel one, where a cart with
                a rack of six spears is racing down. Switch to a side-view as the cart of the trio
                pulls up next to the cart with the spears and they all stare at it, no one making a
                sound. They race past it and both tracks join together. Sokka and Katara scream as
                the two chutes merge into one chute with the spear-cart behind them, but quickly
                gaining. Sokka hears it coming and turn around. He gasps and ducks just in time to
                avoid being skewered by the spears. Katara turns around, and screams in fear as she
                sees the weapons so close. Aang, smiling excitedly, turns as well to see what the
                commotion is all about.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> I'm on it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a frontal view of the cart, as Aang begins to rock it. Hitting
                each side once, the cart flies out of the chute and onto a roof, where it continues
                its descent.</description>
      <description>Cut to a shot of a soldier talking to his men.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">Men, you'll be going off to combat soon. It's important that you be prepared for
            anything.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, Katara, and Sokka come in riding the cart between the soldier and the
                warriors. The scene freezes for a second at that shot as the sound of a little bell
                can be heard, before continuing. The warriors gasp in surprise as the cart ricochets
                and continues moving. Switch to a scene of other carts moving over a chute. The cart
                with the trio breaks through the railing closing off the other chute and crosses the
                track, knocking over one of the supply carts, spilling a load of pumpkins all over
                the ground. The knocked over cart lies on the track, where another incoming cart
                crashes into it.</description>
      <description>Switch to a shot of a chute as the trio enters it. Switch to a front view
                of the speeding cart.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Scared.</charAction> Aang, do something! Use your airbending!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly.</charAction> Yeah! Good idea! That'll make us go even
            faster!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang airbends behind him. They pass by a restaurant, where a couple is
                eating together. They look up in surprise at the kids flashing by while the waiter
                dashes over to see what is going on. The scene switches to an earthbender soldier
                waiting for the arrival of the next cart. As a cart of scrolls stops in front of
                him, the camera tilts to the right, showing how the cart with the trio is flying
                down an incredibly steep slope. As the slope flattens out, the kids cry out in alarm
                as they are moments from colliding with the motionless cart in front of the bender.
                The earthbender on duty at that station sends it on its way, briefly relieving the
                trio in the speeding cart. Much to the riders' horror, another cart instantly pops
                up from the tube below the bender. Before it can be moved, the kids' cart crashes
                into it, catapulting them and their cart into the air, high above a lower level of
                the city. Aang airbends the cart in front of them as they fall, making them drop
                back into the cart. The kids ride down several roofs, leaving damaged tiles in their
                wake. The scene switches to inside a craftsman's home, where he whistles serenely as
                he puts the final touches on a vase. The cart flies through one window, ricochets
                off of the floor where the vase is, smashing it and making the riders grunt, and
                flying out the window opposite. The craftsman peers out the ruined window as a dust
                cloud emerges, revealing that the cart has crashed against something
                else.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Sorry!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>They land on a balcony and slide through another house. Emerging on the
                other side, a bearded cat chases Momo around Aang's wig until the lemur pushes it
                off. The cart smashes through a parapet and drops vertically out of sight. The view
                changes to the same cabbage merchant that had his cabbage cart thrown into the abyss
                earlier, now cuddling a cabbage at a replacement cart. Alerted by something coming
                from up above, he walks from underneath the cart's roof to check it out, and gasps
                in horror as the kids' cart drops on it, smashing the replacement cart to pieces and
                scattering what intact cabbages are left all over. Aang, Katara, and Sokka are in a
                tangled heap by the remains, while Momo elegantly floats down.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">
         <charAction>Grasping his head in despair.</charAction> My cabbages!
                <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You're gonna pay for this!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Guards walk up, surrounding the still dazed trio. Close-up of Aang as he
                sits up, his disguise pretty much gone, revealing his youthful face and airbending
                arrow.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Sheepishly.</charAction> Two cabbages please.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades to the ceiling of the palace of Omashu. The camera pans
                down, revealing a watch guard in the front, and the King of Omashu sitting on his
                throne, flanked by two guards, in the back of an enormous room. The first watch
                guard slightly moves aside to let the three children pass. Sokka looks very uneasy,
                Katara slants her eyes up in an attempt to look sympathetic, and glances to the
                side. As she gazes at the king, the scene switches to a close-up of the elderly
                king, who looks at them questioningly, arching an eyebrow and grunting in wonder.
                The scene switches to a frontal view of the "visitors" as they are being pushed into
                a kneeling position by two guards.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">Your majesty, these juveniles were arrested for vandalism, traveling under false
            pretenses, and malicious destruction of cabbages.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">
         <charAction>Jumping agitatedly up and down, waving his left fist in the
                air.</charAction> Off with their heads! One for each head of cabbage!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Gesturing at the merchant.</charAction> Silence! Only the king can pass
            down judgment. What is your judgment, sire?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera slowly moves in on the king who squints his eyes and grunts
                pensively. Switch to a close-up of the trio, who uneasily eye each other. A close-up
                of a whimpering Sokka, moves to one of a smiling Katara, her hands folded in front
                of her and her eyes twinkling hopefully. Aang is the only one who keeps staring at
                the side, one eyebrow arched and pouting. Switch to a close-up of the dissimilar
                eyes of the elderly king, before going back to a shot of Aang who now whistles
                nonchalantly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Raising his hand.</charAction> Throw them ... <charAction>Sokka, Katara,
                and Aang gasp.</charAction> a feast!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guard gasps and the merchant grasps his head with both hands in dismay
                upon hearing the king's verdict. Sokka is smiling, while Katara darts a
                questioningly look toward Aang, who arches his eyebrows in wonder. Cut to a
                richly-filled dining table. The camera pans to the right, revealing all sorts of
                different dishes and teapots. Camera zooms in on Momo as he eats a lot of the food,
                chittering contently. Switch to a frontal view of the children sitting at the table,
                the king standing behind their chairs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>To Aang.</charAction> The people in my city have gotten fat from too
            many feasts, <charAction>Leaning in over Aang, grabbing the chicken leg that is on his
                plate, holding it in front of him.</charAction> so I hope you like your chicken with
            no skin.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks, but I don't eat meat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>To Sokka.</charAction> How about you? I bet you like meat.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi stuffs the chicken into Sokka's mouth, who eats it appreciatively, and
                walks over to his own seat.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Quietly to Aang.</charAction> Is it just me, or <charAction>Turns
                circles with her index finger beside her temple, implying the king is
                crazy.</charAction> is this guy's crown a little crooked?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Aerial shot of the dining table as Bumi pulls up to his
                seat.</charAction> So tell me, young bald one, <charAction>Sitting
                down.</charAction> where are you from?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> I'm from ... Kangaroo Island!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Cut to the King, two guards standing watch behind him.</charAction> Oh,
            Kangaroo Island, eh? I hear that place is really hopping!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A moment of silence occurs, someone coughs off camera. Cut to a frontal
                shot of the three children, looking straight at the king with blank faces. Sokka
                bursts out laughing. Katara and Aang look at him, still with a blank
                expression.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Stops laughing; unsure.</charAction> What? It was pretty funny.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Cut back to the king, who lazily stretches his arms, and
                yawns.</charAction> Well, all these good jokes are making me tired. Guess it's time
            to hit the hay.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi eyes the children with a weird expression as he leans to the left on
                his chair. Suddenly, he hurls a chicken leg at them. Close-up of the meat as it
                flies through the air. Cut to a side shot of the three children, as Aang nearly
                tumbles off his chair in reflex of catching the chicken leg in a small airball.
                Switch to guards gasping in surprise. Cut to a side shot of the entire table. Aang
                is still suspending the chicken leg in the airball.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Gesturing at Aang.</charAction> There's an airbender in our presence,
            and not just any airbender. <charAction>Close-up as he decisively stands
                up.</charAction> The Avatar!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of a shocked Aang, who quickly stops bending and puts his hands
                behind his back. The chicken leg falls on his plate. Back shot of the three
                children, as Bumi continues.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Sits down again.</charAction> Now, what do you have to say for yourself,
                <charAction>Close-up, smiling satisfied.</charAction> Mr.
            Pippinpaddleopsicopolis?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera fades to black before cutting to a frontal shot of the entire city
                of Omashu. Cut back to an overview shot from inside the dining room from behind
                Aang, Katara, and Sokka. Momo is still sitting in the middle of the table,
                eating.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Standing up, throwing his hands in the air.</charAction> Okay, you
            caught me. <charAction>Frontal shot of the three friends.</charAction> I'm the Avatar.
            Doing my Avatar thing, keeping the world safe. Everything checks out. <charAction>Aang
                looks underneath table.</charAction> No firebenders here. So, good work, everybody!
                <charAction>Pulling Katara and Sokka into a hug.</charAction> Love each other,
                <charAction>Cut to a dismayed looking king.</charAction> respect all life,
                <charAction>Cut to a shot of the threesome walking backward toward the
                exit.</charAction> and don't run with your spears. We'll see you next time!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As they near the guard at the exit door, the two men cross their spears,
                effectively blocking their paths. Camera zooms back to a back shot of the
                king.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Accusingly.</charAction> You can't keep us here! Let us leave!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Frontal shot of the king as he questioningly picks up a lettuce leaf from
                his plate and waves it in the air.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Lettuce leaf?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Switch to a side shot of Bumi's mouth as he takes a bite out of a lettuce
                leaf and chews it slowly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cut to the threesome. Sokka holds his hand for his mouth;
                whispering.</charAction> We're in serious trouble. This guy is
                <description>nuts.</description>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Close-up.</charAction> Tomorrow, the Avatar will <charAction>Slowly
                zooming in close-up of Aang.</charAction> face three deadly challenges.
                <charAction>Back to Bumi.</charAction> But for now, the guards will show you to your
            chamber.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chamberlain">
         <charAction>Leaning in toward Bumi.</charAction> My liege, do you mean the good
            chamber or the bad chamber?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Turning to the guard.</charAction> The newly refurbished
            chamber.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Chamberlain">
         <charAction>Putting finger in the air.</charAction> Wait, which one are we talking
            about?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">The one that used to be the bad chamber, until the recent refurbishing, that is. Of
            course, we've been calling it the new chamber, but we really should number them.
                <charAction>Switch to a frontal shot of the three children as they are being led out
                of the room, flanked by two guards. Commanding.</charAction> Uh, take them to the
            refurbished chamber that was once bad!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>As the children and their guards walk out of the room, the camera rapidly
                zooms in on Bumi's face. He stares at them before chewing on a new lettuce leaf. The
                scene changes to inside a room. A wall cracks and moves down, revealing Aang with
                Momo perched on his shoulders, Katara, and Sokka. They are roughly pushed inside,
                and the wall is immediately bent up again after them. Switch to a scene of the room,
                panning to the left, revealing the content of the room, and the fact that there is
                no door anywhere. The room has three green beds in the center with three green
                drapes hanging from the ceiling above them. The scene stops on the
                children.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">This is a prison cell? But it's so nice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Momo jumps off Aang's shoulders and onto a bed.</charAction> He did say
            it was newly refurbished.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nice or not, we're prisoners!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Close-up; worried.</charAction> I wonder what these challenges are gonna
            to be.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Determined.</charAction> We're not sticking around to find out. There's
            got to be some way out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Excitedly pointing at something at the other side of the
                room.</charAction> The air vents!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene quickly moves around the room and halts at a hole in the wall. Cut
                back to the trio. Aang smiles happily, staring at the hole, while Katara and Sokka
                eye each other in wonder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Harshly.</charAction> If you think we're going to fit through there,
            you're crazier than that king.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Turning to Sokka.</charAction> We can't, but Momo can!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Happily points in front of him. Cut to Momo lazily lying on the bed,
                licking a half-eaten apple. His belly protrudes from eating so much. Aang appears at
                the side of the bed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Hopeful.</charAction> Momo, I need you to find Appa and bust us outta
            here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo looks up surprised to his friend, blinking and chittering softly. Cut
                to a shot from inside the air vent looking out. Momo's head appears and the animal
                is pushed inside the tube. The animal is shoved back and forth a few times, much to
                its displeasure. Cut to Aang standing on a chair, trying to push Momo into the air
                vent without success.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Go on, boy, get Appa!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang quits trying, looking down discouraged, leaving Momo stuck in the
                vent. Cut to Sokka who is relaxing on a bed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Eh, how was Appa supposed to save us anyway?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Momo trying to free himself by pushing against the wall with his
                hind legs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Appa's a ten-ton flying bison; I think he could
            figure something out.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Momo was unsuccessful and gives up, his hind legs hanging down in defeat.
                Cut to an overview shot of the three beds.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Climbing into her bed.</charAction> Well, no point arguing about it now.
            Get some rest, Aang. <charAction>Aang walks toward his bed.</charAction> Looks like
            you'll need it for tomorrow.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang sadly sits on the side of his bed, looking down. Switch to the next
                scene of Aang lying on his bed, snoring loudly and drooling on his pillow. The room
                is only dimly lit, casting a somewhat green glow. The wall behind Aang opens,
                revealing a guard. The crunching sound of the earth being moved wakes Aang, who
                quickly raises his head and glances around.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Alarmed.</charAction> Sokka? <charAction>Switch to Aang's point of view;
                the other beds are empty.</charAction> Katara? <charAction>Frontal shot as Aang
                turns toward the guard.</charAction> Where are my friends?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> The king will free them if you complete your
            challenges.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Frontal shot; unsure.</charAction> And if I fail?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Guard">
         <charAction>Frontal shot.</charAction> He didn't say. <charAction>Extending his arm;
                switch back to a shot of the guard.</charAction> Your staff, please?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang lifts his staff with his foot, grabs it, and spins it around, places
                it upright next to him, before tossing it to the guard. Switch to a frontal shot of
                Aang, flanked by two guards, entering the large throne room. The scene slightly pans
                to the left, showing a bit of King Bumi's back.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Serious.</charAction> First, Avatar, <charAction>Frontal shot as Bumi
                spread his arms, showing off his purple outfit; lighthearted.</charAction> what do
            you think of my new outfit? I want your honest opinion. <charAction>Frontal shot of Aang
                who blankly stares at the king. Someone coughs during the ensuing silence. Switch
                back to a frontal shot of Bumi.</charAction> I'm waiting.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Scratching his head.</charAction> I ... guess it's fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Excellent! You passed the first test.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Really?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Upbeat.</charAction> Well, not one of the deadly tests.
                <charAction>Waving his finger from side to side, emphasizing his words.</charAction>
            The real challenges are much more, uh, challenging.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to a side shot of Aang as he suddenly dashes forward to the surprise of
                his two guards. Using his airbending, his speed is enhanced. Close-up of his feet as
                he quickly crosses the distance between him and King Bumi. Cut to a back shot of
                Bumi as Aang halts in front of him, the wind passing over them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aggressively.</charAction> I don't have time for your crazy games!
                <charAction>Close-up of King Bumi.</charAction> Give me my friends back! We're
            leaving!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Oh, I thought you might refuse, <charAction>Side shot of the two. A wall opens,
                revealing Katara and Sokka struggling in the grasp of a guard. Aang turns to
                them.</charAction> so I will give your friends some special souvenirs.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang looks back at Bumi. Cut to a frightened Katara as her guard slides a
                green ring over her finger. Close-up of the ring being put on. The moment the guard
                retracts his hand, the ring glows and tightens around her finger. The scene
                broadens, showing Sokka has gotten a ring as well, his being blue, and is now
                frantically trying to remove it from his finger. Katara tries to pull it off as
                well, both are unsuccessful.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Those delightful rings are made of pure
            jennamite, also known as creeping crystal. It's a crystal that grows remarkably fast.
                <charAction>Close-up of Bumi; sinister.</charAction> By nightfall your friends will
            be completely covered in it. <charAction>Slightly sympathetic.</charAction> Terrible
            thing, really. <charAction>Serious.</charAction> I can stop it, but only if you
            cooperate.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi glances toward the siblings. Cut to a shot of Sokka's finger now
                donning a blue jennamite ring. The ring glows and expands toward his
                hand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Panicking.</charAction> Ah! It's already creeping!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Cut back to a side shot of Aang and Bumi; serious.</charAction> I'll do
            what you want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Close-up of an evil grinning Bumi. Scene changes to a cave filled with
                stalagmites and stalactites. Camera pans to the left where Aang stands on a flat
                rock with a waterfall in front of him. In the waterfall, there is a ladder, and
                above the ladder hangs a rope. Sokka, Katara, and Bumi are on a balcony cut into the
                wall to the left of the waterfall. King Bumi is laughing. Cut to a frontal shot of
                the king looking over the balcony rim. Katara and Sokka are guarded behind him. The
                jennamite ring has already expanded to engulf part of their right forearm. Bumi
                glances back at the siblings with a grin on his face. Close-up of the jennamite as
                it glows and creeps a bit further on the arms of Sokka and Katara. Switch to a back
                shot of Bumi as he is looking out toward where Aang is standing.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">It seems I've lost my lunch box key and I'm hungry. Ooh, there it is!
                <charAction>Bumi points to inside the waterfall.</charAction> Would you mind
            fetching it for me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The key hanging from a chain and a vertical iron ladder are dimly visible
                behind the waterfall. Aang airbends to the base of the fall and plunges into the
                waterfall. He manages to climb up the rock face to the base of the ladder and grasp
                it with one hand. Before he can get any further, the torrent of water pushes him
                away and out.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Ooh, climbing the ladder. No one's thought
            of that before.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Panting, Aang rests a moment between two stalagmites, leaps from them to
                the stalactites above, and closer to the waterfall still high by the roof of the
                cavern. He dives into the fall above the key and tries to grab the key as he falls
                with the water; the rush of the water carries him past and in a moment he shoots out
                again, keyless.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">That's right. Keep diving head in. I'm sure it'll work eventually.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang cuts a stalagmite with airbending and throws it like a spear at the
                key, accelerating it with another air blast. The stone spear snags the chain
                suspending the key, and carries it out of the waterfall. The spear pierces the stone
                wall above the King's balcony, the key now dangling right in front of
                Bumi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">There! Enjoy your lunch! I want my friends back now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Ah, not yet. I need help with another matter. It seems I've lost my pet,
            Flopsie.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to Aang in a large sunken enclosure in a new room, with Bumi,
                Katara, and Sokka up above. Aang finds a lop-eared bunny.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay! Found him!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Bring him to me. Daddy wants a kiss from Flopsie!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come here, Flopsie. <charAction>Flopsie jumps down behind Aang, startling both him
                and the bunny.</charAction> Huh?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Squealing with terror, the bunny bolts across the arena with Aang in
                pursuit until it goes into a hole. Aang puts his arm in the hole up to the shoulder
                trying to grab hold of the frightened rabbit. The light dawns on his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Flopsie, wait! Flopsie! <charAction>Cut to Bumi laughing. Back to Aang chasing the
                bunny.</charAction> Flopsie!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang puts his arm in the hole up to the shoulder trying to grab hold of the
                frightened rabbit. The light dawns on his face. The snarling goat gorilla bounds
                toward Aang but instead of attacking, picks him up and licks him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait a minute. <charAction>Close-up of Flopsie snarling. Cut to behind
                Aang.</charAction> Flopsie?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The snarling goat gorilla bounds toward Aang but instead of attacking,
                picks him up and licks him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Flopsie!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Flopsie puts Aang down and, obeying a whistle from the king, climbs up from
                the arena to him and rolls onto his back, offering his belly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Rubbing Flopsie's belly.</charAction> Oh, that's a good boy. Yes, who
            has a soft belly?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Aang jumps up to where Katara and Sokka. Both are encased in crystal to
                their shoulders.</charAction> Guys, are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Other than the crystals slowly encasing my entire body, doing great!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>At that moment, a crystal grows on one side of Sokka's body, making him
                become unbalanced and fall. Aang walks over to Bumi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">
         <charAction>Rubbing Flopsie's belly.</charAction> Oh, yes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Come on! I'm ready for the next challenge.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The king gives an evil laugh and the scene dissolves to an earthbending
                arena. Aang and the king are on a balcony overlooking the arena, Sokka and Katara
                along with a guard are on an adjacent balcony. The crystals are past their heads,
                leaving their faces exposed.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Your final test is a duel. And as a special treat, you may choose your
            opponent.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Two tough-looking men come out, standing next to the king. Aang looks at
                them uncertainly.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Point and choose.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So ... you're saying whoever I point to, that's the person I get to fight?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Choose wisely!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I ... choose ... you. <charAction>Aang points to the king.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Wrong choice!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The king straightens up and removes his outer robe, proving himself to be a
                powerfully built old man. He earthbends Aang off of the balcony, making him fly into
                the arena. The king jumps down right in front of Aang, and laughs.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">You thought I was a frail old man, but I'm the most powerful earthbender you'll ever
            see.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Can I fight the guy with the axe instead?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">There are no take-backsies in my kingdom. You might need this. <charAction>Points to
                the guard standing near Katara and Sokka.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The guard tosses Aang his staff. The king bends several rocks at Aang who
                just avoids and evades the attacks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Typical airbender tactic: avoid and evade. I hoped the Avatar would be less
            predictable.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The king attacks Aang some more. Aang just keeps avoiding and
                evading.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Don't you have any surprises for me? Sooner or later you'll have to strike
            back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang uses his staff to helicopter into the air. The king bends a large
                boulder into the ceiling, raining rocks onto Aang, knocking him from the air. He
                charges at the king on foot, but a series of bending attacks leaves him flat atop a
                large rock pile</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">You'll have to be a little more creative than that!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang bends an air scooter and charges forward on it, throwing a huge air
                blast at the king as he comes. The king throws up a stone barrier and the blast
                deflects to both sides of it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Did someone leave the windows open? It feels a little drafty in here. Are you hoping
            I'll catch a cold?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The king bends more attacks at Aang, leading him across half of the
                arena.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">How are you going to get me from way over there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang charges forward on foot again, using airbending to accelerate but the
                king softens the arena floor, leaving him sunk to the waist. The king bends two
                stones to collide on the spot but Aang pops out at the top of them when they meet.
                Visibly angry now, he bends the slab the king is standing on all the way to the back
                of the arena. The king bends the largest boulder yet to come at Aang from behind but
                he does an air-assisted back flip over it. The king makes more bending moves,
                cracking the floors and walls of the arena, tearing out a huge chunk of the wall and
                balcony they had been standing on. Seeing what is coming, Aang gasps and runs in
                tight circles, conjuring a tornado. When the king flings the huge piece at Aang, it
                is caught in the tornado and instantly whips around right back at the king. The king
                bends it to sand before it can smash him, but before he can recover, Aang attacks
                from the top of the tornado, landing at the king's feet with his staff poised to
                strike. The king's arms are raised as if surrendering but a small pebble strikes
                Aang's head, drawing his attention to the large boulder suspended over the both of
                them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Well done, Avatar. You fight with much fire in your heart. <charAction>He tosses the
                boulder aside and bends up to the balcony where the two siblings are almost
                completely encased. Aang joins him.</charAction> You've passed all my tests. Now,
            you must answer one question.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">That's not fair! You said you would release my friends if I finished your
            tests.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Oh, but what's the point of tests if you don't learn anything?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Oh, come on!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Answer this one question and I will set your friends free. What ... is my name? From
            the looks of your friends I'd say you only have a few minutes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi walks out of frame. Aang confers with Katara and Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">How am I supposed to know his name?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Think about the challenges. Maybe it's some kind of riddle.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I got it!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Yeah?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">He's an earthbender, right? Rocky. You know, because of all the rocks.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're going to keep trying, but that is a good back-up.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Okay. So back to the challenges. I got a key from the waterfall, I saved his pet,
            and I had a duel.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">And what did you learn?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, everything was different than I expected.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>The jennamite grows as she talks with anxiety.</charAction>
            And?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Well, they weren't straight forward. To solve each test, I had to think differently
            than I usually would. I know his name.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to Aang confronting Bumi.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I solved the question the same way I solved the challenges. As you said a long time
            ago, I had to open my brain to the possibilities. <charAction>The king laughs with the
                same odd snort Bumi did a hundred years ago.</charAction> Bumi, you're a mad
            genius.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang and Bumi hug like old friends.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Oh Aang, it's good to see you. You haven't changed a bit. Literally.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Uh, over here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Little help?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Bumi breaks the crystals using earthbending, making pieces fly everywhere.
                He catches one of them.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Jennamite is made of rock candy. <charAction>He takes a bite into the
                crystal.</charAction> Delicious!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">So this crazy king is your old friend Bumi?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">Who are you calling old? Okay, I'm old.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Why did you do all of this instead of just telling Aang who you were?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Bumi">First of all, it's pretty fun messing with people. <charAction>Snorts.</charAction>
            But I do have a reason. Aang, you have a difficult task ahead. The world has changed in
            the hundred years that you've been gone. It's the duty of the Avatar to restore balance
            to the world by defeating Fire Lord Ozai. You have much to learn. You must master the
            four elements and confront the Fire Lord. And when you do, I hope you will think like a
            mad genius. And it looks like you're in good hands. You'll need your friends to help
            defeat the Fire Nation. <charAction>Momo climbs up on Aang.</charAction> And you'll need
            Momo, too.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thank you for your wisdom, but before we leave, I have a challenge for you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Scene changes to show Bumi and Aang riding down the mail system. Cut to
                view of the entire city. A cloud of dust is raised as a crash is
                heard.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Cabbage merchant">My cabbages!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
