<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
   <metadata>
      <title>The Southern Raiders</title>
   </metadata>
   <section>
      <description>The episode opens to morning at the Western Air Temple. Cuts to overhead
                shot of the team's campsite, the camera panning downward slightly, showing their
                sleeping bags all arranged in a circular form. Cuts to overhead shot of Suki and
                Chit Sang sleeping, Chit Sang snoring. The camera pans to the right to reveal Hakoda
                asleep next to Chit Sang. Cuts to ground-level shot of Teo asleep, The Duke and Zuko
                in the background also in a slumber.</description>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Aang asleep on Appa as he wakes up, yawning and rubs his
                eyes. Cuts to shot of the nearby fountain from the view of their campsite, several
                birds fluttering about. The birds suddenly fly away as a bomb is launched their way,
                splashing through the waterfall fountain. Cuts to Aang, who grows suddenly alert,
                before switching to shot of Appa as the Avatar rises and uses his glider to airbend
                the bomb away. Cuts to overhead shot of the temple as the bomb explodes. Two more
                bombs pelt the building. Cuts to campsite, where everyone is now fully
                awake.</description>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Aang, his back to the camera, as he races toward the edge
                of the building, glider in hand. The camera zooms in past his figure to a shot of a
                Fire Nation airship coming into view. Cuts to side-view of the bow of the airship,
                which launches another bomb that sails through the air and crashes into a nearby
                bridge. Cuts to Aang, who runs back to the campsite, Appa following close behind,
                and uses airbending to force the large, ceiling-high metal doors surrounding their
                site to close. Several bombs continue to assail the temple. Cuts to shot of a
                portion of the ceiling roof, as it begins to crumble and finally caves in. Cuts to
                overhead shot of Katara standing directly beneath the crumbling ceiling. She looks
                up, alarmed, only to be pushed out of the way by Zuko.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>As he runs and pushes her out of harm's way.</charAction> Watch
            out!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the two as they roll across the floor, the debris from the
                ceiling crashing several feet away from them. They finally settle on the
                ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Calmly.</charAction> Keeping rocks from crushing you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Okay, I'm not crushed. You can get off me now!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara rushes out from under Zuko and exits off screen.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I'll take that as a thank you. <charAction>Rises.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to a section of the wall where a hole is bored through. The camera
                zooms out to show Toph and Haru, who have created the exit way using
                earthbending.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">
         <charAction>Pointing to the exit.</charAction> Come on! We can get out through
            here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to overhead shot of the tunnel as everyone begins entering the
                passageway. Aang stays behind, trying to get Appa to leave with him by pulling on
                the bison's reins. The camera zooms out, as he spots Zuko standing, facing the
                airships.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>To Zuko.</charAction> What are you doing?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Go ahead! I'll hold them off. I think this is a family visit. <charAction>Runs
                off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>In the background, Sokka and Katara run up to him.</charAction> Zuko!
            No!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Come on! We've gotta get out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Aang, Katara, and Sokka begin pulling on the reins together in an attempt
                to budge Appa. Cuts to shot of the doors of the building, which continue to be
                destroyed. Debris continues to fall to the ground as Zuko races toward the doors and
                leaps over to the other side just as another piece of the door falls and shatters.
                Cuts to shot of Zuko running toward the airships. One bomb is launched and lands
                several feet before him where it detonates. Thick gray plumes of smoke rise; after a
                brief moment, Zuko emerges from the smoke cover, unharmed.</description>
      <description>He firebends a large blast from his hand. Cuts to shot of an airship, as it
                receives the blow. Cuts to shot of Zuko standing near the edge of the temple,
                looking at the airships. A podium-like devise suddenly rises; standing atop it is
                Azula. Cuts to shot of the princess, who has an evil, maniacal grin on her
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What are you doing here?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Azula">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> You mean it's not obvious yet? I am about to
            celebrate becoming an only child!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Azula kicks a large blast of flame at her brother. Zuko dodges and runs
                backward into the temple, but falls. Several blasts are sent his way as the temple
                begins to fall apart. He runs toward the airships. As he jumps toward the ship, he
                sends several shots toward Azula, but fails to hit her and jumps onto the airship.
                He falls down into the misty floor below.</description>
      <description>Aang and the group are seen trying to get Appa into the tunnel
                unsuccessfully.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I can't get him to go in there! Appa hates tunnels!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Aang, there's no way we can fly out of here.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We'll have to find a way!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">We need to split up. <charAction>To the others.</charAction> Take the tunnel and get
            to the stolen airship.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns around and suddenly grows angry.</charAction> No!
                <charAction>Walks up to her father.</charAction> The Fire Nation can't separate our
            family again!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">It'll be okay. It's not forever.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara hesitates before hugging her dad and running back to Aang. Sokka and
                Hakoda hug also as Sokka takes Suki and runs with the others. The two groups go
                their separate ways. Toph is seen touching a wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Toph">I can clear that away and we can fly out through there!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">Um, there's an awful lot of fire in that general direction ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">We'll get through. Let's go.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa flies through to the outside of the temple, covered by a shield of
                rock in front. Azula tries to bring him down, only for the shield to absorb the
                blasts. Appa escapes and the shield disintegrates. Behind Azula, a second airship
                rises, revealing Zuko survived his fall by getting onto another
                airship.</description>
      <description>Zuko and Azula face off. Zuko makes the first move. He jumps toward Azula,
                who sends columns of fire at him, which he responds to with more blasts. The two
                attack each other several times.</description>
      <description>Scene changes to Appa, dodging fire blasts, as Katara deflects several
                large whips of fire with her waterbending. The group rises above the airship to
                avoid more fire.</description>
      <description>Back on the airship. Azula and Zuko are evenly matched until they both hit
                each other with fire-packed punches, launching them both off the airship. Zuko is
                caught by Katara, but Azula is left falling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">She's ... not gonna make it ... <charAction>Azula uses her firebending to propel
                herself toward the wall, stopping her fall with her hair pin and saving
                herself.</charAction> Of course she did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Azula, who stands on the side of the cliff, smiling evilly.
                Cuts to shot of her watching as the team escapes, her back to the camera. The scene
                switches to where the gang is camping outside.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wow, camping ... it really seems like old times again, doesn't it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Jokingly.</charAction> If you really want it to feel like old times, I
            could, uh ... chase you around a while and try to capture you. <charAction>He smiles and
                the rest of the group laughs, except for Katara.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Ha, ha.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding up his cup.</charAction> To Zuko! Who knew after all those times
            he tried to snuff us out, today he'd be our hero?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Team Avatar">
         <charAction>Everybody except Katara holds up their cups.</charAction> Hear! Hear!
                <charAction>Aang nudges him with his elbow, before Toph lightly punches
                him.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Smiling.</charAction> I'm touched. <charAction>Stops
                smiling.</charAction> I don't deserve this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Yeah, no kidding. <charAction>Walks
                away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">What's with her?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I wish I knew. <charAction>Follows her.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of the entire campsite.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> What's with him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of a waxing gibbous moon, partially obscured by the clouds.
                Cuts to a shot of Katara sitting on a rock and overlooking a rocky cliff, Zuko
                approaching her from behind. She catches sight of him, immediately grows
                antagonistic, and rises to walk farther away toward the cliff.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">This isn't fair! Everyone else seems to trust me now! What is it with you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Turns around; furiously.</charAction> Oh, everyone trusts you now! I was
            the first person to trust you! <charAction>Places her left hand on her
                heart.</charAction> Remember, back in Ba Sing Se. <charAction>Points to the
                ocean.</charAction> And you turned around and betrayed me, betrayed all of
            us!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Closes eyes in resentment.</charAction> What can I do to make it up to
            you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of her and Zuko standing on the cliff as she approaches him
                while snapping at him angrily.</charAction> You really want to know? Hmm, maybe you
            could reconquer Ba Sing Se in the name of the Earth King. <charAction>Cuts to side-view
                of her and Zuko.</charAction> Or, I know! You could bring my mother back!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara storms away, slightly hitting his left shoulder with her right one
                as she passes Zuko, leaving him disappointed. Cuts to shot of entire cliff side, the
                waves crashing against the rocky wall. The scene switches to the campsite where Zuko
                accidentally runs into Suki on his way to confront Sokka.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">
         <charAction>Embarrassed.</charAction> Oops, wrong tent!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Sorry, do you need to talk to Sokka, too?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Suki">Nope, not me! <charAction>Walks away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Zuko enters the tent, a look of disbelief spreading across his
                face.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Holding a rose in his mouth, surrounded by lit candles.</charAction>
            Well, hello ... <charAction>Surprised to find Zuko in his tent, destroying the rose in
                his mouth.</charAction> Uh, Zuko! Yes, why would I be expecting anyone different?
                <charAction>Painfully swallows rose petals and thorns.</charAction> So what's on
            your mind?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Your sister. She hates me! And I don't know why, but I do care what she thinks of
            me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Nah, she doesn't hate you. Katara doesn't hate anyone. Except maybe some people in
            the Fire Nation. <charAction>His eyes widen as he realizes his mistake.</charAction> No,
            I mean, uh, not people who are good, but used to be bad. I mean, bad people. Fire Nation
            people who are still bad, who've never been good and probably won't be, ever!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Interrupting him.</charAction> Stop. Okay, listen. I know this may seem
            out of nowhere, but I want you to tell me what happened to your mother.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Slightly taken aback.</charAction> What? Why would you want to know
            that?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Katara mentioned it before when we were imprisoned together in Ba Sing Se, and again
            just now when she was yelling at me. I think somehow she's connected her anger at that
            to her anger at me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Sadly.</charAction> It's not a day I like to remember.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>A flashback is shown of a younger Katara having a snowball fight with her
                brother. Sokka peers over a snow wall and prepares to throw a snowball at his sister
                only to be hit by a snowball thrown by a younger Katara, off-screen. Cuts to shot of
                Katara, who giggles joyfully. Cuts to shot of Sokka, who climbs over the snow wall,
                carrying an exceptionally large snowball. He drops it, however, upon witnessing
                blackened snow falling from the sky.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">I'm going to find Mom! <charAction>Runs off.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Many of the warriors had seen the black snow
            before and they knew what it meant: a Fire Nation raid. <charAction>A battle scene is
                depicted of Water Tribe Warriors and Fire Nation soldiers charging and attacking one
                another.</charAction> We were badly outnumbered, but somehow, we managed to drive
            them off. As quickly as they came, they just left.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cuts to shot of Sokka tossing his boomerang toward the retreating soldiers.
                The scene switches back to present day.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">I was so relieved when it was over, but that's because I didn't know yet what had
            happened. I didn't know we had lost our mother.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Wait. Can you remember any details about the soldiers who raided your village? Like
            what the lead ship looked like?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Yeah ... sea ravens. <charAction>Scene shows flashback of three red flags waving in
                the breeze, bearing sea ravens.</charAction> The main ship had flags with sea ravens
            on them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">The symbol of the Southern Raiders. Thanks, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Urging Zuko hurriedly out of the tent.</charAction> No problem. Thanks
            for stopping by! <charAction>Zuko leaves.</charAction> I'd thought he'd never leave.
                <charAction>Peaks head out excitedly and whispers.</charAction> Suki!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Unfortunately for him, Zuko has barely taken two steps away from the tent
                and is looking curiously at Sokka. Sokka pretends to be completely oblivious and
                whistles. The next day, Katara emerges from her tent to find Zuko waiting outside,
                sitting on a rock.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> You look terrible.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I waited out here all night.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Brushing her hair.</charAction> What do you want?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">I know who killed your mother, <charAction>She abruptly stops.</charAction> and I'm
            going to help you find him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara casts him a look of shock, which soon turns to a look of
                anger.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to later in the day where Aang is feeding Appa hay. Sokka
                fiddles around with a flower necklace. Katara and Zuko approach the bison, Zuko
                carrying a sack slung over his shoulder.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I need to borrow Appa.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Jokingly.</charAction> Why? Is it your turn to take a little field trip
            with Zuko?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yes, it is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Slightly surprised.</charAction> Oh. What's going on?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">We're going to find the man who took my mother from me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka pauses and stands up, surprised.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Sokka told me the story of what happened. I know who did it and I know how to find
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Um ... and what exactly do you think this will accomplish?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Shakes her head in dismay.</charAction> Ugh, I knew you wouldn't
            understand. <charAction>Begins to walk away.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Wait! Stop! I do understand. You're feeling unbelievable pain and rage. How do think
            I felt about the sandbenders when they stole Appa? How do you think I felt about the
            Fire Nation when I found out what happened to my people?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">She needs this, Aang. This is about getting closure and justice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I don't think so. I think it's about getting revenge.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Angrily.</charAction> Fine, maybe it is! Maybe that's what I need! Maybe
            that's what he deserves!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, you sound like Jet.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's not the same! Jet attacked the innocent. This man, he's a monster.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">Katara, she was my mother, too, but I think Aang might be right.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Then you didn't love her the way I did!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Hurt.</charAction> Katara!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">The monks used to say that revenge is like a two-headed rat viper. While you watch
            your enemy go down, you're being poisoned yourself.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">That's cute, but this isn't air temple preschool. It's the real world.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Now that I know he's out there ... now that I know we can find him, I feel like I
            have no choice.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara, you do have a choice: forgiveness.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">That's the same as doing nothing!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">No, it's not. It's easy to do nothing, but it's hard to forgive.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's not just hard, it's impossible. <charAction>Cuts to overhead shot of the field
                as she walks away, Zuko following behind.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to later that night where Katara is seen dressed in a
                black cloak, tying her hair in a ponytail. Aang and Sokka watch her from behind a
                rock before emerging from behind it.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">So you were just gonna take Appa anyway?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Yes.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It's okay, because I forgive you. <charAction>Pauses.</charAction> That give you any
            ideas?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Don't try to stop us.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I wasn't planning to. This is a journey you need to take. You need to face this man.
                <charAction>Katara situates herself on Appa's head.</charAction> But when you do,
            please don't choose revenge. Let your anger out, and then let it go. Forgive
            him.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Sarcastically.</charAction> Okay, we'll be sure to do that, guru
            goody-goody. <charAction>Climbs aboard Appa.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Thanks for understanding, Aang. Yip-yip. <charAction>Appa takes flight; Aang and
                Sokka look up at the departing bison, their backs facing the
            camera.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">You know, you're pretty wise for a kid.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Thanks, Sokka.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of the two standing together looking up.</charAction>
            Usually it's annoying, but right now, I'm impressed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">I appreciate that.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Sokka">So, can I borrow Momo for a week?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">
         <charAction>Surprised.</charAction> Why do you need Momo?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sokka simply shrugs.</description>
      <description>The scene changes to Zuko and Katara flying on Appa, heading straight for
                the camera.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We need to find the Fire Navy communication tower. All the navy's movements are
            coordinated by messenger hawk. And every tower has to be up to date on where everyone is
            deployed.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of the communication tower situated on an island in the
                middle of the ocean; off-camera.</charAction> So once we find the communication
            tower, we bust in and take the information we need.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> Not exactly. We need to be stealthy and make
            sure no one spots us, <charAction>Cuts to shot of the communication tower, the camera
                panning downward.</charAction> otherwise they'll warn the Southern Raiders long
            before we reach them.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene switches to where Zuko and Katara run out from behind a mass of
                large rocks. Using waterbending, Katara creates a raft of ice for her and Zuko to
                ride on to the communication tower. The scene cuts to a corridor of tower where the
                two are crouched in a corner, watching two guards walk out a door. After the guards
                have passed, they stealthily run through the open door. The scene cuts to a female
                guard sitting at a writing desk. The duo peers at her from overhead gratings. Katara
                waterbends the ink onto the guard's hands. She rises from the desk and walks away.
                Katara and Zuko use the time to comb through the files stored in the
                drawers.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Okay, Southern Raiders. <charAction>Opens a scroll.</charAction> Bam.
                <charAction>Points to location on map; off-camera.</charAction> On patrol near
            Whaletail Island.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cuts to shot of Zuko and Katara looking at the map.</charAction>
            Whaletail Island, here we come.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to the next morning. Zuko arises from his sleep and looks
                at Katara steering Appa. She has dark circles under her eyes from lack of
                sleep.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You should get some rest. We'll be there in a few hours. You'll need all your
            strength.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, don't you worry about my strength. I have plenty. I'm not the helpless little
            girl I was when they came.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene fades into a flashback of the Southern Raiders'
                attack.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">I'm going to find Mom.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She runs nervously past her brother. Several Water Tribe warriors are shown
                running about in a frantic motion. The camera focuses on Katara again, who arrives
                at their igloo and pushes back the curtain.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">Mom!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She runs in to discover her mother seated on the floor, a man towering over
                her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">Just let her go and I'll give you the information you want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">You heard your mother. Get out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">Mommy, I'm scared.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">Go find your dad, sweetie. I'll handle this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara gazes into the menacing eyes of the Southern Raiders commander and
                runs off. The scene changes to her sprinting across the snowy
                battlefield.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Voice-over.</charAction> I ran as fast as I could.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">
         <charAction>Arrives to where her father is battling Fire Nation
                soldiers.</charAction> Dad, Dad! Please, I think Mom's in trouble! There's a man in
            our house!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Hakoda">Kya!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two run to their house frantically. Hakoda pushes back the blue drapes
                before the scene fades to white back to present day.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But we were too late. When we got there, the man was gone. <charAction>Voice begins
                breaking.</charAction> And so was she.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Your mother was a brave woman.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Clutches her necklace.</charAction> I know.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene changes to later that night, where Zuko has taken command of Appa
                and Katara is sleeping on Appa's saddle. Zuko is looking through a
                telescope.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">There! <charAction>Katara looks up.</charAction> See those sea raven flags?
                <charAction>Tosses the telescope to Katara.</charAction> It's the Southern
            Raiders.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Determined.</charAction> Let's do this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Appa submerges underwater, Katara waterbending an air bubble around his
                head so they can breathe. The camera cuts to a shot of a group of Fire Nation
                soldiers having a conversation on the deck of the ship.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Soldier">So there I was, and I was like, 'You know ...'</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He yells as a large water whip emerges from the surface and coils around
                his body, dragging him off the ship. The other soldiers run to the source of the
                incident in shock. Appa surfaces and Katara waterbends two huge waves at the ship.
                The others turn around to see the torrent of water flood the ship, washing them
                overboard. Appa lands on the deck. One soldier, who has managed to stay aboard the
                ship, attacks Katara, who pushes him away with a gush of water. She and Zuko make
                their way through the corridors of the ship, Katara's arms covered in water for
                defense. One soldier bursts from his cabin, a sword in hand only to be attacked and
                locked back inside by Zuko. Katara follows him to a large doorway, where they
                abruptly halt.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">This is it, Katara. Are you ready to face him?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara pulls down her face mask and lets out a cry as she sends a powerful
                stream of water toward the door. The scene changes to the inside of the room, the
                door having been knocked down by the impact of the water. The Southern Raiders
                commander attempts to attack Zuko, who only deflects his firebending
                attacks.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Raiders commander">Who are you?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You don't remember her? You will soon, trust me.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The Southern Raiders commander prepares to strike once more, however, his
                hand fails to move and begins trembling.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Raiders commander">What's ... <charAction>He attempts to control his arm which bends about
                uncontrollably.</charAction> happening to me?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera focuses on Katara using bloodbending on him. With swift motions,
                she forces him to the ground. Zuko looks on at her, momentarily stunned before
                turning his attention back to the commander.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Think back. Think back to your last raid on the Southern Water Tribe.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Raiders commander">
         <charAction>Helplessly subdued.</charAction> I don't know what you're talking about.
            Please, I don't know!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">
         <charAction>Bending down closer to the commander.</charAction> Don't lie! You look
            her in the eye and you tell me you don't remember what you did.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara bloodbends him, fixing him into a position where the Southern
                Raiders commander looks right into her eyes. She gives him a cold, hard stare. The
                camera closes up on one of the commander's eyes before cutting to where Katara's
                face has changed from one of hate to one of shock.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">It's not him. <charAction>She frees him from her grip.</charAction> He's not the
            man.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">What? What do you mean he's not? He's the leader of the Southern Raiders! He has to
            be the guy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara remains silent and begins walking away. Zuko grabs the weak
                commander and pins him to the wall.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">If you're not the man we're looking for, who is?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Southern Raiders commander">You must be looking for Yon Rha. He retired four years ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The camera focuses on Katara, whose eyes are filled with tears. The scene
                changes to a shot of the ground where an anonymous character rakes the soil with a
                trough. Cuts to a side-view shot of a house where a man is tending to his garden.
                The sky is dark and gray with storm clouds. An elderly woman walks up to the open
                door of the house behind him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha's mother">Yon Rha! You lazy piece of work, I need something.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Stops his work and attempts to placate.</charAction> Yes, Mother. What
            is it?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha's mother">The tomato-carrots from your garden are too hard for my gums. I need something soft
            and juicy!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">Would you like something else from the garden? I would be happy to ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha's mother">
         <charAction>Angrily. Her fists clench as she interrupts.</charAction> Forget your
            stupid garden! <charAction>Cut to a close-up of her as she yells at him;
                irritatingly.</charAction> Get your grimy hind to the market and buy me some real
            food!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Cut to the flower bed as Yon Rha stands up. Cut to the back view of Yon Rha
                as he walks toward the town's entrance. Cut to some vegetables on display at a
                stall. The scene changes to where Yon Rha is walking to the marketplace of the
                village, the place almost desolate. Yon Rha enters the screen. He begins to buy
                vegetables from a stand. A wind chime tinkles from one of the other stands. Yon Rha
                sharply turns around to view the suspicious activity. The camera view changes to
                someone ducking behind the stand.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Suspiciously.</charAction> Hello? <charAction>To stand
                owner.</charAction> Did you see someone?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The stand owner shakes his head. Yon Rha is later seen walking back to
                house down some steps. He stops again and looks up.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">Hello? <charAction>Camera view shifts to show someone hiding.</charAction> Is
            someone there?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>He resumes walking again. Katara and Zuko appear from their hiding
                place.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">That was him. That was the monster.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The scene cuts to where Yon Rha is walking, rain beginning to fall. He
                turns and stops once more.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">Nobody sneaks up on me without getting burned! <charAction>Drops basket of
                vegetables and firebends at a nearby bush.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Sensing no one, he picks up the fallen vegetables and continues on his way.
                He unknowingly steps on a thin wire, causing him to fall into the mud. He tries to
                get up only to see a fire blast coming his way which he quickly avoids. Zuko appears
                before him.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">We weren't behind the bush. <charAction>Cut to a side view of the confrontation as
                Zuko takes a step forward to threaten Yon Rha.</charAction> And I wouldn't try
            firebending again!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Cut to Yon Rha on the ground with his arm shielding his face.
                Frightened.</charAction> Whoever you are, take my money. Take whatever you want.
            I'll cooperate.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara walks up to Yon Rha and pulls down her face mask.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Do you know who I am?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">No. I'm not sure.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">Oh, you better remember me like your life depends on it! Why don't you take a closer
            look? <charAction>Camera focuses on front view of her face.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Camera focuses on him.</charAction> Yes, yes, I remember you now.
                <charAction>Focuses on Katara again.</charAction> You're that little Water Tribe
            girl.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Lightning strikes, darkening the screen and flashing back to the incident
                in the igloo with the young Katara, her mother and Yon Rha.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">Just let her go and <charAction>Camera zooms out to show Kya kneeling on the floor
                in front of Yon Rha.</charAction> I'll give you the information you want.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">You heard your mother. Get out of here!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Young Katara">
         <charAction>Holds her hands together.</charAction> Mommy, I'm scared.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">Go find your dad, sweetie. I'll handle this.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Young Katara leaves the igloo. Yon Rha faces Kya again.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">Now tell me, who is it? Who's the waterbender?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">There are no waterbenders here. The Fire Nation took them all away a long time
            ago.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">You're lying. My source says there's one waterbender left in the Southern Water
            Tribe. We're not leaving until we find the waterbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Kya">If I tell you, do you promise <charAction>She lowers her head and closes her eyes to
                make a decision.</charAction> to leave the rest of the village alone?
                <charAction>Cut to a side view of Yon Rha who nods.</charAction> It's me.
                <charAction>Cut to Kya who looks up.</charAction> Take me as your prisoner.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Yon Rha who smiles evilly.</charAction> I'm afraid
            I'm not taking prisoners today ...</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Fade to present day Yon Rha who gulps in terror as the flashback ends.
                Lightning strikes in the background.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">She lied to you! <charAction>Cut to a close-up of Katara who turns away from Yon Rha
                as she closes her eyes sadly.</charAction> She was protecting the last
            waterbender!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Shocked.</charAction> What? Who?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Cut back to Katara who turns to face him again as she opens her eyes and
                looks back furiously.</charAction> Me!</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>She holds both her arms out, halting the falling raindrops and creating a
                shield above the three of them. After a few moments, she sends a forceful stream of
                water at Yon Rha, transforming the stream into a flurry of ice daggers midway
                through her attack. Yon Rha crouches in fear, preparing to be hit. When he does not
                feel harmed, he looks up to see the ice daggers floating in midair. Katara's
                expression softens and she allows for the daggers to liquefy and drop to the
                ground.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Falls to his knees.</charAction> I did a bad thing! I know I did and you
            deserve revenge, so why don't you take my mother? That would be fair!
                <charAction>Attempts to smile weakly.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Sorrowfully.</charAction> I always wondered what kind of person could do
            such a thing, but now that I see you, I think I understand. There's just nothing inside
            you, nothing at all. You're pathetic and sad and empty.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Yon Rha">
         <charAction>Humbly.</charAction> Please, spare me!
            <charAction>Cries.</charAction>
      </speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">But as much as I hate you ... I just can't do it.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Katara closes her eyes and lowers her head. Cut to Yon Rha, a hint of a
                smile gracing his lips upon realizing he will be spared. Without saying another
                word, Katara turns around and walks away; Zuko looks from Katara to Yon Rha,
                shooting the latter a last dirty look, and follows her. Yon Rha continues crying and
                shivering in the rain. The scene cuts to a boardwalk overlooking the water. It is
                later that day. Scene cuts to Katara, who is sitting on the edge of the dock, her
                eyes closed, paddling the water with her feet. She opens her eyes sadly as Aang and
                Zuko approach her.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Katara? Are you okay?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I'm doing fine.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">Zuko told me what you did. Or what you didn't do, I guess. I'm proud of
            you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">I wanted to do it. I wanted to take out all my anger at him, but I couldn't. I don't
            know if it's because I'm too weak to do it or because I'm strong enough not to.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">You did the right thing. Forgiveness is the first step you have to take to begin
            healing.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Katara">
         <charAction>Rises from boardwalk.</charAction> But I didn't forgive him. I'll never
            forgive him. <charAction>Smiles at Zuko and walks up to him.</charAction> But I am ready
            to forgive you.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>The two hug and Katara begins walking away.</description>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">You were right about what Katara needed. Violence wasn't the answer.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Aang">It never is.</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <speech speaker="Zuko">Then I have a question for you. <charAction>Turns to look at him.</charAction> What
            are you gonna do when you face my father?</speech>
   </section>
   <section>
      <description>Camera focuses on Aang, who now has a worried expression on his face. Fades
                to credits.</description>
   </section>
</root>
