<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <characters>
        <char name="aang">
            <origin>Air Nation (</origin>
            <desc>Aang is an Air Nomad who was also the Avatar, master of all four elements. Aang
                was born 100 years before the events of the first season, but was frozen in an
                iceberg after running away from his home in the Air Nation. Aang is a male Air Nomad
                who was successor to Avatar Roku. As a young avatar he knew he was the only person
                capable of bending all four elements and keeping the peace between the nations. As
                an Air Nomad, he only knew how to airbend. So, he began to feel the pressure that
                comes with being an avatar. A little before the 100 year war, Avatar Aang went
                missing after running away from his duties as avatar. While in the avatar state,
                Aang froze himself and his pet bison, Appa, in an iceburg for 100 years. When found
                by two teenagers from the Southern Waterbending Tribe, Katara and Sokka, he emerged.
                Aang was told what had happened to the nations after he left. He realized he needed
                to learn how to bend the other elements to restore order to the nations. Katara,
                Sokka, and Aang go on a quest to help Aang learn the other elements and save the
                world. </desc>
        </char>
        <char name="katara">
            <origin>Water Nation (Southern Water Tribe)</origin>
            <desc>Katara is a waterbender from the Southern Water tribe. As the only waterbender
                living in the tribe, she was rasied by her grandmother along with her brother,
                Sokka. As teenagers Sokka and Katara found Aang, a young Air Nomad Avatar who had
                been frozen in ice with his bison, Appa. Avatar Aang, recently defrosted, was in
                need of a waterbending teacher. Katara was still learning herself, but offered what
                help she could. Katara and Sokka decided to join Aang in his adventure to save the
                world. Sokka is a Southern Water Tribe warrior and the sun of Chief Hakoda and Kya.
                He was born wihtout any bending ability, so he became a fighter for the tribe
                instead. Sokka is the older brother of Katara. Katara and him were raised by their
                grandmother after their mother died and their father went to go fight in the war.
                Sokka was left behind when the other men went to fight in the war. As the oldest
                male in the Southern Water Tribe he was left as their leader, and became responsible
                for everyone in the tribe. </desc>
        </char>
        <char name="sokka">
            <origin>Water Nation (Southern Water Tribe)</origin>
            <desc>Sokka is the older brother of Katara and was born in the Southern Water Tribe.
                Though he does not have any bending powers, he is proficient in physical combat with
                both his sword and boomerang.As the self-proclaimed "plan guy" of the group, Sokka
                was quick to come up with. Though he often acts as the show's comic relief, he tends
                to be serious when the situation calls for it.</desc>
        </char>
        <char name="Azula">
            <origin>Fire Nation</origin>
            <desc>Azula was the princess of the Fire Nation Royal Family, and younger sister of
                Zuko. Azula believed that Zuko was more loved by their mother, so she always strived
                for greatness. She became vindictive, sadistic, and cold over the years. Azula was
                now obsessed with gaining power and recognizition from her father. When she heard
                that the avatar was alive, she went on a search to look for him with her two best
                friends, Mai and Ty Lee. </desc>
        </char>
        <char name="Zuko">
            <origin>Fire Nation</origin>
            <desc>Zuko was born as a prince into the Fire Nation Royal Family. As a member of the
                fire nation and a firebending master, the Avatar is the essential enemy of Zuko.
                Zuko was banished from the fire nation after disrespecting his father. Then, after
                hearing that the avatar had returned, Zuko went on a mission with his uncle, Iroh,
                to find Aang in hopes his banishment would be lifted.</desc>
        </char>
        <char name="Iroh">
            <origin>Fire Nation</origin>
            <desc>Iroh is a retired Fire Nation General, a Grand Lotus of the Order of the White
                Lotus, a former Crown Prince, a firebending master, and the uncle of Zuko. Iroh
                mentors and watches over Zuko. As a firebending master, Iroh has earned his
                repuation by his ability to breathe fire. This earned him the title "The Dragon of
                the West". Iroh and his nephew, Zuko, travel all over the world to find Avatar Aang
                and put an end to him so that the fire nation can contune to rule over the
                nations.</desc>
        </char>
        <char name="Toph">
            <origin>Earth Nation</origin>
            <desc>Toph Beifong is an earthbender, and one to the most powerful at that. Toph was
                born blind, so she was treated differently because of her impairment. However, her
                blindness turned out to be her super power when she discovered earthbending animals
                called badgermoles. Badgemoles are blind too, so through them she learned how to use
                her other senses to improve her bending and "see" vibrations that pass through the
                ground. She was also the first earthbender to learn the extension of "metalbending".
                Unbeknownst to her parents, Toph is known as the "Blind Bandit" to many because of
                her consistent winning reputation in underground earthbending competitions. When she
                learned of Aang's mission to save the world she wasn't interested, but decided to
                join the cause due to her overprotective parents. Toph travelled with Aang and his
                friends as Aang's earthbending coach.</desc>
        </char>
    </characters>
    <nations>
        <nation>
            <name>Water Nation</name>
            <desc>The Water Nation consists of two major tribes, the Northern and Southern tribes.
                The Southern Water Tribe is the less developed of the two, and consists of primative
                huts made from wood and animal skins. The Southern Water Tribe only has one
                waterbender during the events of The Last Airbender, Katara. The Southern Water
                Tribe is located in the south pole. The Northern Water Tribe is located in the North
                pole and is considerably more developed and populated than the Southern Water Tribe.
                The Northern Water Tribe consists of many large buildings shaped from snow and ice.
                The Northern Water Tribe is home to the Ocean and Moon spirits, the two major
                sources of waterbenders power. The Northern Tribe is also home to the majority of
                the remaining waterbenders. The people of the Water Nation were </desc>
            <notChars> Katara, Sokka, Yue</notChars>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name>Earth Nation</name>
            <desc>The Earth Nation, or Earth Kingdom is the largest nation in the world of Avatar.
                The Earth Kingdom is known for its massive walled cities built by earthbenders,
                namely Omashu and Ba Sing Se. The people of the Earth Nation are typically strong,
                proud, and stalwart. They rarely sought conflict when possible. On the surface, the
                Earth Kingdom appeared to be ruled by its king, but in reality most of the Nation's
                decisions were made by the Dai Li, a group of earthbending masters who acted as
                police enforcing martial law over Ba Sing Se after becoming corrupt at the hands of
                Long Feng. During the events of Avatar, however, this corruption was discovered by
                Aang and his companions and the Earth King's power was restored,</desc>
            <notChars>Toph, Suki</notChars>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name>Fire Nation</name>
            <desc>The Fire Nation is the second largest of the four nations, and arguably the most
                powerful. The Fire Nation was led by Fire Lord Ozai, who sought to expand through
                colonialism. The Fire Nation was well known for its factories and pagoda-style
                buildings. The people of the Fire Nation were typically proud, rash, and strict.
                They placed a large emphasis on military power and developed a large number of metal
                war machines that were incredibly advanced for their time.</desc>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name> Air Nation</name>
            <desc/>
        </nation>
    </nations>
    <animals> </animals>
    <locations> </locations>
</xml>
