<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<xml>
    <characters>
        <char name="aang">
            <origin>Air Nation (</origin>
            <desc>Aang is an Air Nomad who was also the Avatar, master of all four elements. Aang
                was born 100 years before the events of the first season, but was frozen in an
                iceberg after running away from his home in the Air Nation. </desc>
        </char>
        <char name="katara">
            <origin>Water Nation (Southern Water Tribe)</origin>
            <desc>Katara is a waterbender and member of the southern water tribe.</desc>
        </char>
        <char name="sokka">
            <origin>Water Nation (Southern Water Tribe)</origin>
            <desc>Sokka is the older brother of Katara and was born in the Southern Water Tribe.
                Though he does not have any bending powers, he is proficient in physical combat with
                both his sword and boomerang.As the self-proclaimed "plan guy" of the group, Sokka
                was quick to come up with. Though he often acts as the show's comic relief, he tends
                to be serious when the situation calls for it.</desc>
        </char>
    </characters>
    <nations>
        <nation>
            <name>Water Nation</name>
            <desc>The Water Nation consists of two major tribes, the Northern and Southern tribes.
                The Southern Water Tribe is the less developed of the two, and consists of primative
                huts made from wood and animal skins. The Southern Water Tribe only has one
                waterbender during the events of The Last Airbender, Katara. The Southern Water
                Tribe is located in the south pole. The Northern Water Tribe is located in the North
                pole and is considerably more developed and populated than the Southern Water Tribe.
                The Northern Water Tribe consists of many large buildings shaped from snow and ice.
                The Northern Water Tribe is home to the Ocean and Moon spirits, the two major
                sources of waterbenders power. The Northern Tribe is also home to the majority of
                the remaining waterbenders. The people of the Water Nation were </desc>
            <notChars> Katara, Sokka, Yue, </notChars>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name>Earth Nation</name>
            <desc>The Earth Nation, or Earth Kingdom is the largest nation in the world of Avatar.
                The Earth Kingdom is known for its massive walled cities built by earthbenders,
                namely Omashu and Ba Sing Se. The people of the Earth Nation are typically strong,
                proud, and stalwart. They rarely sought conflict when possible. On the surface, the
                Earth Kingdom appeared to be ruled by its king, but in reality most of the Nation's
                decisions were made by the Dai Li, a group of earthbending masters who acted as
                police enforcing martial law over Ba Sing Se after becoming corrupt at the hands of
                Long Feng. During the events of Avatar, however, this corruption was discovered by
                Aang and his companions and the Earth King's power was restored,</desc>
            <notChars>Toph, Suki</notChars>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name>Fire Nation</name>
            <desc>The Fire Nation is the second largest of the four nations, and arguably the most
                powerful. The Fire Nation was led by Fire Lord Ozai, who sought to expand through
                colonialism. The Fire Nation was well known for its factories and pagoda-style
                buildings. The people of the Fire Nation were typically proud, rash, and strict.
                They placed a large emphasis on military power and developed a large number of metal
                war machines that were incredibly advanced for their time.</desc>
        </nation>
        <nation>
            <name> Air Nation</name>
            <desc></desc>
        </nation>
    </nations>
    <animals> </animals>
    <locations> </locations>
</xml>
